<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.030</section_number><catch_line>Rates, classifications and service of utilities to be just and reasonable -- Service to be adequate -- Utilities prohibited from energizing power to electrical service where seal is not present. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every utility may demand, collect and receive fair, just and reasonable rates for the services rendered or to be rendered by it to any person. </section><section prefix="2">Every utility shall furnish adequate, efficient and reasonable service, and may establish reasonable rules governing the conduct of its business and the conditions under which it shall be required to render service. </section><section prefix="3">Every utility may employ in the conduct of its business suitable and reasonable classifications of its service, patrons and rates. The classifications may, in any proper case, take into account the nature of the use, the quality used, the quantity used, the time when used, the purpose for which used, and any other reasonable consideration. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (2) of this section, no utility shall energize power to an electrical service in a manufactured home or mobile home where the certified installer's seal is not present pursuant to KRS 227.570. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (2) of this section, no utility shall energize power to an electrical service in a previously owned manufactured home or previously owned mobile home where the Class B1 seal is not present pursuant to KRS 227.600. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2009. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective March 29, 1976. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3952-28, 3952-29. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14047</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>