<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1">BOUNDARIES </unit></structure><section_number>1.020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983, which is hereby adopted, means a system of plane coordinates which have been established by the National Ocean Service/National Geodetic Survey for defining and stating the geographic positions or locations of points on the surface of the earth within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">For this system, the Commonwealth shall be divided into a north zone and a south zone. The north zone shall be a Lambert conformal conic projection of the North American Datum of 1983, having standard parallels at north latitudes 37 degrees, 58 minutes, and 38 degrees, 58 minutes along which parallels the scale shall be exact. The origin of coordinates shall be at the intersection of the meridian 84 degrees, 15 minutes west of Greenwich, and the parallel 37 degrees, 30 minutes north latitude. This origin shall be given the coordinates: N=0, E=500,000.000 meters. The south zone shall be a Lambert conformal conic projection of the North American Datum of 1983, having standard parallels at north latitudes 36 degrees, 44 minutes, and 37 degrees, 56 minutes along which parallels the scale shall be exact. The origin of coordinates shall be at the intersection of the meridian 85 degrees, 45 minutes west of Greenwich, and the parallel 36 degrees, 20 minutes north latitude. This origin shall be given the coordinates: N=500,000.000, E=500,000.000 meters. The southern edge of the following counties shall delineate the boundary between the north zone and the south zone: Bullitt, Spencer, Anderson, Woodford, Jessamine, Fayette, Clark, Montgomery, Menifee, Morgan, and Lawrence. </section><section prefix="3">One U. S. survey foot equals (1200)/(3937) meter. For conversion of meters to U. S. survey feet, multiply the meters by 3.28083333333 to twelve (12) significant figures. When converting from meters to feet, the conversion factor defined by the U. S. survey foot shall be used. </section><section prefix="4">The plane coordinate values for a point on the earth's surface, used to express the geographic position or location of the point in the appropriate zone of this system, shall consist of two (2) distances expressed in U. S. survey feet and decimals of a foot when using the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983. For the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983, one (1) of the distances, to be known as the "northing" or "N", shall give the position in a north/south direction. The other, to be known as the "easting" or "E" shall give the position in an east/west direction. These coordinates shall be made to depend upon and conform to plane rectangular coordinates values for the monumented points of the North American National Geodetic Horizontal Network as published by the National Ocean Service/National Geodetic Survey, and whose plane coordinates have been computed on the systems established by the National Ocean Service/National Geodetic Survey. Any such station may be used for establishing a survey connection to the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983. </section><section prefix="5">For purposes of describing the location of any survey station or land boundary corner in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, it shall be considered a complete, legal, and satisfactory description of the location to give the position of the survey station or land boundary corner on the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing contained in this section shall require a purchaser or mortgagee of real property to rely wholly on a land description any part of which depends exclusively upon the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983. </section><section prefix="7">When any tract of land to be defined by a single description extends from one (1) into the other of the two (2) zones, the position of all points on its boundaries may be referred to either of the two (2) zones. The zone which is used shall be named in the description. </section><section prefix="8">No coordinates based on the Kentucky Coordinate System of 1983, purporting to define the position of a point on a land boundary, shall be presented to be recorded in any public land records or deed records unless the point has been tied to an existing monumented horizontal control station established in conformity with the standards of accuracy and specifications for first or second order geodetic surveying as prepared and published by the Federal Geodetic Control Committee of the United States Department of Commerce. The survey used to tie a point into these monumented control stations shall conform to the standards and specifications of a minimum of third order accuracies as set forth by the Federal Geodetic Control Committee. Standards and specifications of the Federal Geodetic Control Committee, or its successor, in force on the date of the survey shall apply. Publishing existing control stations, or the acceptance with intent to publish the newly established stations, by the National Ocean Service/National Geodetic Survey shall constitute evidence of adherence to the Federal Geodetic Control Committee specifications. These requirements may be modified by a duly authorized state agency or local agency to meet local conditions. </section><section prefix="9">The use of the terms "KENTUCKY COORDINATE SYSTEM OF 1983 NORTH ZONE" or "KENTUCKY COORDINATE SYSTEM OF 1983 SOUTH ZONE" on any map, report of survey, or other document shall be limited to coordinates based on the Kentucky Coordinate System as defined in this section. </section><section prefix="10">If any provision of this section or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the invalidity shall not affect other provisions or applications of the section which can be given effect without the invalid provision or application, and to this end the provisions of this section are severable. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>