<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.090</section_number><catch_line>Conservation officers, peace officers, and other persons appointed by the commissioner to enforce chapter -- Authority of such officers and persons. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Conservation officers appointed by the commissioner shall have full powers as peace officers for the enforcement of all of the laws of the Commonwealth, except that they shall not enforce laws other than this chapter and the administrative regulations issued thereunder or to serve process unless so directed by the commissioner in life threatening situations or when assistance is requested by another law enforcement agency. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may appoint other persons to enforce only the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations issued thereunder. Such persons shall have the power to make arrests or issue citations only for violations of this chapter and the administrative regulations issued thereunder. </section><section prefix="3">All other peace officers and their deputies shall enforce the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations issued thereunder. </section><section prefix="4">All persons charged with the enforcement of this chapter and the administrative regulations issued thereunder shall have the right to go upon the land of any person or persons whether private or public for the purpose of conducting research or investigation of game or fish or their habitat conditions or engage in restocking game or fish or in any type of work involved in or incident to game and fish restoration projects or their enforcement or in the enforcement of laws or orders of the department relating to game or fish, while in the normal, lawful and peaceful pursuit of such investigation or work or enforcement, may enter upon, cross over, be upon, and remain upon privately owned lands for such purposes, and shall not be subject to arrest for trespass while so engaged or for such cause thereafter. They may arrest on sight, without warrant, any person detected by them in the act of violating any of the provisions of this chapter. They shall have the same rights as sheriffs to require aid in arresting with or without process any person found by them violating any of the provisions of this chapter and may seize without process anything declared by this chapter to be contraband. No liability shall be incurred by any person charged or directed in the enforcement of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">Conservation officers and other officers charged with the enforcement of this chapter, shall have the authority to call for and inspect the license or tag, bag or creel of any person engaged in any activity for the performance of which a license is required under this chapter, and shall also have the authority to take proper identification of any person, or hunter, or fisherman who is actually engaged in any of these activities, and to call for and inspect any and all firearms and any other device that may be used in taking wildlife and is in the possession of any person so engaged. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall resist, obstruct, interfere with or threaten or attempt to intimidate or in any other manner interfere with any officer in the discharge of his duties under the provisions of this chapter. This subsection shall not apply to a criminal homicide or an assault upon such officer. An assault upon such officer shall be deemed an offense under KRS Chapter 507 or 508, as appropriate. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 424, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 3 -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 7 -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 14 -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 9 -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1954d-9. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>