<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.935</section_number><catch_line>Preparation of standardized written summary of information on alternatives in treatment of breast cancer -- Distribution to patients. </catch_line><order_by>935</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No later than one (1) year after July 13, 1984, the McDowell Cancer Network, Inc., and the James Graham Brown Cancer Center shall jointly develop and submit to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and may periodically update a standardized written summary, in layman's language and in language understood by the patient, of the advantages, disadvantages, risks, and descriptions of all medically efficacious and viable alternatives for the treatment of breast cancer. </section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services, within ninety (90) days of receipt of the summary, shall print and make available to all licensed physicians in the Commonwealth sufficient copies of the standardized written summary for distribution by such physicians to their patients. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receipt of the summary, any physician licensed under the laws of the Commonwealth who treats a patient for any form of breast cancer shall provide the patient with a standardized written summary, as provided under this section, informing the patient of medically efficacious and viable alternative methods of treatment for breast cancer which may include surgical, radiological, or chemotherapeutic treatment or combinations thereof. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 589, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 544, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30695</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>