<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.050</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of applicant for license. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>To be eligible for licensure by the board as a speech-language pathologist or audiologist, the applicant must: <section prefix="1">Be a citizen of the United States or have declared his intention to become a citizen. A statement by the applicant under oath that he is a citizen or that he intends to apply for citizenship when he becomes eligible to make application shall be sufficient proof of compliance with this subsection; </section><section prefix="2">Show evidence of meeting the following professionally accepted academic and practicum standards: <section prefix="a">Master's degree in the area of speech-language pathology or audiology or substantive equivalent. The specific course work for this requirement is to be determined by the board and delineated in the administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="b">Completion of supervised direct clinical practicum with individuals presenting a variety of disorders of communication, the experience being obtained with the training institution or in one (1) of its cooperating programs; and </section><section prefix="c">Completion of postgraduate professional experience as deemed necessary by the board; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Pass the national examinations in speech-language pathology or audiology which are approved by the American Speech and Hearing Association and in effect at the time of application for licensure. Written examinations may be supplemented by such oral examinations as the board shall determine. An applicant who fails his examination may be reexamined at a subsequent examination upon payment of another licensing fee. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 3, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 109, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>March 31, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31896</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>