<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="134" order_by="134">PAYMENT, COLLECTION, AND REFUND OF TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>134.119</section_number><catch_line>Sheriff is collector of taxes -- Means of payment -- Penalties -- Sale of personal property -- Compensation of sheriff. </catch_line><order_by>119</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The sheriff shall be the collector of all state, county, county school district, and other taxing district property taxes unless the payment is directed by law to be made to some other person. The sheriff may contract to collect taxes on behalf of cities, independent school districts, or any other governmental unit with the authority to levy a property tax, if the enabling legislation authorizing imposition of the tax permits the governmental unit to contract for the performance of tax collection duties. </section><section prefix="b">The provisions of this chapter relating to the collection of property taxes shall apply to other property tax collectors to the extent that the governing body of the city, school district, or taxing district appointing the tax collector has not adopted alternative tax collection processes and procedures. </section></section><section prefix="2">Payment to the sheriff may be provided by any commercially acceptable means. The sheriff may limit the acceptable methods of payment to those that ensure that payment cannot be reversed or nullified due to insufficient funds. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The sheriff shall accept payment from the day on which the tax bills are mailed by the sheriff to the taxpayer as provided in KRS 133.220 and 133.230, through the day on which the sheriff files the uncollected tax claims with the county clerk pursuant to KRS 134.122. During this time period, the sheriff may accept full or partial payment for any outstanding taxes or tax claims. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any payments received by the sheriff by mail that: i. Are received after the day on which uncollected tax claims are filed with the county clerk pursuant to KRS 134.122; and ii. Have a postmark that reflects a date on or before the day the uncollected tax claims are filed with the county clerk; </section> shall be accepted and processed, and the amount due shall be the amount due immediately before the transfer of the uncollected tax claims by the sheriff to the county clerk. <section prefix="b">Payments described in this subparagraph may be processed as agreed by the sheriff and county clerk. </section><section prefix="c">Absent an agreement between the sheriff and the county clerk, the payment shall be accepted and processed by the sheriff. </section><section prefix="d">If the sheriff accepts and processes the payment, the sheriff shall notify the county clerk, and the county clerk shall update his or her records to reflect payment of the certificate of delinquency. </section><section prefix="e">The sheriff and the county clerk shall reconcile all transactions addressed by this subparagraph by preparation of an addendum to the original reconciliation provided by the sheriff to the county clerk at the time of transfer. The addendum shall be prepared thirty (30) days after the original transfer, and shall be filed by the county clerk in the clerk's order book. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">All payments received by the sheriff shall be entered immediately by the sheriff on his or her books. Partial payments shall be credited against the total amount due and shall be apportioned by the sheriff among the entities included on the tax bill in the same proportion the amount due to each bears to the amount paid. </section><section prefix="c">The acceptance of any payment before the taxpayer's tax liability has been finally determined shall not imply that the payment was the correct amount due and shall not preclude the assessment and collection of additional taxes due or the refund of any part of the amount paid that is in excess of the amount determined to be due. </section><section prefix="d">The sheriff may accept payment of any tax or tax claim from any other person on behalf of the taxpayer. Any person making a payment on behalf of a taxpayer may, upon the written notarized request of the taxpayer, be treated as a transferee as provided in KRS 134.121. </section><section prefix="e">The sheriff may accept payment of any amount due on a delinquent tax claim from any of the persons described in subparagraphs 1., 2., and 3. of this paragraph without permission of the taxpayer. The person seeking to make the payment shall provide sufficient proof to the sheriff that he or she meets the requirements to pay under this paragraph. The sheriff shall be held harmless if he or she relies upon information provided and accepts payment from a person not qualified to pay under this paragraph. Any person listed in subparagraph <section prefix="1">, 2., or 3. of this paragraph who makes full payment, may, upon written </section>request to the sheriff, be treated as a transferee under KRS 134.121: 1. Any person holding a legal or equitable estate in the real or personal property upon which the delinquent taxes are due, other than a person whose only interest in the property is a lien resulting from ownership of a prior year certificate of delinquency; <section prefix="2">A tenant or lawful occupant of real property, or a bailee or person in possession of any personal property upon which the delinquent taxes are due; or </section><section prefix="3">Any person having a mortgage on real property or a security interest in real or personal property upon which the delinquent taxes are due. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">If, upon expiration of the five percent (5%) penalty period established by KRS 134.015(2)(c), the real property tax delinquencies of a sheriff exceed fifteen percent (15%) of the amount charged to the sheriff for collection, the department may require the sheriff to make additional reasonable collection efforts. If the sheriff fails to initiate additional reasonable collection efforts within fifteen (15) business days following notification from the department that such efforts shall be made, the department may assume responsibility for collecting the delinquent taxes. If the department assumes the responsibility for collecting delinquent taxes, the department shall receive the amounts that would otherwise be paid to the sheriff as fees or commissions for the collection of tax bills. </section><section prefix="5">In collecting delinquent taxes, the sheriff: <section prefix="a">May distrain and sell personal property owned by a delinquent taxpayer in the amount necessary to satisfy the delinquent tax claim. The sale shall be made under execution for cash. If the personal property of the delinquent taxpayer within the county is not sufficient to satisfy the delinquent tax claim, the sheriff may sell so much of the personal property as is available; and </section><section prefix="b">Shall retain any amounts that come into his or her possession payable to a delinquent taxpayer, other than claims allowed for attendance as a witness, and shall apply such amounts to the amount due on the delinquent tax claim. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">As compensation for collecting property taxes the sheriff shall be paid the following amounts, regardless of whether the amounts are collected by the sheriff prior to filing the tax claims with the county clerk, or by the county clerk after the tax claims become certificates of delinquency or personal property certificates of delinquency: <section prefix="1">From the Commonwealth the sheriff shall be paid four and one-quarter percent (4.25%) of the amount collected on behalf of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">From counties the sheriff shall be paid four and one-quarter percent (4.25%) of the amount collected on behalf of the counties; </section><section prefix="3">The sheriff shall be compensated as provided by law or as negotiated if negotiation is permitted by law, for collecting taxes on behalf of any taxing district; </section><section prefix="4">The sheriff shall be compensated as provided in KRS 160.500 for collecting school district taxes; and </section><section prefix="5">The sheriff shall be compensated as provided in KRS 91A.070 for collecting taxes on behalf of any city. </section></section><section prefix="b">The sheriff shall include the amounts he or she is entitled to under the provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection as part of the delinquent tax claims filed with the county clerk. The amount so included shall become a part of the certificate of delinquency, and shall be paid by the person paying the certificate of delinquency rather than the taxing jurisdiction for which the taxes were collected. </section></section><section prefix="7">As additional compensation for the collection of delinquent taxes, the sheriff shall be entitled to an amount equal to ten percent (10%) of the total taxes due plus ten percent (10%) of the ten percent (10%) penalty for all delinquent taxes. This fee shall be added to the total amount due, and shall be paid by the person paying the tax claim if payment is made to the sheriff, or the certificate of delinquency or personal property certificate of delinquency if payment is made after the tax claim has been filed with the county clerk. </section><section prefix="8">If, in the process of collecting property taxes, the sheriff becomes aware of a new address for a taxpayer, the sheriff shall provide, on a form provided by the department, the information relating to the new address to the property valuation administrator, who shall update his or her records to reflect the new address. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>