<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="62" order_by="62">OATHS AND BONDS </unit></structure><section_number>62.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates KRS 62.010(1) or 62.050(1) on or after the date thirty (30) days after January 27, 1995, shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If any person violates KRS 62.010(2) or (3) before January 1, 2010, his or her office shall be considered vacant. </section><section prefix="b">If any person violates KRS 62.010(2) or (3) on or after January 1, 2010, his office shall be considered vacant, and he shall not be eligible for the same office for two (2) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person convicted or removed from office under subsection (2) of this section prior to January 10, 1995, may apply to the Circuit Court for relief from the disability of being unable to serve in office. The Circuit Court, upon receipt of the application, shall modify the sentence to remove the disability of holding the office. This subsection shall not be construed to require the removal from office of a person who has been appointed to fill the remainder of the term of a person removed from office under KRS 62.050 and 62.990. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective March 13, 2009. -- Amended 1995 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 3, effective January 27, 1995, retroactive to November 1, 1991. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 66. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3753, 3755. </history><metadata><effective> March 13, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (3/13/2009).  The Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h).  (1/27/95; modified 8/26/97).  The change in the fine for KRS 62.050 set out in subsection (1) of this statute is effective January 27, 1995, and the other changes to this statute made by 1995 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 3 are retroactively effective to November 1, 1991, pursuant to 1995 (2d Extra. Sess.) ch. 4, sec. 5. (This note was modified for clarification and to correct the reference to subsection (1) of this statute.) </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23147</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>