<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.869</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees to operate fund and direct policies -- Membership -- Removal for cause. </catch_line><order_by>869</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The responsibility for the proper operation of the fund and the direction of its policies shall be vested in a board of trustees. If there are no active members of the fund, the board of trustees shall consist of four (4) members who shall be: (a) the mayor ex officio; (b) the city treasurer ex officio; and (c) one (1) retired member of each department who shall be elected by ballot by the retired members of the respective departments. The mayor ex officio and the city treasurer ex officio shall serve for terms of one (1) year under rules adopted by the board. The two (2) retired members of the police and fire department shall serve for terms of at least one (1) year with a maximum of two (2) years under rules adopted by the board. If there are active members of the fund, there shall be two (2) additional board members who shall be one (1) active member of the fund from each department elected by ballot by the active members of the fund from the respective departments and who shall serve for terms of at least one (1) year with a maximum of two (2) years under rules adopted by the board. If all of the active members or all of the retired members are from one (1) department, then both of the active-member board members or both of the retired board members shall be elected from that department. In the event of a vacancy of an elected member, the pension board may fill the vacancy by appointment until the next regular election. </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees membership shall be restructured according to the provisions of this section at the time of the next scheduled election of board members after July 15, 1994. </section><section prefix="3">Any member of the board convicted of an offense relating to mismanagement or embezzlement of the fund created pursuant to KRS 95.852 shall be removed from the board and shall be prohibited from serving on the board. If the board member removed is an ex officio member, the city council shall appoint a replacement until another person shall fill the office entitled to a seat on the board. If the board member removed is an active policeman or firefighter, the board shall fill the vacancy by appointment of another active policeman or firefighter until the next regular election. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 87, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 19, effective July 1, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26094</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>