<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.120</section_number><catch_line>Foreign protective orders.  </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text>(1)All foreign protective orders shall have the rebuttable presumption of validity.The validity of a foreign protective order shall only be determined by a court ofcompetent jurisdiction. Until a foreign protective order is declared to be invalidby a court of competent jurisdiction, it shall be given full faith and credit by allpeace officers and courts in the Commonwealth.(2)All peace officers shall treat a foreign protective order as a legal documentvalid in Kentucky, and shall make arrests for a violation thereof in the samemanner as for a violation of an order of protection issued in Kentucky.(3)The fact that a foreign protective order has not been entered into the LawInformation Network of Kentucky shall not be grounds for a peace officer not toenforce the provisions of the order unless it is readily apparent to the peaceofficer to whom the order is presented that the order has either expiredaccording to a date shown on the order, or that the order's provisions clearly donot prohibit the conduct being complained of. Officers acting in good faith shallbe immune from criminal and civil liability.(4)If the order has expired or its provisions do not prohibit the conduct beingcomplained of, the officer shall not make an arrest unless the provisions of aKentucky statute have been violated, in which case the peace officer shall takethe action required by Kentucky law.(5)Civil proceedings and criminal proceedings for violation of a foreign protectiveorder for the same violation of the protective order shall be mutually exclusive.Once either proceeding has been initiated, the other shall not be undertaken,regardless of the outcome of the original proceeding.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 30, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44778</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>