<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-440</section_number><catch_line>Policies to be readable -- Factors to be considered. </catch_line><order_by>14-440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All insurance policies subject to the provisions of KRS 304.14-420 to 304.14-450 shall be written in language easily readable and understandable by a person of average intelligence and education. </section><section prefix="2">In determining whether a policy or contract is readable within the meaning of this section the commissioner shall consider, at least, the following factors: <section prefix="a">The simplicity of the sentence structure and the shortness of the sentences used; </section><section prefix="b">The extent to which commonly used and understood words are employed; </section><section prefix="c">The extent to which legal terms are avoided; </section><section prefix="d">The extent to which references to other sections or provisions of the contract are minimized; </section><section prefix="e">The extent to which definitional provisions are incorporated in the text of the policy or contract; and </section><section prefix="f">Any additional factors relevant to the readability or understandability of an insurance policy or contract which the commissioner may prescribe by regulation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1158, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17165</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>