<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.15-040</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of assets.   </catch_line><order_by>15-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, a disposition of assets under KRS 272A.15-020 shall be approved by: <section prefix="a">At least two-thirds (2/3) of the voting power of members present at a members meeting called under KRS 272A.15-030(2); and </section><section prefix="b">If the limited cooperative association has investor members, at least a majority of the votes cast by patron members, unless the organic rules require a greater percentage vote by patron members. </section></section><section prefix="2">The organic rules may require that the percentage of votes under subsection (1)(a) of this section is: <section prefix="a">A different percentage that is not less than a majority of members voting at the meeting; </section><section prefix="b">Measured against the voting power of all members; or </section><section prefix="c">A combination of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">Subject to any contractual obligations, after a disposition of assets is approved and at any time before the consummation of the disposition, a limited cooperative association may approve an amendment to the contract for disposition or the resolution authorizing the disposition or approve abandonment of the disposition: <section prefix="a">As provided in the contract or the resolution; and </section><section prefix="b">Except as prohibited by the resolution, with the same affirmative vote of the board of directors and of the members as was required to approve the disposition. </section></section><section prefix="4">The voting requirements for districts, classes, or voting groups under KRS 272A.4-040 apply to approval of a disposition of assets under this subchapter. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 109, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41085</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>