<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.365</section_number><catch_line>Annual report on committed children -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>365</order_by><text>The cabinet shall make an annual report to the Governor, the General Assembly, and the Chief Justice. The report shall be tendered not later than December 1 of each year and shall include information for the previous fiscal year. The report shall include, but not be limited to, the following information: <section prefix="1">The number of children under an order of dependent, status, public, or voluntary commitment to the cabinet, according to: permanency planning goals, current placement, average number of placements, type of commitment, and the average length of time children remain committed to the cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">The number of children in the custody of the cabinet in the following types of residential placements, the average length of stay in these placements, and the average number of placements experienced by these children: family foster homes, private child care facilities, and placement with biological parent or person exercising custodial control or supervision; </section><section prefix="3">The number of children in the custody of the cabinet eligible for adoption, the number placed in an adoptive home, and the number ineligible for adoption and the reasons therefor; </section><section prefix="4">The cost in federal and state general funds to care for the children defined in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, including the average cost per child for each type of placement, direct social worker services, operating expenses, training, and administrative costs; and </section><section prefix="5">Any other matters relating to the care of foster children that the cabinet deems appropriate and that may promote further understanding of the impediments to providing permanent homes for foster children. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 33, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><former-codification>KRS 194B.360.</former-codification><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  KRS 194B.360 was repealed and reenacted as a new section of KRS Chapter 194A by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 33, and repealed by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 674, and has been codified as this section of KRS Chapter 194A. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6666</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>