<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.135</section_number><catch_line>Registration as pharmacy technician required to assist in the practice of pharmacy -- Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Effective April 1, 2009, a person shall not assist in the practice of pharmacy unless he or she is duly registered as a pharmacy technician under the provisions of this chapter or is exempt under subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A person may assist in the practice of pharmacy without obtaining the registration required by this section if the person: <section prefix="a">Has filed an application with the board in accordance with KRS 315.136 and no more than thirty (30) days has elapsed since the date the applicant was first employed by the pharmacy. The exemption shall not apply if: <section prefix="1">The application has been denied; </section><section prefix="2">The person is less than sixteen (16) years of age; or </section><section prefix="3">The person has previously been denied a registration or has had a registration revoked or suspended in any jurisdiction and the registration has not yet been issued or reinstated; </section></section><section prefix="b">Is in the employ of a son, daughter, spouse, parent, or legal guardian; or </section><section prefix="c">Is participating in a work-study program through an accredited secondary or postsecondary educational institution. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31014</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>