<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.2-020</section_number><catch_line>Execution of documents delivered to Secretary of State for filing.   </catch_line><order_by>2-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A document delivered to the Secretary of State for filing shall be executed as follows: <section prefix="a">If delivered by or on behalf of a corporation or foreign corporation, by: <section prefix="1">The chairman of its board of directors, by its president, or by another of its officers; </section><section prefix="2">A duly authorized representative; or </section><section prefix="3">If the directors have not been selected or the corporation has not been formed, by its incorporator; </section></section><section prefix="b">If delivered by or on behalf of a limited liability company or foreign limited liability company, by: <section prefix="1">A manager, if management of the limited liability company or foreign limited liability company is reserved to one (1) or more managers; </section><section prefix="2">A member, if management of the limited liability company or foreign limited liability company is reserved to the members; </section><section prefix="3">A duly authorized representative; or </section><section prefix="4">If the limited liability company or foreign limited liability company has not been formed, by its organizer; </section></section><section prefix="c">If delivered by or on behalf of a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership, by at least one (1) general partner; </section><section prefix="d">If delivered by or on behalf of a business trust or foreign business trust, by at least one (1) trustee; </section><section prefix="e">If delivered by or on behalf of a partnership, by at least two (2) partners; </section><section prefix="f">If delivered by or on behalf of any other entity or foreign entity, by a person certifying the authority and capacity to execute and deliver the document; </section><section prefix="g">If the entity or foreign entity is in the hands of a receiver, trustee, or other court-appointed fiduciary, by that fiduciary; or </section><section prefix="h">If delivered by or on behalf of a limited cooperative association or foreign limited cooperative association, by: <section prefix="1">The chairman of its board of directors, by its president, or by another of its officers; </section><section prefix="2">A duly authorized representative; or </section><section prefix="3">If the directors have not been selected or the association has not been formed, by its organizer. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">This section relates exclusively to execution of documents delivered for filing to the Secretary of State, and shall not control as to the execution of other documents of an entity or foreign entity. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 127, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41103</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>