<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.030</section_number><catch_line>Regional or statewide specialized rescue services -- Alternative affiliations agreement and alternative vehicle and equipment requirements. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A rescue squad which proposes to provide regional or statewide specialized rescue services may apply to the director for an alternative affiliation agreement and alternative vehicle and equipment requirements in lieu of those specified in KRS 39F.120 under the following terms and conditions: <section prefix="a">The rescue squad meets all of the requirements specified in KRS 39F.120 except for a local affiliation agreement, vehicle dedicated solely to rescue service, or possession of basic rescue equipment. </section><section prefix="b">The director accepts, in writing, that the rescue squad will provide a needed rescue service either on a regional or statewide basis. </section><section prefix="c">The rescue squad and the director execute an affiliation agreement containing the same information required in KRS 39F.120 for a local affiliation agreement. </section><section prefix="d">The rescue squad maintains specialized rescue equipment appropriate to its mission as specified in the affiliation agreement or an annex thereto. </section><section prefix="e">The requirement for a vehicle dedicated solely to rescue service may be waived, in writing, by the director upon determination that having a specific vehicle may be inappropriate to the mission of the rescue squad and that the rescue squad has adequate means of transportation enabling it to respond in an efficient manner. </section><section prefix="f">The rescue squad, when requested to provide services, shall immediately notify and coordinate activities with the local director and with the local rescue squads serving the county in which the response is requested. </section></section><section prefix="2">Agreements specified in subsection (1) of this section shall be renewed annually. </section><section prefix="3">Rescue squads participating in the alternative program specified in this section shall be eligible to participate in rescue grant funding, state sponsored workers' compensation, training, and other programs of the division. </section><section prefix="4">Rescue squads operating under an agreement pursuant to this section may respond in any county covered by the agreement, or statewide if the agreement permits. Rescue squads covered under an agreement pursuant to this section may respond in counties not covered by the agreement only by request of the rescue squad or public officials in that county or upon request of the director or his designee. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 85, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21796</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>