<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.027</section_number><catch_line>Orientation and continuing education training for planning and zoning officials and staff. </catch_line><order_by>027</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Each planning commissioner and board of adjustment member of a planning unit shall, within one (1) year prior to appointment, or within one hundred twenty (120) days of appointment, attend a minimum of four (4) hours of orientation training in one (1) or more of the subjects listed in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Each planning professional, zoning administrator, and administrative official, and each planning professional's deputies and assistants, shall, within one (1) year prior to being employed, or within one hundred twenty (120) days of employment, attend a minimum of eight (8) hours of orientation training in one (1) or more of the subjects listed in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">Each of the individuals listed in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection shall certify his or her attendance by a written statement filed with the secretary of his or her respective planning commission within one hundred forty (140) days of appointment or employment. Each statement shall identify the date of each program attended, its subject matter, location, sponsors, and the time spent in each program. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each planning commissioner and board of adjustment member of a planning unit shall, within each period of two (2) consecutive calendar years, starting at the date of the individual's appointment, attend no less than eight (8) hours of continuing education in any of the subjects listed in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Each planning professional, zoning administrator, and administrative official, and each planning professional's deputies and assistants, shall, within each period of two (2) consecutive calendar years, starting at the date of the individual's appointment, attend no less than sixteen (16) hours of continuing education in any of the subjects listed in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">Each of the individuals listed in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection shall certify his or her attendance by a written statement filed with the secretary of his or her respective planning commission by December 31 of each calendar year. Each statement shall identify the date of each program attended, its subject matter, location, sponsors, and the time spent in each program. </section></section><section prefix="3">The planning commission or the legislative body of the city, county, urban-county, charter county government, or consolidated local government in which the planning commission has jurisdiction or, in the case of a joint planning unit, has representation in, shall be responsible for providing training as required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section or for providing funding to each planning commissioner, board of adjustment member, full-time planning professional, zoning administrator, administrative official, and planning professional's deputies or assistants so that each individual may obtain training as required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section from other sources. </section><section prefix="4">The subjects for the education required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall include, but not be limited to, the following: land use planning; zoning; floodplains; transportation; community facilities; ethics; public utilities; wireless telecommunications facilities; parliamentary procedure; public hearing procedure; administrative law; economic development; housing; public buildings; building construction; land subdivision; and powers and duties of the board of adjustment. Other topics reasonably related to the duties of planning officials or planning professionals may be approved by majority vote of the planning commission prior to December 31 of the year for which credit is sought. </section><section prefix="5">Each local planning commission shall keep in its official public records originals of all statements and the written documentation of attendance required in subsection </section><section prefix="6">of this section filed with the secretary of the planning commission pursuant to </section>subsections (1)(c) and (2)(c) of this section for three (3) years after the calendar year in which each statement and appurtenant written documentation is filed. (6) Each planning commissioner, board of adjustment member, full-time planning professional, zoning administrator, administrative official, and planning professional's deputies or assistants shall be responsible for obtaining written documentation signed by a representative of the sponsor of any continuing education course for which credit is claimed, acknowledging the fact that the individual attended the program for which credit is claimed. That documentation shall be filed with the secretary of the planning commission as attachments to the statements required by subsections (1)(c) and (2)(c) of this section. <section prefix="7">If a planning commissioner or board of adjustment member fails to: <section prefix="a">Complete the requisite number of hours of orientation training and continuing education within the time allotted under subsections (1) and (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">File the statement required by subsections (1)(c) and (2)(c) of this section; or </section><section prefix="c">File the documentation required by subsection (6) of this section; </section></section> the planning commissioner shall be subject to removal from office according to the provisions of KRS 100.157, and the board of adjustment member shall be subject to removal according to the provisions of KRS 100.217. <section prefix="8">No city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, planning commission, board of adjustment, or any entity performing local planning under KRS Chapter 100, shall employ a planning professional, zoning administrator, administrative official, or a planning professional's deputy or assistant, who fails to complete the requisite number of hours of orientation and continuing education required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section in the capacity of a planning professional, zoning administrator, administrative official, or planning professional's deputy or assistant. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1646</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>