<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.344</section_number><catch_line>County tobacco addiction and alcohol and substance abuse advisory and coordination boards -- Role of KY-ASAP -- Local long-term community strategy. </catch_line><order_by>344</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KY-ASAP shall establish in each county a local tobacco addiction and alcohol and substance abuse advisory and coordination board to assist in planning, overseeing, and coordinating the implementation of local programs related to smoking cessation and prevention and alcohol and substance abuse prevention, cessation, and treatment, although a single board may be established for multiple counties to ensure a comprehensive range of services. The board shall assist with the coordination of programs provided by public and private entities. If the existing programs of private service providers are of high quality, KY-ASAP shall concentrate on providing missing elements and support for those providers. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall support the communities' efforts. </section><section prefix="2">KY-ASAP shall consult with community leaders to solicit the names of residents from the community to serve on each advisory and coordination board. KY-ASAP shall request from each board the submission of reasonable reports on the effectiveness, efficiency, and efforts of each local program, including recommendations for increased or decreased funding, and KY-ASAP shall supply information as necessary to the advisory and coordination board to enable it to carry out its functions. </section><section prefix="3">KY-ASAP shall provide incentives to encourage multicounty advisory and coordination board requests and shall establish a single board to represent all counties making the request. Priority in establishing a board shall be given to existing regional prevention centers or coalitions, community organizations, or local Kentucky Incentives for Prevention (KIP) project coalitions. Membership shall consist of residents from each of the counties. </section><section prefix="4">Each advisory and coordination board shall develop a long-term community strategy that is designed to reduce the incidence of youth and young adult smoking and tobacco addiction, promote resistance to smoking, reduce the incidence of substance abuse, and promote effective treatment of substance abuse. All county resources, both private and public, for-profit and nonprofit, shall be considered in developing this strategy. <section prefix="a">Employers, local leaders, schools, family resource and youth services centers, health care providers and institutions, economic developers, and other relevant local and regional entities shall be consulted in the development of the strategy. </section><section prefix="b">An assessment of needs and available services shall be included in the strategy. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 12, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 75, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 536, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><former-codification> KRS 12.334. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>