<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.320</section_number><catch_line>Visitation of minor child -- Military deployment of parent or custodian -- Visitation rights of custodial relatives following termination of parental rights of others. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A parent not granted custody of the child is entitled to reasonable visitation rights unless the court finds, after a hearing, that visitation would endanger seriously the child's physical, mental, moral, or emotional health. Upon request of either party, the court shall issue orders which are specific as to the frequency, timing, duration, conditions, and method of scheduling visitation and which reflect the development age of the child. </section><section prefix="2">If domestic violence and abuse, as defined in KRS 403.720, has been alleged, the court shall, after a hearing, determine the visitation arrangement, if any, which would not endanger seriously the child's or the custodial parent's physical, mental, or emotional health. </section><section prefix="3">The court may modify an order granting or denying visitation rights whenever modification would serve the best interests of the child; but the court shall not restrict a parent's visitation rights unless it finds that the visitation would endanger seriously the child's physical, mental, moral, or emotional health. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, any court-ordered modification of a child visitation decree, based in whole or in part on: <section prefix="1">The active duty of a parent or a de facto custodian as a regular member of the United States Armed Forces deployed outside the United States; or </section><section prefix="2">Any federal active duty of a parent or a de facto custodian as a member of a state National Guard or a Reserve component; </section></section> shall be temporary and shall revert back to the previous child visitation decree at the end of the deployment outside the United States or the federal active duty, as appropriate. <section prefix="b">A parent or de facto custodian identified in paragraph (a) of this subsection may consent to a modification of a child visitation decree that continues past the end of the deployment outside the United States or the federal active duty, as appropriate. </section></section><section prefix="5">Under circumstances where the court finds, by clear and convincing evidence, it is in the best interest of the child, any relative, by blood or affinity, that was previously granted temporary custody pursuant to the provisions of KRS 620.090 may be granted reasonable noncustodial parental visitation rights by a Circuit Court or Family Court as an intervenor or by original action. Once the relative has been granted visitation pursuant to this subsection, those rights shall not be adversely affected by the termination of custodial or parental rights of an individual who has permanent custody of the child unless the court determines that termination of the visitation rights are in the best interests of the child. The action shall be brought in the county in which the temporary or permanent custody order was entered or where the child resides. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective March 22, 2013. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 414, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 22. </history><metadata><effective>March 22, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>