<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.305</section_number><catch_line>Use of titles "licensed marriage and family therapist" and "marriage and family therapy associate" -- Application and construction of KRS 335.300 to 335.399. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 335.307 and subsection (2) of this section: <section prefix="a">No person shall use the title "licensed marriage and family therapist," "LMFT," or a title which is substantially the same, or hold himself or herself out as having this status, unless licensed by the board. </section><section prefix="b">No person shall use the title "marriage and family therapy associate" or hold himself or herself out as having this status, unless holding a permit issued by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 335.300 to 335.399 shall not apply to persons licensed, certified, or registered under any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, including, but not limited to, physicians, social workers, psychologists, art therapists, and nurses, or students within accredited training programs of these professions. Nothing in KRS 335.300 to 335.399 shall be construed to limit, interfere with, or restrict the practice, descriptions of services, or manner in which these persons hold themselves out to the public. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 335.300 to 335.399 shall be construed to alter, amend, or interfere with the practice of employment counseling, job placement counseling, or school counseling. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 335.300 to 335.399 shall be construed to apply to the activities and services of a student intern or trainee in marriage and family therapy who is pursuing a program of studies in marriage and family therapy at an accredited institution of higher learning if these activities are performed under the supervision and constitute a part of the supervised program of study, and if the person is designated a counseling intern, a marriage and family therapist intern, or student in training. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31939</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>