<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.777High-Performance</section_number><catch_line>Buildings Advisory Committee -- Membership -- Duties -- Administrative regulations -- Resource utilization.   </catch_line><order_by>777High-Performance</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A High-Performance Buildings Advisory Committee is hereby created and shall be administratively staffed by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The committee shall consist of sixteen (16) members and shall include: <section prefix="a">A representative of the cabinet designated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="b">A representative of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet designated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="c">A representative of the Department of Education designated by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="d">A representative of the Council on Postsecondary Education designated by the president; </section><section prefix="e">A representative of the Department for Energy Development and Independence designated by the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="f">A representative appointed by the Governor from each of the following: <section prefix="1">The design and construction industry involved in public works contracting; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Chapter of the U. S. Green Building Council; </section><section prefix="3">The University of Kentucky College of Design; </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Forest Industries Association; </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Society of the American Institute of Architects; </section><section prefix="6">The American Society of Heating, Refrigerating, and Air-Conditioning Engineers; </section><section prefix="7">The Associated General Contractors of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="8">The West Kentucky Construction Association; </section><section prefix="9">The Kentucky Manufactured Housing Institute; </section><section prefix="10">The Kentucky Ready Mixed Concrete Association; and </section><section prefix="11">The Plantmix Asphalt Industry of Kentucky. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The representative of the cabinet shall serve as the chairperson of the committee. All appointments shall be for a term of two (2) years. Committee members shall serve until their successors are appointed and shall be eligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall meet at least monthly or as convened by the chairperson. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the committee shall receive reimbursement for the cost of travel to and from the meetings and any costs necessarily incurred in carrying out their duties. </section><section prefix="6">The committee shall: <section prefix="a">Consult with architects, engineers, builders, energy and conservation organizations, and other interested stakeholders, and make recommendations to the cabinet regarding: <section prefix="1">Standards and benchmarks developed under existing high-performance building programs, including the ENERGY STAR rating system, Green Globes rating system, and Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) Green Building rating system; and </section><section prefix="2">Standards and guidelines developed and adopted by the U.S. Green Building Council, the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating and Air-Conditioning Engineers, and the Illuminating Engineering Society of North America partnership concerning the design of sustainable buildings to balance environmental responsibility, resource efficiency, occupant comfort and well-being, and community sensitivity; </section></section><section prefix="b">Assist the cabinet in the review of state building projects to ensure that building performance and efficiency are maximized to the extent economically feasible using a life-cycle cost analysis; </section><section prefix="c">Assist the cabinet in developing a process of documentation of the attainment of high-performance building standards; and </section><section prefix="d">Assist the cabinet in conducting an ongoing professional development program for state and local building designers, construction companies, school districts, building managers, and the general public on high-performance building design, construction, maintenance, and operation. </section></section><section prefix="7">Prior to the implementation of KRS 56.770 to 56.784, the cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A necessary to implement this section. The cabinet shall consider the recommendations made by the High-Performance Buildings Advisory Committee pursuant to subsection (6) of this section and shall establish the criteria for the high-performance building standards and the benchmarks by which the high-performance building standards will be measured. At a minimum, the cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Include the standards for site selection and management, water efficiency, energy conservation, waste reduction, material and resource use, and indoor air quality; and </section><section prefix="b">Require that each high-performance building be designed, constructed, or renovated so that it is capable of being rated as an ENERGY STAR building in accordance with the criteria and rating system adopted by the United States Environmental Protection Agency and in effect at the time the building is designed or, in the case of leased buildings, at the time the lease is entered into on or after July 1, 2018. </section></section><section prefix="8">In developing the criteria for the high-performance building standards, the cabinet shall consider and encourage the use of: <section prefix="a">Locally grown lumber from forest lands implementing sustainable practices established by the American Tree Farm System's Sustainable Forest Initiative or the Kentucky Forest Stewardship Program established under KRS 149.330 to 149.355; </section><section prefix="b">Building materials manufactured with recycled content within the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="c">Renewable energy sources. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 5, effective February 25, 2010; and amended ch. 24, sec. 54, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24 and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5. Notwithstanding KRS 446.260, these Acts do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44578</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>