<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.272</section_number><catch_line>Contribution rate of new employer engaged in contract construction trades. </catch_line><order_by>272</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any section of this chapter to the contrary, on or after July 15, 1984, any new domestic corporation, or any foreign corporation authorized to do business in this state, or any foreign corporation active in conjunction with a domestic corporation in a joint venture, partnership or other legal entity engaged in the contract construction trades shall pay contributions equal to the maximum rate of contributions payable under the rate schedule in effect for any given calendar year as determined by KRS 341.270; and, such maximum rate of contributions shall remain in effect until the employer has employed persons in this state for not less than twelve (12) consecutive calendar quarters ending as of June 30 immediately preceding the computation date. Thereafter, such employer's contribution rate shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of subsection (4) of KRS 341.270. </section><section prefix="2">On or after January 1, 1989, any new domestic or foreign proprietorship or partnership engaged in the contract construction trades shall be subject to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 5, effective August 28, 2010. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> August 28, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32275</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>