<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.100</section_number><catch_line>Procedure on charge. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>If the offense was against the General Assembly, or a joint committee, the house in which the charge is filed may adopt a resolution providing for an investigation. If the resolution is concurred in by the other house, the President of the Senate shall appoint two (2) of its members and the Speaker of the House three (3) of its members, who shall constitute a joint committee of investigation. If the offense was against the house in which the charge is filed or one (1) of its committees, the President or Speaker shall appoint five (5) of its members as a committee of investigation. The committee of investigation shall select one <section prefix="1">of its number chairman, who may summon and swear witnesses and require the </section>production of papers to be used as evidence. The committee shall summon the accused to appear before it and answer the charge, and, after reasonable notice to him of the time and place of trial, shall hear testimony, and cause the testimony or its substance to be reduced to writing, and report its conclusions, with the testimony taken and its recommendations, to the house in which the charge is pending, or to the Senate if the committee is a joint committee. </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1995. </history><metadata><effective> October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=259</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>