<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.9-110</section_number><catch_line>Revocation or suspension of license -- Effect of denial, revocation, suspension, expiration, or surrender of license -- Circuit Court remedy. </catch_line><order_by>9-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may suspend, revoke, place on probation, condition, restrict, refuse to issue or renew a license, accept the surrender of a license in lieu of revocation or suspension, order that refunds to customers be made, or issue a cease-and-desist order, if the commissioner finds that the person, licensee, or a person in control of a licensee: <section prefix="a">Has committed any fraud, engaged in any dishonest activities, or made any misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="b">Does not meet, has failed to comply with, or has violated any provisions of this subtitle or any administrative regulation issued pursuant thereto, or any order of the commissioner issued pursuant thereto, or has violated any other law in the course of its or his or her dealings as a licensee; </section><section prefix="c">Has made a false statement in the application for the license or failed to give a truthful reply to a question in the application; </section><section prefix="d">Has demonstrated his or her incompetence or untrustworthiness to act as a licensee; </section><section prefix="e">Is unfit, through lack of financial responsibility or experience, to conduct the business of a check-cashing or deferred deposit service business, as the case may be; </section><section prefix="f">Does not conduct his or her business in accordance with the law or conducts business by a method that includes, or would include, activities that are illegal where performed, or has willfully violated any provision of this subtitle; or any administrative regulation promulgated or order of the commissioner issued hereunder; </section><section prefix="g">Is insolvent; </section><section prefix="h">Is the subject of an administrative cease-and-desist order or similar order, or a permanent or temporary injunction of any court of competent jurisdiction entered under any other federal or state act applicable to the person, applicant, or licensee; </section><section prefix="i">Has made or caused to be made to the commissioner any false representation of material fact or has suppressed or withheld from the commissioner any information that the applicant or licensee possesses and which, if submitted by him or her, would have rendered the applicant or licensee ineligible to be licensed under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="j">Has refused to permit an examination or investigation by the commissioner of his or her books and affairs or has refused or failed, within a reasonable time, to furnish any information or records, or make any report that may be required or requested by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="k">Has been convicted of a felony; </section><section prefix="l">Has been convicted of any misdemeanor of which an essential element is fraud, breach of trust, or dishonesty; </section><section prefix="m">Has had any license, registration, or claim of exemption related to the financial services industry denied, revoked, suspended, conditioned, restricted, or probated under the laws of this state, any other state, or the United States, or has surrendered, withdrawn, or terminated any license, registration, or claim of exemption issued or registration granted by this state or any other jurisdiction under threat of administrative action; </section><section prefix="n">Has employed or contracted with a person who has failed to license or has had a license, registration, or claim of exemption denied, revoked, suspended, conditioned, restricted, or probated in this Commonwealth or another state; </section><section prefix="o">Has failed to pay any required fee under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="p">Has abandoned an application or renewal application by failing to provide the commissioner any information required under this subtitle, or requested by the commissioner, to complete an application; </section><section prefix="q">Has failed to comply with an administrative or court order imposing child support obligations; </section><section prefix="r">Has failed to pay state income taxes or to comply with any administrative or court order directing the payment of state income tax; </section><section prefix="s">Has failed to properly verify a customer's eligibility for a deferred deposit transaction; </section><section prefix="t">Has applied for an adjudication of bankruptcy, reorganization, arrangement, or other relief under the United States Bankruptcy Code, 11 U.S.C. secs. 101 to 110; </section><section prefix="u">Has suspended payment of its obligations or has made an assignment for the benefit of its creditors; </section><section prefix="v">Has violated any of the recordkeeping and reporting requirements of the United States government including 31 U.S.C. secs. 5311 to 5332 and 31 C.F.R. pt. 103; or </section><section prefix="w">No longer meets the requirements under this subtitle to hold a license. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the reason for revocation, suspension, restriction, condition, or probation of a licensee's license at any one location is of general application to all locations operated by a licensee, the commissioner may revoke, suspend, restrict, condition, or probate all licenses issued to a licensee. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who has had a license denied by the commissioner shall not be eligible to apply for a license under this subtitle until after expiration of one (1) year from the date of denial. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who has had a license revoked by the commissioner shall not be eligible to apply for a license under this subtitle until after expiration of three (3) years from the date of revocation. A person whose license has been revoked twice shall be deemed permanently revoked and shall not again be eligible for a license under this subtitle. </section><section prefix="5">Any person whose license has been denied, suspended, revoked, or surrendered in lieu of revocation or suspension under this section is prohibited from participating in any business activity of a licensee under this subtitle and from engaging in any business activity on the premises where a licensee under this subtitle is conducting its business. </section><section prefix="6">The surrender or expiration of a license shall not affect the person's civil or criminal liability for acts committed prior to the license surrender or expiration. Revocation, suspension, refusal to renew, surrender, or expiration of a license shall not impair or affect the obligation of any preexisting contract between a licensee and a customer. The surrender or expiration of a license shall not affect a proceeding to suspend or revoke a license. </section><section prefix="7">The commissioner may notify the Department of Revenue, which may institute an action in the name of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, in the Franklin Circuit Court, or any court of competent jurisdiction, for the recovery of any civil penalty, fine, cost, or fee assessed or levied under this subtitle. </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner may file a complaint in the Franklin Circuit Court, or any court of competent jurisdiction, for a temporary restraining order or injunction against any person, where the commissioner has reason to believe from evidence satisfactory to the commissioner that such person has violated, or is about to violate, a provision in this subtitle, for the purpose of restraining and enjoining such person from continuing or engaging in the violation or doing any act in furtherance thereof. The court shall have jurisdiction over the proceeding and shall have the power to enter an order or judgment awarding preliminary or final injunctive relief and any other relief that the court deems proper. Any person who violates a temporary restraining order or injunction issued by the court entered as a result of a violation of this subtitle shall be held in contempt of court and the court may assess a civil penalty in an amount equivalent to the amounts found in KRS 286.9-991. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 814, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 601, sec. 10, effective April 14, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 341, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.110. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>