<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.380</section_number><catch_line>Noncompetitive negotiation. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text>A local public agency may contract or purchase through noncompetitive negotiation only when a written determination is made that competition is not feasible and it is further determined in writing by a designee of the local public agency that:  <section prefix="1">An emergency exists which will cause public harm as a result of the delay in competitive procedures; or  </section><section prefix="2">There is a single source within a reasonable geographical area of the product or service to be procured; or  </section><section prefix="3">The contract is for the services of a licensed professional, such as attorney, physician, psychiatrist, psychologist, certified public accountant, registered nurse, or educational specialist; a technician such as a plumber, electrician, carpenter, or mechanic; or an artist such as a sculptor, aesthetic painter, or musician, provided, however, that this provision shall not apply to architects or engineers providing construction management services rather than professional architect or engineer services; or  </section><section prefix="4">The contract is for the purchase of perishable items purchased on a weekly or more frequent basis, such as fresh fruits, vegetables, fish or meat;  </section><section prefix="5">The contract is for replacement parts where the need cannot be reasonably anticipated and stockpiling is not feasible;  </section><section prefix="6">The contract is for proprietary items for resale;  </section><section prefix="7">In school districts the contract relates to an enterprise in which the buying or selling by students is a part of the educational experience;  </section><section prefix="8">The contract or purchase is for expenditures made on authorized trips outside of the boundaries of the local public agency;  </section><section prefix="9">The contract is for the purchase of supplies which are sold at public auction or by receiving sealed bids;  </section><section prefix="10">The contract is for group life insurance, group health and accident insurance, group professional liability insurance, worker's compensation insurance, and unemployment insurance; or  </section><section prefix="11">The contract is for a sale of supplies at reduced prices that will afford a purchase at savings to the local public agency. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 12, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 77, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>April 9, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22410</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>