<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.500</section_number><catch_line>Persons with assistance dogs not to be denied accommodations, transportation, or elevator service -- Conditions -- Exemption from licensing fees -- Denial of emergency medical treatment for assistance dog prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in subsections (1) to (11) of this section, "person" means a "person with a disability" as defined by KRS 210.770. "Person" also includes a trainer of an assistance dog. </section><section prefix="2">If a person is accompanied by an assistance dog, neither the person nor the dog shall be denied admittance to any hotel, motel, restaurant, or eating establishment, nor shall the person be denied full and equal accommodations, facilities, and privileges of all public places of amusement, theater, or resort when accompanied by an assistance dog. </section><section prefix="3">Any person accompanied by an assistance dog shall be entitled to full and equal accommodations on all public transportation, if the dog does not occupy a seat in any public conveyance, nor endanger the public safety. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall be required to pay additional charges or fare for the transportation of any accompanying assistance dog. </section><section prefix="5">No person accompanied by an assistance dog shall be denied admittance and use of any public building, nor denied the use of any elevator operated for public use. </section><section prefix="6">Any person accompanied by an assistance dog may keep the dog in his immediate custody while a tenant in any apartment, or building used as a public lodging. </section><section prefix="7">All trainers accompanied by an assistance dog shall have in their personal possession identification verifying that they are trainers of assistance dogs. </section><section prefix="8">The provisions of this section shall not apply unless the person complies with the legal limitations applicable to nondisabled persons and unless all requirements of KRS 258.015 and 258.135 have been complied with. </section><section prefix="9">Assistance dogs are exempt from all state and local licensing fees. </section><section prefix="10">Licensing authorities shall accept that the dog for which the license is sought is an assistance dog if the person requesting the license is a person with a disability or the trainer of the dog. </section><section prefix="11">Emergency medical treatment shall not be denied to an assistance dog assigned to a person regardless of the person's ability to pay prior to treatment. </section><section prefix="12">No person shall willfully or maliciously interfere with an assistance dog or the dog's user. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 23, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 81. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 118, secs. 1 to 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12501</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>