<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.354</section_number><catch_line>Instructors -- Requirements for approval. </catch_line><order_by>354</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall approve instructors for the motorcycle rider training courses. A person shall not be approved as an instructor unless the person meets the requirements of this section and administrative regulations of the cabinet and holds a currently valid instructor certification issued by the Motorcycle Safety Foundation. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall offer instructor training courses to prepare instructors to teach the motorcycle rider training courses. Successful completion of the instructor training course shall require the participant to demonstrate knowledge of the course material, knowledge of proper motorcycle operation, motorcycle riding proficiency, and the necessary aptitude for instructing students. A person shall not be approved as an instructor unless the person has successfully completed the instructor training course or an equivalent course offered in another state. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall establish additional requirements for the approval of instructors, including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">The person shall have a high school diploma or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="b">The person shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age and hold a valid motorcycle driver's license or endorsement; </section><section prefix="c">The person shall have at least two (2) years of recent motorcycle riding experience; </section><section prefix="d">The person's driver's license shall not have been suspended or revoked at any time during the preceding two (2) years or at any time within the preceding five (5) years for any alcohol or drug related offense; and </section><section prefix="e">The person shall not have been convicted of a felony. </section></section><section prefix="4">In the case of a nonresident, the cabinet shall obtain and review the person's driving record from the state where the person is licensed prior to approval or reapproval of the person as an instructor. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall annually review the status of all approved instructors and shall withdraw approval from any instructor who is no longer qualified under the requirements of this section. The cabinet shall immediately withdraw approval of an instructor when it receives adequate notice of any disqualification. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 3, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1075</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>