<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-100</section_number><catch_line>Application as evidence. </catch_line><order_by>14-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No application for the issuance of any life insurance policy shall be admissible in evidence in any action relative to such policy, unless a true copy of the application was attached to or otherwise made a part of the policy when issued and delivered. A photostatic or other process copy or reduction of the application or medical examination, if any, may be so used if clearly legible. This provision shall not apply to industrial life insurance policies. </section><section prefix="2">If any policy of life or health insurance delivered in this state is reinstated or renewed, and the insured or the beneficiary or assignee of the policy makes written request to the insurer for a copy of the application, if any, for such reinstatement or renewal, the insurer shall, within thirty (30) days after receipt of such request at its principal office or any of its branch offices, deliver or mail to the person making such request, a copy of such application. If such copy is not so delivered or mailed, the insurer shall be precluded from introducing such application as evidence in any action or proceeding based upon or involving the policy or its reinstatement or renewal. </section><section prefix="3">As to the kinds of insurance other than life insurance, no application for insurance signed by or on behalf of the insured shall be admissible in evidence in any action between the insured and the insurer arising out of the policy so applied for, if the insurer has failed, within thirty (30) days after receipt by the insurer of written demand therefor by or on behalf of the insured, to furnish to the insured a copy of such application reproduced by any legible means. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 14, sec. 10, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17129</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>