<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">STATE AND AREA PLANNING -- REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147.640</section_number><catch_line>Area council -- Membership -- Relation to commission.   </catch_line><order_by>640</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide more effective representation of the various governmental units participating in the creation of the area planning commission, an area council shall be created. </section><section prefix="2">The area council shall be composed of one (1) representative and one (1) alternate from each municipality and county within the area planning territory. Each such representative and alternate shall be appointed annually in the manner prescribed by law respecting appointments by such city or county. </section><section prefix="3">Only elected officials of each respective jurisdiction shall be eligible for appointment to the area planning council. </section><section prefix="4">At its first regular meeting in each year, the council shall elect from its membership a president and vice president. The vice president shall have the authority to act as president of the council during the absence or disability of the president. </section><section prefix="5">The council may appoint from within or without its own membership a secretary, prescribe his duties and fix his compensation. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall act in a supervisory and advisory capacity with the area planning commission created hereunder. All actions taken by the council must receive the affirmative vote of the following, if in attendance: two (2) counties or two (2) cities with a population equal to or greater than fifteen thousand (15,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census or one (1) county and one (1) city with a population equal to or greater than fifteen thousand (15,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census and a majority of the remaining membership in attendance for passage. </section><section prefix="7">The area council may budget in each year for the payment of a per diem for each member of the area planning commission not to exceed in any one (1) year the sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each member. </section><section prefix="8">A quorum of the area council shall consist of a majority of its membership. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 220, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>