<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.036</section_number><catch_line>Local registrars. </catch_line><order_by>036</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county in the Commonwealth shall constitute a registration district for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall, upon the recommendation of the state registrar, designate a local registrar in each registration district to aid in the efficient administration of the system of vital statistics. The local registrar shall be an employee of the local health department. The designation may be revoked by the secretary. </section><section prefix="3">The local registrar may designate one (1) or more employees of the local health department as deputy registrar. The local registrar may also appoint persons as deputy registrars who are not employees of the local health department if, in the opinion of the cabinet, the appointments are necessary. All appointments shall be subject to the approval of the state registrar. </section><section prefix="4">The local registrar shall supply blank forms of certificates to persons who require them. The local registrar shall carefully examine each certificate of birth or fetal death when presented for filing, to ensure the record has been properly completed. If the certificates are properly completed the local registrar shall sign as local registrar and attest to the date of filing. The local registrar shall also make a complete and accurate copy of each certificate to be filed and permanently preserved in the local registrar's office as the local record, in the manner directed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. When a birth or fetal death certificate filed with a local registrar indicates the residence of the mother or the deceased to be in another county, the registrar shall mail a copy of the certificate to the local registrar of the county of residence. </section><section prefix="5">The local registrar shall provide for voluntary acknowledgment of paternity services in accordance with 42 U.S.C. secs. 651 et seq., and transmit original certificates and affidavits of paternity to the Vital Statistics Branch as directed by the state registrar. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 432, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 382, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8708</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>