<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.652</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning Contractors. </catch_line><order_by>652</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning Contractors is hereby created, which shall be attached to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction for administrative purposes. The board shall consist of eight (8) members, one (1) of whom shall be a member of the Home Builders Association of Kentucky; one (1) of whom shall be a member of the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers; one (1) of whom shall be a member of the Kentucky Association of Plumbing-Heating-Cooling Contractors; one (1) of whom shall be a member of the Mechanical Contractors Association of Kentucky; one (1) of whom shall be a heating, ventilation, or air conditioning contractor; one (1) of whom shall represent the public and shall not be associated with or financially interested in heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting; one (1) of whom shall be the commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction or his or her designee; and one (1) of whom shall be a local government official or employee, who shall have a background in the heating, ventilation, or air conditioning industry. Each member of the board shall be a citizen and resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">All members of the board, except those who represent the public, local government, the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, and the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers, shall have been actively engaged in the heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting business as a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor for not less than five (5) years immediately preceding the date of the appointment to the board and shall hold a valid license or certificate for that status. </section><section prefix="3">Except for the commissioner, who shall serve for so long as he or she holds his or her appointment as commissioner, the terms of the board members shall be as follows. The remaining seven (7) board members shall be appointed by the Governor with initial appointments for three (3) members for terms of three (3) years, two (2) members for terms of two (2) years, and two (2) members for terms of one (1) year. All appointments shall expire on June 30 of the last year of the terms. Thereafter, these members shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of three (3) years. No person shall serve more than two (2) full consecutive terms. Members shall serve until their successors are appointed. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, or his or her designee, shall serve as chairman of the board. A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum to conduct business. The board shall meet at least once each calendar quarter in a location designated by the chairman or commissioner. The board may meet upon special call by the chairman, the commissioner, or a majority of the board. </section><section prefix="5">Each member of the board, except the commissioner, shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for attending each meeting and shall be reimbursed for all necessary expenses incurred in the performance of his or her official duties. </section><section prefix="6">Vacancies in the membership of the board for any cause shall be filled by appointment by the Governor for the balance of the unexpired term. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 288, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7051</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>