<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.441</section_number><catch_line>Duties of community action agency. </catch_line><order_by>441</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each community action agency shall: <section prefix="a">Plan systematically for an effective community action program, develop information as to the problems and causes of poverty in the community; determine how much and how effectively assistance is being provided to deal with those problems and causes; and establish priorities among projects, activities, and areas as needed for the best and most efficient use of resources; </section><section prefix="b">Provide planning or technical assistance to agencies; and generally, in cooperation with community agencies and officials, undertake actions to improve existing efforts to reduce poverty, such as improving day-to-day communications, closing service gaps, focusing resources on the most needy, and providing additional opportunities to low-income individuals for regular employment or participation in the programs or activities for which those community agencies and officials are responsible; </section><section prefix="c">Initiate and sponsor projects responsive to needs of the poor which are not otherwise being met, with particular emphasis on providing central or common services that can be drawn upon by a variety of related programs, developing new approaches or new types of services that can be incorporated into other programs, and filling gaps pending the expansion or modification of those programs; </section><section prefix="d">Establish effective procedures by which the poor and area residents concerned will be enabled to influence the character of programs affecting their interests, provide for their regular participation in the implementation of those programs, and provide technical and other support needed to enable the poor and neighborhood groups to secure on their own behalf available assistance from public and private sources; </section><section prefix="e">Join with and encourage business, labor and other private groups and organizations to undertake, together with public officials and agencies, activities in support of the community action program which will result in the additional use of private resources and capabilities, with a view to developing new employment opportunities, stimulating investment that will have a measurable impact on reducing poverty among residents of areas of concentrated poverty, and providing methods by which residents of those areas can work with private groups, firms, and institutions in seeking solutions to problems of common concern. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a community action agency places responsibility for the character, funding, extent, administration of, or budgeting for programs of the agency with another agency or organization, public or private, it shall do so by contract. No contract shall be made with an agency or organization which does not have a board which is broadly representative of the citizens of the geographic area served by the agency or organization. </section><section prefix="3">Each community action agency shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 80, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>