<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.115</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky soil erosion and water quality cost-share fund -- Uses -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the "Kentucky Soil Erosion and Water Quality Cost-Share Fund" to be administered by the Soil and Water Conservation Commission. Moneys from the fund shall be used for cost-share programs to provide financial assistance for implementation of best management practices for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">Providing cleaner water through the reduction in sediment loading of Kentucky streams, rivers, and lakes; </section><section prefix="b">Reducing the loss of topsoil vital to the sustained production of food and fiber; and </section><section prefix="c">Preventing surface water and groundwater pollution. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commission is empowered to promulgate administrative regulations establishing practices eligible for cost-sharing funds, prioritizing applications, and prescribing amounts and limits of cost sharing. Practices eligible for cost-sharing funds shall include agricultural and silvicultural practices. Local conservation districts shall determine the eligibility of persons to receive the funds allocated to the districts by the commission. Priority for funding within each local conservation district shall be given to animal waste management systems, where animal waste has been identified as a water pollution problem, and to members of an agricultural district. </section><section prefix="3">Any person engaged in agricultural or silvicultural production may be considered for funding under this section if the person has had prepared a soil and water conservation plan with the local conservation district, has had prepared a forest management or forest stewardship plan, or has had prepared a groundwater protection plan and agrees to maintain best management practices for a period of time specified by the commission. </section><section prefix="4">Up to five percent (5%) of any total annual appropriation may be used for administrative costs of the local conservation districts and the commission. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 390, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 146.121, renumbered effective January 1, 1995. </former-codification><lrc-note> (1/11/95).  1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 34, originally codified as KRS 146.121, is identical to this statute and has been merged into this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29292</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>