<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.557</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Statewide system of evaluation for all certifiedpersonnel -- Criteria for statewide plan -- Policy and procedures forevaluation -- Administrative regulations -- Use of alternative effectivenessand evaluation system -- Appeals -- Prohibition against disclosure ofconfidential information.  </catch_line><order_by>557</order_by><text>(1)As used in this section:(a)"Formative evaluation" means a continuous cycle of collecting evaluationinformation and providing feedback with suggestions regarding thecertified employee's professional growth and performance;(b)"Local formative growth measures" means measures that are rigorousand comparable across schools in a local district;(c)"Student growth" means the change in student achievement for anindividual student between two (2) or more points in time includingachievement on state assessments required per KRS 158.6453; and(d)"Summative evaluation" means the summary of, and conclusions from,the evaluation data, including formative evaluation data that:1.Occur at the end of an evaluation cycle; and2.Include a conference between the evaluator and the evaluatedcertified employee and a written evaluation report.(2)Prior to the beginning of the 2014-2015 school year, the Kentucky Departmentof Education, in consultation with the Kentucky teacher and principal steeringcommittees and other groups deemed appropriate by the commissioner ofeducation, shall develop a framework for a statewide personnel evaluationsystem. The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrativeregulations to establish a statewide professional growth and effectivenesssystem for the purposes of supporting and improving the performance of allcertified school personnel. The system shall promote the continuousprofessional growth and development of skills needed to be a highly effectiveteacher or a highly effective administrator in a school or district. The KentuckyBoard of Education shall include parent surveys as a source of data once avalid and reliable survey tool becomes available for this purpose.(3)The professional growth and effectiveness system shall:(a)Use multiple measures of effectiveness, including student growth data asa significant factor in determining the effectiveness of teachers andadministrators, that utilize both state standardized tests and localformative growth measures that are rigorous and comparable acrossschools in a local district;(b)Include both formative and summative evaluation components;(c)Measure professional effectiveness;(d)Support professional growth;(e)Have at least three (3) performance levels;(f)Be used to inform personnel decisions;(g)Be considerate of the time requirements of evaluators at the local leveland shall not require that all certified school personnel have a formalsummative evaluation each year; and(h)Rate teachers or administrators by multiple measures instead of a singlemeasure.(4)The performance criteria by which teachers and administrators shall beevaluated shall include but not be limited to:(a)Performance of professional responsibilities related to his or herassignment, including attendance and punctuality and evaluating results;(b)Demonstration of effective planning of curricula, classroom instruction,and classroom management, based on research-based instructionalpractices, or school management skills based on validated managerialpractices;(c)Demonstration of knowledge and understanding of subject matter contentor administrative functions and effective leadership techniques;(d)Promotion and incorporation of instructional strategies or managementtechniques that are fair and respect diversity and individual differences;(e)Demonstration of effective interpersonal, communication, andcollaboration skills among peers, students, parents, and others;(f)Performance of duties consistent with the goals for Kentucky studentsand mission of the school, the local community, laws, and administrativeregulations;(g)Demonstration of the effective use of resources, including technology;(h)Demonstration of professional growth;(i)Adherence to the professional code of ethics; and(j)Attainment of the teacher standards or the administrator standards asestablished by the Education Professional Standards Board that are notreferenced in paragraphs (a) to (i) of this subsection.(5)The following provisions shall apply to the statewide professional growth andeffectiveness system:(a)Certified school personnel, below the level of superintendent, shall beevaluated by using the system developed by the Kentucky Department ofEducation;(b)The evaluation system shall include formative evaluation and summativeevaluation components; and(c)The Kentucky Board of Education shall adopt administrative regulationsincorporating written guidelines for a local school district to follow inimplementing the professional growth and effectiveness system and shallrequire the following:1.All evaluations of certified school personnel below the level of thedistrict superintendent shall be in writing on evaluation forms andunder evaluation procedures developed by a committee composedof an equal number of teachers and administrators;2.The immediate supervisor of the certified school personnel membershall be designated as the primary evaluator. At the request of ateacher, observations by other teachers trained in the teacher'scontent area or curriculum content specialists may be incorporatedinto the formative process for evaluating teachers;3.All monitoring or observation of performance of a certified schoolpersonnel member shall be conducted openly and with fullknowledge of the personnel member;4.Evaluators shall be trained, tested, and approved in accordancewith administrative regulations adopted by the Kentucky Board ofEducation in the proper techniques for effectively evaluating certifiedschool personnel. Evaluators shall receive support and resourcesnecessary to ensure consistent and reliable ratings;5.The professional growth and effectiveness system shall include aplan whereby the person evaluated is given assistance forprofessional growth as a teacher or administrator. The system shallalso specify the processes to be used when corrective actions arenecessary in relation to the performance of one's assignment; and6.The training requirement for evaluators contained in subparagraph4. of this paragraph shall not apply to district board of educationmembers.(6)(a)Each superintendent shall be evaluated according to a policy andprocedures developed by the local board of education and approved bythe department.(b)The summative evaluation of the superintendent shall be in writing,discussed and adopted in an open meeting of the board and reflected inthe minutes, and made available to the public upon request.(c)Any preliminary discussions relating to the evaluation of thesuperintendent by the board or between the board and the superintendentprior to the summative evaluation shall be conducted in closed session.(7)Local districts may submit a written request to use an alternative effectivenessand evaluation system to the Kentucky Board of Education. The KentuckyBoard of Education shall consider and approve a local district's use of analternative effectiveness and evaluation system instead of the statewidesystem only if the Kentucky Board of Education determines the alternativesystem:(a)Is as rigorous, reliable, valid, and educationally sound as the statewideprofessional growth and effectiveness system;(b)Uses multiple measures of effectiveness, including student growth dataas a significant factor in determining the effectiveness of teachers andadministrators, that utilize both state standardized tests and localformative growth measures that are rigorous and comparable acrossschools in a local district;(c)Includes both formative and summative evaluation components;(d)Measures professional effectiveness;(e)Supports professional growth;(f)Has at least three (3) performance levels;(g)Is used to inform personnel decisions;(h)Is considerate of the time requirements of evaluators at the local leveland does not require that all certified school personnel have a formalsummative evaluation each year; and(i)Rates teachers and administrators by multiple measures instead of asingle measure.(8)The Kentucky Board of Education shall establish an appeals procedure forcertified school personnel who believe that the local school district failed toproperly implement the evaluation system. The appeals procedure shall notinvolve requests from individual certified school personnel members for reviewof the judgmental conclusions of their personnel evaluations.(9)The local board of education shall establish an evaluation appeals panel forcertified school personnel that shall consist of two (2) members elected by thecertified employees of the local district and one (1) member appointed by theboard of education who is a certified employee of the local board of education.Certified school personnel who think they were not fairly evaluated may submitan appeal to the panel for a timely review of their evaluation.(10)The Kentucky Department of Education shall annually provide for on-site visitsby trained personnel to a minimum of fifteen (15) school districts to review andensure appropriate implementation of the evaluation system by the local schooldistrict. The department shall provide technical assistance to local districts toeliminate deficiencies and to improve the effectiveness of the evaluationsystem. The department may implement the requirement in this subsection inconjunction with other requirements, including, but not limited to, the scholasticaudit process required by KRS 158.6455.(11)The disclosure, pursuant to KRS Chapter 61, of any data or information,including student growth data, that local school districts or the Department ofEducation collect on individual classroom teachers under the requirements ofKRS 156.557 is prohibited.</text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. --Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000.</history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013</effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  The internal numbering ofsubsection (4) of this statute has been modified by the Reviser of Statutes fromthe way it appeared in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1, under the authority of KRS7.136(1).</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42137</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>