<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.130</section_number><catch_line>Reemployment of career employee terminated on or after January 1, 1980. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A career employee whose employment is terminated on or after January 1, 1980, by lay-off, dismissal, other than for cause, and, in the case of an unclassified management employee, resignation other than resignation in lieu of dismissal for cause, shall, upon his written request, be reemployed or placed on reemployment lists in accordance with this section and KRS 18A.135. </section><section prefix="2">If the career employee has previously attained status in a position in the classified service, he shall revert to a position in that class in the agency from which he was terminated if a vacancy in that class exists. If no such vacancy exists, he shall be considered for employment in any vacant position for which he is qualified pursuant to the reemployment procedures. </section><section prefix="3">If the career employee has not previously attained status in the classified service or if he has attained status but no vacancy exists in a position to which subsection (2) of this section applies, the employee shall be placed on reemployment lists for any positions for which he is qualified. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.130, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.216. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1372</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>