<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.6947</section_number><catch_line>Use of assessment funds. </catch_line><order_by>6947</order_by><text>The funds, including donations from individuals, concerns, corporations, and grants from the state or governmental agencies, shall be used for the purpose of promoting and stimulating, by research, market development, and education, the increased use and sale, domestic and foreign, of ovine or caprine animals; and for the prevention, modification, or elimination of trade barriers which obstruct the free flow of ovine or caprine animals to market. None of these funds shall be used to lobby as defined in KRS 6.611. The duly certified association receiving the assessment funds shall, upon the advice and consent of the Kentucky Sheep and Goat Council, use and disburse the funds as follows: <section prefix="1">The association may first refund to itself the costs and expenses incurred in the conduct of the referendum; and </section><section prefix="2">The association may spend or disburse the necessary funds for administrative costs and expenses as determined by the Kentucky Sheep and Goat Council, with the balance remaining to be used for the purposes provided in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 69, effective September 16, 1993. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>