<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.045</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for admission -- Discharge planning. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Admission: <section prefix="a">Residents shall be admitted only upon the approval of an interdisciplinary team. The facility shall admit only persons who have a physical or mental condition which requires developmental nursing services and a planned program of active treatment; </section><section prefix="b">The interdisciplinary team shall: <section prefix="1">Conduct a comprehensive evaluation of the individual, not more than three (3) months before admission, covering physical, emotional, social, and cognitive factors; and </section><section prefix="2">Prior to admission define the need for service without regard to availability of those services. The team shall review all available and applicable programs of care, treatment, and training and record its findings; </section></section><section prefix="c">If admission is not the best plan but the individual must be admitted nevertheless, the facility shall clearly acknowledge that the admission is inappropriate and initiate plans to actively explore alternatives; </section><section prefix="d">Before admission, the resident and a responsible member of his family or guardian shall be informed in writing of the established policies of the facility and fees, reimbursement, visitation rights during serious illness, visiting hours, type of diets offered, and services offered; and </section><section prefix="e">The facility shall provide and maintain a system for identifying each resident's personal property and facilities for safekeeping of his declared valuables. Each resident's clothing and other property shall be reserved for the resident's own use. </section></section><section prefix="2">Discharge planning. Prior to discharge the facility shall have a postinstitutional plan which identifies the residential setting and support services which would enable the resident to live in a less restrictive alternative to the current setting. Before a resident is released, the facility shall: <section prefix="a">Offer counseling to parents or guardians who request the release of a resident concerning the advantages and disadvantages of the release; </section><section prefix="b">Plan for release of the resident, to assure that appropriate services are available in the resident's new environment, including protective supervision and other follow-up services; and </section><section prefix="c">Prepare and place in the resident's record a summary of findings, progress, and plans. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 4, effective March 6, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7518</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>