<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">A UNIFORM MILITARY AND OVERSEAS VOTERS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>117A.030</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of Secretary of State.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State is the state official responsible for implementing this chapter and the Commonwealth of Kentucky’s responsibilities under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 1973ff et seq. </section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State may delegate to the State Board of Elections responsibilities under this chapter, including but not limited to the promulgation of administrative regulations necessary to implement this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State shall make available to covered voters information regarding voter registration procedures for covered voters and procedures for casting military-overseas ballots. </section><section prefix="4">The Secretary of State shall establish an electronic transmission system through which a covered voter may apply for and receive voter registration materials, military-overseas ballots, and other information authorized under this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The Secretary of State shall: <section prefix="a">Develop standardized absentee-voting materials, including privacy and transmission envelopes and their electronic equivalents, authentication materials, and voting instructions, to be used with the military-overseas ballot of a voter authorized to vote in any jurisdiction in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="b">To the extent reasonably possible, coordinate with other states to carry out this section. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Secretary of State shall prescribe the form and content of a declaration for use by a covered voter to swear or affirm specific representations pertaining to the voter’s identity, eligibility to vote, status as a covered voter, and timely and proper completion of a military-overseas ballot. The declaration shall be based on the declaration prescribed to accompany a federal write-in absentee ballot, as modified to be consistent with this chapter. The Secretary of State shall ensure that a form for the execution of the declaration, including an indication of the date of execution of the declaration, is a prominent part of all balloting materials for which the declaration is required. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42724</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>