<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.323</section_number><catch_line>Duties of council. </catch_line><order_by>323</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Local Government Training Advisory Council shall: <section prefix="a">Develop and update on a biennial basis a local government training plan that: <section prefix="1">Quantifies the training needs of local governments; </section><section prefix="2">Evaluates the abilities of existing training programs to meet the needs; </section><section prefix="3">Identifies areas of unmet need that justify expanding existing programs or the creation of new programs; and </section><section prefix="4">Formulates a strategy, giving consideration to the use of state-of-the-art communication techniques to enhance training efforts, that meets the needs of local governments; </section></section><section prefix="b">Submit a copy of the local government training plan to the Legislative Research Commission by November 1 of odd-numbered years; </section><section prefix="c">Ensure the proper coordination of training programs for city and county governments; and </section><section prefix="d">Elect a chairperson annually from its membership. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall adopt the plan provided for in subsection (1)(a) of this section by majority vote, at which time it shall become the policy document used by the Department for Local Government to determine priorities for the expenditure of training funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 53, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 46, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23389</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>