<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.090</section_number><catch_line>Removal of guardian, limited guardian or conservator. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The District Court shall remove a guardian, limited guardian, or conservator if: <section prefix="a">The guardian, limited guardian, or conservator becomes insane, moves out of the Commonwealth, becomes incapable of discharging the duties of the appointment, or fails for any reason to discharge the duties of the appointment; or </section><section prefix="b">The District Court deems the removal of the guardian, limited guardian, or conservator to be in the best interest of the ward. </section></section><section prefix="2">The District Court may permit a guardian, limited guardian, or conservator to resign if the guardian, limited guardian, or conservator first files a final settlement and delivers the ward's estate as directed by the District Court. </section><section prefix="3">When a guardian, limited guardian, or conservator resigns or is removed from office by the District Court, the District Court shall appoint a new person or entity to serve as the ward's guardian, limited guardian, or conservator. </section><section prefix="4">The District Court may remove a guardian, limited guardian, or conservator for failing to make an account or inventory as required by law, or as may be required by the District Court, or for failing to give additional surety when required. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 154, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2024, 2026. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35998</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>