<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.360</section_number><catch_line>Family literacy services. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Adult Education Program shall provide technical assistance to providers to develop family literacy services. The technical assistance shall be evaluated on a regular basis by contracted evaluators outside the program. </section><section prefix="2">The services shall: <section prefix="a">Provide parents with instruction in basic academic skills, life skills which include parenting skills, and employability skills; </section><section prefix="b">Provide the children with developmentally appropriate educational activities; </section><section prefix="c">Provide planned high-quality educational experiences requiring interaction between parents and their children; </section><section prefix="d">Be of sufficient intensity and duration to help move families to self-sufficiency and break the cycle of under education and poverty; and </section><section prefix="e">Be designed to reduce duplication with other educational providers to ensure high quality and efficient services. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 87, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, secs. 11 and 26, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 25, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 406, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3504</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>