<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-620</section_number><catch_line>Acceptance of collateral in full or partial satisfaction of obligation -- Compulsory disposition of collateral. </catch_line><order_by>9-620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (7) of this section, a secured party may accept collateral in full or partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if: <section prefix="a">The debtor consents to the acceptance under subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">The secured party does not receive, within the time set forth in subsection (4) of this section, a notification of objection to the proposal authenticated by: <section prefix="1">A person to which the secured party was required to send a proposal under KRS 355.9-621; or </section><section prefix="2">Any other person, other than the debtor, holding an interest in the collateral subordinate to the security interest that is the subject of the proposal; </section></section><section prefix="c">If the collateral is consumer goods, the collateral is not in the possession of the debtor when the debtor consents to the acceptance; and </section><section prefix="d">Subsection (5) of this section does not require the secured party to dispose of the collateral or the debtor waives the requirement pursuant to KRS 355.9-624. </section></section><section prefix="2">A purported or apparent acceptance of collateral under this section is ineffective unless: <section prefix="a">The secured party consents to the acceptance in an authenticated record or sends a proposal to the debtor; and </section><section prefix="b">The conditions of subsection (1) of this section are met. </section></section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">A debtor consents to an acceptance of collateral in partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if the debtor agrees to the terms of the acceptance in a record authenticated after default; and </section><section prefix="b">A debtor consents to an acceptance of collateral in full satisfaction of the obligation it secures only if the debtor agrees to the terms of the acceptance in a record authenticated after default or the secured party: <section prefix="1">Sends to the debtor after default a proposal that is unconditional or subject only to a condition that collateral not in the possession of the secured party be preserved or maintained; </section><section prefix="2">In the proposal, proposes to accept collateral in full satisfaction of the obligation it secures; and </section><section prefix="3">Does not receive a notification of objection authenticated by the debtor within twenty (20) days after the proposal is sent. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">To be effective under subsection (1)(b) of this section, a notification of objection must be received by the secured party: <section prefix="a">In the case of a person to which the proposal was sent pursuant to KRS 355.9-621, within twenty (20) days after notification was sent to that person; and </section><section prefix="b">In other cases: <section prefix="1">Within twenty (20) days after the last notification was sent pursuant to KRS 355.9-621; or </section><section prefix="2">If a notification was not sent, before the debtor consents to the acceptance under subsection (3) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">A secured party that has taken possession of collateral shall dispose of the collateral pursuant to KRS 355.9-610 within the time specified in subsection (6) of this section if: <section prefix="a">Sixty percent (60%) of the cash price has been paid in the case of a purchase-money security interest in consumer goods; or </section><section prefix="b">Sixty percent (60%) of the principal amount of the obligation secured has been paid in the case of a non-purchase-money security interest in consumer goods. </section></section><section prefix="6">To comply with subsection (5) of this section, the secured party shall dispose of the collateral: <section prefix="a">Within ninety (90) days after taking possession; or </section><section prefix="b">Within any longer period to which the debtor and all secondary obligors have agreed in an agreement to that effect entered into and authenticated after default. </section></section><section prefix="7">In a consumer transaction, a secured party may not accept collateral in partial satisfaction of the obligation it secures. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 138, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>