<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.155</section_number><catch_line>Nomination of candidates serving in Armed Forces. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 118.125 shall not apply to any eligible person serving in the Armed Forces of the United States while this country is at war. The name of such person shall be printed on the official ballot of his party for an office for which he is eligible in any primary election when an application has been filed on his behalf by two (2) reputable electors of the party at whose hands he seeks the nomination. </section><section prefix="2">Such application shall be accompanied by a statement signed by the proposed candidate authorizing the action of the electors. </section><section prefix="3">The application and the candidate's statement, herein mentioned, shall be filed in good faith and with the proper officer at the proper time, as provided for other candidates in primary elections. </section><section prefix="4">The form of such application shall be similar to that of the affidavits required of electors in behalf of other candidates as provided in KRS 118.125. </section><section prefix="5">Before such a successful candidate is given a certificate of nomination, he shall file with the county clerk of the county in which he resides a statement that during the campaign for the nomination he did not, and while a candidate for the office will not, knowingly violate any election law or any law relating to corrupt and fraudulent practice in campaigns or elections in this state, and if elected will qualify for the office. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 25, effective March 10, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 105, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>March 10, 1976 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27585</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>