<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.672</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky delegation to Southern Dairy Compact.  (Effective upon contingency) </catch_line><order_by>672</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The delegation from the Commonwealth of Kentucky to the Southern Dairy Compact Commission, as established in Article III of the compact, set out in KRS 260.670, shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the commissioner of agriculture as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members shall represent the Commonwealth at large; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a dairy farmer engaged in the production of milk at the time of appointment or reappointment; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall represent consumers of milk; and </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall represent fluid milk processors. </section></section><section prefix="2">Members must be registered to vote in the state. </section><section prefix="3">Members shall serve a term of four (4) years and may be reappointed, but no member shall serve more than three (3) consecutive terms. Members shall serve until their successors are duly appointed. Any appointment to fill an unexpired term shall be for the balance of the unexpired term and shall be made by the appropriate appointing authority. A member may be removed by the appointing authority for cause. The Commissioner of Agriculture shall designate one (1) member of the delegation to serve as chair, at the pleasure of the Commissioner. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the delegation shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per diem while performing official duties for the commission. </section><section prefix="5">A majority of the delegation shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="6">All clerical and other services required by the delegation shall be provided by the Commissioner of Agriculture. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 2, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> Upon contingency </effective><lrc-note>1998 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 4, provides: "This Act becomes effective at such time as three states of the group of states given in Section 20 of the Southern Dairy Compact set out in Section 1 (KRS 260.670) of this Act enact that compact into law, substantially in the form given in this Act, and when the consent of the Congress has been obtained to that compact." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12614</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>