<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-275</section_number><catch_line>Limits on liability of bank or trust company acting as fiduciary. </catch_line><order_by>3-275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When an instrument, under which a bank empowered to act as a fiduciary or trust company acts, reserves in the grantor, or vests in an advisory or investment committee or in one (1) or more other persons, any power, including, but not limited to, the authority to direct the acquisition, disposition, or retention of any investment or the power to authorize any act that the bank or trust company may propose, the fiduciary is not liable, either individually or as a fiduciary, for either of the following: <section prefix="a">Any loss that results from compliance with an authorized direction of the grantor, committee, person, or persons; or </section><section prefix="b">Any loss that results from a failure to take any action proposed by the bank or trust company that requires the prior authorization of the grantor, committee, person, or persons if the bank or trust company timely sought but failed to obtain that authorization. </section></section><section prefix="2">The bank or trust company referred to in subsection (1) of this section is relieved from any obligation to perform investment reviews and make recommendations with respect to any investments to the extent the grantor, an advisory or investment committee, or one (1) or more other persons have authority to direct the acquisition, disposition, or retention of any investment. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to the extent that the instrument, under which the bank or trust company referred to in subsection (1) of this section acts, contains provisions that are inconsistent with this section. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.275. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>