<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="98" order_by="98">HEALTH AND WELFARE IN CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS AND IN COUNTIES CONTAINING SUCH CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>98.080</section_number><catch_line>Organization -- Employees -- Bonds of employees. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each commission shall elect a chairman from the appointed members, and a secretary and treasurer not a member of the commission, who shall hold the combined offices at the pleasure of a majority of the commission and receive a salary to be fixed by the commission. It may also elect a superintendent of construction, who shall not be a member of the commission. This officer must be a draughtsman experienced in and familiar with fireproof construction, the erection of large buildings and their mechanical equipment and experienced in reading and executing architect's plans and specifications. He shall give his entire attention to the affairs of the commission, shall receive a salary to be fixed by the commission and shall be removable at the pleasure of the commission. The commission may employ one or more architects to submit and carry out plans for the construction and furnishing, and shall pay them a reasonable compensation. The commission may employ such other professional or technical advisers and such agents and employees as it deems requisite for the proper execution of the duties of the commission, and may fix their compensation and remove or discharge them at pleasure. </section><section prefix="2">The commission may exact from any of its officers or employees indemnity bonds for the proper performance of their duties. The commission may pay the premiums on the indemnity bonds of any of its officers or employees. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3037e-5. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>