<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.015</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Articles of organization" means the articles filed in conformity with the provisions of KRS 275.020 and 275.025, and those articles as amended or restated; </section><section prefix="2">"Business entity" means a domestic or foreign limited liability company, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, business or statutory trust, and not-for-profit unincorporated association; </section><section prefix="3">"Corporation" means a profit or nonprofit corporation formed under the laws of any state or a foreign country; </section><section prefix="4">"Court" means every court having jurisdiction in the case; </section><section prefix="5">"Deliver" or "delivery" means any method of delivery used in conventional commercial practice, including delivery by hand, mail, commercial delivery, and electronic transmission; </section><section prefix="6">"Dissent" means a right to object to a proposed action or transaction and, in connection therewith, to demand a redemption of a limited liability company interest; </section><section prefix="7">"Electronic transmission" or "electronically transmitted" means any process of communication not directly involving the physical transfer of paper that is suitable for the retention, retrieval, and reproduction of information by the recipient; </section><section prefix="8">"Event of disassociation" means an event that causes a person to cease to be a member as provided in KRS 275.280; </section><section prefix="9">"Foreign limited liability company" means an organization that is: <section prefix="a">An unincorporated association; </section><section prefix="b">Organized under laws of a state other than the laws of this Commonwealth, or under the laws of any foreign country; and </section><section prefix="c">Organized under a statute pursuant to which an association may be formed that affords to each of its members limited liability with respect to the liabilities of the entity; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Foreign nonprofit corporation" means a corporation incorporated for a nonprofit purpose under the laws of a state other than the Commonwealth or under the laws of a foreign country; </section><section prefix="11">"Knowledge" means actual knowledge of a fact; </section><section prefix="12">"Limited liability company" or "domestic limited liability company" means a limited liability company formed under this chapter and, except with respect to a nonprofit limited liability company, having one (1) or more members; </section><section prefix="13">"Limited liability company interest" or "interest in the limited liability company" means the interest that may be issued in accordance with KRS 275.195; </section><section prefix="14">"Limited partnership" means a limited partnership formed under the laws of the Commonwealth or any other state or a foreign country; </section><section prefix="15">"Majority-in-interest of the members" means those members entitled to cast a majority of the votes to be cast by the members on any matter under the terms of the operating agreement described in KRS 275.175(3); </section><section prefix="16">"Manager" or "managers" means, with respect to a limited liability company that has set forth in its articles of organization that it is to be managed by managers, the person or persons designated in accordance with KRS 275.165; </section><section prefix="17">"Member" or "members" means a person or persons who have been admitted to membership in a limited liability company as provided in KRS 275.275 and who have not ceased to be members as provided in KRS 275.280; </section><section prefix="18">"Name of record with the Secretary of State" means any real, fictitious, reserved, registered, or assumed name of a business entity; </section><section prefix="19">"Nonprofit limited liability company" means a limited liability company formed for a nonprofit purpose having one (1) or more or no members; </section><section prefix="20">"Nonprofit purpose" includes any purpose authorized under KRS 273.167; </section><section prefix="21">"Operating agreement" means any agreement, written or oral, among all of the members, as to the conduct of the business and affairs of a limited liability company. If a limited liability company has only one (1) member, an operating agreement shall be deemed to include: <section prefix="a">A writing executed by the member that relates to the affairs of the limited liability company and the conduct of its business regardless of whether the writing constitutes an agreement; or </section><section prefix="b">If the limited liability company is managed by a manager, any other agreement between the member and the limited liability company as it relates to the limited liability company and the conduct of its business, regardless of whether the agreement is in writing; </section></section><section prefix="22">"Person" means an individual, a partnership, a domestic or foreign limited liability company, a trust, an estate, an association, a corporation, or any other legal entity; </section><section prefix="23">"Principal office" means the office, in or out of the Commonwealth, so designated in writing with the Secretary of State where the principal executive offices of a domestic or foreign limited liability company are located; </section><section prefix="24">"Proceeding" means civil suit and criminal, administrative, and investigative action; </section><section prefix="25">"Professional limited liability company" means a limited liability company organized under this chapter or the laws of another state or foreign country for purposes that include, but are not limited to, the providing of one (1) or more professional services. Except as otherwise expressly provided in this chapter, all provisions of this chapter governing limited liability companies shall be applicable to professional limited liability companies; </section><section prefix="26">"Professional services" mean the personal services rendered by physicians, osteopaths, optometrists, podiatrists, chiropractors, dentists, nurses, pharmacists, psychologists, occupational therapists, veterinarians, engineers, architects, landscape architects, certified public accountants, public accountants, physical therapists, and attorneys; </section><section prefix="27">"Real name" shall have the meaning set forth in KRS 365.015; </section><section prefix="28">"Regulating board" means the governmental agency which is charged by law with the licensing and regulation of the practice of the profession which the professional limited liability company is organized to provide; and </section><section prefix="29">"State" means a state, territory, or possession of the United States, the District of Columbia, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 45, effective June 24, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 93, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 93, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 232, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section."  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 93, subsection (26) cited "Section 164 of this Act." It is apparent from context that the section referred to should have been Section 163 of the Act, KRS 365.015. The Reviser of Statutes has made this change under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>