<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.060</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors for each district -- Appointment -- Terms -- State officers and members of General Assembly may serve only in advisory capacity. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>There shall be in each area development district a board of directors. The composition of the board and the terms and appointments of its members in each district shall be specified by administrative regulation promulgated by the Department for Local Government in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. The designee of a mayor or county judge/executive shall be a member of the designator's respective legislative body or their staff. Other persons who are not elected officials or members of their staffs may be designated as representatives with the consent of that body. The Department for Local Government, in specifying the composition of the board, shall conform to applicable federal requirements. A person who is a state officer, a deputy state officer, or a member of the General Assembly may serve only in a nonmember advisory capacity to the board of directors of an area development district. An area development district board of directors shall notify legislators of the provisions of this section and of their right to participate in the activities of the area development district. If a legislator chooses to participate in accordance with this section, the area development district shall send meeting notices to that legislator at the same time board members are notified of the meetings. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 73, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 58, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 187, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 69, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(4). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>