<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="109" order_by="109">LOCAL SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>109.310</section_number><catch_line>Collection of solid waste pick-up fees -- Combination with property tax bill -- Notice -- Waiver if owner of property is not the occupant. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county or urban-county government may collect solid waste pick-up fees which are delinquent three (3) consecutive months or more by combining the delinquent fees with the property tax bill for the property where the solid waste pick-up is made. The fees shall be limited to a return on capital expenditures and to cover operational costs. </section><section prefix="2">The pick-up fee when combined with the property tax bill shall be clearly set out as the delinquent amount owed for solid waste pick-up services and shall in no way be represented as an assessment based on the value of the property. </section><section prefix="3">Sixty (60) days before a property tax bill which includes a delinquent solid waste pick-up fee is mailed, the county office responsible for solid waste pick-up billing shall give written notice to the owner of the property that the pick-up bill is delinquent and that, if left unpaid, the fee will be combined with the next property tax bill. </section><section prefix="4">A county or urban-county government may waive the solid waste pick-up fee for businesses which request a waiver. The request for a waiver shall include a certification that the solid waste generated by the business is disposed of properly and include a description of the disposal method and the property owner's federal employer's identification number. </section><section prefix="5">If the owner of the property is not the occupant of the property where the solid waste is picked up, the county or urban-county government shall waive the delinquent solid waste pick-up fee portion of the property tax bill if the owner of the property requests a waiver. In requesting the waiver, the owner shall certify he is not the occupant of the property and that the occupant will be notified that failure of the occupant to pay the solid waste pick-up fee will be considered a breach of the occupant's lease making the occupant subject to eviction. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27286</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>