<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.850</section_number><catch_line>False representation of kosher meats or meat preparations -- Advertising -- Sale. </catch_line><order_by>850</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who, with intent to defraud, sells or exposes for sale any meat or meat preparations, and falsely represents the same to be kosher, whether such meat or meat preparations be raw or prepared for human consumption, or as having been prepared under, and of a product or products sanctioned by, the orthodox Hebrew religious requirements, either by direct statement orally, or in writing, which might reasonably be calculated to deceive or lead a reasonable man to believe that a representation is being made that such meat or meat preparation is kosher or prepared in accordance with the orthodox Hebrew religious requirements, or falsely represents any meat products or the contents of any package or container to be so constituted and prepared, by having or permitting to be inscribed thereon the word "kosher" in any language; or sells or exposes for sale in the same place of business both kosher and non-kosher meat or meat preparations, whether raw or prepared for human consumption, and who fails to indicate on his window signs and all display advertising, in block letters at least four (4) inches in height, "kosher and non-kosher meat sold here"; or who exposes for sale in any show window or place of business both kosher and non-kosher meat or meat preparations, either raw or prepared for human consumption, and who fails to display over each kind of meat or meat preparations, so exposed a sign in block letters at least four (4) inches in height reading "kosher meat," or "non-kosher meat," as the case may be, or who displays on his window, or in his place of business, or in handbills or other printed matter distributed in or outside of his place of business, words or letters in Hebraic characters other than the word "kosher," or any sign, emblem, insignia, six (6) pointed star, symbol, or mark in simulation of same, without displaying in conjunction therewith, in English letters of at least the same size as such characters, signs, emblems, insignia, symbols, or marks, the words "we sell kosher meat only," or "we sell non-kosher meat only," or "we sell both kosher and non-kosher meat," as the case may be, is guilty of a misdemeanor. Possession of non-kosher meat or meat preparations, in any place of business advertising the sale of kosher meat and meat preparations only, is presumptive evidence that the person in possession exposes the same for sale with intent to defraud, in violation of the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A person who, with intent to defraud, sells or exposes for sale in any hotel, restaurant, or other place where meat products are sold for consumption on or off the premises, and falsely represents the same to be kosher, whether such meat or meat preparations, be raw or prepared for human consumption, or as having been prepared under, and of a product or products sanctioned by the orthodox Hebrew religious requirements, either by direct statement orally, or in writing, which might reasonably be calculated to deceive or lead a reasonable man to believe that a representation is being made that such meat is kosher or prepared in accordance with the orthodox Hebrew religious requirements, or falsely represents any meat or meat product or the contents of any package to be so constituted and prepared, by having or permitting to be inscribed thereon the word "kosher" in any language; or sells or exposes for sale in the same place of business both kosher and non-kosher meat or meat preparations, either raw or prepared for human consumption, and who fails to indicate on his window signs and all display advertising, in block letters at least four (4) inches in height, "kosher and non-kosher meat sold here," either raw or prepared for human consumption, and who fails to display over each kind of meat or meat preparation so exposed a sign in block letters at least four (4) inches in height reading "kosher meat" or "non-kosher meat," as the case may be, or who displays on his window, door, or in his place of business, or in handbills or other printed matter distributed in or outside of his place of business, words or letters in Hebraic characters other than the word "kosher," or any sign, emblem, insignia, six (6) pointed star, symbol, or mark in simulation of same, without displaying in conjunction therewith in English letters of at least the same size as such characters, signs, emblems, insignia, symbols, or marks the words "we sell kosher meat only," or "we sell non-kosher meat only," or "we sell both kosher and non-kosher meat," as the case may be, is guilty of a misdemeanor. Possession of non-kosher meat, in any place of business advertising the sale of kosher meat only, is presumptive evidence that the person in possession exposes the same for sale with intent to defraud, in violation of the provisions of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35093</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>