<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.310</section_number><catch_line>Board to provide insurance for school buses. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text>Each board of education may set aside funds to provide for liability and indemnity insurance against the negligence of the drivers or operators of school buses, other motor vehicles, and mobile equipment owned or operated by the board. If the transportation of pupils is let out under contract, the contract shall require the contractor to carry indemnity or liability insurance against negligence in such amount as the board designates. In either case, the indemnity bond or insurance policy shall be issued by some surety or insurance company authorized to transact business in this state, and shall bind the company to pay any final judgment, not to exceed the limits of the policy, rendered against the insured for loss or damage to property of any school child or death or injury of any school child or other person. </text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 436, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4399-20a, 4399-20b. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 57 and 106 (HB 117 and HB 525, respectively), which are in conflict. The later-passed bill, HB 525, prevails in the event of a conflict. In this case, HB 525 reversed the amendments made to this statute in HB 117, resulting in no change being made to this statute in the 2015 Regular Session. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>