<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.020</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of council. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The Council on Postsecondary Education in Kentucky shall: <section prefix="1">Develop and implement the strategic agenda with the advice and counsel of the Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education. The council shall provide for and direct the planning process and subsequent strategic implementation plans based on the strategic agenda as provided in KRS 164.0203; </section><section prefix="2">Revise the strategic agenda and strategic implementation plan with the advice and counsel of the committee as set forth in KRS 164.004; </section><section prefix="3">Develop a system of public accountability related to the strategic agenda by evaluating the performance and effectiveness of the state's postsecondary system. The council shall prepare a report in conjunction with the accountability reporting described in KRS 164.095, which shall be submitted to the committee, the Governor, and the General Assembly by December 1 annually. This report shall include a description of contributions by postsecondary institutions to the quality of elementary and secondary education in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="4">Review, revise, and approve the missions of the state's universities and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. The Council on Postsecondary Education shall have the final authority to determine the compliance of postsecondary institutions with their academic, service, and research missions; </section><section prefix="5">Establish and ensure that all postsecondary institutions in Kentucky cooperatively provide for an integrated system of postsecondary education. The council shall guard against inappropriate and unnecessary conflict and duplication by promoting transferability of credits and easy access of information among institutions; </section><section prefix="6">Engage in analyses and research to determine the overall needs of postsecondary education and adult education in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="7">Develop plans that may be required by federal legislation. The council shall for all purposes of federal legislation relating to planning be considered the "single state agency" as that term may be used in federal legislation. When federal legislation requires additional representation on any "single state agency," the Council on Postsecondary Education shall establish advisory groups necessary to satisfy federal legislative or regulatory guidelines; </section><section prefix="8">Determine tuition and approve the minimum qualifications for admission to the state postsecondary educational system. In defining residency, the council shall classify a student as having Kentucky residency if the student met the residency requirements at the beginning of his or her last year in high school and enters a Kentucky postsecondary education institution within two (2) years of high school graduation. In determining the tuition for non-Kentucky residents, the council shall consider the fees required of Kentucky students by institutions in adjoining states, the resident fees charged by other states, the total actual per student cost of training in the institutions for which the fees are being determined, and the ratios of Kentucky students to non-Kentucky students comprising the enrollments of the respective institutions, and other factors the council may in its sole discretion deem pertinent; </section><section prefix="9">Devise, establish, and periodically review and revise policies to be used in making recommendations to the Governor for consideration in developing recommendations to the General Assembly for appropriations to the universities, the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, and to support strategies for persons to maintain necessary levels of literacy throughout their lifetimes including but not limited to appropriations to the Kentucky Adult Education Program. The council has sole discretion, with advice of the Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education and the executive officers of the postsecondary education system, to devise policies that provide for allocation of funds among the universities and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="10">Lead and provide staff support for the biennial budget process as provided under KRS Chapter 48, in cooperation with the committee; </section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, review and approve all capital construction projects covered by KRS 45.750(1)(f), including real property acquisitions, and regardless of the source of funding for projects or acquisitions. Approval of capital projects and real property acquisitions shall be on a basis consistent with the strategic agenda and the mission of the respective universities and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section><section prefix="b">The organized groups that are establishing community college satellites as branches of existing community colleges in the counties of Laurel, Leslie, and Muhlenberg, and that have substantially obtained cash, pledges, real property, or other commitments to build the satellite at no cost to the Commonwealth, other than operating costs that shall be paid as part of the operating budget of the main community college of which the satellite is a branch, are authorized to begin construction of the satellite on or after January 1, 1998; </section></section><section prefix="12">Require reports from the executive officer of each institution it deems necessary for the effectual performance of its duties; </section><section prefix="13">Ensure that the state postsecondary system does not unnecessarily duplicate services and programs provided by private postsecondary institutions and shall promote maximum cooperation between the state postsecondary system and private postsecondary institutions. Receive and consider an annual report prepared by the Association of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities stating the condition of independent institutions, listing opportunities for more collaboration between the state and independent institutions and other information as appropriate; </section><section prefix="14">Establish course credit, transfer, and degree components as required in KRS 164.2951; </section><section prefix="15">Define and approve the offering of all postsecondary education technical, associate, baccalaureate, graduate, and professional degree, certificate, or diploma programs in the public postsecondary education institutions. The council shall expedite wherever possible the approval of requests from the Kentucky Community and Technical College System board of regents relating to new certificate, diploma, technical, or associate degree programs of a vocational-technical and occupational nature. Without the consent of the General Assembly, the council shall not abolish or limit the total enrollment of the general program offered at any community college to meet the goal of reasonable access throughout the Commonwealth to a two (2) year course of general studies designed for transfer to a baccalaureate program. This does not restrict or limit the authority of the council, as set forth in this section, to eliminate or make changes in individual programs within that general program; </section><section prefix="16">Eliminate, in its discretion, existing programs or make any changes in existing academic programs at the state's postsecondary educational institutions, taking into consideration these criteria: <section prefix="a">Consistency with the institution's mission and the strategic agenda; </section><section prefix="b">Alignment with the priorities in the strategic implementation plan for achieving the strategic agenda; </section><section prefix="c">Elimination of unnecessary duplication of programs within and among institutions; and </section><section prefix="d">Efforts to create cooperative programs with other institutions through traditional means, or by use of distance learning technology and electronic resources, to achieve effective and efficient program delivery; </section></section><section prefix="17">Ensure the governing board and faculty of all postsecondary education institutions are committed to providing instruction free of discrimination against students who hold political views and opinions contrary to those of the governing board and faculty; </section><section prefix="18">Review proposals and make recommendations to the Governor regarding the establishment of new public community colleges, technical institutions, and new four (4) year colleges; </section><section prefix="19">Postpone the approval of any new program at a state postsecondary educational institution, unless the institution has met its equal educational opportunity goals, as established by the council. In accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the council, those institutions not meeting the goals shall be able to obtain a temporary waiver, if the institution has made substantial progress toward meeting its equal educational opportunity goals; </section><section prefix="20">Ensure the coordination, transferability, and connectivity of technology among postsecondary institutions in the Commonwealth including the development and implementation of a technology plan as a component of the strategic agenda; </section><section prefix="21">Approve the teacher education programs in the public institutions that comply with standards established by the Education Professional Standards Board pursuant to KRS 161.028; </section><section prefix="22">Constitute the representative agency of the Commonwealth in all matters of postsecondary education of a general and statewide nature which are not otherwise delegated to one (1) or more institutions of postsecondary learning. The responsibility may be exercised through appropriate contractual relationships with individuals or agencies located within or without the Commonwealth. The authority includes but is not limited to contractual arrangements for programs of research, specialized training, and cultural enrichment; </section><section prefix="23">Maintain procedures for the approval of a designated receiver to provide for the maintenance of student records of the public institutions of higher education and the colleges as defined in KRS 164.945, and institutions operating pursuant to KRS 165A.310 which offer collegiate level courses for academic credit, which cease to operate. Procedures shall include assurances that, upon proper request, subject to federal and state laws and regulations, copies of student records shall be made available within a reasonable length of time for a minimum fee; </section><section prefix="24">Monitor and transmit a report on compliance with KRS 164.351 to the director of the Legislative Research Commission for distribution to the Health and Welfare Committee; </section><section prefix="25">Develop in cooperation with each state postsecondary educational institution a comprehensive orientation program for new members of the council and the governing boards. The orientation program shall include but not be limited to the information concerning the roles of the council, the strategic agenda and the strategic implementation plan, and the respective institution's mission, budget, plans, policies, strengths, and weaknesses; </section><section prefix="26">Develop a financial reporting procedure to be used by all state postsecondary education institutions to ensure uniformity of financial information available to state agencies and the public; </section><section prefix="27">Select and appoint a president of the council under KRS 164.013; </section><section prefix="28">Employ consultants and other persons and employees as may be required for the council's operations, functions, and responsibilities; </section><section prefix="29">Promulgate administrative regulations, in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A, governing its powers, duties, and responsibilities as described in this section; </section><section prefix="30">Prepare and present by January 31 of each year an annual status report on postsecondary education in the Commonwealth to the Governor, the Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education, and the Legislative Research Commission; </section><section prefix="31">Consider the role, function, and capacity of independent institutions of postsecondary education in developing policies to meet the immediate and future needs of the state. When it is found that independent institutions can meet state needs effectively, state resources may be used to contract with or otherwise assist independent institutions in meeting these needs; </section><section prefix="32">Create advisory groups representing the presidents, faculty, nonteaching staff, and students of the public postsecondary education system and the independent colleges and universities; </section><section prefix="33">Develop a statewide policy to promote employee and faculty development in all postsecondary institutions and in state and locally operated secondary area technology centers through the waiver of tuition for college credit coursework in the public postsecondary education system. Any regular full-time employee of a postsecondary public institution or a state or locally operated secondary area technology center may, with prior administrative approval of the course offering institution, take a maximum of six (6) credit hours per term at any public postsecondary institution. The institution shall waive the tuition up to a maximum of six (6) credit hours per term; </section><section prefix="34">Establish a statewide mission for adult education and develop a twenty (20) year strategy, in partnership with the Kentucky Adult Education Program, under the provisions of KRS 164.0203 for raising the knowledge and skills of the state's adult population. The council shall: <section prefix="a">Promote coordination of programs and responsibilities linked to the issue of adult education with the Kentucky Adult Education Program and with other agencies and institutions; </section><section prefix="b">Facilitate the development of strategies to increase the knowledge and skills of adults in all counties by promoting the efficient and effective coordination of all available education and training resources; </section><section prefix="c">Lead a statewide public information and marketing campaign to convey the critical nature of Kentucky's adult literacy challenge and to reach adults and employers with practical information about available education and training opportunities; </section><section prefix="d">Establish standards for adult literacy and monitor progress in achieving the state's adult literacy goals, including existing standards that may have been developed to meet requirements of federal law in conjunction with the Collaborative Center for Literacy Development: Early Childhood through Adulthood; and </section><section prefix="e">Administer the adult education and literacy initiative fund created under KRS 164.041; </section></section><section prefix="35">Participate with the Kentucky Department of Education, the Kentucky Board of Education, and postsecondary education institutions to ensure that academic content requirements for successful entry into postsecondary education programs are aligned with high school content standards and that students who master the high school academic content standards shall not need remedial courses. The council shall monitor the results on an ongoing basis; </section><section prefix="36">Cooperate with the Kentucky Department of Education and the Education Professional Standards Board in providing information sessions to selected postsecondary education content faculty and teacher educators of the high school academic content standards as required under KRS 158.6453(2)(j); </section><section prefix="37">Cooperate with the Office for Education and Workforce Statistics and ensure the participation of the public institutions as required in KRS 151B.133; and </section><section prefix="38">Exercise any other powers, duties, and responsibilities necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to grant the Council on Postsecondary Education authority to disestablish or eliminate any college of law which became a part of the state system of higher education through merger with a state college. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 13, effective March 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 101, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 526, secs. 3 and 27, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 74, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 2, effective February 20, 1992; and ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 39, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 4, effective April 9, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, secs. 41, 106, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 295, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(2). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 118. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 2. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4527-1, 4527-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 11, (6) at 659.</budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (3/25/2009) The Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering of subsections (35), (36), and (37) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 13, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>