<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.2867</section_number><catch_line>Provision of vaccination information regarding meningococcal meningitis disease to postsecondary students. </catch_line><order_by>2867</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each public or private educational institution that offers a postsecondary degree and has a residential campus shall provide vaccination information on meningococcal meningitis disease to full-time students living in resident housing. </section><section prefix="2">The vaccination information shall be contained in the student housing or enrollment application or lease document and shall include a space for the student to indicate whether or not the student has received the vaccination against meningococcal meningitis disease. If institutions provide electronic enrollment or registration to first-time students, the information required by this section may be provided or collected electronically. </section><section prefix="3">Vaccination information about meningococcal meningitis disease shall include detailed information on the risks of the disease and any recommendations issued by the National Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. </section><section prefix="4">The vaccination information obtained under this section that is in the possession of the educational institution is confidential and shall not be a public record. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not be construed to require the educational institution or the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to provide or pay for the meningococcal meningitis disease vaccination. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 139, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4242</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>