<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.474</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for funds -- Need-based applications by member's spouse or dependent for necessary expenses -- Expenditure of funds to benefit group of members, spouses, or dependents -- Expenditure of funds to Adoption Assistance Program applicants -- Adjutant general to award or decline -- Identification of other funding sources available to applicant -- Emergency regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>474</order_by><text><section prefix="1">During active duty of a regular member of the United States Armed Forces deployed outside the United States who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes, or any federal active duty of a member of a state National Guard or a Reserve component, who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes, and for one hundred eighty (180) days following the end of deployment outside the United States or deactivation, as appropriate, trust fund moneys shall be used to support: <section prefix="a">The person who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes; </section><section prefix="b">The person's Kentucky resident spouse; </section><section prefix="c">The person's dependent or dependents; or </section><section prefix="d">A group of several members of the military or their families as described in paragraphs (a) to (c) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">An application for a trust fund grant may be filed by the member who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes or his or her Kentucky resident spouse. The application shall be accompanied by an appropriate authorization to access personnel information contained in the military database Defense Enrollment Reporting System (DEERS) for verification purposes. </section><section prefix="3">Subject to the availability of trust fund moneys, the adjutant general shall award a grant to an applicant described in paragraphs (a) to (c) of subsection (1) of this section if that person's application is need-based, and the amount of the grant does not exceed the dollar cap established by the board through the promulgation of administrative regulations. An application shall be need-based if: <section prefix="a">Funds are requested for necessary expenses incurred, or to be incurred. Necessary expenses shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Housing; </section><section prefix="2">Utilities; </section><section prefix="3">Groceries; </section><section prefix="4">Health insurance copay; and </section><section prefix="5">Child care; </section></section><section prefix="b">The necessary expenses created, or will create, an undue hardship on a person referred to in subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">The undue hardship is directly related to the member's deployment outside the United States or federal active duty, as appropriate; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant does not have reasonable access to any other funding source, whether public or private; and </section><section prefix="e">The military family assistance trust fund is the last resort. </section></section><section prefix="4">Subject to the availability of trust fund moneys, the adjutant general may expend trust fund money, in amounts up to one thousand dollars ($1,000) per situation and up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per calendar year, to benefit individuals described in paragraph (d) of subsection (1) of this section if: <section prefix="a">The individuals have a demonstrated need that affects their health, safety, or well-being; and </section><section prefix="b">A majority of the members of the military family assistance trust fund board has approved the expenditure, verbally or in writing. </section></section><section prefix="5">Subject to the availability of trust fund moneys, the director of the Kentucky National Guard Family Services Program within the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs may expend trust fund money, in amounts up to one thousand dollars ($1,000) per situation and up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per calendar year, to benefit individuals described in subsection (1) of this section if: <section prefix="a">The individuals have a demonstrated need that affects their health, safety, or well-being; and </section><section prefix="b">A majority of the members of the military family assistance trust fund board has approved the expenditure, verbally or in writing. </section></section><section prefix="6">Subject to the availability of military family assistance trust fund moneys, the adjutant general shall expend trust fund money to eligible applicants to the Kentucky National Guard Adoption Assistance Program as provided in KRS 36.477. Eligible applicants to the Kentucky National Guard Adoption Assistance Program shall not be subject to the requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">The adjutant general shall award or decline to award a grant within sixty (60) days of receiving an application. </section><section prefix="b">If the adjutant general awards or declines to award a grant, he or she shall state in writing the reason for the decision and keep the writing on file. </section><section prefix="c">If the adjutant general declines to award a grant, he or she shall provide the applicant with a copy of the writing referred to in paragraph (b) of this subsection. In addition, if the adjutant general declines to award a grant due to the availability of public or private funds, the adjutant general shall identify the source of available funds for the applicant and provide assistance with regard to seeking funds from that source. </section></section><section prefix="8">No later than August 15, 2006, the military family assistance trust fund board shall promulgate emergency administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. These emergency regulations shall, at a minimum, enhance administrative efficiency and limit the dollar amount that a person may receive in grants per twelve (12) month period. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 3, effective April 25, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40096</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>