<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.858</section_number><catch_line>Services and procedures that may be performed by physician assistant -- Restrictions. </catch_line><order_by>858</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A physician assistant may perform medical services and procedures within the scope of medical services and procedures described in the initial or any supplemental application received by the board under KRS 311.854. </section><section prefix="2">A physician assistant shall be considered an agent of the supervising physician in performing medical services and procedures described in the initial application or any supplemental application received by the board under KRS 311.854. </section><section prefix="3">A physician assistant may initiate evaluation and treatment in emergency situations without specific approval. </section><section prefix="4">A physician assistant may prescribe and administer all nonscheduled legend drugs and medical devices as delegated by the supervising physician. A physician assistant who is delegated prescribing authority may request, receive, and distribute professional sample drugs to patients. </section><section prefix="5">A physician assistant shall not submit direct billing for medical services and procedures performed by the physician assistant. </section><section prefix="6">A physician assistant may perform local infiltrative anesthesia under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, but a physician assistant shall not administer or monitor general or regional anesthesia unless the requirements of KRS 311.862 are met. </section><section prefix="7">A physician assistant may perform services in the offices or clinics of the supervising physician. A physician assistant may also render services in hospitals or other licensed health care facilities only with written permission of the facility's governing body, and the facility may restrict the physician assistant's scope of practice within the facility as deemed appropriate by the facility. </section><section prefix="8">A physician assistant shall not practice medicine or osteopathy independently. Each physician assistant shall practice under supervision as defined in KRS 311.840. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 32, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30657</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>