<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.241</section_number><catch_line>Statement of General Assembly. </catch_line><order_by>241</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds and declares the following: <section prefix="1">Thousands of Kentuckians enter underground mines each day to produce coal that is so vital to the economy of our nation and the well-being of its people. </section><section prefix="2">The underground coal mine is a hazardous environment that constantly requires the highest degree of safety consciousness on the part of every individual. </section><section prefix="3">Despite training and a variety of safety efforts, each year coal mines continue to take a heavy human toll: large numbers of miners are injured; many are left permanently disabled; and a lesser number pay the ultimate price--death. </section><section prefix="4">Many activities are performed by a variety of persons; therefore, each coal miner is expected to learn and perform a large number of tasks. </section><section prefix="5">Miners frequently become engaged in unfamiliar tasks when substituting for others or assisting a fellow worker. </section><section prefix="6">The American zeal for work and productivity very frequently causes the miner to give second priority to normal safety measures and precautions. </section><section prefix="7">Studies have demonstrated that experienced persons observing and providing on-the-job counseling to individual miners regarding their work habits can bring about a significant reduction in underground mine accidents and fatalities. </section></text><history>Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32947</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>