<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.628</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of property to board of health -- Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>628</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All real, personal, and mixed property belonging to the city-county board of health or city-county department of health is hereby transferred to the board and the city-county board of health or city-county department of health shall take all the necessary and proper steps to effect the legal transfer of title and possession of all such property to the board. </section><section prefix="2">When the board has been organized and all property transferred as provided under subsection (1) of this section, the board may control, operate, or monitor all matters within the county affecting public health including institutions established to safeguard the public health which may encompass city or county medical facilities, nursing homes, medical care of the indigent, and laboratories and clinics necessary for the promotion of public health and environmental protection and which are required or permitted under the provisions of any act of the General Assembly, under any ordinances, orders, and resolutions of the legislative body of the county, or under any rules or regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 415, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 366, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>