<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.152</section_number><catch_line>Requirement of registration -- Application requirements -- Criminal background checks -- Annual renewal of registration -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>152</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not act or offer to act as an appraisal management company or perform appraisal management services within the Commonwealth unless registered by the board. </section><section prefix="2">To be registered by the board, a person shall make written application to the board, submit to a criminal background check as provided in subsection (3) of this section, pay a filing fee established by the board, and pay the fee required to be included in the appraisal management company recovery fund created in KRS 324A.155. The written application shall include the following information: <section prefix="a">The name, street address, and telephone contact information of the person seeking registration; </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">If the registrant is a domestic organization, the designation of an agent for service of process; or </section><section prefix="2">If the registrant is a foreign organization, documentation that the foreign organization is authorized to transact business in the Commonwealth and has appointed an agent for service of process by submitting a copy of: <section prefix="a">The registrant's filing with the Secretary of State appointing an agent for service of process; and </section><section prefix="b">A certificate of authority issued by the Secretary of State. </section> A foreign organization's failure to comply with this paragraph may result in rejection of the application; </section></section><section prefix="c">The name, residential street address, and contact information of any person who owns ten percent (10%) or more of the appraisal management company for which registration is being requested; </section><section prefix="d">The name, residential street address, and contact information of a controlling person or managing principal; </section><section prefix="e">A certification that the registrant: <section prefix="1">Has a system and process in place to verify that any person being added to the appraiser panel of the appraisal management company, or who may be used by the appraisal management company to otherwise perform appraisals, holds a license in good standing in this state under this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Has a system and process in place to review the work of all appraisers that are performing appraisal services for the appraisal management company on a periodic basis to ensure that the appraisal services are being conducted in accordance with the minimum USPAP standards; and </section><section prefix="3">Maintains a detailed record of each request for appraisal services that it receives and the appraiser that performs the appraisal services for the appraisal management company; </section></section><section prefix="f">A certification from the registrant and any partner, member, manager, officer, director, managing principal, controlling person, or person occupying a similar status or performing similar functions, or person directly or indirectly controlling the registrant that: <section prefix="1">The application for registration when filed or after filing contains no statement that, in light of the circumstances under which it was made, is false or misleading with respect to a material fact; </section><section prefix="2">The person certifying has not violated or failed to comply with KRS 324A.154, 324A.156, or 324A.158; </section><section prefix="3">The person certifying and each person who owns ten percent (10%) or more of the registrant has not pled guilty or nolo contendere to or been found guilty of: <section prefix="a">A felony; or </section><section prefix="b">Within the past ten (10) years, a misdemeanor involving mortgage lending or real estate appraising, or an offense involving breach of trust or fraudulent or dishonest dealing; </section></section><section prefix="4">The person certifying is not permanently or temporarily enjoined by a court of competent jurisdiction from engaging in or continuing any conduct or practice involving appraisal management services or operating an appraisal management company; </section><section prefix="5">The person certifying is not the subject of an order of the board or any other state's appraisal management company regulatory agency denying, suspending, or revoking the person's privilege to operate as an appraisal management company; and </section><section prefix="6">The person certifying has not acted as an appraisal management company while not properly registered by the board; and </section></section><section prefix="g">Any other information required by the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall require a national and state criminal background check on the person certifying under subsection (2)(f) of this section and each person who owns ten percent (10%) or more of the registrant under the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The person certifying and each person who owns ten percent (10%) or more of the registrant shall provide his or her fingerprints to the Department of Kentucky State Police for submission to the Federal Bureau of Investigation after a state criminal background check is conducted; </section><section prefix="b">The results of the national and state criminal background check shall be sent to the board; and </section><section prefix="c">Any fee charged by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall be an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request and conducting the check. </section></section><section prefix="4">The board shall issue a certificate of registration to a registrant authorizing the registrant to act or offer to act as an appraisal management company in this state upon: <section prefix="a">Receipt of a properly completed application; </section><section prefix="b">Payment of the required filing fee; </section><section prefix="c">Payment of the fee required to be included in the appraisal management company recovery fund; and </section><section prefix="d">A determination by the board that: <section prefix="1">The registrant has not had a previous registration suspended or revoked; and </section><section prefix="2">The activities of the applicant shall be directed and conducted by persons who: <section prefix="a">Have not had a previous registration suspended or revoked; </section><section prefix="b">Have not pled guilty or nolo contendere to or been found guilty of a felony; or </section><section prefix="c">Within the past ten (10) years have not pled guilty, pled nolo contendere to, or been found guilty of a misdemeanor involving mortgage lending or real estate appraising or an offense involving a breach of trust or fraudulent or dishonest dealing. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">If the board finds that there is substantial reason to deny the application for registration, the board shall notify the registrant that the application has been denied and shall afford the registrant an opportunity for a hearing before the board to show cause why the registration should not be denied. </section><section prefix="b">All proceedings concerning the denial of a certificate of registration shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="c">The acceptance by the board of an application for registration does not constitute the approval of its contents or waive the authority of the board to take disciplinary action under KRS 324A.162. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Registrations issued under this section shall be renewed annually. </section><section prefix="b">Renewal shall occur on October 31 of each year. </section><section prefix="c">If the initial registration occurs less than six (6) months before October 31, the renewal shall not be required until October 31 of the following year, and shall then be renewed on October 31 of each year thereafter. </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Failure to renew a registration in a timely manner shall result in a loss of authority to operate. </section><section prefix="b">A request to reinstate a certificate of registration shall be accompanied by payment of a penalty of fifty dollars ($50) for each month of delinquency, up to six (6) months after expiration. </section><section prefix="c">After six (6) months' delinquency, a new application for registration shall be required. </section></section><section prefix="8">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish standards for the operation of appraisal management companies and for the implementation and enforcement of KRS 324A.150 to 324A.164. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42091</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>