<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="388" order_by="388">UNIFORM VETERANS' GUARDIANSHIP ACT </unit></structure><section_number>388.270</section_number><catch_line>Court to approve appointment -- Bond of guardian or conservator. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before making an appointment under the provisions of this chapter, the court shall be satisfied that the person whose appointment is sought is a fit and proper person to be appointed. Upon the appointment being made, the guardian or conservator shall execute and file a bond to be approved by the court in an amount not less than the estimated value of the personal estate and anticipated income during the ensuing year. The said bond shall be in the form and be conditioned as required of guardians and conservators appointed under the general guardianship laws of this state. The court shall have power from time to time to require the guardian or conservator to file an additional bond.  </section><section prefix="2">Where a bond is tendered by a guardian or conservator with personal sureties, there shall be at least two (2) such sureties and they shall file with the court a certificate under oath which shall describe the property owned, both real and personal, and shall state that they are each worth the sum named in the bond as the penalty thereof over and above all their debts and liabilities and exclusive of property exempt from execution. Notwithstanding such tender, the court may require additional security or may require a corporate surety bond, the premium thereon to be paid from the ward's estate. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 121, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982</effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 132 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36098</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>