<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.186</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 16.186 to 16.195. </catch_line><order_by>186</order_by><text>As used in KRS 16.186 to 16.195, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" means the secretary of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="4">"Officer" means any individual appointed to one (1) of the positions established by KRS 16.187 who has the powers of a peace officer; </section><section prefix="5">"Department" means the Department of Kentucky State Police; and </section><section prefix="6">"Continuous service" for participation in and eligibility for the promotional process for each rank of commercial vehicle enforcement officer means: <section prefix="a">For sergeant, service as a commissioned officer that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, or termination; </section><section prefix="b">For lieutenant, service in grade as a sergeant that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, termination, or by demotion in accordance with KRS 16.192; and </section><section prefix="c">For captain, service in grade as a lieutenant that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, termination, or by demotion in accordance with KRS 16.192. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009). 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75 sec. 1, provided that a new KRS Chapter 16A was to be established and a new section thereof was to be created for this statute. In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has instead created new sections of existing KRS Chapter 16 for 2009 Ky. Acts. ch. 75, secs. 1 to 10, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>