<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.515</section_number><catch_line>Pretrial release investigation and services -- Provision of information on services and programs for combat veterans. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All trial courts in this Commonwealth having jurisdiction of criminal causes shall provide such pretrial release investigation and services as necessary to effectuate the purposes of KRS 431.510 to 431.550, including KRS 431.518, and, where practical, to assist in the earliest possible determination of: <section prefix="a">Whether a person is a needy person under KRS Chapter 31; and </section><section prefix="b">Whether a person has been in combat by asking the question, "Have you served in the National Guard or the United States Armed Forces and been in combat?" during the pretrial release investigation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Supreme Court may by appropriate rule or order establish and provide for such pretrial investigation and release services including, where practical, the taking of financial statements, and the court's determination of whether a person is a needy person as provided in KRS 31.120. </section><section prefix="3">Pretrial officers shall give contact information on the Kentucky National Guard Family Services Program within the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs or similar programs which provide a full range of services for combat veterans to any person who states that he or she has been in combat, including an opportunity to call the program during the interview. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, effective March 24, 2009. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>