<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.295</section_number><catch_line>Offenses -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any officer or employee of a board or any other person who prevents, attempts to prevent, or obstructs an examination by the accountant made under KRS 156.265 and 156.275 is guilty of a high misdemeanor and shall, upon indictment and conviction in the Circuit Court of competent jurisdiction, be fined five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who fails or refuses to permit the examination provided for in KRS 156.285 or who interferes with such examination shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) or imprisoned in the county jail for not less than one (1) month nor more than twelve (12) months, or both. Each refusal shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who has custody of any books, accounts, reports, vouchers, correspondence, files, records, money, and property that the accountant is authorized to examine under KRS 156.265 and 156.285 who fails or refuses when called upon by the committee for that purpose to permit the accountant to inspect any of such materials shall, upon conviction in the Circuit Court of competent jurisdiction, be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500) and be subject to removal as provided by law. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who refuses to be sworn when required by the committee to be sworn for the purpose mentioned in subsection (2) of KRS 156.285 shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="5">Any witness called by the committee under subsection (3) of KRS 156.285 who fails, without legal excuse, to attend or testify shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section></text><history>Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 369, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. II, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (9/2/94).  By letter of September 2, 1994, the Secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, acting under KRS 48.500, advised the Reviser of Statutes of his determination "that no funds appropriated by the Executive Branch Appropriations Act for the 1995-96 biennium can be identified as having been appropriated for the purpose of implementing Sections 1 to 7 of House Bill No. 616, Chapter (296), Acts of the 1994 Regular Session of the General Assembly." Accordingly, the amendment to this statute contained in 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 296 is void under sec. 3(8) of that Act and has not been codified into the statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3165</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>