<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.547</section_number><catch_line>Public inspection of cabinet inspection reports, service descriptions, listings of rates and charges, and court orders on premises -- Duties of Inspector General -- Construction of section with respect to Kentucky Open Records Law. </catch_line><order_by>547</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All long-term care facilities shall retain the following for public inspection in the office of the administrator and in the lobby of the facility: <section prefix="a">A complete copy of every inspection report of the facility received from the cabinet during the past three (3) years, including the most recent inspection report; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the services currently provided by the facility; </section><section prefix="c">A listing of the rates currently charged for services provided by the facility; </section><section prefix="d">A listing together with the charges for the services and items not included in the basic rate for which residents may be charged separately; and </section><section prefix="e">A copy of every court order issued pertaining to the quality of care or services provided in the facility. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Office of the Inspector General shall be responsible for providing public notice of results of licensure inspections of long-term care facilities and shall issue administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to carry this out. Any licensure result that has not become final shall not be subject to release for public notice until the result becomes final. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit access to public records otherwise allowed pursuant to the provisions of KRS 61.872 to 61.884. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>