<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.020</section_number><catch_line>Petition for election.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petition for an election shall be signed by a number of constitutionally qualified voters of the territory to be affected, equal to twenty-five percent (25%) of the votes cast in the territory at the last preceding general election. The petition may consist of one (1) or more separate units, and shall be filed with the county clerk. </section><section prefix="2">The petition for election, in addition to the name of the voter, shall state also the voter's residence address, date of birth, and the correct date upon which the voter's name was signed. </section><section prefix="3">No signer may withdraw his or her name or have it taken from the petition after the petition has been filed. If the name of any person has been placed on the petition for election without that person's authority, the person may appear before the county judge/executive before the election is ordered and upon proof that the person's name was placed on the petition without his or her authority, the person's name may be eliminated by an order of the county judge/executive. When the person's name has been eliminated, he or she shall not be counted as a petitioner. </section><section prefix="4">A petition seeking a local option election under this section shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages in (name of territory)?'". No petition for a referendum shall be circulated for more than six (6) months prior to its filing. </section><section prefix="5">After a petition for election has been filed, the county judge/executive shall make an order on the order book of the court directing an election to be held in that territory. </section><section prefix="6">Substantial compliance with the wording designated under this chapter for a particular type of petition is sufficient to validate the actual wording of the petition. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 87, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 112, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 374, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554c-2, 2554c-3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42440</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>