<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.050</section_number><catch_line>Membership of Public Service Commission -- Appointment -- Terms -- Chairman -- Vacancies. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Public Service Commission shall consist of three (3) members appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Senate. If the Senate is not in session when a term expires or a vacancy occurs, the Governor shall make the appointment to take effect at once, subject to the approval of the Senate when convened. Appointments to the Public Service Commission made more than ninety (90) days prior to a regular session of the General Assembly shall be subject to confirmation by the Joint Interim Committee on Energy. Each of the three (3) members of the commission shall be appointed on or before the first day of July, 1982, for staggered terms as follows: one (1) shall serve until the first day of July, 1983, one (1) until the first day of July, 1984, and one (1) until the first day of July, 1985, and thereafter for a term of four (4) years and until a successor is appointed and qualified. Each member of the commission shall be a full-time employee as defined in KRS 18A.005(17). </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint one (1) of the commissioners on the commission to act as chairman thereof and the chairman shall be the chief executive officer of the commission. The Governor shall designate one (1) of the commissioners on the commission to serve as vice chairman thereof and act for the chairman in the latter's absence. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies for unexpired terms shall be filled in the same manner as original appointments, but the appointee shall hold office only to the end of the unexpired term. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 11, effective April 1, 1979. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 3, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3952-3, 3952-3a. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>