<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0552</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for establishing precincts. </catch_line><order_by>0552</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 117.055 to 117.0555 and KRS 117.0557, "establish a precinct" shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Creating a new precinct; </section><section prefix="b">Dividing one (1) precinct into two (2) or more precincts; </section><section prefix="c">Combining two (2) or more precincts into one (1) precinct; and </section><section prefix="d">Altering a boundary line between two (2) or more precincts. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each county board of elections shall establish precincts by issuing a proposed precinct establishment order. Each proposed precinct establishment order shall be submitted to the executive director of the State Board of Elections for approval. </section><section prefix="3">The order prescribed in subsection (2) of this section shall include: <section prefix="a">A written description of the boundaries of each precinct to be established; </section><section prefix="b">A map or maps clearly showing the boundaries of each precinct to be established; </section><section prefix="c">The estimated number of registered voters in each precinct to be established; and </section><section prefix="d">Any additional information which may be required by an administrative regulation adopted by the State Board of Elections under KRS Chapter 13A for the purposes of assuring compliance with KRS 117.055 to 117.0555 and KRS 117.0557. </section></section><section prefix="4">If a proposed precinct establishment order includes a description of a precinct with a boundary that follows the boundary of an entity referred to in KRS 117.0551(1), the order shall include the following: <section prefix="a">A description that precisely identifies the boundary line; and </section><section prefix="b">A notation on the map of the precinct indicating that the boundary is that of an entity referred to in KRS 117.0551(1) and naming the specific entity. </section></section><section prefix="5">If a proposed precinct establishment order includes a description of a precinct boundary that follows one or more visible features, the order shall include a description that precisely identifies each feature that forms the precinct boundary. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 3, , effective July 14,1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>