<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.46955</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited telephone solicitation acts and practices. </catch_line><order_by>46955</order_by><text>It is a prohibited telephone solicitation act or practice and a violation of KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999 for any person making a telephone solicitation to engage in the following conduct: <section prefix="1">Advertising or representing that registration as a telemarketer equals an endorsement or approval by any government or governmental agency; </section><section prefix="2">Requesting a fee in advance to remove derogatory information from or improve a person's credit history or credit record; </section><section prefix="3">Requesting or receiving a payment in advance from a person to recover or otherwise aid in the return of money or any other item lost by the consumer in a prior telephone solicitation transaction; </section><section prefix="4">Requesting or receiving payment of any fee or consideration in advance of obtaining a loan or other extension of credit when the telemarketing company has guaranteed or represented a high likelihood of success in obtaining or arranging a loan or other extension of credit for a person; </section><section prefix="5">Obtaining or submitting for payment a check, draft, or other form of negotiable paper drawn on a person's checking, savings, or bond or other account without the consumer's express written authorization, or charging a credit card account or making electronic transfer of funds except in conformity with KRS 367.46963; </section><section prefix="6">Procuring the services of any professional delivery, courier, or other pickup service to obtain immediate receipt or possession of a consumer's payment, unless the goods are delivered with the opportunity to inspect before any payment is collected; </section><section prefix="7">Assisting, supporting, or providing substantial assistance to any telemarketer when the telemarketing company knew or should have known that the telemarketer was engaged in any act or practice prohibited under this section; </section><section prefix="8">Making a telephone solicitation to anyone under eighteen (18) years of age. When making a telephone solicitation the telemarketer shall inquire as to whether the person is eighteen (18) years of age or older and the answer shall be presumed to be correct; </section><section prefix="9">Utilizing any method to block or otherwise circumvent the use of a caller identification service when placing an unsolicited telephone solicitation call; </section><section prefix="10">Directing or permitting employees to use a fictitious name or not to use their name while making a telephone solicitation; </section><section prefix="11">Threatening, intimidating, or using profane or obscene language; </section><section prefix="12">Causing the telephone to ring more than thirty (30) seconds in an intended telephone solicitation; </section><section prefix="13">Engaging any person repeatedly or continuously with behavior a reasonable person would deem to be annoying, abusive, or harassing; </section><section prefix="14">Initiating a telephone solicitation call to a person, when that person has stated previously that he or she does not wish to receive solicitation calls from that seller; </section><section prefix="15">Making or causing to be made an unsolicited telephone solicitation call if the residential number for that telephone appears in the current publication of the national Do Not Call Registry maintained by the United States Federal Trade Commission; </section><section prefix="16">Making telephone solicitations to a person's residence at any time other than between 10 a.m. - 9 p.m. local time, at the called person's location; </section><section prefix="17">Selling or making available for economic gain any information revealed during a telephone solicitation without the express written consent of the consumer; </section><section prefix="18">Making a telephone solicitation to any residential telephone using an artificial or prerecorded voice to deliver a message, unless the call is initiated for emergency purposes by schools regulated by the Kentucky Department of Education or the call is made with the prior express consent of the called party; or </section><section prefix="19">Engaging in any unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive practice or act as part of a telephone solicitation. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 581, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (07/15/2002). Under the authority of KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected a clearly erroneous statutory reference in subsection (5) of this section as enacted in 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 2, by changing "KRS 367.46953" to "KRS 367.46963." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34971</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>