<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.520</section_number><catch_line>Participation determined by board and fixed by executive order -- Authority for order.   </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each department determined by the board to be eligible and qualified for participation shall participate in the system when the Governor by appropriate executive order, the authority to issue such executive order being granted, directs such department to participate in the system. The effective date of such participation shall be determined by the board and fixed by the Governor in his executive order. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section the Governor is authorized to permit any state college or university, which he directs by appropriate executive order to participate in the system after January 1, 1972, to include its noninstructional employees in the membership of the system while excluding the instructional employees of the state college or university from membership. </section><section prefix="b">All employees of an agency participating under authority of subsection (2)(a) of this section shall be considered noninstructional employees except the members of the instructional staff of the state college or university who are responsible for teaching and the administrative positions which are included in the Teachers' Insurance and Annuity Association (TIAA) or the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System. </section></section><section prefix="3">All executive orders issued under authority of this section since July 1, 1956, are hereby ratified by the General Assembly and each participating and contributing department, board, agency, corporation, board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability, or entity participating since that date under such executive order is hereby declared to be a participating department under the Kentucky Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided by KRS 61.522: <section prefix="a">Once a department participates it shall continue to participate as long as it remains qualified; and </section><section prefix="b">Any position initially required to participate in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System shall continue to participate as long as the position exists. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 6, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 13, effective March 26, 1974. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 21. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 2. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 165, Part II, sec. 2. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44275</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>