<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-140</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations concerning the adoption of carbon dioxide emission reduction performance standards for electric generating units. </catch_line><order_by>20-140</order_by><text>The Kentucky General Assembly hereby finds and declares that: <section prefix="1">The United States Environmental Protection Agency intends to adopt guidelines to reduce carbon dioxide emissions from existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units under 42 U.S.C. sec. 7411(d); </section><section prefix="2">The United States Congress charges states, rather than the United States Environmental Protection Agency, with establishing standards of performance under 42 U.S.C. sec. 7411(d) for existing stationary sources, including fossil fuel-fired electric generating units, as a means of furthering the scheme of cooperative federalism under the federal Clean Air Act and with ensuring that the states have the primary role in managing their own economic and environmental resources; and </section><section prefix="3">Providing reliable and affordable electricity through using various energy feedstocks for electric generation, including coal, natural gas, nuclear, and renewable resources, as well as using energy efficiently will provide economic and environmental benefits for the citizens of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43008</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>