<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.025</section_number><catch_line>County responsibility for incarceration of prisoners. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of each county shall provide for the incarceration of prisoners arrested in the county or sentenced or held by order of the courts in the county. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall provide for the incarceration of prisoners by: <section prefix="a">Providing and maintaining a facility that complies with KRS 441.055; </section><section prefix="b">Providing and maintaining a safe, secure, and clean jail in the county; or that complies with the health and life safety standards defined in KRS 441.055; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Contracting with another county or a city for the incarceration and care of its prisoners; and </section><section prefix="2">Providing for the transportation of prisoners, as provided for in KRS 441.505 and 441.510 including the provision of vehicles, drivers, and guards. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a county from providing facilities for holding prisoners for limited periods of time and contracting with another county or a city for longer periods of incarceration. </section><section prefix="4">Any county may enter into an agreement pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300 to provide or to use jail facilities. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.006. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19286</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>