<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.150</section_number><catch_line>Investigation of licensee -- Disciplinary action against licensee --Investigative powers of commission -- Emergency hearings. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The commission or its staff may on its own initiative investigate the actions of any licensee or any person who acts in that capacity. On the verified written complaint of any person, the commission shall investigate the actions of any person who assumes to act in that capacity, if the complaint, together with any evidence presented in connection with it, alleges a prima facie case that a violation set out in KRS 324.160 has been committed. After the investigation, the commission may order a hearing and, in appropriate cases, take disciplinary action against any licensee who is found in violation of KRS 324.160. </section><section prefix="b">The commission may conduct an emergency hearing when alleged escrow account violations warrant emergency action. The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations to describe the specific circumstances and allegations that authorize emergency action. The emergency hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, as it relates to emergency orders and emergency hearings. </section></section><section prefix="2">To investigate allegations of practices violating the provisions of this chapter, the commission may: <section prefix="a">Issue subpoenas to compel attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, documents, or other evidence; </section><section prefix="b">Administer oaths; </section><section prefix="c">Review evidence; </section><section prefix="d">Enter the office or branch office of any principal broker for the purpose of inspecting all documents required by the commission to be maintained in the principal broker's office or branch office which relate to the allegations of practices violating the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="e">Examine witnesses; and </section><section prefix="f">Pay appropriate witness fees. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 15, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 16. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-6. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31576</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>