<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.677</section_number><catch_line>Persons and activities not regulated by KRS 311.671 to 311.686. </catch_line><order_by>677</order_by><text>The provisions of KRS 311.671 to 311.686 shall not apply to: <section prefix="1">Persons licensed, certified, or registered under any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and does not prohibit them from rendering services consistent with the laws regulating their professional practices and the ethics of their professions; </section><section prefix="2">Student interns or trainees pursuing a program of studies in an institution approved by the board for teaching the practice of acupuncture, if the person is designated an acupuncture intern or student in training and his or her activities are performed under supervision and constitute a part of the supervised program of study; </section><section prefix="3">Activities of visiting acupuncturists who are legally qualified to perform acupuncture in another state in performing their duties as teachers at a board-approved institution or board-approved workshop or tutorial. As used in this subsection, "duties" means classroom instruction and demonstration of relevant techniques. It does not include the provision of any services to a patient in exchange for a fee; or </section><section prefix="4">Activities, services, and use of title on the part of a person as part of their employment by the federal government. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30615</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>