<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.041</section_number><catch_line>National uniformity of documents. </catch_line><order_by>041</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to promote and maintain nationwide uniformity in the system of vital statistics, the forms of certificates and reports required by this chapter, or by administrative regulations adopted hereunder, shall include, as a minimum, the items recommended by the federal agency responsible for national vital statistics. </section><section prefix="2">Each certificate, report, and other documents required by this chapter shall be on a form or in a format prescribed by the cabinet with due consideration for national uniformity. All certificates shall be typewritten with the exception of required signatures which shall be written legibly in unfading black or blue ink. </section><section prefix="3">No certificate shall be held to be complete and correct that does not supply all items of information called for therein or satisfactorily account for their omission, except as provided in KRS 199.570(3). If a certificate is incomplete, the local registrar shall immediately notify the responsible person and require that person to supply the missing items, if that information can be obtained. </section><section prefix="4">All vital records shall contain the data required for registration. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall charge or collect from any member of a family in which a birth or death occurs, any fee for completing and filing a report, or any other act or duty imposed upon them by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>