<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.750</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 353.750 to 353.776. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>As used in KRS 353.750 to 353.776, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Agreement" means a written contract between the authority and any person or persons, firm, corporation, local government, or public entity providing for or relating to the financing of the construction, reconstruction, improvement, or repair of one (1) or more projects of the authority; </section><section prefix="2">"Authority" means the Kentucky Gas Pipeline Authority created by KRS 353.752; </section><section prefix="3">"Bonds" mean revenue bonds, notes, or other obligations issued under the provisions of KRS 353.756, 353.758, or 353.768; </section><section prefix="4">"Cost" means the expenditures for construction, acquisition, financing charges, interest prior to and during construction, principal and interest on any bonds or notes or obligations issued by the authority, engineering and legal expenses, plans, specifications, cost and revenue estimates, other expenses necessary or incidental to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing any project, administrative expenses, and such other expenses necessary or incident to the construction of and placing into operation a project, the financing of the construction, and the acquisition of the project; </section><section prefix="5">"Project" means the construction, reconstruction, improvement, or repair of any gas pipeline or appurtenant facilities, together with all property, rights, easements, and interests which may be acquired by the authority to facilitate the construction, reconstruction, improvement, or repair of any gas pipeline or appurtenant facilities. Except for projects involving repair or replacement, projects shall be limited to areas where no gas pipelines exist or where existing lines have insufficient capacity to transport Kentucky gases to market; and </section><section prefix="6">"Gas" means natural gas, coalbed or other methane gas, carbon dioxide gas, crude oil or petroleum products, or any elements of natural gas or other gas. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33150</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>