<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.165</section_number><catch_line>Duty to report quality of care and safety problems -- Investigation and report -- Prohibition against retaliation. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any agent or employee of a health care facility or service licensed under this chapter who knows or has reasonable cause to believe that the quality of care of a patient, patient safety, or the health care facility's or service's safety is in jeopardy shall make an oral or written report of the problem to the health care facility or service, and may make it to any appropriate private, public, state, or federal agency. </section><section prefix="2">Any individual in an administrative or supervisory capacity at the health care facility or service who receives a report under subsection (1) of this section shall investigate the problem, take appropriate action, and provide a response to the individual reporting the problem within seven (7) working days. </section><section prefix="3">No health care facility or service licensed under this chapter shall by policy, contract, procedure, or other formal or informal means subject to reprisal, or directly or indirectly use, or threaten to use, any authority or influence, in any manner whatsoever, which tends to discourage, restrain, suppress, dissuade, deter, prevent, interfere with, coerce, or discriminate against any agent or employee who in good faith reports, discloses, divulges, or otherwise brings to the attention of the health care facility or service the circumstances or facts to form the basis of a report under subsections (1) or (2) of this section. No health care facility or service shall require any agent or employee to give notice prior to making a report, disclosure, or divulgence under subsections (1) or (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">All reports, investigations, and action taken subject to this chapter shall be conducted in a manner that protects and maintains the confidentiality of patients and personnel and preserves the integrity of data, information, and medical records. </section><section prefix="5">All health care facilities and services licensed under this chapter shall, as a condition of licensure, abide by the terms of KRS 216B.155 and this section. </section><section prefix="6">No agent or employee of a health care facility or service shall file a report under subsection (1) or (2) of this section in bad faith and shall have a reasonable basis for filing a report. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9230</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>