<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.40-040</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board -- Executive director. </catch_line><order_by>40-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may develop articles of incorporation and appropriate documentation to establish its existence as a corporation under KRS 58.180. </section><section prefix="2">A quorum of the board shall consist of four (4) members, with a majority of members present authorized to act upon any matter legally before the corporation. </section><section prefix="3">The board may enact bylaws concerning the election of officers and other administrative procedures it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="4">The board may adopt administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to govern the operation, maintenance, or use of property under its custody and control. </section><section prefix="5">Minutes and records of all meetings of the board shall be kept, and all official actions shall be recorded. </section><section prefix="6">The board may establish an executive committee from among its membership with full authority to act between meetings of the board to the extent delegated by vote of a majority of the members of the board. </section><section prefix="7">The board may employ a full-time executive director who shall hold office at its pleasure. <section prefix="a">The executive director shall act under the direction of the board in employing necessary staff to perform the corporation's duties and exercise its powers. </section><section prefix="b">The executive director shall keep all minutes, records, and orders of the corporation and shall be responsible for the preservation of all the documents, which shall be public records under KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section></section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2916</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>