<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.440</section_number><catch_line>Statement filed listing property seized -- Investigation of utilization of proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each law enforcement agency seizing money or property pursuant to KRS 218A.415 shall, at the close of each fiscal year, file a statement with the Auditor of Public Accounts, and with the secretary of justice and public safety containing, a detailed listing of all money and property seized in that fiscal year and the disposition thereof. The listing shall identify all property so seized. </section><section prefix="2">Any agency failing to report as required by this section shall be liable to the state for the full value of all property and money so seized. The Attorney General shall institute civil actions for recovery of money or property obtained or retained in violation of KRS 218A.405 to 218A.460. </section><section prefix="3">The Auditor of Public Accounts, the secretary of justice and public safety or the Attorney General may at any time initiate an inquiry to determine that property is being forfeited as required by KRS 218A.405 to 218A.460. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 255, effective June 26, 2007; and ch.124, sec. 15, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 124, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9709</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>