<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.320</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 219.330 to 219.410. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text>As used in KRS 219.330 to 219.410: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Manufactured home" means a single-family residential dwelling constructed in accordance with the National Manufactured Housing Construction in Safety Standards Act, manufactured after June 15, 1976, and designed to be used as a single-family residential dwelling with or without a permanent foundation when connected to the required utilities, and including plumbing, heating, air conditioning, and electrical systems. A manufactured home may also be used as a place of business, profession, or trade by the owner, the lessee, or the assigns of the owner or lessee and may comprise an integral unit or condominium structure. Buildings, the construction of which are not preempted by the National Manufactured Housing Construction in Safety Standards Act, are subject to the building code requirements of KRS Chapter 198B; </section><section prefix="4">"Mobile home" means a structure manufactured prior to June 15, 1976, that was not required to be constructed in accordance with the National Manufactured Housing Construction in Safety Standards Act, that is transportable in one (1) or more sections, that, in the traveling mode is eight (8) body feet or more in width and forty (40) body feet or more in length, or when erected on site, four hundred (400) or more square feet, and that is built on a permanent chassis and designed to be used as a dwelling on a temporary or permanent foundation, when connected with the permanent required utilities, including plumbing, heating, air conditioning, and electrical systems; </section><section prefix="5">"Manufactured or mobile home lot" means a parcel of land in a manufactured or mobile home community for the placement of a single manufactured or mobile home; </section><section prefix="6">"Manufactured or mobile home community" means a parcel of land, under single or multiple ownership and developed specifically for the purpose of leasing two (2) or more residential spaces for the location of manufactured or mobile home dwellings and which contain common facilities and utilities located on the premises as licensed by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="7">"Community" means a manufactured home,mobile home, and recreational vehicle community; </section><section prefix="8">"ANSI/NFPA" means the American National Standards Institute/National Fire Protection Association; </section><section prefix="9">"Underskirting" means a weather resistant material used to enclose the space from the bottom of a manufactured or mobile home to grade; </section><section prefix="10">"Person" means an individual, or a firm, partnership, company, corporation, trustee, association, or any public or private entity owning or operating a community; </section><section prefix="11">"Recreational vehicle" means any of the following: <section prefix="a">"Travel trailer" means a vehicular, portable structure built on a chassis, designed to be used as a temporary dwelling for travel, recreation, or vacation; </section><section prefix="b">"Pickup coach" means a structure designed to be mounted on a truck for use as a temporary dwelling for travel, recreation, or vacation; </section><section prefix="c">"Motorhome" means a portable, temporary dwelling to be used for travel, recreation, or vacation, constructed as an integral part of a self-propelled vehicle; </section><section prefix="d">"Camping trailer" means a canvas or other collapsible folding structure, mounted on wheels and designed for travel, recreation, or vacation use; </section><section prefix="e">"Dependent recreational vehicle" means a recreational vehicle which does not have toilet, lavatory, or bathing facilities; or </section><section prefix="f">"Self-contained recreational vehicle" means a recreational vehicle which can operate independent of connections to sewer, water, and electric systems. It contains a water-flushed toilet, lavatory, shower or bath, kitchen sink, all of which are connected to water storage and sewage holding tanks located within the recreational vehicle; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Recreational vehicle community" means a parcel of land available to the public in which two (2) or more recreational vehicle spaces are occupied or intended for occupancy by recreational vehicles for transient dwelling purposes and includes any service building, structure, enclosure, or other facility used as a part of the community; </section><section prefix="13">"Recreational vehicle space" means a parcel of land in a recreational vehicle community for the placement of a single recreational vehicle; </section><section prefix="14">"Sanitary station" means a facility used for receiving and disposing of wastes from recreational vehicle holding tanks; </section><section prefix="15">"Service building" means a building containing water closets, urinals, lavatories, and bathing facilities for use by persons using the community; and </section><section prefix="16">"Watering station" means a facility for filling the water storage tanks of recreational vehicles with potable water from an approved water system. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 554, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 494, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (11), and (22). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>