<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.24-110</section_number><catch_line>Tax credits -- Employee job assessment fees. </catch_line><order_by>24-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The approved company shall be entitled to a tax credit equal to one hundred percent (100%) of the income tax and one hundred percent (100%) of the limited liability entity tax imposed by KRS 141.0401 that would otherwise be due to the Commonwealth by the approved company attributable to the economic development project, as limited by the provisions of this section and KRS 154.24-130. The amount of the approved company's income, Kentucky gross profits, or Kentucky gross receipts that is attributable to the economic development project shall be determined under KRS 141.407. The ordering of credits shall be as provided in KRS 141.0205. <section prefix="a">The tax credit allowed to the approved company shall be subtracted from the approved cost balance in the fiscal year of the approved company for which the tax return of the approved company is filed; and </section><section prefix="b">By October 1 of each year, the Department of Revenue of the Commonwealth shall certify to the authority, in the form of an annual report, aggregate tax credits claimed on tax returns filed during the fiscal year ending June 30 of that year, and assessments taken by approved companies with respect to their economic development projects during the prior calendar year under this subchapter, and shall certify to the authority, within ninety (90) days from the date an approved company has filed its state tax return, when an approved company has taken tax credits and assessments equal to its total inducements. </section></section><section prefix="2">The approved company or, with the authority's consent, an affiliate of the approved company may require each employee, subject to state tax imposed by KRS 141.020, as a condition of employment, to agree to pay a service and technology job creation assessment fee up to five percent (5%) of the gross wages exclusive of any noncash benefits provided to an employee for each employee whose job has been deemed by the authority to be created as a result of the economic development project, provided that the service and technology job creation assessment fee shall not exceed the amount determined in accordance with KRS 154.24-150(5) if the circumstances in that subsection apply. Where a person is already employed by the approved company at a site other than the site of the economic development project and where that employee is subject to state tax imposed by KRS 141.020, the employee's job shall be deemed to have been created when the employee is transferred to the site of the economic development project, provided that the employee's existing job is filled with a new employee. <section prefix="a">Each employee paying the assessment shall be entitled to a credit against his Kentucky income tax required to be withheld under KRS 141.310 equal to four-fifths (4/5) of the assessment; </section><section prefix="b">If the assessment has been approved by the local jurisdiction as provided in KRS 154.24-150, each employee paying the assessment also shall be entitled, in the local jurisdiction in which the economic development project is located, to a credit against his local occupational license fee in the form of a simultaneous adjustment of his local occupational license fee withholding equal to one-fifth (1/5) of the assessment. If more than one (1) local tax is incurred, the one-fifth (1/5) assessment shall be prorated proportionately among the taxes unless one (1) local jurisdiction agrees to forgo the receipt of these taxes in an amount equal to the one-fifth (1/5) assessment, in which case no proration need be made; </section><section prefix="c">If an approved company elects to impose the assessment as a condition of employment, it shall be authorized to deduct the assessment from each payment of wages to the employee; </section><section prefix="d">No credit, or portion thereof, shall be allowed against any occupational license fee imposed by or dedicated solely to the board of education in a local jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="e">The approved company collecting an assessment shall make its payroll, books, and records available to the authority when the authority shall request, and shall file with the authority documentation pertaining to the assessment as the authority may require; and </section><section prefix="f">Any assessment of the wages of employees of an approved company in connection with their employment at an economic development project shall permanently cease at the expiration of the agreement. </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding subsection (2) of this section, if a local government in which the project is located has a local occupational license fee that is less than one percent (1%) and agrees to forgo all of its local occupational license fee, then the assessment shall be four percent (4%), all of which shall be contributed by the Commonwealth, plus the percentage of the local occupational license fee that the local government has agreed to forgo. Each employee paying the assessment under this subsection shall be entitled to a credit against Kentucky income tax, under KRS 141.350, equal to four percent (4%) and a credit against the local occupational license fee equal to the local occupational license fee that the local jurisdiction has agreed to forgo. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 52, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 580, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 34, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 20, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 28, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>(6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>