<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.201</section_number><catch_line>Voting. </catch_line><order_by>201</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The right of the members, or any class or classes of members, to vote may be limited, enlarged or denied to the extent specified in the articles of incorporation or the bylaws. Unless so limited, enlarged or denied, each member, regardless of class, shall be entitled to one (1) vote on each matter submitted to a vote of members.  </section><section prefix="2">A member entitled to vote may vote in person or, unless the articles of incorporation or the bylaws otherwise provide, may vote by proxy executed in writing by the member or by his duly authorized attorney-in-fact. No proxy shall be valid after eleven (11) months from the date of its execution, unless otherwise provided in the proxy. Where directors or officers are to be elected by members, the bylaws may provide that such elections may be conducted by mail.  </section><section prefix="3">The articles of incorporation or the bylaws may provide that in all elections for directors every member entitled to vote shall have the right to cumulate his vote and to give one (1) candidate a number of votes equal to his vote multiplied by the number of directors to be elected, or by distributing such votes on the same principle among any number of such candidates.  </section><section prefix="4">If a corporation has no members or its members have no right to vote, the directors shall have the sole voting power. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 14. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13627</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>