<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.770</section_number><catch_line>Advisory committee on writing program. </catch_line><order_by>770</order_by><text>An advisory committee on writing shall be created by the Kentucky Board of Education to make recommendations to the board regarding the establishment of an intensive writing component in the state program of studies for grades seven (7) through ten (10) and the establishment of innovative pilot writing programs in selected local school districts in grades seven (7) through ten (10). <section prefix="1">The advisory committee shall be composed of nine (9) members appointed by the Kentucky Board of Education. The majority of the membership shall be educators currently employed by local school districts or public universities. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">On July 13, 1990, the terms of the current members of the advisory committee shall expire and the Kentucky Board of Education shall appoint members as follows: three (3) members shall serve two (2) year terms, three (3) members shall serve three (3) year terms, and three (3) members shall serve four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="b">As the terms described in subsection (a) of this section expire, members appointed thereafter shall serve four (4) year terms. </section></section><section prefix="3">All operating expenses of the committee shall be approved by the Kentucky Board of Education and paid from funds budgeted to the writing programs. Members shall be reimbursed for actual expenses for attendance at committee meetings and for other actual expenses incurred in carrying out their official duties. </section><section prefix="4">The functions of the committee shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Analyze the program of studies of grades seven (7) through ten (10) and make recommendations to the Kentucky Board of Education on the options for including an intensive writing program; </section><section prefix="b">Make recommendations to the Kentucky Board of Education on methods of integrating writing into the curriculum in grades seven (7) through ten (10); </section><section prefix="c">Make recommendations to the Kentucky Board of Education relative to the development of teacher training programs and workshops designed to facilitate the effective teaching of writing; </section><section prefix="d">Develop and recommend to the Kentucky Board of Education criteria for local district participation in the pilot program; </section><section prefix="e">Develop a monitoring and ongoing evaluation system; and </section><section prefix="f">Recommend to the Kentucky Board of Education a grant allotment system to award funds to eligible districts. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 213, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 14, effective October 18, 1985. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3582</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>