<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.040</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for involuntary admission for individuals with an intellectual disability.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>When a person who is alleged to be an individual with an intellectual disability is involuntarily admitted, there shall be a determination that: <section prefix="1">The person is an individual with an intellectual disability; </section><section prefix="2">The person presents a danger or a threat of danger to self, family, or others; </section><section prefix="3">The least restrictive alternative mode of treatment presently available requires placement in an ICF/ID; and </section><section prefix="4">Treatment that can reasonably benefit the person is available in an ICF/ID. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 41, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 2, effective March 6, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 37, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 5.</history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>