<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.580</section_number><catch_line>Certificates of acceptability -- Requirements for issuance. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is unlawful for any manufacturer to manufacture, import, or sell manufactured homes within this state unless such manufacturer has been issued a certificate of acceptability for such manufactured homes from the board or its designee. This provision shall not, however, apply to manufactured homes manufactured in this state and designated for delivery to and sale in another state. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall require that the manufacturer establish and submit to the department for approval systems for quality control for recreational vehicles prior to the issuance of a certificate of acceptability. Certificates of acceptability shall be numbered and a record shall be kept by the department, by number, of the certificates issued to manufacturers. </section><section prefix="3">No manufacturer to which a certificate of acceptability has been issued shall modify in any way its manufacturing specifications without prior written approval of the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 415, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 5. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10682</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>