<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.007</section_number><catch_line>Arrest powers of peace officers assisting in another county -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>007</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A peace officer certified pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404, who is directly employed as a police officer by a Kentucky city, county, or urban-county government and whose department meets the requirements of KRS 15.440 and a sheriff, or deputy sheriff who has been certified pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404, who is officially requested by a law enforcement agency in another county in Kentucky to assist in any matter within the jurisdiction of the requesting agency shall possess, while responding to and for the duration of the matter for which the request was made, the same powers of arrest in the requesting county as he possesses in the county in which he is a police officer. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of this section shall not: <section prefix="a">Authorize assistance in any labor dispute or strike; </section><section prefix="b">Authorize assistance by a constable or deputy constable; </section><section prefix="c">Authorize assistance by a special local peace officer; or </section><section prefix="d">Authorize assistance by a special deputy sheriff. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18563</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>