<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person, firm, partnership, or corporation to operate in this state a boiler or pressure vessel without a valid certificate of inspection. The operation of a boiler or pressure vessel without a valid certificate, or at a pressure exceeding that specified in an inspection certificate, shall constitute a Class B misdemeanor on the part of the owner, user, or operator. Each day of unlawful operation shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 236.040(1); 236.080(4); 236.110(1), (4) and (5); 236.210(1); 236.220(1); 236.240(1) and (2); 236.250(1); or any proper order or administrative regulation made or promulgated thereunder; or who hinders or obstructs an authorized inspector in the performance of his or her duties under this chapter, shall be subject to the penalties in subsection (1) above. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who willfully violates any provision of this chapter, or any administrative regulation, emergency order, order of the state fire marshal, order of an authorized deputy state fire marshal, order of the chief boiler inspector, or order of any authorized boiler inspector, promulgated or made pursuant to this chapter, shall be subject to suspension or revocation of any appointment, commission, certification, registration, license, or permit made or issued by the department and held by that person, in accordance with the procedures specified in KRS 236.220, or in lieu of a suspension or revocation, shall be subject to an administrative fine of not less than ten dollars ($10) and not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500) after notice and hearing by the board in accordance with KRS 236.220. Each day these violations exist shall, in the discretion of the board, be considered as a separate violation. </section><section prefix="4">As an aid to enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, or of any administrative regulation or order relating thereto, the department or chief boiler inspector may take any administrative action or bring any authorized legal action designed to prevent or correct any condition constituting or threatening to constitute a violation of any provision of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 532, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 157, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 21 and 22, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40122</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>