<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.240</section_number><catch_line>Distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler not to be interested in retail premises -- Transactions prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text>No distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler and no employee, servant, or agent of a distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler shall: <section prefix="1">Be interested directly or indirectly in any way in any premises where distilled spirits or wine is sold at retail or in any business devoted wholly or partially to the sale of distilled spirits or wine at retail. </section><section prefix="2">Make or cause to be made any loan to any person engaged in the manufacture or sale of distilled spirits or wine at wholesale or retail. </section><section prefix="3">Make any gift or render any kind of service whatsoever, directly or indirectly, to any licensee under KRS 243.030 which in the sound judgment of the board may tend to influence the licensee to purchase the product of the distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler. </section><section prefix="4">Enter into a contract with any retail licensee under KRS Chapters 241 to 244 whereby the licensee agrees to confine his or her sales to distilled spirits or wine manufactured or sold by one (1) or more such distillers, rectifiers, wineries, or wholesalers. Such a contract shall be void. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 88, effective June 25, 2013. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-168. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42523</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>