<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.280</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board limited -- Private connections -- Type of improvements authorized -- Rights as to public corporations -- Annual audit. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The powers of the board of directors shall be limited to the construction, maintenance and operation of such works as are necessary to carry out the purposes of the district in improvement of sanitation, as set forth in KRS 220.030. The board shall not permit house and users' connections at the cost of the district, and every connection shall be made under the supervision of the district. No house or users' connection shall be made unless and until the house or user is provided with an adequate water supply. </section><section prefix="2">In order to effect the proper collection and disposal of sewage and other liquid wastes produced within the district, to promote the public health, comfort, convenience and welfare, and to accomplish all other purposes of the district, the board may clean out, straighten, alter, deepen or otherwise improve any stream, watercourse or body of water receiving sewage or other liquid wastes and located in or out of the district; fill up any abandoned or altered stream, watercourse or body of water located in or out of the district; construct and maintain laterals, trunk sewers, intercepting sewers, siphons, pumping stations, treatment and disposal works and improvements deemed necessary to accomplish the purposes of the district and construct, preserve, operate or maintain such works in or out of the district; construct connections to the works of the district for the delivery thereto of sewage and other liquid wastes; incorporate with the works of the district or otherwise utilize any public sewers, drains or other sewerage improvements either without modifications or with repairs, modifications or changes deemed necessary; construct any and all of the works and improvements across or through any public or private property in or out of the district; hold, encumber, control, acquire by donation, purchase or condemnation, and construct, own, lease, use and sell, any real or personal property, or any easement necessary for rights-of-way or locations for the works and improvements of the district, or for any necessary purpose, or for obtaining or storing material to be used in constructing and maintaining the works and improvements. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 220.010 to 220.540 shall not limit or interfere with the right of public corporations to install, maintain and operate sewerage systems as otherwise permitted by law, but the board of directors shall have full power and authority in the construction and maintenance of improvements for the purposes of the district to serve the area included within the district, and the board of directors may require the use of the improvements of the district by persons and public corporations included within the district and for which the improvements were installed. </section><section prefix="4">The board of directors shall have an annual audit made by a certified public accountant, copies of which shall be filed with the Secretary of State and with the county judge/executive of the county or counties in which the sanitation district is located. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-28. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9798</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>