<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.718</section_number><catch_line>Training and continuing education for Commonwealth's attorneys and county attorneys and their staffs -- Completion requirements.   </catch_line><order_by>718</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General shall provide initial training courses and, at least once every two (2) years, continuing education courses for Commonwealth's attorneys and county attorneys and their staffs concerning: <section prefix="a">The dynamics of domestic violence, child physical and sexual abuse, rape, effects of crime on adult and child victims, legal remedies for protection, lethality and risk issues, profiles of offenders, model protocols for addressing domestic violence, child abuse, rape, available community resources and victims services, and reporting requirements; and </section><section prefix="b">The appropriate response to victims of human trafficking, including but not limited to screening for victims of human trafficking, federal and state legislation on human trafficking, appropriate services and referrals for victims of human trafficking, working with interpreters, and agency protocol for handling child trafficking cases. </section></section><section prefix="2">The training shall be developed in consultation with prosecutors, victims services, victim advocacy, and mental health professionals with an expertise in domestic violence, child abuse, human trafficking, and rape. </section><section prefix="3">Each Commonwealth's Attorney, assistant Commonwealth's Attorney, county attorney, and assistant county attorney shall successfully complete the training. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41847</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>