<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.37-540</section_number><catch_line>Annual statement -- Limitation on aggregate pledges and encumbrances of assets -- Investment of net worth in subsidiaries. </catch_line><order_by>37-540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to any other items required to be filed with the department under this chapter, each mutual insurance holding company shall supply to the Department of Insurance, by March 1 of each year, an annual statement consisting of the following: <section prefix="a">An income statement; </section><section prefix="b">A balance sheet; </section><section prefix="c">A cash flow statement; </section><section prefix="d">Complete information on the status of any closed block of business formed as a part of a plan or reorganization; </section><section prefix="e">An investment plan covering all assets; and </section><section prefix="f">A statement disclosing any intention to pledge, borrow against, alienate, hypothecate, or in any way encumber the assets of the mutual insurance holding company. </section></section><section prefix="2">The aggregate pledges and encumbrances of a mutual holding company's assets shall not affect more than forty-nine percent (49%) of the company's stock in any subsidiary insurance holding company or subsidiary insurance company that resulted from a reorganization or merger. </section><section prefix="3">At least fifty percent (50%) of the generally accepted accounting practices net worth of a mutual insurance holding company shall be invested in insurance company subsidiaries. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1491, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 546, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29953</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>