<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.550</section_number><catch_line>Community Flood Damage Abatement Program. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Community Flood Damage Abatement Program within the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">It is hereby declared to be the purpose of the program to provide funds and technical assistance to local governments to initiate flood control projects and programs. </section><section prefix="3">This program shall be administered by the secretary according to standards designed to promote adequate planning, construction and conservation measures to deal with water drainage problems. </section><section prefix="4">Any local sponsoring community desiring to qualify for funding, must: <section prefix="a">Make application to the cabinet which shall be in the form and manner prescribed by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Provide at no expense to the cabinet, all lands and easements necessary for project construction; </section><section prefix="c">Agree to operate and maintain the project in a manner acceptable to the Commonwealth to insure the continued capacity of the project to prevent or minimize flood damages; </section><section prefix="d">Submit evidence of the history of flooding within the last five (5) years; </section><section prefix="e">Submit evidence of flood damage in dollars within the last five (5) years. </section></section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall have and exercise the power and authority to annually inspect the completed project to insure compliance with any of the provisions of this section or with any rules, regulations or orders adopted pursuant thereto, or with any of the conditions contained in subsection (4)(c) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 178, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2128</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>