<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.420</section_number><catch_line>Approval of construction plans required -- Department to pay for architectural plans and engineering services -- Fee schedule.   </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No political subdivision of this Commonwealth, combination of subdivisions, or regional jail authority shall build a new local correctional facility unless: <section prefix="a">The facility meets the approval or complies with the standards and administrative regulations of the department promulgated pursuant to KRS 441.055; </section><section prefix="b">The construction results in a new facility with: <section prefix="1">A minimum capacity of one hundred fifty (150) prisoner beds; or </section><section prefix="2">If a larger facility is needed, more than one hundred fifty (150) prisoner beds in fifty (50) bed increments; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Construction of the local correctional facility is approved by the construction authority. </section></section><section prefix="2">Final authority for approval of plans for the construction of a local correctional facility, or an addition to a local correctional facility shall rest with the construction authority. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall pay for the architectural plans and engineering services associated with any new local correctional facility approved by the construction authority. </section><section prefix="4">The department may promulgate administrative regulations to create a fee schedule for architectural plans and engineering services required for the construction of local correctional facilities. A sample fee schedule for architectural plans and engineering services may be developed by a committee consisting of department personnel, architects, and construction managers. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.78, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 124, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 44, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42276</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>