<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.737Location</section_number><catch_line>of well drilled through workable coal bed to be provided.   </catch_line><order_by>737Location</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to collect and provide accurate information regarding the location of a well drilled through a workable coal bed, the well operator shall, within thirty (30) days following the drilling of the well, provide to the division a plat which shows the well's as-drilled location and elevation. The plat shall be certified as accurate by a professional land surveyor licensed in accordance with KRS Chapter 322 and shall be provided in addition to the plat accompanying the application for permit, which is required under KRS 353.590(6). The as-drilled well location plat required by this section shall provide coordinates in feet units, using NAD 83, with Single Zone Projection as those terms are defined in KRS 353.010. </section><section prefix="2">A well shall be deemed to be in compliance with applicable permit requirements if the as-drilled location of the well is: <section prefix="a">At the surface, within fifteen (15) feet of the location specified in the permit to drill; and </section><section prefix="b">Drilled through the base of the lowest workable coal bed within one hundred fifty (150) feet from the true vertical of the as-drilled surface location. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 19, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>