<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.710</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities and functions of educationally deficient districts and education development districts -- Plans required -- Reports required. (Expired) </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text>Each educationally deficient district and education development district shall assume the following responsibilities and functions in implementing the provisions of KRS 158.680 to 158.710: <section prefix="1">The district shall develop a plan to improve the education of all students enrolled in preschool and the primary program through grade twelve (12). In developing the plan and prior to approval by the local board of education, the district shall involve local citizens, parents, students, teachers, and administrators. The district, pursuant to KRS 158.685, shall involve Department of Education consultants in the development of the plan; </section><section prefix="2">Educationally deficient districts and education development districts pursuant to KRS 158.685 shall submit a plan each year, or more frequently if ordered by the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education, listing new process goals, the interim performance goals, and timelines until the deficiency has been eliminated; </section><section prefix="3">Local school personnel shall ascertain areas of strength and areas needing improvement in the school program as revealed by the test results and other student assessments and with the advice and counsel of the representatives mentioned in subsection (1) of this section, shall develop appropriate programs to address educational areas needing improvement for all students in preschool and the primary program through grade twelve (12); </section><section prefix="4">The district improvement plan developed and submitted to the department shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Performance goals or interim performance goals; </section><section prefix="b">Product goals; </section><section prefix="c">A list of individuals, by occupation, or groups involved in developing the plan; </section><section prefix="d">The areas of needed improvement as revealed by the district assessment results; </section><section prefix="e">A list of priorities for program implementation; </section><section prefix="f">The objectives and activities deemed appropriate and necessary for alleviating the observed educational areas of needed improvement; </section><section prefix="g">A calendar of events and timeline, for implementation; </section><section prefix="h">A brief report, each succeeding year, or more frequently if required by the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education, after submission of the initial plan, of the program status and progress made in areas of needed improvement. </section></section><section prefix="5">The district improvement plan shall be coordinated with the master staff development plan and the Department of Education shall provide technical assistance in the planning, implementation, and evaluation of this coordination. </section><section prefix="6">Effective June 30, 1996, KRS 158.650 to 158.710 shall become null and void. </section></text><history>Expired 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 11, effective June 30, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978.</history><metadata><lrc-note>(7/15/96).  Because this statute has expired as of June 30, 1996, under subsection (6) of the statute, references to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education within the statute have not been changed to the Kentucky Board of Education as required by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3575</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>