<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Boiler" or "boilers" means and includes a closed vessel in which water or other liquid is heated, steam or vapor is generated, steam is superheated, or in which any combination of these functions is accomplished, under pressure or vacuum, for use externally to itself, by the direct application of energy from the combustion of fuels, or from electricity, solar or nuclear energy. The term "boiler" shall include fired units for heating or vaporizing liquids other than water where these units are separate from processing systems and are complete within themselves: <section prefix="a">"Power boiler" means a boiler in which steam or other vapor is generated at a pressure of more than fifteen (15) pounds per square inch gauge; </section><section prefix="b">"High pressure, high temperature water boiler" means a water boiler operating at pressures exceeding one hundred sixty (160) pounds per square inch gauge or temperatures exceeding two hundred fifty (250) degrees Fahrenheit; </section><section prefix="c">"Heating boiler" means a steam or vapor boiler operating at pressures not exceeding fifteen (15) pounds per square inch gauge or a hot water boiler operating at pressures not exceeding one hundred sixty (160) pounds per square inch gauge or temperatures not exceeding two hundred fifty (250) degrees Fahrenheit; and </section><section prefix="d">"Portable boiler" means a boiler which is primarily intended for a temporary location, construction and usage of which allows the boiler to be readily removed from one (1) location to another; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Pressure vessel" means a vessel in which the pressure is obtained from an external source or by the application of heat other than those vessels defined in subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of housing, buildings and construction; </section><section prefix="4">"Department" means the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="5">"ASME" means American Society of Mechanical Engineers; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Rules; </section><section prefix="7">"Certificate inspection" means an inspection, the report of which is used by the chief boiler inspector to determine whether or not a certificate, as provided by subsection (1) of KRS 236.120, may be issued; </section><section prefix="8">"Rule" or "regulation" means a general regulation adopted by the commissioner upon advisement of the board and filed and approved in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A designed to insure the safety of boilers and pressure vessels that affects or may affect property rights of a designated class of owners, or designed for the prevention of loss or damage to property, loss of life, or personal injury from boiler or pressure vessel explosion or from certain indicated hazards related thereto; </section><section prefix="9">"Order" or "emergency order" means an order of the department, chief boiler inspector, or boiler inspector issued in accordance with this chapter for the prevention of: <section prefix="a">Loss or damage to property; </section><section prefix="b">Loss of life from boiler or pressure vessel malfunction or explosion; or </section><section prefix="c">Personal injury from boiler or pressure vessel malfunction or explosion; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Division" means the Division of Plumbing in the department; </section><section prefix="11">"Qualified welder" means a welder or welding machine operator who has successfully passed the tests required by the appropriate ASME boiler, pressure vessel, or piping code; </section><section prefix="12">"Person" or "firm" means any individual, firm, partnership, or corporation; </section><section prefix="13">"Chief boiler inspector" means the person employed by the department who shall serve as the boiler section supervisor within the Division of Plumbing; </section><section prefix="14">"Boiler inspector" means a duly authorized employee of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction who is charged with the responsibility of inspecting boilers and pressure vessels and with the enforcement of the state boiler laws; </section><section prefix="15">"Special boiler inspector" means any person employed by an insurance company authorized to insure boilers and pressure vessels in the Commonwealth and who holds a commission as provided in KRS 236.080. This term shall apply to both in-service inspectors and authorized inspectors of repairs, alterations, and shop work; </section><section prefix="16">"Domestic water" means potable water delivered by a piping system for personal use or consumption; </section><section prefix="17">"Potable water" means water free from impurities present in amounts sufficient to cause disease or harmful physiological effects and conforming in its bacteriological and chemical quality to the requirements of the Division of Water or the administrative regulations of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="18">"Cryogenic service" means a fluid held under pressure and having a boiling point below one hundred degrees below zero (-100) Fahrenheit at one (1) atmospheric pressure, which upon release results in auto-refrigeration or cooling effect; </section><section prefix="19">"Oil refinery" means a facility used primarily for the refinement of petroleum products; </section><section prefix="20">"Qualified welding procedure" means a welding procedure that has passed tests required by the applicable ASME boiler, pressure vessel, or piping code; </section><section prefix="21">"Boiler external piping" means boiler piping as defined in ASME Section I, which shall conform to ASME B31.1 and ASME Section I; </section><section prefix="22">"Non-boiler external piping" means boiler piping and boiler proper connections as defined in ASME Section I and applicable figures, and shall conform to either ASME B31.1 or ASME B31.3, including steam, boiler feedwater, blowdown, vents and drains, and chemical injection piping outside the boiler boundary; </section><section prefix="23">"MAWP" means the maximum allowable working pressure for a boiler, pressure vessel, or piping system; </section><section prefix="24">"Owner facility" means any facility licensed pursuant to KRS 236.097(1); </section><section prefix="25">"Owner's piping inspector" means any person licensed pursuant to KRS 236.097(2); </section><section prefix="26">"Independent inspection agency" means a person or company licensed under KRS 236.097(3) who is retained by an owner facility to conduct inspections under KRS 236.097(1); and </section><section prefix="27">"Owner-user facility" means any facility that operates pressure vessels and is accredited as an owner-user inspection organization by the national board. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 514, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 31, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1, par. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40104</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>