<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.120</section_number><catch_line>Statute revision functions of Commission -- Records -- Confidentiality of drafts of legislative proposals. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Legislative Research Commission shall formulate, supervise, and execute plans and methods for the future revision, clarification, classification, codification, and arrangement of the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="2">The Commission shall prepare and submit to the General Assembly such consolidation, revision, and other matters relating to the statutes as can be completed from time to time. </section><section prefix="3">The Commission shall keep in its office an accurate and complete record of all legislation enacted by the General Assembly and shall study same for the purpose of determining the intention and the effect thereof. The Commission shall advise and assist the members of the General Assembly in the preparation and revision of legislation and matters connected therewith. When preparing and revising legislation for members of the General Assembly, the Commission shall maintain the confidentiality of each item of legislation which it is requested to prepare, and of the fact that the request has been made, until the member or members of the General Assembly having made the request shall introduce the legislation at a regular or extraordinary session of the General Assembly or shall in writing authorize its publication by the Commission.  The Commission shall, when requested by the General Assembly or either house thereof, report to the General Assembly on bills introduced, calling attention to their effect on existing legislation and to any deficiencies in their form. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1(1), (6), and (7), effective June 16, 1966. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=466</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>