<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.555</section_number><catch_line>Priorities for expenditure of moneys from fund. </catch_line><order_by>555</order_by><text>Expenditure of moneys from the fund on lands and water eligible pursuant to KRS 350.560 for the purposes of the Abandoned Mine Lands Program shall reflect the following priorities in the order stated: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The protection of public health, safety, and property from extreme danger of adverse effects of coal mining practices; and </section><section prefix="b">The restoration of land and water resources and the environment that have been degraded by the adverse effects of coal mining practices and which are situated adjacent to a site that has been or will be remediated under this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The protection of public health and safety from the adverse effects of coal mining practices; and </section><section prefix="b">The restoration of land and water resources and the environment that have been degraded by the adverse effects of coal mining practices and which are situated adjacent to a site that has been or will be remediated under this subsection; and </section></section><section prefix="3">The restoration of land and water resources and the environment previously degraded by adverse effects of coal mining practices, including measures for the conservation and development of soil, water (excluding channelization), and woodland resources, fish and wildlife, recreation resources, and economic productivity. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>The provisions of this section became operative on May 18, 1982, when the conditional approval granted by the United States Secretary of the Interior appeared in the Federal Register. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32860</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>