<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.420</section_number><catch_line>Cooperative purchasing -- Price agreements with Commonwealth. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any local public agency may enter into an agreement for cooperative purchasing with any other local public agency. When the contracting local public agency contracts for supplies, services or construction pursuant to KRS 45A.365, 45A.370, 45A.375, or 45A.380, all other parties to the agreement shall be deemed to have complied with the provisions of those sections. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 45A.345 to 45A.990 shall deprive a local public agency from negotiating with vendors for supplies where such supplies are the subject of a price agreement with the Commonwealth of Kentucky provided, however, that no contract executed under this section would authorize a price higher than is contained in the price agreement with the Commonwealth of Kentucky for such specific supplies. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 45A.345 to 45A.990 shall deprive a local school district from acquiring supplies outside of price agreements with the Commonwealth of Kentucky if the supplies meet the same specifications as the contract items and the supplies are purchased at a lower price than is contained in the price agreement with the Commonwealth of Kentucky for such specific supplies and the purchase does not exceed two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500). </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 14, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 85, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>