<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="534" order_by="534">FINES </unit></structure><section_number>534.050</section_number><catch_line>Fines against corporations. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For an offense defined in this code a corporation convicted of an offense may be sentenced to pay a fine in an amount not to exceed: <section prefix="a">For a felony of any class, $20,000; or </section><section prefix="b">For a Class A misdemeanor, $10,000; or </section><section prefix="c">For a Class B misdemeanor, $5,000; or </section><section prefix="d">For a violation, $500; or </section><section prefix="e">Double the amount of the defendant's gain from commission of the offense, whichever is the greater. </section></section><section prefix="2">For an offense defined outside this code for which no special corporate fine is specified, a corporation convicted of an offense may be sentenced to pay a fine in an amount not to exceed: <section prefix="a">$20,000, if the offense when committed by an individual has an authorized term of imprisonment in the penitentiary; or </section><section prefix="b">$10,000, if the offense when committed by an individual has an authorized term of imprisonment of not less than ninety (90) days nor more than twelve (12) months; or </section><section prefix="c">$5,000, if the offense when committed by an individual has an authorized term of imprisonment of less than ninety (90) days; or </section><section prefix="d">$500, if the offense when committed by an individual has no authorized term of imprisonment; or </section><section prefix="e">Double the amount of the defendant's gain from commission of the offense, whichever is the greater. </section></section><section prefix="3">For an offense defined outside this code for which a special corporate fine is specified, a corporation convicted of the offense may be sentenced to pay a fine in the amount specified in the law that defines the offense. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 294, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975.</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20100</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>