<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.544</section_number><catch_line>Provisions applicable to all telephone utilities. </catch_line><order_by>544</order_by><text>The following provisions of this section shall apply and be enforced equally to all telephone utilities, unless otherwise specifically stated in this section. <section prefix="1">Telephone utilities may file with the commission schedules or tariffs reflecting the rates, terms, and conditions for nonbasic services that are generally available to all subscribers qualifying for the rates, terms, and conditions. The rates, terms, and conditions for basic and nonbasic services shall be valid upon the effective date stated in the schedule. Tariffs for nonbasic services in effect on July 12, 2006, shall continue to be effective as binding rates, terms, and conditions until withdrawn or modified by the telephone utility. </section><section prefix="2">A telephone utility offering a package that includes any optional telephone features tariffed as of February 1, 2006, shall maintain schedules or tariffs on file with the commission for each such optional telephone feature available on a stand-alone basis to residential customers who purchase basic local exchange service from that telephone utility. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding the terms of any adopted regulation plan or any provision of law to the contrary, telephone utilities may provide nonbasic services pursuant to terms and conditions provided to the customer. Telephone utilities shall not be required to file nonbasic contracts with the commission. Telephone utilities shall permit a residential customer with nonbasic service to purchase basic local exchange service and any optional telephone feature on file in a schedule or tariff at the commission at the current rates, terms, and conditions without incurring termination charges, unless the customer has entered into an agreement containing termination charges and the customer is given thirty (30) days from receipt of the terms and conditions to cancel the agreement. If a customer cancels the agreement within thirty (30) days from receipt of the terms and conditions, termination charges are limited to the price of unreturned equipment or services, including installation, received at that point. Telephone utilities that provide services pursuant to this subsection shall provide customers with notice, as part of the terms and conditions of such services, that basic local exchange service and any optional telephone feature on file in a schedule or tariff with the commission may be purchased separately at the price posted on the company's Web site or on file with the commission. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, nonbasic services offered pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be set by the marketplace and are not governed by KRS 278.030 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. The nonbasic services are exempt from action or review by the commission under KRS 278.160, 278.170, 278.180, 278.190, 278.192, 278.200, 278.230(3), 278.250, 278.255, 278.260, 278.270, 278.280, 278.290, and 278.300 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder, except as specifically stated in KRS 278.541 to 278.544. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>