<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.099</section_number><catch_line>Local taxation of personal property held for shipment out of state -- Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>099</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The tax rate levied by cities, counties, charter counties, urban-counties, and school districts on personal property placed in a warehouse or distribution center for the purpose of subsequent shipment to an out-of-state destination shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Eighty percent (80%) of the tax rate levied on other tangible personal property for tax assessments made on January 1, 2000; and </section><section prefix="b">Fifty percent (50%) of the tax rate levied on other tangible personal property for tax assessments made on January 1, 2001. </section></section><section prefix="2">Personal property placed in a warehouse or distribution center for the purpose of subsequent shipment to an out-of-state destination shall be exempt from the ad valorem tax levied by cities, counties, charter counties, urban-counties, and school districts for tax assessments made on or after January 1, 2002. </section><section prefix="3">Any fire district or other special taxing district may exempt from the ad valorem tax personal property placed in a warehouse or distribution center for the purpose of subsequent shipment to an out-of-state destination. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">As used in this subsection: <section prefix="1">"Affiliate" means a partnership, limited liability entity, corporation, or any other business entity that directly or indirectly owns or controls, or is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with, another partnership, limited liability entity, corporation, or other business entity; </section><section prefix="2">"Drug" means a compound, substance, or preparation and any component of a compound, substance, or preparation that is recognized in the official United States Pharmacopoeia, official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, or official National Formulary, or a supplement to any of them, or is: <section prefix="a">Intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in humans; or </section><section prefix="b">Intended to affect the structure or any function of the human body; and </section></section><section prefix="3">"Pharmaceutical manufacturer" means any entity which is engaged in the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, conversion, or processing of drug products, either directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of natural origin, or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis; but does not include a drug wholesaler or a retail pharmacy. </section></section><section prefix="b">For assessments made on and after January 1, 2012, the maximum ad valorem tax rate that may be levied by any special taxing district on drugs held by a pharmaceutical manufacturer or by an affiliate of a pharmaceutical manufacturer in a warehouse or distribution center for the purpose of subsequent shipment to an out-of-state destination shall not exceed three cents ($0.03) upon each one hundred dollars ($100) of value. This subsection shall not apply to any fire district. </section></section><section prefix="5">For the purpose of this section, personal property shall be deemed to be held for shipment to an out-of-state destination if the owner can reasonably demonstrate that the personal property will be shipped out of state within the next six (6) months. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 11, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40056</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>