<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="440" order_by="440">ESCAPES, FUGITIVES FROM JUSTICE, AND EXTRADITION </unit></structure><section_number>440.270</section_number><catch_line>Person charged with crime in other state may be arrested in this state -- Procedure -- Warrant required. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever any person within this state shall be charged on the oath of any credible person before any judge of this state with the commission of any crime in any other state and, except in cases arising under KRS 440.210, with having fled from justice, or with having been convicted of a crime in that state and having escaped from confinement, or having broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole, or whenever complaint shall have been made before any judge in this state setting forth on the affidavit of any credible person in another state that a crime has been committed in such other state and that the accused has been charged in such state with the commission of the crime, and, except in cases arising under KRS 440.210, has fled from justice, or with having been convicted of a crime in that state and having escaped from confinement, or having broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole and is believed to be in this state, the judge shall issue a warrant directed to any peace officer commanding him to apprehend the person named therein, wherever he may be found in this state, and to bring him before the Circuit or District Judge of the county in which he was arrested who may be available in or convenient of access to the place where the arrest may be made, to answer the charge or complaint and affidavit, and a certified copy of the sworn charge or complaint and affidavit upon which the warrant is issued shall be attached to the warrant. </section><section prefix="2">No bail bondsman or his agent shall arrest, detain, imprison, or remove from the state any person for having broken the terms of his bail unless a warrant for that person's arrest has been issued as provided for in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Any violation of subsection (2) of this section shall be deemed as a Class D felony and punishable thereas. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 454, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 14, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19246</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>