<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-080</section_number><catch_line>Licensure requirements -- Forms.   </catch_line><order_by>9-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual or business entity shall not sell, solicit, or negotiate insurance in this state unless duly licensed as the appropriate insurance producer for that line of authority in accordance with this subtitle or Subtitle 10 of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">No individual or business entity shall in this state be, act as, or hold himself, herself, or itself out as an adjuster unless then licensed as an adjuster. </section><section prefix="3">No individual or business entity shall in this state be, act as, or hold himself, herself, or itself out as a consultant unless then licensed as a consultant. No consultant shall act as a consultant with respect to any kind of insurance unless duly licensed as a consultant for that line of authority. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in KRS 304.9-410 and 304.9-270(4), no agent shall place, and no insurer shall accept, any insurance with any insurer as to which the agent does not then hold a license and appointment as agent under this subtitle. </section><section prefix="5">A rental vehicle agent or rental vehicle managing employee shall not place, and an insurer shall not accept, any insurance with any insurer as to which the licensee does not then hold a license and appointment under this subtitle. </section><section prefix="6">A travel retailer, its employee, or its representative shall not offer and disseminate travel insurance, and an insurer shall not accept any travel insurance, for which the limited lines travel insurance producer does not then hold a license and appointment pursuant to KRS 304.9-475. </section><section prefix="7">The commissioner shall prescribe and furnish all forms required under this subtitle as to licenses and appointments. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1044, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 21, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 393, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 2, effective April 1, 1985. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>