<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.441</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of cities over parks and boulevards.   </catch_line><order_by>441</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city that has the care, management and custody of the parks and grounds used for park purposes, the boulevards and parkways belonging to the city or in the control of the city, and all property acquired for park purposes or public squares by the city may:  <section prefix="a">Acquire and hold property for public parks and public squares and for parkways connecting the parks, by condemnation, contract, purchase or gift;  </section><section prefix="b">Lay out and improve the parks, parkways, squares and other property held or managed by it with walks, drives, roads, trees and other proper improvements, and contract for such improvements;  </section><section prefix="c">Protect all park property and improvements belonging to the city or under its management or control from injury or decay;  </section><section prefix="d">Adopt rules and regulations for the reasonable and proper use and for preventing injuries to or misuse of all parks, parkways, public squares, boulevards, driveways, walks and park property generally;  </section><section prefix="e">Prevent disorder and improper conduct within the precincts of any park or inclosure, or upon any drive, walk or avenue under the control of the city;  </section><section prefix="f">Control and manage the planting and care of all shade trees along the sidewalks and thoroughfares of the city, and adopt and enforce rules and regulations necessary for the protection and care of the trees.  </section></section><section prefix="2">In locating parks the city shall regard the needs of the different sections of the city and the suitability of the ground for park purposes, as well as the cost thereof. The city shall have discretion as to the location and improvement of parks.  </section><section prefix="3">The police power of the city extends over the park property of every kind, as it is acquired. All violations of the park rules and regulations and all other offenses committed within any park property or precinct shall be punished as provided by law in cases of misdemeanors and violations of city ordinances.  </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 177, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 114. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43762</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>