<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.175</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for school bus endorsement.   </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for a school bus endorsement shall satisfy the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Qualify for a passenger vehicle endorsement by passing the knowledge and skills test for obtaining a passenger vehicle endorsement; </section><section prefix="b">Demonstrate knowledge of loading and unloading children, including the safe operation of stop signal devices, external mirror systems, flashing lights, and other warning and safety devices required for school buses by state or federal law or regulation; </section><section prefix="c">Demonstrate knowledge of emergency exits and procedures for safely evacuating passengers in an emergency;  </section><section prefix="d">Demonstrate knowledge of state and federal laws and regulations related to safely traversing highway rail grade crossings; and </section><section prefix="e">Submit to an annual physical examination in accordance with 49 C.F.R. pt. 391, completed by a medical examiner as defined by 49 C.F.R. pt. 390. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant for a school bus endorsement shall take a driving skills test in a school bus of the same vehicle group as the school bus the applicant will drive. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>