<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6415</section_number><catch_line>Suspension, revocation, or nonrenewal of certification -- Grounds -- Hearing -- Appeal.  </catch_line><order_by>6415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the commissioner may suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew the certification of a certified fire sprinkler inspector for any of the following actions: <section prefix="a">Use of false evidence or misrepresentation in an application for a fire sprinkler inspector's certification; </section><section prefix="b">Attempting to transfer authority granted to the certified inspector to another individual; </section><section prefix="c">Incompetence or negligence in the inspection of fire protection sprinkler systems as determined by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="d">Conviction of a felony or of any crime an element of which is dishonesty or fraud, under the laws of any state or of the United States; </section><section prefix="e">Fraudulent or dishonest practices while engaging in the business of sprinkler system inspections; </section><section prefix="f">Aiding or abetting any person attempting to evade the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="g">Violating any provision of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall revoke, subject to a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the certification of a fire sprinkler inspector who engages in inspection activities during a suspension of his or her certification. </section><section prefix="3">Any certification holder who is aggrieved by a final order of the commissioner, resulting in the suspension or revocation of certification, may appeal to the Circuit Court of the county of the certified inspector's place of business in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 37, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "executive director" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts. ch. 116, sec. 37, have been changed in codification to the "commissioner" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts. ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36634</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>