<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.120</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary actions relating to certificates -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as described in KRS 161.795, the Education Professional Standards Board may revoke, suspend, or refuse to issue or renew; impose probationary or supervisory conditions upon; issue a written reprimand or admonishment; or any combination of those actions regarding any certificate issued under KRS 161.010 to 161.100, or any certificate or license issued under any previous law to superintendents, principals, teachers, substitute teachers, interns, supervisors, directors of pupil personnel, or other administrative, supervisory, or instructional employees for the following reasons: <section prefix="a">Being convicted of, or entering an "Alford" plea or plea of nolo contendere to, notwithstanding an order granting probation or suspending imposition of any sentence imposed following the conviction or entry of the plea, one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">A felony; </section><section prefix="2">A misdemeanor under KRS Chapter 218A, 508, 509, 510, 522, 525, 529, 530, or 531; or </section><section prefix="3">A misdemeanor involving a student or minor. </section></section> A certified copy of the conviction or plea shall be conclusive evidence of the conviction or plea; <section prefix="b">Having sexual contact as defined in KRS 510.010(7) with a student or minor. Conviction in a criminal proceeding shall not be a requirement for disciplinary action; </section><section prefix="c">Committing any act that constitutes fraudulent, corrupt, dishonest, or immoral conduct. If the act constitutes a crime, conviction in a criminal proceeding shall not be a condition precedent to disciplinary action; </section><section prefix="d">Demonstrating willful or careless disregard for the health, welfare, or safety of others; </section><section prefix="e">Physical or mental incapacity that prevents the certificate holder from performing duties with reasonable skill, competence, or safety; </section><section prefix="f">Possessing, using, or being under the influence of alcohol, which impairs the performance of duties; </section><section prefix="g">Unlawfully possessing or unlawfully using a drug during the performance of duties; </section><section prefix="h">Incompetency or neglect of duty; </section><section prefix="i">Making, or causing to be made, any false or misleading statement or concealing a material fact in obtaining issuance or renewal of any certificate; </section><section prefix="j">Failing to report as required by subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="k">Failing to comply with an order of the Education Professional Standards Board; </section><section prefix="l">Violating any state statute relating to schools or the teaching profession; </section><section prefix="m">Violating the professional code of ethics for Kentucky school certified personnel established by the Education Professional Standards Board through the promulgation of administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="n">Violating any administrative regulation promulgated by the Education Professional Standards Board or the Kentucky Board of Education; or </section><section prefix="o">Receiving disciplinary action or having the issuance of a certificate denied or restricted by another jurisdiction on grounds that constitute a violation of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The superintendent of each local school district shall report in writing to the Education Professional Standards Board the name, address, phone number, Social Security number, and position name of any certified school employee in the employee's district whose contract is terminated or not renewed, for cause except failure to meet local standards for quality of teaching performance prior to the employee gaining tenure; who resigns from, or otherwise leaves, a position under threat of contract termination, or nonrenewal, for cause; who is convicted in a criminal prosecution; or who otherwise may have engaged in any actions or conduct while employed in the school district that might reasonably be expected to warrant consideration for action against the certificate under subsection (1) of this section. The duty to report shall exist without regard to any disciplinary action, or lack thereof, by the superintendent, and the required report shall be submitted within thirty (30) days of the event giving rise to the duty to report. </section><section prefix="b">The district superintendent shall inform the Education Professional Standards Board in writing of the full facts and circumstances leading to the contract termination or nonrenewal, resignation, or other absence, conviction, or otherwise reported actions or conduct of the certified employee, that may warrant action against the certificate under subsection (1) of this section, and shall forward copies of all relevant documents and records in his possession. </section><section prefix="c">The Education Professional Standards Board may consider reports and information received from other sources. </section><section prefix="d">The certified school employee shall be given a copy of any report provided to the Education Professional Standards Board by the district superintendent or other sources. The employee shall have the right to file a written rebuttal to the report which shall be placed in the official file with the report. </section></section><section prefix="3">A finding or action by a school superintendent or tribunal does not create a presumption of a violation or lack of a violation of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The board may issue a written admonishment to the certificate holder if the board determines, based on the evidence, that a violation has occurred that is not of a serious nature. A copy of the written admonishment shall be placed in the official file of the certificate holder. The certificate holder may respond in writing to the admonishment within thirty (30) days of receipt and have that response placed in his official certification file. Alternatively, the certificate holder may file a request for a hearing with the board within thirty (30) days of receipt of the admonishment. Upon receipt of a request for a hearing, the board shall set aside the written admonishment and set the matter for hearing pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The Education Professional Standards Board shall schedule and conduct a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B: <section prefix="1">Before revoking, suspending, refusing to renew, imposing probationary or supervisory conditions upon, issuing a written reprimand, or any combination of these actions regarding any certificate; </section><section prefix="2">After denying an application for a certificate, upon written request filed within thirty (30) days of receipt of the letter advising of the denial; or </section><section prefix="3">After issuing a written admonishment, upon written request for a hearing filed within thirty (30) days of receipt of the written admonishment. </section></section><section prefix="b">Upon request, a hearing may be public or private at the discretion of the certified employee or applicant. </section><section prefix="c">The hearing shall be conducted before the full board, a panel of three (3) members of the board, or a person appointed as hearing officer by the board pursuant to KRS 13B.030(1). </section></section><section prefix="6">The Education Professional Standards Board or its chair may take emergency action pursuant to KRS 13B.125. Emergency action shall not affect a certificate holder's contract or tenure rights in the school district. </section><section prefix="7">If the Education Professional Standards Board substantiates that sexual contact occurred between a certified employee and a student or minor, the employee's certificate may be revoked or suspended with mandatory treatment of the employee as prescribed by the Education Professional Standards Board. The Education Professional Standards Board may require the employee to pay a specified amount for mental health services for the student or minor which are needed as a result of the sexual contact. </section><section prefix="8">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may enter into an agreed order or accept an assurance of voluntary compliance with the certificate holder. </section><section prefix="9">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its decision on any disciplinary action. </section><section prefix="10">Suspension of a certificate shall be for a specified period of time, not to exceed two (2) years. <section prefix="a">At the conclusion of the specified period, upon demonstration of compliance with any educational requirements and the terms set forth in the agreed order, the certificate shall be reactivated. </section><section prefix="b">A suspended certificate is subject to expiration and termination. </section></section><section prefix="11">Revocation of a certificate is a permanent forfeiture. The board shall establish the minimum period of time before an applicant can apply for a new certificate. <section prefix="a">At the conclusion of the specified period, and upon demonstration of compliance with any educational requirements and the terms set forth in the agreed order, the applicant shall bear the burden of proof to show that he or she is again fit for practice. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall have discretion to impose conditions that it deems reasonably appropriate to ensure the applicant's fitness and the protection of public safety. Any conditions imposed by the board shall address or apply to only that time period after the revocation of the certificate. </section></section><section prefix="12">An appeal from any final order of the Education Professional Standards Board shall be filed in Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 465, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 343, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 64, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 119, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4502-9. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  This section was amended by 1996 Ky. Acts chs. 318 and 343. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 343, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.  (7/15/94).  This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>