<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.020</section_number><catch_line>Interpretation of chapter.  </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>(1)This chapter shall be interpreted to:(a)Allow victims to obtain effective, short-term protection against furtherwrongful conduct in order that their lives may be as secure and asuninterrupted as possible;(b)Expand the ability of law enforcement officers to effectively respond tofurther wrongful conduct so as to prevent future incidents and to provideassistance to the victims;(c)Provide peace officers with the authority to immediately apprehend andcharge for violation of an order of protection any person whom the officerhas probable cause to believe has violated an order of protection and toprovide courts with the authority to conduct contempt of court proceedingsfor these violations;(d)Provide for the collection of data concerning incidents of dating violenceand abuse, sexual assault, and stalking in order to develop acomprehensive analysis of the numbers and causes of such incidents;and(e)Supplement and not repeal or supplant any duties, responsibilities,services, or penalties under KRS Chapters 209, 209A, and 620.(2)Nothing in this chapter is intended to trigger the application of the provisions of18 U.S.C sec. 922(g) as to an interpersonal protective order issued on thebasis of the existence of a current or previous dating relationship.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 20, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>