<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.866</section_number><catch_line>Certification requirement -- When not required. </catch_line><order_by>866</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is not required to hold a certificate under KRS 311.864 to 311.890 if the person is: <section prefix="a">A student enrolled in a surgical assistant education program approved by the board who is assisting in a surgical operation that is an integral part of the program of study; </section><section prefix="b">A surgical assistant employed in the service of the federal government while performing surgical assisting duties related to that employment; </section><section prefix="c">A health care worker, licensed or certified within this Commonwealth, acting within the scope of the person's license; </section><section prefix="d">A registered nurse or licensed practical nurse; </section><section prefix="e">A certified physician assistant; or </section><section prefix="f">An individual employed by a hospital who is performing the duties of a surgical assistant under the direct supervision of a registered nurse. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (1) of this section, a person shall not practice as a surgical assistant unless the person is certified under KRS 311.864 to 311.890 and shall not use the title "Kentucky Certified Surgical Assistant" or any other designation that would imply that the person is a certified surgical assistant. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30661</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>