<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">A PLANNING AND OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENTAL FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>7A.220</section_number><catch_line>Membership of board.     </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Public Pension Oversight Board shall be composed of the following thirteen (13) members: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members of the General Assembly appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, each of whom shall serve while a member of the House for the term for which he or she has been elected, and one (1) of whom the Speaker shall designate as co-chair; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members of the General Assembly appointed by the President of the Senate, each of whom shall serve while a member of the Senate for the term for which he or she has been elected, and one (1) of whom the President shall designate as co-chair; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member of the General Assembly appointed by the Minority Floor Leader of the Senate, who shall serve while a member of the Senate for the term for which he or she has been elected; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member of the General Assembly appointed by the Minority Floor Leader of the House of Representatives, who shall serve while a member of the House for the term for which he or she has been elected; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) individual appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, who shall be certified as a chartered financial analyst (CFA) with at least ten (10) years of investment experience or who shall possess at least ten (10) years of retirement experience as defined by subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) individual appointed by the President of the Senate, who shall be certified as a chartered financial analyst (CFA) with at least ten (10) years of investment experience or who shall possess at least ten (10) years of retirement experience as defined by subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="g">The state budget director or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="h">The Auditor of Public Accounts or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="i">The Attorney General or his or her designee; and </section><section prefix="j">Two (2) individuals appointed by the Governor, one (1) of whom shall be certified as a chartered financial analyst (CFA) with at least ten (10) years of investment experience and one (1) of whom shall possess at least ten (10) years of retirement experience as defined by subsection (2) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section, "retirement experience" means: <section prefix="a">Experience in retirement or pension plan management; </section><section prefix="b">A certified public accountant with relevant experience in retirement or pension plan accounting; </section><section prefix="c">An actuary with relevant experience in retirement or pension plan consulting; </section><section prefix="d">An attorney licensed to practice law in the Commonwealth of Kentucky with relevant experience in retirement or pension plans; or </section><section prefix="e">A current or former university professor whose primary area of emphasis is economics or finance. </section></section><section prefix="3">Individuals appointed under subsection (1)(e), (f), and (j) of this section shall not: <section prefix="a">Be a member of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="b">Be employed by a state agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or receiving a contractual payment for services rendered to a state agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that would conflict with his or her service to the board; or </section><section prefix="c">Serve more than three (3) consecutive four (4) year terms on the board. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any vacancy which may occur in the membership of the board shall be filled by the appointing authority who made the original appointment. </section><section prefix="5">Individuals appointed under subsection (1)(e), (f), and (j) of this section shall serve a term of four (4) years. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 3, effective July 1, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44270</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>