<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" means the secretary for health and family services or his authorized representative; </section><section prefix="3">"Public assistance" means money grants, assistance in kind, or services to or for the benefit of needy aged, needy blind, needy permanently and totally disabled persons, needy children, or persons with whom a needy child lives or a family containing a combination of these categories, except that the term shall not be construed to permit the granting of financial aid where the purpose of such aid is to obtain an abortion. For purposes of this section and KRS 205.560, "abortion" means an act, procedure, device, or prescription administered or prescribed for a pregnant woman by any person, including the pregnant woman herself, producing premature expulsion of the fetus. Abortion does not include an induced premature birth intended to produce a live viable child; </section><section prefix="4">"Needy child" means a child who has been deprived of parental support by reasons prescribed by regulations within the scope of Title IV of the Social Security Act, its amendments, and federal regulations and who does not have otherwise provided for him a subsistence compatible with decency and health; </section><section prefix="5">"Parent," in addition to biological or adoptive parent, shall include stepparent; </section><section prefix="6">"Needy aged" means a person who has attained the age of sixty-five (65) and who is unable to provide for himself and who does not have otherwise provided for him a subsistence compatible with decency and health; </section><section prefix="7">"Needy blind" means a person who has no vision or whose vision is so defective as to prevent the performance of ordinary activities for which eyesight is essential and who is unable to provide for himself and who does not have otherwise provided for him a subsistence compatible with decency and health; </section><section prefix="8">"Person with whom a needy child lives" means the individual prescribed by regulation, with whom such child is living in a place of residence maintained by such individual by himself or together with one (1) or more other persons; </section><section prefix="9">"Needy permanently and totally disabled" means a person eighteen (18) years of age or older and who has a permanent physical or mental impairment, disease, or loss that substantially precludes him from engaging in useful occupations within his competence and who is unable to provide for himself and who does not have otherwise provided for him a subsistence compatible with decency and health; </section><section prefix="10">"Private institution" means any establishment or place other than a public institution operated or maintained by any individual, association, corporation, or other organization which provides a group living arrangement for four (4) or more individuals, who are cared for and maintained in residence for compensation or otherwise; </section><section prefix="11">"Public institution" means any establishment or place which is the responsibility of and administered by the state or any political subdivision thereof providing a group living arrangement in which one (1) or more individuals are cared for and maintained in residence; </section><section prefix="12">"Public medical institution" means any public institution the primary purpose of which is to furnish hospital care and medical treatment; </section><section prefix="13">"Person determined to be potentially responsible" means any person who: <section prefix="a">Is not aged, blind, disabled, incapacitated, or needed in the home: <section prefix="1">Because of the illness or incapacity of a member of the family; or </section><section prefix="2">Because of children in the home under the age of six (6); or </section></section><section prefix="b">Volunteers for such determination; </section></section><section prefix="14">Nothing in this section shall be deemed to deprive a woman of all appropriate medical care necessary to prevent her physical death; </section><section prefix="15">"Adult day-care center" means any adult care facility which provides part-time care, day or night, but less than twenty-four (24) hours, to at least four (4) adults not related to the operator of the adult care facility by blood, marriage, or adoption. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 51, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 181, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 422, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, secs. 44 and 107(21); and ch. 180, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 6. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1. -- Repealed and new section substituted 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 110, secs. 1 and 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3766bb. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7624</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>