<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.6908</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for an agreement -- Enforcement in Circuit Court. </catch_line><order_by>6908</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any agreement reached by the negotiators shall be reduced to writing and shall be executed by both parties. </section><section prefix="2">An agreement between the urban-county government and a labor organization shall be valid and enforced under its terms when entered into in accordance with the provisions of this section and signed by the mayor of the urban-county government or his or her representative. No publication thereof shall be required to make it effective. The procedure for the making of an agreement between an urban-county government and a labor organization provided by this section shall be the exclusive method of making a valid agreement for police officers, firefighter personnel, firefighters, or corrections personnel represented by a labor organization. </section><section prefix="3">Suits for violation of agreements between an urban-county government and a labor organization representing police officers, firefighter personnel, firefighters, or corrections personnel may be brought by the parties to the agreement in the Circuit Court of the urban-county government. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23918</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>