<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.172</section_number><catch_line>Special license plates for firefighters. </catch_line><order_by>172</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application to the county clerk of the county of his residence, any current or retired member of a fire department, volunteer fire department, or fire protection district in the Commonwealth shall be issued a special firefighter license plate that shall bear the inscription "Firefighter," a registration number, and an appropriate standardized insignia. </section><section prefix="2">Each initial or renewal application shall be accompanied by proof of current service or retirement as a firefighter as furnished by the fire chief, the mayor or trustee of a city, or the county judge/executive in appropriate rural areas, and the payment of the fees set forth in KRS 186.162. </section><section prefix="3">The special firefighter license plate shall be administered in the same manner as other special license plates as prescribed in KRS 186.164. The Kentucky Firefighters Association may petition the Transportation Cabinet to place a voluntary contribution on special firefighter license plates in accordance with KRS 186.164(12) to (14). </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5974</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>