<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="184" order_by="184">PUBLIC ROAD DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>184.020</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of public road district -- Preparation of map -- Estimate of cost.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A public road district may be established in accordance with the procedures of KRS 65.810 to improve any public road (which is neither a county road nor a state road) in the following areas: <section prefix="a">Within cities containing a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) but less than twenty thousand (20,000); </section><section prefix="b">Within cities containing a population of less than one thousand (1,000) that are located within counties that contain a consolidated local government or a city with a population equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000); or </section><section prefix="c">Within an area that abuts a public road, which is neither a county road nor a state road, that is in an unincorporated area in a county that contains a city with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000). </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to the information required to be submitted to the fiscal court pursuant to KRS 65.810, the sponsors shall prepare or have prepared for them a map of that section of such public road which they desire to have improved. Such map shall show the boundary lines and terminal points of the road desired to be improved and shall set forth on such map the names of the owners of all property and the number of linear feet owned by them abutting upon such road, the location and size of drainage ditches and sidewalks. The sponsors of said road district shall also have estimated for them by an engineer, who must be a private engineer licensed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, pursuant to KRS Chapter 322, the approximate cost of constructing the improvements desired and reasonable maintenance for the duration of the road district, together with a statement of the approximate cost which shall be borne by each owner of property abutting on the road, determined by the number of linear feet of property owned by each abutting property holder. </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of this section, the population of a city shall be determined by using data from the most recent federal decennial census. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 265, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 2. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 2. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43850</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>