<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.090</section_number><catch_line>Certification of professional classifications -- Training program for building code administration and enforcement. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before July 1, 1983, the department shall create and administer a certification program with sufficient testing procedures to certify the following professional classifications: <section prefix="a">Building inspector; </section><section prefix="b">Plans and specifications inspector; and </section><section prefix="c">Plumbing inspector. </section></section><section prefix="2">The testing procedures shall be sufficient to reflect the ability of the person applying for certification to inspect in accordance with those local, state, and federal building codes, fire codes, plumbing codes, or health and safety codes, that are applicable to the inspection duties for which he or she requests certification. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall conduct or sponsor preentry and in-service education and training programs on the technical, legal, and administrative aspects of building code administration and enforcement. For this purpose it may cooperate and contract with educational institutions, area development districts, local, regional, state or national building officials' organizations, and any other appropriate organization. </section><section prefix="4">On or before July 1, 1983, the department shall create and administer an educational program designed to prepare building officials, code enforcement officers and other persons interested in obtaining from the department a certification as a building inspector, plans and specifications inspector, or plumbing inspector. The program shall be so designed as to insure uniform statewide enforcement of the applicable state building and plumbing codes. Training material coverage shall be adequate to prepare the participants with a working knowledge of construction design, specification terms, and the state building codes applicable to the particular field in which the applicant requests certification. </section><section prefix="5">Plumbing inspectors who are in compliance with KRS 318.090 as state inspectors and KRS 318.140 as city-county inspectors, shall be considered in accordance with subsections (1)(c) and (2) of this section and shall not be required to be retested by the department prior to consideration for certification as a plumbing inspector. The department shall review the plumbing inspector's qualifications and credentials for compliance with KRS 318.090 or 318.140 prior to issuing a certification to the inspector's certificate applicant. </section><section prefix="6">Attendance at the training sessions shall not be mandatory prior to testing for certification if the applicant's previous education or experience qualifies the applicant to obtain a passing score on the required certification test. </section><section prefix="7">Training sessions shall be held as frequently as is felt necessary by the commissioner to adequately provide for local and state building inspection needs. </section><section prefix="8">The department's plans and specifications review staff and the field inspection staff shall attend the training and become certified in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="9">All building inspectors, plans and specification inspectors, and plumbing inspectors shall be certified or enrolled and actively pursuing department certification by October 1, 1983, or within ninety (90) days after employment as an inspector, whichever comes later. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall establish a schedule of fees to cover the cost of the education, testing, and certification programs to be paid by the applicants for certification. The fees shall not exceed the actual cost of the services performed by the department to administer the programs listed in this section. </section><section prefix="11">The department may reimburse building officials, code enforcement officers and other employees of the state and its subdivisions for related expenses incurred by them for attendance at in-service training programs approved by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 253, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 8, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>