<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-904</section_number><catch_line>Effect of conversion -- Entity unchanged.   </catch_line><order_by>1-904</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A converted organization that has been converted pursuant to KRS 362.1-901 to 362.1-908 is for all purposes the same entity that existed before the conversion. </section><section prefix="2">When a conversion takes place: <section prefix="a">All property and contract rights owned by, and all rights, privileges, and immunities of, the converting organization shall remain vested in the converted organization without assignment, reversions, or impairment and without the converting organization having been dissolved; </section><section prefix="b">All obligations of the converting partnership organization shall continue as obligations of the converted organization; </section><section prefix="c">An action or proceeding pending against the converting partnership organization may be continued as if the organization had not occurred, and the name of the converted organization may be substituted in any pending action or proceeding for the name of the converting organization; </section><section prefix="d">Any written partnership agreement of the converted partnership or limited partnership shall be binding upon each person who becomes a partner in the converted partnership or limited partnership; and </section><section prefix="e">Except as otherwise provided in the plan of conversion, the terms and conditions of the plan of conversion take effect. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless otherwise provided in the partnership agreement, a partner has no right to dissent from a conversion. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 119, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 64, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40458</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>