<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.405</section_number><catch_line>Personnel Steering Committee. </catch_line><order_by>405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Personnel Steering Committee which shall be attached to the Finance and Administration Cabinet for administrative purposes. The Personnel Cabinet shall provide technical assistance and support services to the committee. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the Personnel Steering Committee shall be appointed by the Governor and shall consist of: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members from the Governor's Commission on Quality and Efficiency established by Executive Order 93-282. At least one (1) of these members shall also be a member of the Career Service System Task Force created by Executive Order 93-1139; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members from private industry, at least one of whom shall also be a member of Career Service System Task Force; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) employee with status who has at least ten (10) years of experience in an Executive Department agency other than the Personnel Cabinet; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) employee with status in a management classification in an Executive Department agency other than the Personnel Cabinet; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) Personnel Cabinet employees with status who have personnel system experience; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member who is either a member of the Personnel Board, or a member of its staff. </section></section><section prefix="3">No less than four (4) nor more than six (6) of the persons appointed to serve on the Personnel Steering Committee shall be employees with status under this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">The employees with status under this chapter who are appointed to the Personnel Steering Committee shall be appointed by the Governor from lists provided by state employee organizations as set forth in this subsection. Any state employee organization having at least two hundred fifty (250) members as of January 1, 1994, may submit the names of two (2) employees with status to the Governor on or before fifteen (15) days after July 15, 1994. The Governor shall select the appointees from a list that is comprised of names of employees submitted by all of the state employee organizations as provided by this subsection which have been compiled into a single list. </section><section prefix="5">The committee's chairman shall be elected by and from the members of the committee for a one (1) year term at the first meeting of the committee and annually thereafter. </section><section prefix="6">If they are not reimbursed by a state agency in which they are employed, Personnel Steering Committee members shall be reimbursed for travel to meetings at the established state rate for travel expenses from the budget of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 55, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20431</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>