<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.020</section_number><catch_line>Application of chapter -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this chapter shall apply to all administrative hearings conducted by an agency, with the exception of those specifically exempted under this section. The provisions of this chapter shall supersede any other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and administrative regulations, unless exempted under this section, to the extent these other provisions are duplicative or in conflict. This chapter creates only procedural rights and shall not be construed to confer upon any person a right to hearing not expressly provided by law. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of this chapter shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Investigations, hearings to determine probable cause, or any other type of information gathering or fact finding activities; </section><section prefix="b">Public hearings required in KRS Chapter 13A for the promulgation of administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="c">Any other public hearing conducted by an administrative agency which is nonadjudicatory in nature and the primary purpose of which is to seek public input on public policy making; </section><section prefix="d">Military adjudicatory proceedings conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 35; </section><section prefix="e">Administrative hearings conducted by the legislative and judicial branches of state government; </section><section prefix="f">Administrative hearings conducted by any city, county, urban-county, charter county, or special district contained in KRS Chapters 65 to 109, or any other unit of local government operating strictly in a local jurisdictional capacity; </section><section prefix="g">Informal hearings which are part of a multilevel hearing process that affords an administrative hearing at some point in the hearing process if the procedures for informal hearings are approved and promulgated in accordance with subsections (4) and (5) of this section; </section><section prefix="h">Limited exemptions granted for specific hearing provisions and denoted by reference in the text of the applicable statutes or administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="i">Administrative hearings exempted pursuant to subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="j">Administrative hearings exempted, in whole or in part, pursuant to subsections (4) and (5) of this section; and </section><section prefix="k">Any administrative hearing which was commenced but not completed prior to July 15, 1996. </section></section><section prefix="3">The following administrative hearings are exempt from application of this chapter in compliance with 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 19: <section prefix="a">Finance and Administration Cabinet <section prefix="1">Higher Education Assistance Authority <section prefix="a">Wage garnishment hearings conducted under authority of 20 U.S.C. sec. 1095a and 34 C.F.R. sec. 682.410 </section><section prefix="b">Offset hearings conducted under authority of 31 U.S.C. sec. 3720A and sec. 3716, and 34 C.F.R. sec. 30.33 </section></section><section prefix="2">Department of Revenue <section prefix="a">Any licensing and bond revocation hearings conducted under the authority of KRS 138.210 to 138.448 and 234.310 to 234.440 </section><section prefix="b">Any license revocation hearings under KRS 131.630 and 138.130 to 138.205 </section></section></section><section prefix="b">Cabinet for Health and Family Services <section prefix="1">Office of Health Policy <section prefix="a">Certificate-of-need hearings and licensure conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 216B </section><section prefix="b">Licensure revocation hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 216B </section></section><section prefix="2">Department for Community Based Services <section prefix="a">Supervised placement revocation hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 630 </section></section><section prefix="3">Department for Income Support <section prefix="a">Disability determination hearings conducted under authority of 20 C.F.R. sec. 404 </section></section></section><section prefix="c">Justice and Public Safety Cabinet <section prefix="1">Department of Kentucky State Police <section prefix="a">Kentucky State Police Trial Board disciplinary hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 16 </section></section><section prefix="2">Department of Corrections <section prefix="a">Parole Board hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 439 </section><section prefix="b">Prison adjustment committee hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 197 </section><section prefix="c">Prison grievance committee hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapters 196 and 197 </section></section><section prefix="3">Department of Juvenile Justice <section prefix="a">Supervised placement revocation hearings conducted under KRS Chapter 635 </section></section></section><section prefix="d">Energy and Environment Cabinet <section prefix="1">Department for Natural Resources <section prefix="a">Surface mining hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 350 </section></section><section prefix="2">Department for Environmental Protection <section prefix="a">Wild River hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 146 </section><section prefix="b">Water resources hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 151 </section><section prefix="c">Water plant operator and water well driller hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 223 </section><section prefix="d">Environmental protection hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 224 </section><section prefix="e">Petroleum Storage Tank Environmental Assurance Fund hearings under authority of KRS Chapter 224 </section></section><section prefix="3">Public Service Commission <section prefix="a">Utility hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapters 74, 278, and 279 </section></section></section><section prefix="e">Labor Cabinet <section prefix="1">Department of Workers' Claims <section prefix="a">Workers' compensation hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 342 </section></section><section prefix="2">Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission <section prefix="a">Occupational safety and health hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 338 </section></section></section><section prefix="f">Public Protection Cabinet <section prefix="1">Board of Claims <section prefix="a">Liability hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 44 </section></section></section><section prefix="g">Education and Workforce Development Cabinet <section prefix="1">Unemployment Insurance hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 341 </section></section><section prefix="h">Secretary of State <section prefix="1">Registry of Election Finance <section prefix="a">Campaign finance hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 121 </section></section></section><section prefix="i">State universities and colleges <section prefix="1">Student suspension and expulsion hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 164 </section><section prefix="2">University presidents and faculty removal hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 164 </section><section prefix="3">Campus residency hearings conducted under authority of KRS Chapter 164 </section><section prefix="4">Family Education Rights to Privacy Act hearings conducted under authority of 20 U.S.C. sec. 1232 and 34 C.F.R. sec. 99 </section><section prefix="5">Federal Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 hearings conducted under authority of 42 U.S.C. sec. 11101 to 11115 and KRS Chapter 311. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Any administrative hearing, or portion thereof, may be certified as exempt by the Attorney General based on the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The provisions of this chapter conflict with any provision of federal law or regulation with which the agency must comply, or with any federal law or regulation with which the agency must comply to permit the agency or persons within the Commonwealth to receive federal tax benefits or federal funds or other benefits; </section><section prefix="b">Conformity with the requirement of this chapter from which exemption is sought would be so unreasonable or so impractical as to deny due process because of undue delay in the conduct of administrative hearings; or </section><section prefix="c">The hearing procedures represent informal proceedings which are the preliminary stages or the review stages of a multilevel hearing process, if the provisions of this chapter or the provisions of a substantially equivalent hearing procedure exempted under subsection (3) of this section are applied at some level within the multilevel process. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Attorney General shall not exempt an agency from any requirement of this chapter until the agency establishes alternative procedures by administrative regulation which, insofar as practical, shall be consistent with the intent and purpose of this chapter. When regulations for alternative procedures are submitted to the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee, they shall be accompanied by the request for exemption and the approval of exemption from the Attorney General. The decision of the Attorney General, whether affirmative or negative, shall be subject to judicial review in the Franklin Circuit Court within thirty (30) days of the date of issuance. The court shall not overturn a decision of the Attorney General unless the decision was arbitrary or capricious or contrary to law. </section><section prefix="6">Except to the extent precluded by another provision of law, a person may waive any procedural right conferred upon that person by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 13, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 211, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 123, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 63, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 538, sec. 12, effective April 13, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 426 and 538. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 538, which was a nonrevisory Act, prevails under KRS 7.136(3). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>