<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.002Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>002Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS Chapter 164, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Advanced placement" or "AP" means a college-level course that incorporates all topics and instructional strategies specified by the College Board on its standard syllabus for a given subject area and is licensed by the College Board; </section><section prefix="2">"Cambridge Advanced International" means the Cambridge Advanced International Certificate of Education Diploma program, an international pre-university curriculum and examination system offered by Cambridge International Examinations at the University of Cambridge; </section><section prefix="3">"College Board Advanced Placement examination" means the advanced placement test administered by the College Entrance Examination Board; </section><section prefix="4">"College Board" means the College Entrance Examination Board, a national nonprofit association that provides college admission guidance and advanced placement examinations; </section><section prefix="5">"Dual credit" means a college-level course of study developed in accordance with KRS 164.098 in which a high school student receives credit from both the high school and postsecondary institution in which the student is enrolled upon completion of a single class or designated program of study, including participating in the Gatton Academy of Mathematics and Science in Kentucky or the Craft Academy for Excellence in Science and Mathematics; </section><section prefix="6">"Dual enrollment" means a college-level course of study developed in accordance with KRS 164.098 in which a student is enrolled in a high school and postsecondary institution simultaneously, including participating in the Gatton Academy of Mathematics and Science in Kentucky or the Craft Academy for Excellence in Science and Mathematics; and </section><section prefix="7">"International Baccalaureate" or "IB" means the International Baccalaureate Organization's Diploma Programme, a comprehensive two (2) year program designed for highly motivated students. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 112, sec. 1, effective April 2, 2015. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 15 and 112, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>