<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.086Installation</section_number><catch_line>management fund.   </catch_line><order_by>086Installation</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Military Affairs may establish an installation management fund account in a local bank for each Department of Military Affairs facility, notwithstanding KRS 41.070 and 45A.655. Funds derived from the use of the buildings and grounds shall be deposited in the Department of Military Affairs local installation management fund account. </section><section prefix="2">The adjutant general shall determine the maximum authorized balance in each Department of Military Affairs local installation management fund account. The adjutant general or his designated representative shall review at least annually each installation management fund account. If the account balance is excessive, the surplus funds shall be withdrawn from the installation management fund account for deposit in the appropriate Department of Military Affairs trust and agency fund account. </section><section prefix="3">The local installation management fund account shall be used for expenses associated with routine Department of Military Affairs and Kentucky National Guard functions and operations. Any expense in excess of one hundred fifty dollars ($150) but not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) shall have approval from the facilities division director. Any expense in excess of one thousand dollars ($1,000) but not more than two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500) shall have approval from the executive director of the Department of Military Affairs. Any expense in excess of two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500) but not more than four thousand dollars ($4,000) shall have approval from the adjutant general or his designated representative. </section><section prefix="4">The adjutant general shall provide an annual report to the Legislative Research Commission and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet which identifies the receipts and expenditures of the installation management fund accounts. This report shall be transmitted to the Legislative Research Commission and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet within sixty (60) days after the close of each fiscal year. In addition, the adjutant general shall also provide information to the Legislative Research Commission and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet during the preparation of the biennial budget relating to the receipts, expenditures, and balances of these accounts. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 27, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 420, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44504</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>