<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.18-030</section_number><catch_line>Required provisions in group policies. </catch_line><order_by>18-030</order_by><text>Each such group health insurance policy shall contain in substance the following provisions: <section prefix="1">A provision that, in the absence of fraud, all statements made by applicants or the policyholders or by an insured person shall be deemed representations and not warranties, and that no statement made for the purpose of effecting insurance shall void such insurance or reduce benefits unless contained in a written instrument signed by the policyholder or the insured person, a copy of which has been furnished to such policyholder or to such person or his beneficiary. </section><section prefix="2">A provision that the insurer will furnish to the policyholder for delivery to each employee or member of the insured group a statement in summary form of the essential features of the insurance coverage of such employee or member and to whom benefits thereunder are payable. If dependents are included in the coverage, only one (1) statement need be issued for each family unit. </section><section prefix="3">A provision that to the group originally insured may be added from time to time eligible new employees or members or dependents, as the case may be, in accordance with the terms of the policy. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 18, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29419</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>