<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.590</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility to receive family preservation services. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Family preservation services shall be provided only to those children who are at actual, imminent risk of out-of-home placement, in situations in which family preservation services afford effective protection of children, youth, families, and the community. This shall include children: <section prefix="a">Who are at risk of commitment as dependent, abused, or neglected; </section><section prefix="b">Who are emotionally disturbed; and </section><section prefix="c">Whose families are in conflict such that they are unable to exercise reasonable control of the child. </section></section><section prefix="2">Families in the following situations shall not be eligible for family preservation services: <section prefix="a">Families in which children are at risk of recurring sexual abuse perpetrated by a member of their immediate household who remains in close physical proximity to the victim or whose continued safety from recurring abuse cannot be reasonably assured; and </section><section prefix="b">Families in which one (1) or more adults in the immediate household are drug or alcohol dependent and not in active treatment for such dependency. </section></section><section prefix="3">The implementation of family preservation services shall be limited to those situations where protection can be assured for children, families, and the community. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7317</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>