<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="299" order_by="299">ASSESSMENT OR COOPERATIVE INSURANCE </unit></structure><section_number>299.210</section_number><catch_line>Reinsurance. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An assessment or cooperative life insurance company, including such companies as are organized under the provisions of KRS Chapter 303 and KRS 304.32-010 to 304.32-270, may be wholly reinsured in, and its assets to the extent required to establish adequate reserves transferred to, and its liabilities assumed by a mutual or stock insurer pursuant to an agreement of reinsurance approved by the commissioner of insurance after such hearing as the commissioner may require, and approved by two-thirds (2/3) of the members of such company who are present at a meeting of such members duly called for such purpose, and vote thereon. </section><section prefix="2">Any such reinsurance agreement shall determine the amount of surplus, if any, of such cooperative or assessment company and shall make adequate provision for paying to the members of such company their respective shares of such surplus determined in such manner as may be approved by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">If the transfer or reinsurance is approved, every policyholder of the company who files with its secretary, within ten (10) days after the meeting, written notice of his preference to be transferred to some other company than that named in the contract, shall be accorded all the rights and privileges, if any, in aid of the transfer, that would have been accorded under the terms of the contract had he been transferred to the company named therein. </section><section prefix="4">No domestic company shall transfer its risks or any part thereof to, or reinsure its risks or any part thereof in, any insurance company of another state or country that is not at the time of the transfer or reinsurance authorized to do insurance business in this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 887, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 50, effective June 16, 1972. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 5, effective September 1, 1950. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 668. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=15842</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>