<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.190</section_number><catch_line>Vocational rehabilitation services. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>Vocational rehabilitation services shall be provided directly or through public or private instrumentalities to any individual with a physical or mental disability: <section prefix="1">Who maintains a domicile in the Commonwealth at the time of filing his application therefor, and whose vocational rehabilitation the State Vocational Rehabilitation Agency determines after full investigation can be satisfactorily achieved; or </section><section prefix="2">Who is eligible therefor under the terms of an agreement with another state or with the federal government. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 151B.190 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 37, effective July 1, 1990, which prevailed over the repeal and renactment of KRS 163.130 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 596, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 163.130.</former-codification><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Act chs. 405 and 469 which appear to be identical and have been codified together.  (7/13/90).  This section has been treated by two 1990 Acts; its repeal and reenactment in Acts ch. 470 renumbered the section into KRS ch. 151B. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>