<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">C APPLIED BEHAVIOR ANALYSTS </unit></structure><section_number>319C.070</section_number><catch_line>Probation, suspension, limitation, restriction, revocation, or nonissuance of license by board -- Reasons for. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text>The board may deny an application or reregistration for a license, place a licensee on probation for a period not to exceed five (5) years, suspend a license for a period not to exceed five (5) years, limit or restrict a license for an indefinite period, or revoke any license issued by the board, upon proof that the licensee has: <section prefix="1">Knowingly made or presented, or caused to be made or presented, any false, fraudulent, or forged statement, writing, certificate, diploma, or other thing, in connection with an application for a license or permit; </section><section prefix="2">Practiced, or aided or abetted in the practice of, fraud, forgery, deception, collusion, or conspiracy in connection with an examination for a license; </section><section prefix="3">Entered a guilty or nolo contendere plea, or been convicted, by any court within or without the Commonwealth of Kentucky, of committing an act which is, or would be, a felony under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or of the United States, or of any crime involving moral turpitude which is a misdemeanor under the laws of this or another state; </section><section prefix="4">Been convicted of a misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 510 involving a patient, or a felony offense under KRS Chapter 510, or KRS 530.064(1)(a) or 531.310, or been found by the board to have had sexual contact as defined in KRS 510.010(7) with a patient while the patient was under the care of the licensee; </section><section prefix="5">Become addicted to a controlled substance; </section><section prefix="6">Become a chronic or persistent alcoholic; </section><section prefix="7">Been unable or is unable to practice applied behavior analysis according to acceptable and prevailing standards of care by reason of mental or physical illness or other condition, including but not limited to physical deterioration that adversely affects cognitive, motor, or perceptive skills, or by reason of an extended absence from the active practice of applied behavior analysis; </section><section prefix="8">Engaged in dishonorable, unethical, or unprofessional conduct of a character likely to deceive, defraud, or harm the public or any member thereof; or </section><section prefix="9">Knowingly made, or caused to be made, or aided or abetted in the making of, a false statement in any document executed in connection with the practice of his profession. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>