<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.080</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 309.080 to 309.089.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>As used in KRS 309.080 to 309.089, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Alcohol and Drug Counselors; </section><section prefix="2">"Certified alcohol and drug counselor" means a person certified by the board who meets the requirements in KRS 309.083; </section><section prefix="3">"Certificate holder" means an alcohol and drug counselor who is certified pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="4">"Licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor" means a person licensed by the board who meets the requirements of KRS 309.0832; </section><section prefix="5">"Licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associate" means a person licensed by the board who meets the requirements of KRS 309.0833; </section><section prefix="6">"Licensee" means a clinical alcohol and drug counselor who is licensed pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="7">"Practice of alcohol and drug counseling": <section prefix="a">Means the assessment and counseling of an individual, family, or group dealing with an alcohol or drug problem or addiction; and </section><section prefix="b">Does not include the diagnosis or treatment of a mental health condition, or the administration or interpretation of psychological tests; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Registered alcohol and drug peer support specialist" means a person registered by the board who meets the requirements in KRS 309.0831; and </section><section prefix="9">"Registrant" means an alcohol and drug peer support specialist who is registered pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>