<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.430</section_number><catch_line>Transportation Cabinet to study needs of highways and develop recommended six (6) year road plan that identifies individual transportation projects -- Proposed biennial highway construction plan -- Factors to be considered in development of each project -- Monthly transmission of project data to General Assembly -- Cabinet may expend funds necessary to complete authorized projects -- Digitized maps. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall undertake a continuing study of the needs of the highways under its jurisdiction for the purpose of bringing existing facilities to acceptable standards or for the replacement of existing facilities when required. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet shall develop a recommended six (6) year road plan that identifies the individual transportation projects or portions thereof that are scheduled to be constructed in each county. The recommended six (6) year road plan shall include a recommended biennial highway construction plan. The recommended six (6) year road plan and recommended biennial highway construction plan shall be submitted to the General Assembly as required by KRS 48.110(6)(f). The six (6) year road plan shall include but shall not be limited to the following information for each project: <section prefix="a">The county name; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Transportation Cabinet project identification number; </section><section prefix="c">The route where the project is located; </section><section prefix="d">The length of the project; </section><section prefix="e">A description of the project and the scope of improvement; </section><section prefix="f">The type of local, state, or federal funds to be used on the project; </section><section prefix="g">The stage of development for the design, right-of-way, utility, and construction phase; </section><section prefix="h">The fiscal year in which each phase of the project should commence; </section><section prefix="i">The estimated cost for each phase of the project; and </section><section prefix="j">The estimated cost to complete the project. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall identify projects in the six (6) year road plan that may, in accordance with this section, be advanced from later years, to maximize the use of all funds available to the cabinet, and to plan for the historical precedent of projects being delayed due to unforeseen circumstances. As required by KRS 48.110, the Governor shall submit to the General Assembly, as part of the proposed biennial highway construction plan, a list of projects from the last four (4) years of the six (6) year road plan, not to exceed ten percent (10%) of the recommended biennial highway construction appropriation, which can be advanced if additional money is received and all projects included in the enacted biennial highway construction plan have been advanced or completed to the extent possible. </section><section prefix="4">In developing the design, right-of-way, utility, and construction phase of each project, the following factors shall be considered but are not exclusive: <section prefix="a">Alignment of existing roads; </section><section prefix="b">The width or elevation of existing roadways and shoulder surfaces; </section><section prefix="c">The width of rights-of-way; </section><section prefix="d">The cost of each phase of the project plus a separate identification of the cabinet's administrative costs for each phase; </section><section prefix="e">The type and volume of traffic; </section><section prefix="f">The condition of structures and drainage; </section><section prefix="g">The accident rate; </section><section prefix="h">The geographic distribution of roadways to be constructed or reconstructed; and </section><section prefix="i">The social, economic, and environmental impact of the proposed project. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Transportation Cabinet shall, on a monthly basis, transmit electronically to the General Assembly through the Legislative Research Commission a report on all activity relating to all projects with open activity conducted by the Transportation Cabinet during the biennium. The data for each project shall contain all cabinet activity on projects funded through the road fund, including resurfacing and rural and secondary projects, and shall also include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">District number and project item number, which shall remain in effect throughout the entire life of the project, subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="1">A project split into more than one (1) project during its life shall maintain the same item number with a suffix; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) or more projects merged shall be identified by the new merged project maintaining the project item number of one (1) of the projects being merged. The total cost of the merged project shall be set forth; and </section><section prefix="3">A project that has been merged with another project and all funds authorized for the initial project that is subsequently shifted to the new merged project shall remain in the six (6) year road plan and shall be identified with a cross reference to the superseded project and superseded project item number; </section></section><section prefix="b">The county name and county number; </section><section prefix="c">The route prefix, route number, and route suffix; </section><section prefix="d">Termini description including beginning milepoint and ending milepoint; </section><section prefix="e">Type of work; </section><section prefix="f">Length of the project in miles; </section><section prefix="g">Project authorization system number, date the project was authorized, the TD-10 number authorizing the project, and the amount authorized; </section><section prefix="h">Year the project was enacted in a six (6) year road plan, and the notation "A" if the project is active and the notation "I" if the project is inactive; </section><section prefix="i">The phase code "P" for the planning phase, "D" for the design phase, "R" for the right-of-way phase, "U" for the utility phase, and "C" for the construction phase; </section><section prefix="j">The original estimate, fund code, and fiscal year each phase is expected to begin as enacted in the six (6) year road plan; </section><section prefix="k">The current estimate, fund code, and fiscal year each phase is expected to begin; </section><section prefix="l">The status of funding for each phase; </section><section prefix="m">The date current information has been changed for each phase; </section><section prefix="n">The letting date for each phase; </section><section prefix="o">Total number of right-of-way parcels, deeds signed, suits filed, and right-of-way entries completed; </section><section prefix="p">The date right-of-way plans are to be submitted to the central office in Frankfort and the status of right-of-way plans; </section><section prefix="q">Total utility relocations to be completed and the actual number completed; </section><section prefix="r">The award date, the construction project code number, and the award amount for the construction phase; </section><section prefix="s">The total number of contract change orders issued for each phase, the date of the most recent change order, and the net change order amount for each phase; </section><section prefix="t">The name of the contractor, the contractor's vendor number in the Statewide accounting system, current contract amount, and the current amount earned by the contractor; </section><section prefix="u">The estimated date for completion of the project, current percentage of work completed based upon time, and the actual contract completion date; </section><section prefix="v">The department's engineer's estimate for the project; and </section><section prefix="w">Total expenditures by phase. </section></section><section prefix="6">The department shall transmit on a monthly basis, electronic data to the General Assembly through the Legislative Research Commission on the activity on all state resurfacing projects and all rural secondary projects that shall include as much applicable information as possible as identified in subsection (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">In implementing the enacted biennial highway construction plan, the Transportation Cabinet may expend funds necessary to complete the projects authorized, amended only by variations necessitated by bid or unforeseen circumstances. </section><section prefix="8">The department shall pursue digitizing all Kentucky roads on a geographic information system as funds are made available by the General Assembly. The digitized maps shall merge map layers and text layers to produce maps that display geographic information and textual information detailing the six (6) year road plan as enacted by the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 20, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 532, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 433, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 502, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5214</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>