<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.12-060</section_number><catch_line>Winding up.   </catch_line><order_by>12-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited cooperative association continues after dissolution only for purposes of winding up its activities. </section><section prefix="2">In winding up a limited cooperative association’s activities, the board of directors shall cause the association to: <section prefix="a">Discharge its liabilities, settle and close its activities, and marshal and distribute its assets; </section><section prefix="b">Preserve the association or its property as a going concern for no more than a reasonable time; </section><section prefix="c">Prosecute and defend actions and proceedings; </section><section prefix="d">Transfer association property; and </section><section prefix="e">Perform other necessary acts. </section></section><section prefix="3">After dissolution and upon application of a limited cooperative association, a member, or a holder of financial rights, the appropriate court may order judicial supervision of the winding up of the association, including the appointment of a person to wind up the association’s activities, if: <section prefix="a">After a reasonable time, the association has not wound up its activities; or </section><section prefix="b">The applicant establishes other good cause. </section></section><section prefix="4">If a person is appointed pursuant to subsection (3) of this section to wind up the activities of a limited cooperative association, the association shall promptly deliver to the Secretary of State for filing an amendment to the articles of association to reflect the appointment. </section><section prefix="5">Dissolution of a limited cooperative association shall not abate or suspend KRS 272A.5-030 or 272A.8-020. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 93, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41069</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>