<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.123</section_number><catch_line>Local option election for limited sale of alcoholic beverages in precinct containing golf course -- Petition language.   </catch_line><order_by>123</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">To promote economic development and tourism in a county containing a wet or moist city, with the exception of a moist territory in accordance with KRS 242.1292(1), a local option election for the limited sale of alcoholic beverages may be held in any precinct containing a nine (9) or an eighteen (18) hole golf course that meets United States Golf Association criteria as a regulation golf course, notwithstanding any other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="b">A petition seeking a local option election under this section shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election under KRS 242.123 on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at (name of golf course) in the (name of precinct)?'". </section></section><section prefix="2">A local option election for the limited sale of alcoholic beverages held under subsection (1) of this section shall be conducted in the same manner specified in KRS 242.020 to 242.120, except that the form of the proposition to be voted upon shall be "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at (name of golf course) in the (name of precinct)?". </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 558, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>