<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-810</section_number><catch_line>Policy declaration. </catch_line><order_by>43-810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to encourage and promote the establishment of a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility which utilizes efficient, environmentally acceptable and commercially feasible technologies, techniques, and processes for maximizing resource recovery and energy generation from the treatment and disposal of hazardous waste in Kentucky and minimizing land disposal. </section><section prefix="2">This policy may be implemented by contracts and agreements with the federal government and its agencies and with other organizations, including private industry, and through organizations that may be formed jointly by the state, the federal government or its agencies, and private industry to establish a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility in such organizational form or legal entity deemed appropriate by the participants. </section><section prefix="3">This policy may be implemented by the expenditure of state funds for the preliminary engineering and planning, design, construction and operation of a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility project in Kentucky, and for the acquisition and improvement of land, construction of roads, and provision of other public facilities incidental and necessary to the accomplishment of this project in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">This policy may be implemented by the sale of state property to organizations engaged in a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility project in Kentucky, either for a fair and reasonable consideration or solely or partly as all or a portion of the state's participation in this project. </section><section prefix="5">This policy may be implemented by acquisition, by purchase, or by option to purchase the fee simple title to, or any acceptable lesser interest in such rights-of-way, franchises, or easements, including submerged lands and riparian rights that are necessary for the construction, use or operation of any authorized regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility project and for the construction and operation of a line of railroad, truck road, overhead conveyor, or other transportation facilities together with the necessary rights of ingress and egress to construct, examine, alter, repair, maintain, operate, or remove such transportation facilities. </section><section prefix="6">This policy may be implemented by contracts and agreements for the Commonwealth to purchase all or a portion of the usable output of this project, either for a fair and reasonable consideration or solely or partly as all or a portion of the state's participation in the project, and to dispose of this output by use in state facilities or by resale at fair market value. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.896, and also previously codified as KRS 224.212. </former-codification><lrc-note>.  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>