<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="327" order_by="327">PHYSICAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>327.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Physical therapy" means the use of selected knowledge and skills in planning, organizing, and directing programs for the care of individuals whose ability to function is impaired or threatened by disease or injury, encompassing preventive measures, screening, tests in aid of diagnosis by a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, chiropractic, or podiatry and evaluation and invasive or noninvasive procedures with emphasis on the skeletal system, neuromuscular and cardiopulmonary function, as it relates to physical therapy. Physical therapy includes screening or evaluations performed to determine the degree of impairment of relevant aspects, such as but not limited to nerve and muscle function including subcutaneous bioelectrical potentials, motor development, functional capacity, and respiratory or circulatory efficiency. Physical therapy also includes physical therapy treatment performed upon referral by a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, chiropractic, or podiatry, including but not limited to exercises for increasing or restoring strength, endurance, coordination and range of motion, stimuli to facilitate motor activity and learning, instruction in activities of daily living, and the use of assistive devices and the application of physical agents to relieve pain or alter physiological status. The use of roentgen rays and radium for diagnostic or therapeutic purposes, the use of electricity for surgical purposes, including cauterization and colonic irrigations are not authorized under the term "physical therapy" as used in this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">"Physical therapist" means a professional person who has met the educational requirements of this chapter and who is licensed to practice physical therapy pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Board of Physical Therapy established by KRS 327.030; </section><section prefix="4">"Referral" means the procedure by which a licensed doctor of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, chiropractic, or podiatry designates the initiation of physical therapy treatment by a licensed physical therapist; and </section><section prefix="5">"Temporary permit" means a permit granted to an individual who has met all requirements in Kentucky for license application by examination and has made application for examination but who has not yet successfully completed the board approved examination in this or another state. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31711</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>