<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.380</section_number><catch_line>Delivery of orders by electronic transmission or mail. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text>The commission shall deliver a certified copy of any order issued by it to each party to the proceeding in which the order was made, and to an officer or agent of the utility affected thereby. Notwithstanding any statute to the contrary, the commission may deliver its orders by means of electronic transmission rather than by mail. The commission, however, shall deliver its orders by mail to any party that requests and demonstrates good cause for that means of delivery. When service of a commission order is by electronic transmission, mailing shall be deemed to have occurred on the date the transmission of the order is completed. For purposes of this section, electronic transmission of a commission order includes the sending of an electronic mail message that contains an electronic version of the commission order or a hyperlink that enables the recipient to access, view, and download an electronic copy of the commission order from the commission's Web site. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 45, effective April 1, 1979. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3952-35. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43239</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>