<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.505</section_number><catch_line>Definition of "prevailing wage" -- Fringe benefits included. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text>For the purpose of KRS 337.505 to 337.550, the term "prevailing wage" for each classification of laborers, workmen, and mechanics engaged in the construction of public works within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, means the sum of: <section prefix="1">The basic hourly rate paid or being paid subsequent to the commissioner's most recent wage determination to the majority of laborers, workmen, and mechanics employed in each classification of construction upon reasonably comparable construction in the locality where the work is to be performed; such rate shall be determined by the commissioner in accordance with paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of subsection (3) of KRS 337.520; in the event that there is not a majority paid at the same rate, then the basic hourly rate of pay shall be the average basic hourly rate which shall be determined by adding the basic hourly rates paid to all workers in the classification and dividing by the total number of such workers; and </section><section prefix="2">An additional amount per hour equal to the hourly rate of contribution irrevocably made or to be made by an employer on behalf of employees within each classification of construction to a trustee or to a third person pursuant to an enforceable commitment to carry out a financially responsible plan or program, which was communicated in writing to the employees affected, for the following fringe benefits: medical or hospital care, pensions on retirement, death compensation for injuries or illness resulting from occupational activity or insurance to provide any of the foregoing, unemployment benefits, life insurance, disability and sickness insurance, accident insurance, vacation and holiday pay, defraying costs of apprenticeship or other similar programs, or other bona fide fringe benefits, but only where the employer is not required by other federal, state or local law to provide any of such benefits: provided, said additional amount may, at the discretion of the employer, be paid either in cash to the employee or by contributions for fringe benefits, or partly in cash and partly by such contributions, it being the intention of this subsection to recognize fringe benefits as a part of the prevailing wage rate where made in accordance with this subsection. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1740, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32095</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>