<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.850</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>850</order_by><text>As used in KRS 365.855 to 365.875: <section prefix="1">"Artist" means the person who creates a work of fine art or, if such person is deceased, such person's heir, legatee, or personal representative; </section><section prefix="2">"Fine art" shall include, but is not limited to, a painting, sculpture, drawing, work of graphic or photographic art, including an etching, lithograph, offset print, silk screen, or work of graphic art of like nature, a work of calligraphy, a work of folk art or craft, or a work in mixed media including a collage, assemblage, or any combination of the foregoing art media; </section><section prefix="3">"Art dealer" means a person engaged in the business of selling, as either a primary or supplemental source of income, works of fine art, other than a person exclusively engaged in the business of selling goods at public auction; </section><section prefix="4">"Person" means an individual partnership, corporation, association or other group, however organized; and </section><section prefix="5">"Consignment" means a delivery of a work of fine art under which no title to, estate in, or right to possession of, fine art, superior to that of the consignor shall vest in the consignee, notwithstanding the consignee's power or authority to transfer and convey to a third person all of the right, title and interest of the consignor in and to such fine art. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986 </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>