<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.3765</section_number><catch_line>Review of compact rules under consideration.  (Effective upon contingency) </catch_line><order_by>3765</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each proposed compact rule under consideration for adoption in Kentucky shall be forwarded to the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee ("ARRS") and the subcommittee or standing committee of appropriate jurisdiction over the subject matter of the proposed compact rule ("subject matter committee") by the Kentucky compact commissioner for review when a rule is initially proposed and, if a rule is substantially modified during the compact commission rule-making process, when the rule is modified. </section><section prefix="2">Each proposed compact rule adopted by the compact commission and upon which the Kentucky compact commissioner has voted in favor shall be forwarded to the ARRS and the subject matter committee simultaneously by the Kentucky compact commissioner for review within sixty (60) days after adoption. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receipt of a proposed, modified, or adopted compact rule, the ARRS and subject matter committee shall review the rule and may forward their respective findings to the Kentucky compact commissioner in writing within ten (10) calendar days. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 3, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> Upon contingency (see note) </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  2011 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2, provides that this statute shall take effect upon the enactment of the Interstate Racing and Wagering Compact by at least six eligible states. As of the codification of this statute, that contingency had not been met. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>