<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.035</section_number><catch_line>Executive Mansion -- Maintenance and operation -- Duties of cabinet as to food, personnel and Governor's travel expenses. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall be responsible for the management, maintenance, and operation, including the purchase for all purposes of all food and related supplies, of the Executive Mansion, and further including the reasonable and necessary expenses of the chief executive while traveling on business of the Commonwealth outside of the state. Such personnel, including domestic and household servants, as are necessary for the operation and maintenance of the Executive Mansion shall be employed by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The provisions of KRS Chapter 42 shall apply to all purchases made for the maintenance and operation of the mansion. None of the provisions of KRS 18A.110 and 18A.155 shall apply to personnel employed for the maintenance and operation of the mansion. </section><section prefix="2">A reasonable amount shall be deducted from the salary or other allowance of the Governor for the consumption by the Governor and his family of such food and supplies. </section><section prefix="3">A reasonable amount shall be deducted from the salaries of personnel employed in operational and maintenance functions, including domestic and household servants, for the consumption by such personnel of such food and supplies. </section><section prefix="4">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall maintain such records relative to the management, maintenance, and operation of the Governor's Mansion and travel expenses of the chief executive as may be dictated by sound accounting practices. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 6. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21972</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>