<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.402</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 353.400 to 353.410. </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text>As used in KRS 353.400 to 353.410, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Gas acquisition authority" or "authority" means a natural gas acquisition authority created pursuant to this section; </section><section prefix="2">"Bond" means any bond, note, or other evidence of indebtedness issued by an Authority; </section><section prefix="3">"Gas" or "natural gas" means natural gas or any substitute for natural gas, including synthetic natural gas, liquefied natural gas, coal gas, or other substance usable in lieu of natural gas; </section><section prefix="4">"Municipal utility" means any public agency that: <section prefix="a">Provides gas or electric service to retail customers within a municipal service area; or </section><section prefix="b">Provides wholesale natural gas supply services to public agencies described in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Project" means any plant, works, system, facility, other real or personal property, and interests therein, including drilling rights, operating rights, royalties, overriding royalties, and other rights, titles, and interests, production payments, gas purchase contracts, prepaid gas purchase contracts, and other contractual rights and interests necessary or convenient for the acquisition, transportation, storage, or management of natural gas for the purpose of providing the supply requirements of municipal utilities; and </section><section prefix="6">"Public agency" has the same meaning as specified in KRS 65.230. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33090</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>