<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.108</section_number><catch_line>Persons adjudicated mentally defective and committed to mental institutions -- Identifying information to be forwarded to Department of Kentucky State Police and Federal Bureau of Investigation -- Information to be included in National Instant Criminal Background Check System database -- Petition to court for relief from prohibition against possession of firearms -- Prohibition against allowing improper use of information obtained by Kentucky State Police. </catch_line><order_by>108</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A court that orders a commitment or makes a finding or adjudication under which a person becomes subject to the provisions of 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(4) and (g)(4) shall order the circuit clerk to forward the person's name and nonclinical identifying information, including the person's Social Security number and date of birth, along with a copy of the order of commitment to the Department of Kentucky State Police, which in turn shall forward the information to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, its successor agency, or agency designated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, for inclusion in the National Instant Criminal Background Check System database. The court shall also notify the person of the prohibitions of 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(4) and (g)(4). </section><section prefix="2">A person who is subject to the provisions of 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(4) and (g)(4) because of a commitment, finding, or adjudication that occurred in this state may petition the court in which such commitment, finding, or adjudication occurred to remove, pursuant to Section 105(a) of Pub. L. No. 110-180, the disabilities imposed under 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(4) and (g)(4). A copy of the petition for relief shall also be served on the director of the Division of Behavioral Health and the county attorney of the county in which the original commitment, finding, or adjudication occurred. The director of the Division of Behavioral Health and the county attorney may, as each deems appropriate, appear, support, object to, or present evidence relevant to the relief sought by the petitioner. The court shall receive and consider evidence in a closed proceeding, including evidence offered by the petitioner concerning: <section prefix="a">The circumstances of the original commitment, finding, or adjudication; </section><section prefix="b">The petitioner's mental health and criminal history records, if any; </section><section prefix="c">The petitioner's reputation; </section><section prefix="d">The petitioner's date of birth and Social Security number; and </section><section prefix="e">Changes in the petitioner's condition or circumstances relevant to the relief sought. </section></section> The court shall grant the petition for relief if it finds by a preponderance of the evidence that the petitioner will not be likely to act in a manner dangerous to public safety and that granting of the relief would not be contrary to the public interest. A record shall be kept of the proceedings, but it shall remain confidential and be disclosed only to a court in the event of an appeal. The petitioner may appeal a denial of the requested relief, and review on appeal shall be de novo. A person may file a petition for relief under this section no more than once every two (2) years. <section prefix="3">When the court issues an order granting a petition for relief under subsection (2) of this section, the circuit clerk shall immediately forward a copy of the order to the Department of Kentucky State Police, which in turn shall immediately forward a copy to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or its successor agency, for updating of the National Instant Criminal Background Check System database and shall remove all information in any database over which the department exercises control relating to the person whose relief from disability is granted and shall immediately destroy all paper copies of the order of commitment and other documents relating to the matter. </section><section prefix="4">If a petition is granted under this section, the order, finding, or adjudication for which relief is granted shall, pursuant to Section 105(a) of Pub. L. No. 110-180, be deemed not to have occurred for purposes of 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(4) and (g)(4). </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall not use or permit the use of the records or information obtained or retained pursuant to this section for any purpose not specified in this section. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall supersede any other statute to the contrary for the purposes set forth in this section but otherwise shall be held and construed as ancillary and supplemental to any other statute. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39752</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>