<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="259" order_by="259">STRAYS AND ANIMALS RUNNING AT LARGE </unit></structure><section_number>259.140Taker-up</section_number><catch_line>to pay owner value of stray equines or cattle, when -- Limitation of liability.   </catch_line><order_by>140Taker-up</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If cattle taken up under KRS 259.120 are sold for a profit before absolute ownership of the stray cattle has vested in the taker-up as provided by KRS 259.130, then the taker-up shall pay to the owner upon demand and proof of ownership the amount received for the stray cattle less the amount owed by the owner to the taker-up under KRS 259.120. The owner shall not be entitled to any payment from the taker-up under this section if demand for payment is made more than fifteen (15) days after the posting of the stray equine and vesting of ownership pursuant to KRS 259.130 or more than twelve (12) months after the posting of the stray cattle under KRS 259.120. </section><section prefix="2">County judges/executive or participating state agency, county clerks, and all other local government employees acting in good faith in the discharge of the duties imposed by KRS 259.105, 259.110, 259.120, 259.130, and this section shall be immune from criminal and civil liability for any act related to the taking up and posting of stray equines or stray cattle. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4655. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44056</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>