<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-010</section_number><catch_line>Policy and purpose -- Priorities for solid waste management practices -- Findings relating to solid waste management plans. </catch_line><order_by>43-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby declared to be the policy of this Commonwealth and the purpose of this chapter to provide for the management of solid waste, including reduction, collection, transportation, and disposal in a manner that will protect the public health and welfare, prevent the spread of disease and creation of nuisances, conserve our natural resources, and enhance the beauty and quality of our environment. </section><section prefix="2">It is the policy of the Commonwealth to limit and reduce the amount of solid waste disposed in municipal solid waste disposal facilities in the Commonwealth through reduction in the amount of waste generated, reuse of solid waste, waste recycling or yard waste composting, and resource recovery, and to encourage a regional approach to solid waste management. </section><section prefix="3">It is the policy of the Commonwealth that municipal solid waste disposal facilities that ceased accepting waste before July 1, 1992, undergo proper closure, characterization, and corrective action. </section><section prefix="4">It is the policy of the Commonwealth that a comprehensive and integrated waste management system to handle solid waste is to be fostered. State policies and funding assistance shall reflect a preference for projects and practices consistent with the policies and goals established by this section and the following: <section prefix="a">Education of the citizens of the Commonwealth regarding proper disposal of waste; </section><section prefix="b">Collection and proper disposal of all of solid waste for proper management; </section><section prefix="c">Elimination of illegal dumps throughout the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="d">Abatement of litter on state and county rights-of-way. </section></section><section prefix="5">It is the policy of the Commonwealth that existing illegal open dumps be eliminated and that new open dumps be prevented. </section><section prefix="6">The General Assembly finds that counties and waste management districts, when enabled by complete and accurate information relating to the municipal solid waste collection and management practices within the solid waste management area, are in the best position to make plans for municipal solid waste collection services for its citizens. The General Assembly also finds that assistance from the cabinet, combined with state financial incentives, can aid counties and waste management districts with implementing solid waste management plans. </section><section prefix="7">The General Assembly finds that the goal of reducing the amount of solid waste disposed of in municipal solid waste disposal facilities cannot be achieved without first identifying the amount of municipal solid waste generated statewide per capita, including the waste now disposed of in open dumps, and providing incentives for the elimination of existing open dumps and the prevention of new open dumps. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2, effective February 26, 1991. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 12, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.830, and also previously codified as KRS 224.250. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  A reference to "July 12, 1992" in subsection (3) of this statute as amended by 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 1, has been changed in codification to read "July 1, 1992," to correct a manifest clerical or typographical error under KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10409</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>