<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.097</section_number><catch_line>Registration of imported motor vehicles -- Transfer of title -- Inspection of vehicle. </catch_line><order_by>097</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No county clerk shall accept an initial application for a certificate of registration or title, or license plate, from an importer of a motor vehicle not manufactured for sale or distribution in the United States unless the importer of such a vehicle shall furnish to the county clerk of the county where the vehicle is sought to be titled or registered the following: <section prefix="a">A manufacturer's certificate of origin in the English language issued by the actual vehicle manufacturer; </section><section prefix="b">The original documents constituting valid proof of ownership in the country in which the vehicle was originally purchased, together with a complete translation of the documents into the English language verified as to accuracy of the translation by affidavit of a competent translator; or </section><section prefix="c">In the case of a vehicle imported from a country that cancels the vehicle registration and title for export, the documents assigned to the vehicle after the registration and title have been canceled, together with a complete translation of the documents into the English language, verified as to accuracy of the translation by affidavit of the translator. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the initial transfer of a vehicle not manufactured for sale or distribution in the United States by an importer of a vehicle, or upon registration of such a vehicle by the importer for their own use, no county clerk shall accept an application for certificate of registration or title or license plate until the following information is provided: <section prefix="a">A bond release letter, with all attachments, issued by the United States Department of Transportation acknowledging receipt of a statement of compliance submitted by the importer of the vehicle and that the statement meets the safety requirements of 19 C.F.R. 12.80 (e); </section><section prefix="b">A bond release letter, with all attachments, issued by the United States Environmental Protection Agency stating that the vehicle has been tested and shown to be in conformity with federal emission requirements; </section><section prefix="c">A receipt or certificate issued by the United States Department of Treasury showing that any and all gas guzzler taxes due on the vehicle under the provision of Public Law 95-618, Title II, Section 201(a), (26 U.S.C. Sec. 4064), have been fully paid; and </section><section prefix="d">True and accurate copies of all documents, photographs, reports and all other records submitted to and used in obtaining United States customs bond release authorization from the United States Environmental Protection Agency and the United States Department of Transportation, and on which the authorization to release the bond was based. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon the initial transfer of a vehicle not manufactured for sale or distribution in the United States by an importer of a vehicle, or upon registration of such a vehicle by the importer for their own use, the applicant shall, before submitting his application to the county clerk, have the vehicle together with his application for title or registration and its supporting documents inspected by a certified inspector according to the provisions of the KRS 186A.115. When requested to inspect a vehicle pursuant to this section, the certified inspector shall personally and physically inspect the vehicle, together with the application for title or registration, and its supporting documentation. He shall insure that the documents, photographs, reports and other records submitted to the United States Department of Transportation and the United States Environmental Protection Agency, upon which the decision to issue bond release authorization to the United States Customs Service was based, correspond with the vehicle he is physically inspecting, by matching such records with the following: <section prefix="a">The vehicle identification number; </section><section prefix="b">The engine serial number; </section><section prefix="c">The make and model of the vehicle; and </section><section prefix="d">Photographs of the vehicle (if submitted). </section></section><section prefix="4">In lieu of the foregoing requirements, the applicant shall furnish to the county clerk proof satisfactory that the vehicle for which registration or title is sought was manufactured in the United States, or that such was lawfully imported into the United States by an authorized distributor from the manufacturer of the motor vehicle. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>