<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.37-150</section_number><catch_line>Voting rights of holder of security acquired in contravention of chapter or action of commissioner -- Legal actions to enjoin voting and to seize or sequester security. </catch_line><order_by>37-150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No security which is the subject of any agreement or arrangement regarding acquisition, or which is acquired or to be acquired, in contravention of the provisions of this chapter or of any rule, administrative regulation, or order issued by the commissioner may be voted at any shareholders' meeting, or may be counted for quorum purposes, and any action of shareholders requiring the affirmative vote of a percentage of shares may be taken as though the securities were not issued and outstanding; but no action taken at the meeting shall be invalidated by the voting of the securities, unless the action would materially affect control of the insurer or unless the courts of this state have so ordered. If an insurer or the commissioner has reason to believe that any security of the insurer has been or is about to be acquired in contravention of the provisions of this chapter or of any rule, administrative regulation, or order issued by the commissioner, the insurer or the commissioner may apply to the Circuit Court for the county in which the insurer has its principal place of business to enjoin any offer, request, invitation, agreement, or acquisition made in contravention of KRS 304.37-130 or any other provision of this chapter, or any rule, administrative regulation, or order issued by the commissioner to enjoin the voting of any security so acquired, to void any vote of the security already cast at any meeting of shareholders, and for any other equitable relief as required by the nature of the case and the interest of the insurer's policyholders, creditors, shareholders, or the public. </section><section prefix="2">In any case where a person has acquired or is proposing to acquire any voting securities in violation of this chapter or any rule, administrative regulation, or order issued by the commissioner, the Circuit Court for Franklin County or the Circuit Court for the county in which the insurer has its principal place of business may, upon notice the court deems appropriate, upon the application of the insurer or the commissioner seize or sequester any voting securities of the insurer owned directly or indirectly by the person, and issue the appropriate order to effectuate the provisions of this subtitle. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, for the purposes of this chapter the situs of the ownership of the securities of domestic insurers shall be deemed to be in this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1485, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 16, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>