<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="529" order_by="529">PROSTITUTION OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>529.150</section_number><catch_line>Forfeiture of property used in connection with human trafficking -- Distribution of proceeds.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All property used in connection with or acquired as a result of a violation of KRS 529.100 or 529.110 shall be subject to forfeiture under the same terms, conditions, and defenses and using the same process as set out in KRS 218A.405 to 218A.460, with the exception of the distribution of proceeds, which shall be distributed as required in this section. </section><section prefix="2">Proceeds from the assets seized and forfeited shall be distributed as follows:<section prefix="a">Fifty percent (50%) shall be paid to the human trafficking victims fund; </section><section prefix="b">Forty-two and one-half percent (42.5%) shall be paid to the law enforcement agency or agencies that seized the property, to be used for direct law enforcement purposes; and </section><section prefix="c">Seven and one-half percent (7.5%) shall be paid to the Office of the Attorney General or, in the alternative, to the Prosecutors Advisory Council for deposit on behalf of the Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney who has participated in the forfeiture proceeding, as determined by the court pursuant to KRS 218A.420(9). Notwithstanding KRS Chapter 48, these funds shall be exempt from any state budget reduction acts. </section></section> The moneys identified in this subsection are intended to supplement any funds otherwise appropriated to the recipient and shall not supplant other funding of any recipient. </text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41841</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>