<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.8483</section_number><catch_line>Toll-free hotline for receiving reports of fraud and abuse -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>8483</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of the Inspector General in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish, maintain, and publicize a twenty-four (24) hour toll-free hotline for the purpose of receiving reports of alleged fraud and abuse by Medical Assistance Program recipients and participating providers. </section><section prefix="2">The Office of the Inspector General in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall prepare a written description of the reported information and immediately make a written referral to: <section prefix="a">The state Medicaid Fraud Control Unit and to the Office of the Attorney General of all reports of alleged fraud and abuse by providers or recipients participating in the Medical Assistance Program; and </section><section prefix="b">Other agencies and licensure boards of all reports relevant to their jurisdiction. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Office of the Inspector General in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, jointly with the state Medicaid Fraud Control Unit and the Office of the Attorney General, shall prepare a Medicaid fraud and abuse report, for the prior fiscal year, categorized by types of fraud and abuse and by recipient and provider group. This report shall be submitted no later than July 1 of each year to the Legislative Research Commission, the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare and shall identify: <section prefix="a">The number and type of reports received in the Office of the Inspector General in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, from the Medicaid fraud and abuse hotline categorized by recipient and provider groups; </section><section prefix="b">The number and type of alleged Medicaid fraud and abuse reports which were discovered by, received by, or referred to the Office of the Attorney General, the state Medicaid Fraud Control Unit, the Office of the Inspector General, and the Department for Medicaid Services; the number and type of reports which were opened for investigation by the Office of the Attorney General, the state Medicaid Fraud Control Unit, the Department for Medicaid Services, or the Office of the Inspector General and their disposition including: <section prefix="1">Administrative actions taken; </section><section prefix="2">Criminal penalties and civil payments received; </section><section prefix="3">The amount of state and federal funds involved in the alleged fraud and abuse; </section><section prefix="4">The cost of administering the hotline; and </section><section prefix="5">Recommendations for legislative action to prevent, detect, and prosecute medical assistance abuse and fraud in the Commonwealth. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 287, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 234, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 316, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7867</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>