<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.225</section_number><catch_line>Voter's signature -- Use of original registration forms to compare signature -- Voting supplemental paper ballot. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person desiring to vote on election day shall give his name and address to the clerk of the election. If the person's name is listed on the precinct list furnished by the State Board of Elections as provided in KRS 117.025 and if no challenge is made, he shall sign his name on the precinct list in the space opposite his printed name. The voter's signature shall constitute his verification that he is a properly registered and qualified voter. The voter shall then retire alone to cast his vote on the voting machine. The county board of elections may provide to each precinct the original registration form of each voter entitled to vote in that precinct. These forms shall be used to compare signatures in those precincts to which the forms are provided. </section><section prefix="2">If supplemental paper ballots are used, as provided in KRS 118.215, after voting on the voting machine the voter shall take the supplemental paper ballot with the stub intact and retire alone to the voting booth provided for voting paper ballots.  After voting the supplemental paper ballot, the voter shall remove the numbered stub, hand the stub to an election official and deposit the voted ballot in the locked ballot box. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 561, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, effective March 19, 1977. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 36, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27405</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>