<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.560</section_number><catch_line>Manufactured Home Certification and Licensure Board -- Membership -- Compensation -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Manufactured Home Certification and Licensure Board which shall issue certificates of acceptability to qualifying manufacturers and licenses to retailers and shall certify installers. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of the state fire marshal, the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, or their designees, and seven (7) citizens of the Commonwealth appointed by the Governor, which shall include three (3) manufactured or mobile home retailers, one (1) certified manufactured or mobile home installer, and three (3) members who shall have no interest in the industry to be regulated. </section><section prefix="3">The state fire marshal, the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, and the commissioner of the Department for Public Health shall be permanent members of the board, by virtue of their respective offices. The appointed members of the board shall hold office for terms of four (4) years with their terms expiring on September 1 of even-numbered years. Each member shall hold office until his or her successor is appointed and has qualified. </section><section prefix="4">In the initial appointments to the board, the Governor shall designate three (3) members to serve for two (2) years and three (3) to serve for four (4) years. In the initial appointment of the certified manufactured or mobile home installer to the board, the Governor shall designate the member to serve for a term expiring September 1, 2004. </section><section prefix="5">All members appointed from the manufactured housing industry shall be required to remain licensed and certified during their term and are subject to removal for chronic absenteeism. </section><section prefix="6">If a vacancy occurs in the office of one (1) of the members of the board, the position shall be filled by a person appointed by the Governor, and the person so appointed shall serve only to the end of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="7">The chairman of the board shall be elected by the board. In the event of the chairman's absence or disability, the members of the board shall elect a temporary chairman by a majority vote of those present at a meeting. </section><section prefix="8">Each appointed member shall be entitled to fifty dollars ($50) for each day he is in attendance at meetings or hearings or on authorized business of the board, including time spent in traveling to and from the place of the meeting, hearing, or other authorized business. Each member of the board shall also be entitled to reimbursement for travel and other necessary expenses incurred in performing official duties. </section><section prefix="9">The chairman, or in his absence a temporary chairman selected by the members of the board present at the meeting, shall preside at all meetings of the board. The board shall have regular meetings at times specified by a majority vote of the board. The chairman may call special meetings at any time. He shall call a special meeting on written request by two (2) or more members of the board. A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum to transact business. </section><section prefix="10">All staff assistance deemed necessary by the board to carry out the functions and duties assigned to it in KRS 227.550 to 227.660 shall be provided by the department and shall function under the supervision of the head of the department. </section><section prefix="11">The provisions of KRS 198B.030(8) and (9) and 198B.040(11) shall not apply to the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 17, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 413, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 511, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 21, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 2. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39912</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>