<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.560</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of completion of training course required for appointment or retention as law enforcement telecommunicator -- Grandfather clause -- Annual in-service training course. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall receive an official appointment on a permanent basis as a law enforcement telecommunicator unless the person has previously been awarded a certificate by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council attesting to such person's satisfactory completion of a non-CJIS telecommunications academy. Every person who is employed after June 24, 2003, as a law enforcement telecommunicator by any law enforcement agency in this state, regardless of prior experience as a non-CJIS telecommunicator, shall forfeit his or her position as such unless, within twelve (12) months from the date of his or her employment, he or she satisfactorily completes the non-CJIS telecommunications academy and is awarded a certificate attesting thereto. The council shall waive the training requirements listed in this section for all law enforcement telecommunicators who are serving on July 15, 2006, and possess a certificate of completion of an approved law enforcement telecommunicator basic training program. </section><section prefix="2">All non-CJIS telecommunicators, whether originally employed before or after July 15, 2006, shall successfully complete each calendar year an in-service training course, appropriate to their job assignment and responsibility, of at least eight (8) hours' duration at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="3">In the event of extenuating circumstances beyond the control of a non-CJIS telecommunicator that prevent completion of training within the time specified, the commissioner or the commissioner's designee may grant the non-CJIS telecommunicator an extension of time, not to exceed one hundred eighty (180) days, in which to complete the training. </section><section prefix="4">A non-CJIS telecommunicator who fails to complete the training within a period of twelve (12) months and any extension of time granted under this section shall be terminated by the employing agency and shall not be permitted to serve as a telecommunicator with any governmental agency in the Commonwealth for a period of one (1) year. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=971</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>