<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.810</section_number><catch_line>State geographer -- Appointment -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Office of State Geographer. The state geographer shall be appointed by the Governor and shall serve for a term of one (1) year. No one (1) person shall be appointed state geographer for two (2) terms in succession nor shall the state geographer be from the same institution of higher education as the person immediately preceding him as state geographer. The state geographer shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="2">The state geographer shall be a person who holds a graduate degree in geography from an accredited college or university and who has demonstrated a professional knowledge of Kentucky geography through his teaching or research activities. </section><section prefix="3">To the extent funds permit, the state geographer shall: <section prefix="a">Utilize the facilities of geography departments of major universities in the state; </section><section prefix="b">Advise state officials and agencies on geographic matters; </section><section prefix="c">Serve as a resource for teachers of geography and for publishers of geography textbooks and atlases; </section><section prefix="d">Assist state and local officials with boundary studies; </section><section prefix="e">Advise state and local agencies on mapping and cartographic programs; </section><section prefix="f">Assist state and local officials with planning, zoning and land-use studies; </section><section prefix="g">Cooperate with other states in exchanging geographic information; and </section><section prefix="h">Compile, analyze and disseminate geographic information necessary to perform the foregoing duties. </section></section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2170</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>