<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.440</section_number><catch_line>Bases for organizational units for pilot programs. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Personnel Steering Committee shall consider organizational units for the pilot personnel program based on the following: <section prefix="a">The advantage gained by the organizational unit in the fulfillment of its statutory mission and improved service to the taxpayer; </section><section prefix="b">The program goals and objectives which would operate to create a high performance workplace as outlined in the first report of the Governor's Commission on Quality and Efficiency, which may include: <section prefix="1">Increased employee involvement; </section><section prefix="2">Continuous improvement of operating systems and customer services; </section><section prefix="3">Decision-making at all levels of the organization; </section><section prefix="4">Manager and employee training in high involvement skills; </section><section prefix="5">Defined measures that recognize success; and </section><section prefix="6">Improved means of lawful employee negotiations. </section></section><section prefix="c">The method by which the organizational unit would identify benchmarks for the measurement of the effectiveness of the pilot program, including periodic employee and customer evaluations of the pilot program; </section><section prefix="d">Evidence of support for the pilot program by a majority of the employees to be involved in the proposed pilot program. The Governmental Services Center shall develop a survey to measure employee support for the proposed pilot programs. In organizational units for which pilot programs are considered, the Governmental Services Center shall also devise a process which insures confidentiality in the administration of and the tabulation of the results of the survey; and </section><section prefix="e">Additional information which may be requested by the Personnel Steering Committee to consider an agency's application, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Training plans for managers and employees; </section><section prefix="2">Identification of fiscal and personnel resources; and </section><section prefix="3">A proposed agency coordinator for the project. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The Personnel Steering Committee's recommendation of organizational units for the pilot personnel programs shall not affect more than fifteen percent (15%) of the permanent, full-time state employees employed as of July 15, 1994, except as provided in KRS 18A.450. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>