<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.152</section_number><catch_line>County clerk's settlement with fiscal court for excess fees in counties of less than 75,000. </catch_line><order_by>152</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In counties containing a population of less than seventy-five thousand (75,000), the county clerk shall provide to the fiscal court by March 15 of each year a complete statement for the preceding calendar year of all funds received by his office in an official capacity or for official services, and of all expenditures of his office, including his salary, compensation of deputies and assistants, and reasonable expenses. </section><section prefix="2">At the time of filing the statement required by subsection (1) of this section, the clerk shall pay to the fiscal court any income of his office, including income from investments, which exceeds the sum of his maximum salary as permitted by the Constitution and other reasonable expenses, including compensation of deputies and assistants. The settlement for excess fees shall be subject to correction by audit conducted pursuant to KRS 43.070 or 64.810, and the provisions of this section shall not be construed to amend KRS 64.820. </section><section prefix="3">When the county clerk vacates his office, the provisions of KRS 64.830 shall be applicable. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23204</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>