<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.026</section_number><catch_line>Applications for scholarships -- Awards.   </catch_line><order_by>026</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall make nursing scholarships in schools of nursing and graduate programs in nursing available to Kentucky residents through the Kentucky nursing incentive scholarship fund, as set forth by KRS 314.025 to 314.027 and by administrative regulations of the board promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall administer the Kentucky nursing incentive scholarship fund and may recover reasonable costs for administering the fund. The board shall be responsible for receiving and evaluating all applications for the scholarship made by persons who are bona fide residents of the Commonwealth and who desire to become nurses. The board shall evaluate each application to determine if the applicant complies with criteria for such scholarships as set forth in KRS 314.025 to 314.027 and in administrative regulations of the board. </section><section prefix="3">Applications from all persons determined to be qualified shall be forwarded to the board. The board shall designate the persons to receive assistance and the amount thereof. Decisions of the board in these matters shall be final. Disbursement of funds shall be pursuant to a written contract between the board and the applicant. </section><section prefix="4">The yearly individual nursing scholarship award granted shall be determined annually by the board. In determining the amount of the award and the number of scholarships to be granted, the board shall use its best judgment and shall seek to maintain the scholarship funds for future use. </section><section prefix="5">Each recipient of a scholarship shall agree in the written contract to practice as a nurse in Kentucky for at least one (1) year for each academic year funded. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>