<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.183</section_number><catch_line>Licensure requirements for speech-language pathologist. </catch_line><order_by>183</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be eligible for initial interim licensure by the board as a speech-language pathologist, the applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Provide a certified university transcript conferring a master's degree or doctorate degree in the area of speech-language pathology or communication disorders, or substantive equivalent. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to specify the required course work; or </section><section prefix="b">Provide documentation of completion of degree requirements, including a supervised direct clinical practicum with individuals presenting with a variety of disorders of communications and swallowing. The experience shall be obtained with a training institution or in one (1) of its cooperating programs. </section></section><section prefix="2">To be eligible for initial licensure by the board as a speech-language pathologist, the applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Provide a certified university transcript conferring a master's degree or doctorate degree in the area of speech-language pathology or communication disorders, or substantive equivalent. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to specify the required course work; </section><section prefix="b">Provide documentation of completion of a postgraduate professional experience approved by the board pursuant to administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">Pass a national examination approved by the board at the time of the application for licensure or provide documentation of national certification. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2008).  Subsection (3) of this statute as it appeared in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 4 has been renumbered as subsection (2)(c) as it appears here following codification under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31912</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>