<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.515</section_number><catch_line>Participation in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund by a police officer who is elected jailer. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A police officer who is elected as a jailer shall retain eligibility for Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund participation following his or her term of office as jailer, subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The police officer successfully completed a basic training course approved or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council; </section><section prefix="b">The person has been continuously employed as a police officer since basic training and has maintained his or her annual in-service training prior to the police officer's election to the office of jailer; and </section><section prefix="c">During his or her term of office as jailer, the person has successfully completed forty (40) hours of annual in-service training approved or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section></section><section prefix="2">During his or her term of office, the jailer shall not be eligible to participate in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the jailer's return to a law enforcement agency that is eligible to participate in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund, he or she may participate in the fund, if otherwise eligible, without repeating basic training in its entirety. The jailer may be required to complete no more than eighty (80) hours of training as determined by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council to participate in the fund. </section><section prefix="4">In-service training required of the jailer under this section shall be provided by the Department of Criminal Justice Training without the cost of tuition to the jailer. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of this section shall apply to any person serving as elected jailer on or after June 21, 2001, regardless of when the initial basic training was completed. </section><section prefix="6">An elected jailer who is in office as of June 21, 2001, and who has successfully completed annual Department of Corrections in-service training during his or her term of office shall be deemed to have met the in-service training requirement of subsection (1) of this section. After June 21, 2001, an elected jailer shall meet the requirements of subsection (1) of this section to retain Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund eligibility. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=966</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>