<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.031</section_number><catch_line>Employment of personnel -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall employ the personnel and operate and maintain data collection and processing systems necessary to comply with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall annually on July 1 of each year report to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Kentucky State Corrections Commission on: <section prefix="a">The placement of prisoners within the Commonwealth's correctional system by institution, whether imprisoned in a state prison or other institution, including county jails, on probation, paroled, housed in halfway houses, sentenced to community service or otherwise; </section><section prefix="b">Numbers of prisoners by type of offense; </section><section prefix="c">Numbers of prisoners by number and type of prior convictions; </section><section prefix="d">Numbers of prisoners paroled by type of offense and by length of time served; </section><section prefix="e">Numbers of prisoners released through shock probation by type of offense and by length of time served; </section><section prefix="f">Numbers of prisoners serving their full sentence by type of offense; </section><section prefix="g">The percentage of felony offenders on parole or some form of post-release supervision who are participating or completing treatment consistent with assessment results, in prison and in the community; </section><section prefix="h">The percentage of felony offenders whose reassessment results demonstrate reductions in criminal risk factors; </section><section prefix="i">The percentage of programs that demonstrate their effectiveness in reducing recidivism; </section><section prefix="j">The percentage of felony offenders on parole or some form of post-release supervision, by supervision type, who: <section prefix="1">Are employed or in school within thirty (30) days, six (6) months, and one (1) year of the start of supervision; </section><section prefix="2">Have had part-time employment for a minimum of six (6) months, and the percentage of offenders who have had full-time employment for a minimum of six (6) months; </section><section prefix="3">Have housing upon release from incarceration; </section><section prefix="4">Had stable housing for at least six (6) months; and </section><section prefix="5">Are arrested, convicted, or incarcerated within six (6) months, one (1) year, and three (3) years; </section></section><section prefix="k">The percentage of admissions to prison by offenders under supervision at the time of admission, including information regarding whether the violations were criminal or technical; and </section><section prefix="l">Any other data that provides information on state-funded crime reduction and recidivism reduction efforts, including caseload sizes by risk level, participation in treatment and intervention programming, public safety outcomes, and cost effectiveness. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall annually report to the Governor and to the Legislative Research Commission on: <section prefix="a">Numbers and types of prison beds necessary to meet current population needs and six (6) year projections of those needs; </section><section prefix="b">Current personnel needs of the cabinet and five (5) year projections of the needs; and </section><section prefix="c">A six (6) year projection of needed capital construction, program development, and anticipated requests for appropriations. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.65, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>