<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.674</section_number><catch_line>Licensure as an acupuncturist -- Approval and denial of applications -- Renewal -- Reciprocity.   </catch_line><order_by>674</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be licensed by the board as an acupuncturist, an applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Submit an application approved by the board, with all sections completed, with the required fee; </section><section prefix="b">Be of good character and reputation; </section><section prefix="c">Have achieved a passing score on the acupuncture examination administered by the National Commission for Certification of Acupuncture and Oriental Medicine; and </section><section prefix="d">Have graduated from a course of training of at least one thousand eight hundred (1,800) hours, including three hundred (300) clinical hours, that is approved by the Accreditation Commission for Acupuncture and Oriental Medicine. </section></section> All provisions of this subsection, including graduation from an approved course of training as specified in paragraph (d) of this subsection, must be met by all applicants before initial licensure as an acupuncturist may be granted. <section prefix="2">An acupuncturist who is legally authorized to practice acupuncture in another state and who is presently in good standing in that other state may be licensed by endorsement from the state of his or her credentialing if that state has standards substantially equivalent to those of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">The board may request any reasonable information from the applicant and from collateral sources that is necessary for the board to make an informed decision. The applicant will execute any necessary waiver or release so that the board may obtain necessary information from collateral sources. An application will be considered completed when the applicant has fully answered all sections of the approved application and the board has received all necessary additional information from the applicant and collateral sources. </section><section prefix="4">An acupuncturist's license shall be renewed every two (2) years upon fulfillment of the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The applicant has submitted a renewal application approved by the board within the time specified, with all sections completed, with the required fee; and </section><section prefix="b">The applicant is of good character and reputation. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall notify each applicant in writing of the action it takes on an application within one hundred twenty (120) days following the board's receipt of a completed application. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any of the requirements for licensure established in this section, and after providing the applicant with reasonable notice of its intended action and after providing a reasonable opportunity to be heard, the board may deny licensure to an applicant without a prior evidentiary hearing upon a finding that the applicant has violated any provision of this section or is otherwise unfit to practice. If the board denies an application, it shall notify the applicant of the grounds on which the denial is based. Orders denying a license may be appealed pursuant to KRS 311.593. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  For the sake of clarity and under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c), the Reviser of Statutes has further divided subsection (1) of 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 4. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>