<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.183Tax</section_number><catch_line>interest rate.   </catch_line><order_by>183Tax</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">All taxes payable to the Commonwealth not paid at the time prescribed by statute shall accrue interest at the tax interest rate. </section><section prefix="b">The tax interest rate shall be equal to the adjusted prime rate charged by banks rounded to the nearest full percent as adjusted by subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of revenue shall adjust the tax interest rate not later than November 15 of each year if the adjusted prime rate charged by banks during September of that year, rounded to the nearest full percent, is at least one (1) percentage point more or less than the tax interest rate which is then in effect. The adjusted tax interest rate shall become effective on January 1 of the immediately succeeding year. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">All taxes payable to the Commonwealth that have not been paid at the time prescribed by statute shall accrue interest at the tax interest rate as determined in accordance with subsection (1) of this section until May 1, 2008. </section><section prefix="2">Beginning on May 1, 2008, all taxes payable to the Commonwealth that have not been paid at the time prescribed by statute shall accrue interest at the tax interest rate as determined in accordance with subsection (1) of this section plus two percent (2%). </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Interest shall be allowed and paid upon any overpayment as defined in KRS 134.580 in respect of any of the taxes provided for in Chapters 131, 132, 134, 136, 137, 138, 139, 140, 141, 142, 143, 143A, and 243 of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and KRS 160.613 and 160.614 at the rate provided in subsection (1) of this section until May 1, 2008. </section><section prefix="2">Beginning on May 1, 2008, interest shall be allowed and paid upon any overpayment as defined in KRS 134.580 at the rate provided in subsection (1) of this section minus two percent (2%). </section><section prefix="3">Effective for refunds issued after April 24, 2008, except for the provisions of KRS 138.351, 141.044(2), 141.235(3), and subsection (3) of this section, interest authorized under this subsection shall begin to accrue sixty (60) days after the latest of: <section prefix="a">The due date of the return; </section><section prefix="b">The date the return was filed; </section><section prefix="c">The date the tax was paid; </section><section prefix="d">The last day prescribed by law for filing the return; or </section><section prefix="e">The date an amended return claiming a refund is filed. </section></section></section><section prefix="c">In no case shall interest be paid in an amount less than five dollars ($5). </section></section><section prefix="3">Effective for refund claims filed on or after July 15, 1992, if any overpayment of the tax imposed under KRS Chapter 141 results from a carryback of a net operating loss or a net capital loss, the overpayment shall be deemed to have been made on the date the claim for refund was filed. Interest authorized under subsection (2) of this section shall begin to accrue ninety (90) days from the date the claim for refund was filed. </section><section prefix="4">No interest shall be allowed or paid on any sales tax refund as provided by KRS 139.536. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 7, effective March 24, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 8, effective April 24, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1, effective March 6, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 124, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 5, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 264, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/24/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 15, provides that "the provisions of Sections 7 to 10 of this Act shall apply retroactively to all outstanding refund claims for taxable years ending prior to the effective date of this Act and shall apply to all claims for those taxable years pending in any judicial or administrative forum." (3/24/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 17, provides that "The intent of the General Assembly in repealing and reenacting KRS 136.392, 138.195, 141.160, 160.6156, 160.6157, 160.6158, 131.183, 141.044, 141.235, 134.580, 393.060, and 157.621 in Sections 1 to 12 of this Act is to affirm the amendments made to these sections in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 132. The provisions in Sections 1 to 12 of this Act shall apply retroactively to April 24, 2008." (3/24/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 18, provides "To the extent that any provision included in this Act is considered new language, the provisions of KRS 446.145 requiring such new language to be underlined are notwithstood." (4/24/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 15 provides that the amendments made to this statute by that Act "shall apply retroactively to all outstanding refund claims for taxable years ending prior to the effective date of this Act (April 24, 2008) and shall apply to all claims for those taxable years pending in any judicial or administrative forum."  (3/6/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 26, provides that this section applies retroactively to January 1, 2006. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44484</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>