<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.8994</section_number><catch_line>Uniform administration of child-care funds -- Dedicated child-care licensing surveyors. </catch_line><order_by>8994</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All child-day-care funds administered by the cabinet, including Title XX of the Social Security Act, shall be administered by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to the extent allowable under federal law or regulation and in a manner which is in the best interest of the clients to be served. To the extent permitted by federal law or regulations, requirements relating to application, eligibility, provider agreements, and payment for child-care services shall be the same regardless of the source of public funding. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall, to the extent allowable under federal law or regulation and in a manner which is in the best interest of the clients to be served, develop a system which provides a single intake point in each county through which parents seeking public subsidies for child-care services can make application. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall, subject to the extent funds are available, cooperate with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to fund and establish dedicated child-care licensing surveyor positions within the Division of Licensed Child Care to conduct all the cabinet's child-care licensing activities. The cabinet shall have the authority to request the transfer of funds to establish these positions. Where possible, dedicated child-care surveyors shall have expertise or experience in child-care or early childhood education. </section><section prefix="4">The targeted ratio of dedicated child-care licensing surveyor positions shall be one (1) surveyor for each fifty (50) child-care facilities in order to allow for the provision of an expedient, constructive, and thorough licensing visit. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall, in cooperation with the Division of Licensed Child Care, Cabinet for Health and Family Services, provide appropriate specialized training for child-care surveyors. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">The cabinet shall evaluate ways to improve the monitoring of unregulated child-care providers that receive a public subsidy for child care, and promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A that establish minimum health and safety standards, limitations on the maximum number of children in care, training requirements for a child-care provider that receives a child-care subsidy administered by the cabinet, and criteria for the denial of subsidies if criminal records indicate convictions that impact the safety and security of children in care. </section><section prefix="b">If the cabinet has probable cause to believe that there is an immediate threat to the public health, safety, or welfare, it may take emergency action to deny a public subsidy for child-care services under KRS 13B.125. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 198, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 22, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 162, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7248</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>