<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.620</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet for Health and Family Services, in consultation with professional associations, to develop instructional material on HIV -- Comprehensive information to be presented to any person receiving treatment.   </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall develop instructional material on the human immunodeficiency virus, including information related to methods of transmission, education, and infection control. To expeditiously and economically develop, produce, and distribute the instructional material required under this section, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall consult with the professional associations of professions to determine whether suitable instructional materials already exist that may be lawfully reproduced or reprinted. </section><section prefix="2">Information on the human immunodeficiency virus infection shall be presented to any person who receives treatment at any hospital, however named, skilled-nursing facilities, primary-care centers, rural health clinics, outpatient clinics, ambulatory-care facilities, ambulatory surgical centers, and emergency-care centers licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 216B. The information shall include but not be limited to methods of transmission and prevention and appropriate behavior and attitude change. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 466, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 49, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 413, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 30, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44607</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>