<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">MOTOR VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190.053</section_number><catch_line>Citation of suspected violators. </catch_line><order_by>053</order_by><text>If a licensee is found to be violating any of the provisions of this chapter, or any administrative regulation promulgated by the commission pursuant thereto, or is found to be permitting any of its salesmen to violate any of the provisions of this chapter, or any administrative regulation promulgated by the commission pursuant thereto, the commission may, upon complaint or upon its own motion, issue its order to a licensee notifying it to appear before the commission at a fixed time and place, at which time and place the commission shall have a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. If the commission is satisfied, after a hearing, that the licensee has violated or refused to observe any of the provisions of this chapter, or any order or administrative regulation of the commission, or has permitted any of its salesmen to violate any of the provisions of this chapter or any order or administrative regulation promulgated by the commission pursuant thereto, the commission may suspend or revoke the license of the licensee. The renewal by the commission of any license shall not be construed to be a waiver or condonement of any violation which occurred prior to renewal and shall not prevent subsequent proceedings against the licensee for the violation. </text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 78, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>