<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.245</section_number><catch_line>Pre-session filing of bills. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Members of the General Assembly and members-elect of the General Assembly who have received their certificates of election are hereby authorized, during such time as the General Assembly is not in session, to pre-file bills and resolutions for introduction in the next succeeding regular legislative session with the director of the Legislative Research Commission. Bills and resolutions which are pre-filed under the provisions of this section shall be in such final and correct form for introduction in the General Assembly as required by the constitution, laws and rules of the respective houses of the Legislature. The original copy of every bill and resolution pre-filed shall include thereon, immediately below the typed or printed name of the sponsor thereof, the full signature of said sponsor. </section><section prefix="2">The director of the Legislative Research Commission is authorized and directed to receive pre-filed bills and resolutions, to assign numbers for introduction in the proper house in order of receipt, and, subject to the provisions of subsection (3) of this section, to deliver the original and four (4) copies of each bill and resolution to the secretary of the Senate or the chief clerk of the House, as the case may be, on the first day of the regular session. Pre-filed bills and resolutions shall be considered as introduced on the day of their delivery to each house. No measure that is filed and printed pursuant to this section shall be distributed to members, members-elect, or the public unless the person filing the measure specifically authorizes in writing such distribution. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (2) of this section, in the event all the persons sponsoring a pre-filed bill or resolution shall have ceased to be members of the General Assembly at the time of the convening of the next succeeding regular legislative session, the pre-filing of that bill or resolution shall be considered to be without effect, and the director of the Legislative Research Commission shall not deliver the original or copies to the secretary of the Senate or the chief clerk of the House. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984. </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>