<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.0704</section_number><catch_line>License tax credit for economic revitalization projects -- Computation -- Cap. </catch_line><order_by>0704</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Approved company" means a company approved under KRS 154.26-010 and subject to license tax under KRS 136.070; </section><section prefix="b">"Economic revitalization project" shall have the same meaning as set forth in KRS 154.26-010; and </section><section prefix="c">"Tax credit" means the tax credit allowed in KRS 154.26-090(1)(c)2. </section></section><section prefix="2">An approved company that entered into a revitalization agreement prior to July 13, 2004, shall: <section prefix="a">Compute the company's total license tax due as provided by KRS 136.070; and </section><section prefix="b">Compute the license tax due excluding the capital attributable to an economic revitalization project. </section></section><section prefix="3">The tax credit shall be the amount by which the tax computed under subsection (2)(a) of this section exceeds the tax computed under subsection (2)(b) of this section; however, the credit shall not exceed the limits set forth in KRS 154.26-090. </section><section prefix="4">The capital attributable to an economic revitalization project shall be determined by a formula approved by the Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="5">For an approved company that enters into a revitalization agreement after July 13, 2004, the tax credit shall be negotiated pursuant to KRS 154.26-090, but shall not exceed one hundred percent (100%) of the computed license tax attributable to the location of the economic revitalization project. In no case shall the tax credit exceed the limits set forth in KRS 154.26-090. </section><section prefix="6">The license tax attributable to a revitalization project shall be determined by a formula approved by the Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Revenue may promulgate administrative regulations and require the filing of forms designed by the Department of Revenue to reflect the intent of KRS 154.26-010 to 154.26-100 and the allowable income tax credit which an approved company may retain under KRS 154.26-010 to 154.26-100. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 296, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004; and ch. 105, sec. 14, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 547, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28498</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>