<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.165</section_number><catch_line>Recruitment of minority teachers. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Department of Education in cooperation with the Education Professional Standards Board, the Kentucky Board of Education, local school districts, universities, and colleges, and the Council on Postsecondary Education shall review and revise as needed the strategic plan for increasing the number of minority teachers and administrators in the Commonwealth. The plan shall include, but not be limited to, recommendations on ways to: <section prefix="a">Identify methods for increasing the percentage of minority educators in proportion to the number of minority students; </section><section prefix="b">Establish programs to identify, recruit, and prepare as teachers minority persons who have already earned college degrees in other job fields; </section><section prefix="c">Create awareness among secondary school guidance counselors of the need for minority teachers. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Department of Education and the Education Professional Standards Board shall promote programs that increase the percentage of minorities who enter and successfully complete a four (4) year teacher preparation program and provide support to minority students in meeting qualifying requirements for students entering a teacher preparation program at institutions of higher education. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Department of Education with input from the Education Professional Standards Board shall periodically submit a report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education that evaluates the results of these efforts and includes accompanying recommendations to establish a continuing program for increasing the number of minorities in teacher education. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 14, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 67, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 432, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3883</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>