<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="231" order_by="231">PLACES OF ENTERTAINMENT </unit></structure><section_number>231.110</section_number><catch_line>Conduct prohibited on premises. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>No person who has been granted a permit shall allow:  <section prefix="1">Drunken, disorderly, or boisterous persons, or persons of lewd or lascivious reputation to congregate in or about the premises;  </section><section prefix="2">People to congregate there for immoral or unlawful purposes or to permit any man or woman who are not married to each other to occupy any cabin, cottage, or secreted room or place from which the view of the public is excluded;  </section><section prefix="3">The premises to be used as a place of assemblage or entertainment at later hours than those which are stated in the permit or recorded on the order book of the county judge/executive;  </section><section prefix="4">Engaging in fortune-telling at any location except that specifically stated in his permit;  </section><section prefix="5">Engaging in fortune-telling without first posting in a conspicuous place, both inside and outside the premises at which he is authorized to engage in fortune-telling, and without first filing with the county clerk of the county in which the premises are located, a schedule showing in detail the fees charged for readings, predictions, and services of any nature. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 368, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec.  2, effective June 17, 1954. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599f-9. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10948</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>