<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.305</section_number><catch_line>Installment payments of estimated tax. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The estimated tax provided for in KRS 141.300 shall be paid as follows: <section prefix="a">If the declaration is filed on or before April 15 of the taxable year, the estimated tax shall be paid in four (4) equal installments. The first installment shall be paid at the time of the filing of the declaration, the second and third on June 15 and September 15, respectively, of the taxable year, and the fourth on January 15 of the succeeding taxable year; </section><section prefix="b">If the declaration is filed after April 15 and not after June 15 of the taxable year and is not required by subsection (3) of KRS 141.300 to be filed on or before April 15 of the taxable year, the estimated tax shall be paid in three (3) equal installments. The first installment shall be paid at the time of the filing of the declaration, the second on September 15 of the taxable year, and the third on January 15 of the succeeding taxable year; </section><section prefix="c">If the declaration is filed after June 15 and not after September 15 of the taxable year and is not required by subsection (3) of KRS 141.300 to be filed on or before June 15 of the taxable year, the estimated tax shall be paid in two </section></section><section prefix="2">equal installments. The first installment shall be paid at the time of the </section>filing of the declaration and the second on January 15 of the succeeding taxable year; (d) If the declaration is filed after September 15 of the taxable year, and is not required by subsection (3) of KRS 141.300 to be filed on or before September 15 of the taxable year, the declaration shall be filed and estimated tax shall be paid on or before January 15 of the succeeding taxable year; (e) If the declaration is filed after the time prescribed in KRS 141.300, including cases where extensions of time have been granted, paragraphs (b), (c), and (d) of this subsection shall not apply, and there shall be paid at the time of such filing all installments of estimated tax which would have been payable on or before such time if the declaration has been filed within the time prescribed in subsection (3) of KRS 141.300, and the remaining installments shall be paid at the times at which, and in the amounts in which, they would have been payable if the declaration had been so filed. Provided, that payments required under this section for purposes of the taxable year 1954 shall be limited to fifty percent (50%) of the total estimated tax for 1954. (2) If any amendment of a declaration is filed, the remaining installments, if any, shall be ratably increased or decreased as the case may be, to reflect the respective increase or decrease in the estimated tax by reason of such amendment, and if any amendment is made after September 15 of the taxable year any increase in the estimated tax by reasons thereof shall be paid at the time of making such amendment. <section prefix="3">At the election of the individual, any installment of the estimated tax may be paid prior to the date prescribed for its payment. </section><section prefix="4">Payment of the estimated tax, or any installment thereof, shall be considered payment on account of the tax for the taxable year. Assessment in respect of the estimated tax shall be limited to the amount paid. </section><section prefix="5">In the case of an individual whose estimated gross income from farming for the taxable year is at least two-thirds (2/3) of the total estimated gross income from all sources for the taxable year, in lieu of the time prescribed in subsection (3) of KRS 141.300, the declaration for the taxable year may be made at any time on or before January 15 of the succeeding taxable year; and if such an individual files a return on or before March 1 of the succeeding taxable year, and pays in full the amount computed on the return as payable, such return shall have the same effect as that prescribed in subsection (5) of KRS 141.300 in the case of a return filed on or before January 31. </section><section prefix="6">The application of this section and KRS 141.300 to taxable years of less than twelve (12) months shall be as prescribed in administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="7">In the application of this section and KRS 141.300 to taxpayers reporting income on a fiscal year basis, there shall be substituted for the date specified therein, the months corresponding thereto. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 494, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 18, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 15. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Pt. II, sec. 5. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 21, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The amendment to this section made by House Bill 255, 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 29, was made effective for taxable years beginning on or after July 1, 1990. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29105</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>