<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.270</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet secretaries -- Authority, powers, and duties. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of each cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Be a member of the Governor's Cabinet and shall serve as the Governor's liaison in carrying out the responsibilities for overall direction and coordination of the departments, boards, and commissions included in the related cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Recommend to the Governor desired reorganization affecting the related cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the Governor on executive actions, legislative matters, and other steps that may be desirable for better program service; </section><section prefix="d">Evaluate and pass upon all budget requests originated by the departments, boards, and commissions within the related cabinet; </section><section prefix="e">Advise the Governor on the appointment of commissioners and heads of units included in the related cabinet, except for those whose election or selection is otherwise provided for by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each secretary is authorized to accept and expend funds from any source, whether public or private, in support of the duties and responsibilities of the related cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Each secretary shall have any and all necessary power and authority, subject to appropriate provisions of the statutes, to create such positions and to employ the necessary personnel in such positions to enable the secretary to perform the functions of his office. </section><section prefix="4">Each secretary shall have exclusive control and direction over the administration of the related cabinet programs as required by law. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VII, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=665</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>