<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.180</section_number><catch_line>Distribution by practitioner or pharmacist -- Prescription requirements -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except when dispensed directly by a practitioner to an ultimate user, no methamphetamine or controlled substance in Schedule II may be dispensed without the written, facsimile, or electronic prescription of a practitioner. A prescription for a controlled substance in Schedule II may be dispensed by a facsimile prescription only as specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the cabinet. No prescription for a controlled substance in Schedule II shall be valid after sixty (60) days from the date issued. No prescription for a controlled substance in Schedule II shall be refilled. All prescriptions for controlled substances classified in Schedule II shall be maintained in a separate prescription file. </section><section prefix="2">Except when dispensed directly by a practitioner to an ultimate user, a controlled substance included in Schedules III, IV, and V, which is a prescription drug, shall not be dispensed without a written, facsimile, electronic, or oral prescription by a practitioner. The prescription shall not be filled or refilled more than six (6) months after the date issued or be refilled more than five (5) times, unless renewed by the practitioner and a new prescription, written, electronic, or oral shall be required. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">To be valid, a prescription for a controlled substance shall be issued only for a legitimate medical purpose by a practitioner acting in the usual course of his professional practice. Responsibility for the proper dispensing of a controlled substance pursuant to a prescription for a legitimate medical purpose is upon the pharmacist who fills the prescription. </section><section prefix="b">A prescription shall not be issued for a practitioner to obtain a controlled substance for the purpose of general dispensing or administering to patients. </section></section><section prefix="4">All written and facsimile prescriptions for controlled substances shall be dated and signed by the practitioner on the date issued and shall bear the full name and address of the patient, drug name, strength, dosage form, quantity prescribed, directions for use, and the name, address and registration number of the practitioner. </section><section prefix="5">All oral, facsimile, or electronic prescriptions shall include the full name and address of the patient, drug name, strength, dosage form, quantity prescribed, directions for use, and the name, address and registration number of the practitioner. </section><section prefix="6">All oral prescriptions shall be immediately reduced to writing, dated, and signed by the pharmacist. </section><section prefix="7">A pharmacist refilling any prescription shall record on the prescription or other equivalent record the date, the quantity, and the pharmacist's initials. The maintenance of prescription records under the federal controlled substances laws and regulations containing substantially the same information as specified in this subsection shall constitute compliance with this subsection. </section><section prefix="8">The pharmacist filling a written, facsimile, electronic, or oral prescription for a controlled substance shall affix to the package a label showing the date of filling, the pharmacy name and address, the serial number of the prescription, the name of the patient, the name of the prescribing practitioner and directions for use and cautionary statements, if any, contained in such prescription or required by law. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates any provision of this section shall: <section prefix="a">For the first offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="b">For a second or subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 606, sec. 68, effective July 15, 1998 -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39762</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>