<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.072</section_number><catch_line>Career and technical education accessibility fund. </catch_line><order_by>072</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Career academy" means a small learning community within a larger high school that: <section prefix="1">Consists of a heterogeneous group of students taking classes together for at least two (2) years and who are taught by a team of teachers from different disciplines; </section><section prefix="2">Provides a college-preparatory academic curriculum based on a career theme that helps students see relationships and connections between academic subjects and their applications in specific career pathways and in broad career areas such as health science, business, pre-engineering, agribusiness, and advanced manufacturing; and </section><section prefix="3">Provides opportunities through partnerships with employers, colleges, and the community for students to engage in internships and work-based learning with adult mentors to motivate students to achieve; </section></section><section prefix="b">"Career guidance coach" means a person who is assigned one hundred percent (100%) of his or her time to: <section prefix="1">The development of students', teachers', and parents' understanding of broad career themes and opportunities through career pathways; </section><section prefix="2">Academic advising and career counseling; </section><section prefix="3">Assisting students in the development of individual learning plans; and </section><section prefix="4">Providing assistance to other teachers; </section></section><section prefix="c">"Career pathway" means a coherent, articulated sequence of rigorous academic and career-related courses, commencing in ninth grade and leading to an associate degree, an industry-recognized certificate or license, or a baccalaureate or higher degree. A career pathway is developed, implemented, and maintained in partnership among secondary and postsecondary education institutions, businesses, and employers. Career pathways are available to all students, including adult learners, and are designed to lead to rewarding careers; and </section><section prefix="d">"Career pathway program of study" means a coherent, articulated sequence of rigorous academic and career and technical education courses, including dual credit opportunities, that prepares secondary students for postsecondary study leading to postsecondary degrees, industry certifications, or licensure. </section></section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created a trust and agency account to be known as the career and technical education accessibility fund, to be administered by the Kentucky Department of Education. The fund shall consist of proceeds from grants, federal funds, contributions, appropriations, or other moneys made available for the purposes of the fund. The fund shall provide grants to be used for: <section prefix="a">The development of career pathways and programs of study in high-demand occupational fields for students in middle schools and high schools; and </section><section prefix="b">The establishment of career academies in secondary schools. Each career academy shall employ general education faculty who teach the academic core content and career and technical education faculty who focus the majority of the content around a broad career area and, when possible, employ career guidance coaches to advise students. Career academies shall provide students an opportunity to earn a high school diploma and simultaneously earn postsecondary education credit. They shall also provide opportunities to earn industry certification in high-demand fields, including biotechnology, environmental sustainability, agriculture, health, engineering, information technology, and other emerging career areas. </section></section><section prefix="3">The grants may be used within a high school facility, career and technical education center, or in an area technology center. </section><section prefix="4">The programs may, based on written policies of the education institution in consultation with and approval of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, serve adult learners who may have interrupted their secondary education and wish to reenter a program or adults who wish to pursue initial study in a career and technical education field. </section><section prefix="5">Funds shall be distributed through a grant program to eligible school districts and the Kentucky Tech System on a matching basis as funds are available. </section><section prefix="6">Financial gifts and in-kind contributions from any business or industry, a community college, or other entity may be accepted to meet the matching requirements based on criteria established by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section><section prefix="7">Pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, the Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations that specify the: <section prefix="a">Eligibility requirements for participation in the grant program. Low graduation rates, as determined in accordance with the methodology established by the National Center for Education Statistics, shall be high priority for participation in the grant program; </section><section prefix="b">Matching requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Application and review process; </section><section prefix="d">Accountability and data requirements for grant recipients; </section><section prefix="e">Procedures for the reallocation of any unused fund balance; </section><section prefix="f">Grant continuation requirements; and </section><section prefix="g">Other components essential to the implementation of this section. </section></section><section prefix="8">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any unused balance in the career and technical education accessibility fund shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the next fiscal year and used only for the purposes described in subsection (2) of this section. Any interest earnings of the fund shall become a part of the fund and shall not lapse. Moneys in the fund are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="9">Schools receiving grants shall have an active local advisory council comprised of industry leaders and employers and postsecondary education faculty to provide input on long-range goals for career and technical education. </section><section prefix="10">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a school that has begun the implementation of a career pathway or a career academy prior to April 19, 2012, from qualifying for funds under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 5, effective April 19, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> April 19, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included the creation of this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>