<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142">MISCELLANEOUS TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>142.406</section_number><catch_line>Tourism, meeting, and convention marketing fund -- Creation and fund sources -- Authorized investments -- Use of funds -- Annual report to Legislative Research Commission and to Governor. </catch_line><order_by>406</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created and established in the State Treasury a trust and agency account to be known as the tourism, meeting, and convention marketing fund. The fund shall be administered by the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, with the approval of the Governor's Office for Policy and Management. </section><section prefix="2">All tax receipts from the tax imposed under KRS 142.400 shall be deposited into the tourism, meeting, and convention marketing fund, and shall be appropriated for the purposes set forth in subsection (3) of this section. The fund shall also contain any other money contributed, allocated, or appropriated to it from any other source. Money in the fund shall be invested by the Finance and Administration Cabinet in instruments authorized under KRS 42.500. Investment proceeds shall be deposited to the credit of the fund. Money in the fund shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year or biennium. </section><section prefix="3">The tourism, meeting, and convention marketing fund shall be used for the sole purpose of marketing and promoting tourism in the Commonwealth including expenditures to market and promote events and venues related to meetings, conventions, trade shows, cultural activities, historical sites, recreation, entertainment, natural phenomena, areas of scenic beauty, craft marketing, and any other economic activity that brings tourists and visitors to the Commonwealth. Marketing and promoting tourism shall not include expenditures on capital construction projects. </section><section prefix="4">By September 1 of each year, the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission concerning the receipts, expenditures, and carryforwards of the fund for the preceding fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 70, effective June 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/1/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29230</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>