<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63">RESIGNATIONS, REMOVALS, AND VACANCIES </unit></structure><section_number>63.040</section_number><catch_line>Prosecution -- Witnesses. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an impeachment is ordered by the House of Representatives a committee shall be appointed to prosecute it, and the committee chairman shall, within five (5) days, lay the impeachment before the Senate. </section><section prefix="2">The Senate shall appoint a day for hearing the impeachment. The accused shall be summoned by precept, issued by the clerk of the Senate, to appear on that day. The precept shall be served in person, or a copy left at his residence with a member of his family over the age of sixteen (16) years, together with a copy of the impeachment. </section><section prefix="3">The clerk of the Senate shall, at the instance of the chairman of the committee, or of the accused, issue process for the summoning of witnesses, and the production of books, papers, documents or tangible things. Process so issued shall be executed by peace officers or officers specially appointed by the Senate for that purpose in the same manner as similar process of courts. Upon disobedience to the process, the Senate may order the clerk to issue process for arresting the witnesses and seizing the books, papers, documents or tangible things. Disobedience may be punished in the manner provided for other witnesses before the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="4">A witness so summoned shall receive the same compensation, and have the same privilege in going, remaining and returning, as a witness in Circuit Court. </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec.12. --  Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2172. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>