<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.480</section_number><catch_line>Employees of department or school districts with decision-making authority prohibited from supplying goods or services for which school funds are expended -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No commissioner, associate commissioner, deputy commissioner, director, manager, purchasing agent, or other employee of the Department of Education with decision-making authority over the financial position of a school, school district, or school system shall have any pecuniary interest in the school, school district, or school system, either directly or indirectly, in an amount exceeding twenty-five dollars ($25) per year, either at the time of or after his appointment to office, in supplying any goods, services, property, merchandise, or services, except personal services that are in addition to those required by contract for employment, of any nature whatsoever for which school funds are expended. If any person specified in this subsection receives, directly or indirectly, any gift, reward, or promise of reward for his influence in recommending or procuring the use of any goods, services, property, or merchandise of any kind whatsoever for which school funds are expended, he shall upon conviction be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), and his office or appointment shall without further action be vacant. </section><section prefix="2">No employee of any county or independent school district with decision-making authority over the financial position of the school district shall have any pecuniary interest, either directly or indirectly, in an amount exceeding twenty-five dollars ($25) per year, either at the time of or after his appointment to office, in supplying any goods, services, property, merchandise, or services, except personal services that are in addition to those required by contract for employment, of any nature whatsoever for which school funds are expended. If any person specified in this subsection receives, directly or indirectly, any gift, reward, or promise of reward for his influence in recommending or procuring the use of any goods, services, property, or merchandise of any kind whatsoever for which school funds are expended, he shall upon conviction be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), and his office or appointment shall without further action be vacant. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 370, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. II, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3200</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>