<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.2-323</section_number><catch_line>Form of bill of lading required in overseas shipment -- "Overseas." </catch_line><order_by>2-323</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Where the contract contemplates overseas shipment and contains a term C.I.F. or C. &amp; F. or F.O.B. vessel, the seller unless otherwise agreed must obtain a negotiable bill of lading stating that the goods have been loaded on board or, in the case of a term C.I.F. or C. &amp; F., received for shipment.  </section><section prefix="2">Where in a case within subsection (1) a bill of lading has been issued in a set of parts, unless otherwise agreed if the documents are not to be sent from abroad the buyer may demand tender of the full set; otherwise only one part of the bill of lading need be tendered. Even if the agreement expressly requires a full set  <section prefix="a">due tender of a single part is acceptable within the provisions of this article on cure of improper delivery (subsection (1) of KRS 355.2-508); and  </section><section prefix="b">even though the full set is demanded, if the documents are sent from abroad the person tendering an incomplete set may nevertheless require payment upon furnishing an indemnity which the buyer in good faith deems adequate.  </section></section><section prefix="3">A shipment by water or by air or a contract contemplating such shipment is "overseas" insofar as by usage of trade or agreement it is subject to the commercial, financing or shipping practices characteristic of international deep water commerce.  </section></text><history>Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2-323, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1960 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33283</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>