<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.030</section_number><catch_line>Considerations in determination to abstain from action on official decision -- Advisory opinion. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>In determining whether to abstain from action on an official decision because of a possible conflict of interest, a public servant should consider the following guidelines: <section prefix="1">Whether a substantial threat to his independence of judgment has been created by his personal or private interest; </section><section prefix="2">The effect of his participation on public confidence in the integrity of the executive branch; </section><section prefix="3">Whether his participation is likely to have any significant effect on the disposition of the matter; </section><section prefix="4">The need for his particular contribution, such as special knowledge of the subject matter, to the effective functioning of the executive branch; or </section><section prefix="5">Whether the official decision will affect him in a manner differently from the public or will affect him as a member of a business, profession, occupation, or group to no greater extent generally than other members of such business, profession, occupation, or group. A public servant may request an advisory opinion from the Executive Branch Ethics Commission in accordance with the commission's rules of procedure. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=593</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>