<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.245</section_number><catch_line>Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation is hereby created within the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation to accomplish the purposes and functions enumerated in 29 U.S.C. sec. 725 (Title I, Part A, Section 105 of the Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1998). Members of the council shall be appointed by the Governor from recommendations submitted by the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation consistent with the federal mandate to include a majority of individuals with disabilities not employed by the office, as well as representatives of specified organizations, service providers, and advocacy groups. The compensation, qualifications, and terms of service of the council shall conform to the federal law. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, any vacancy occurring in the membership of the Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. The vacancy shall not affect the power of the remaining members of the council. </section><section prefix="b">The Governor may delegate the authority to fill a vacancy to the remaining voting members of the council. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each member of the Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation may receive a per diem of one hundred dollars ($100), not to exceed six hundred dollars ($600) annually, for each regular or special meeting attended if the member is not employed or must forfeit wages from other employment. Each member may have travel expenses approved at the established state rate and expenses reimbursed at the established state agency rate for services such as personal assistance, child care, and drivers for attendance at council meetings, and in the performance of duties authorized by the Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation. The per diem and expenses shall be paid out of the federal funds appropriated under Title I, Part A, of the Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1998, Pub. L. 105-220. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 51, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2228</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>