<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="402" order_by="402">MARRIAGE </unit></structure><section_number>402.030</section_number><catch_line>Courts may declare certain marriages void. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Courts having general jurisdiction may declare void any marriage obtained by force or fraud. </section><section prefix="2">At the instance of any next friend, courts having general jurisdiction may declare any marriage void where the person was under eighteen (18) but over sixteen (16) years of age at the time of the marriage, and the marriage was without the consent required by KRS 402.020(1)(f) and has not been ratified by cohabitation after that age. </section><section prefix="3">At the instance of any next friend, courts having general jurisdiction may declare void any marriage where: <section prefix="a">The person was under sixteen (16) years of age at the time of the marriage; </section><section prefix="b">The marriage was not conducted with the permission of a District Judge, as required by KRS 402.020(1)(f)3., in the form of a written court order; and </section><section prefix="c">The marriage has not been ratified by cohabitation after the person reached eighteen (18) years of age. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective March 26, 1998 and ch. 258, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 400, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2100. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 122 and 258 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36467</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>