<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">A HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>164A.325</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers of board as to savings plan trust. </catch_line><order_by>325</order_by><text>In addition to effectuating and carrying out all of the powers granted by KRS 164A.300 to 164A.380, the board, as trustee, shall have all powers necessary to carry out and effectuate the purposes, objectives, and provisions of KRS 164A.300 to 164A.380 pertaining to the savings plan trust, including, but not limited to, the power to: <section prefix="1">Engage investment advisors to assist in the investment of savings plan trust assets; </section><section prefix="2">Carry out studies and projections in order to advise participants regarding present and estimated future higher education costs and levels of financial participation in the trust required in order to enable participants to achieve their educational funding objectives; </section><section prefix="3">Contract, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 45A.345 to 45A.460 under KRS 45A.343, for goods and services and engage personnel as necessary, including consultants, actuaries, managers, counsel, and auditors for the purpose of rendering professional, managerial, and technical assistance and advice, all of which contract obligations and services shall be payable from any moneys of the trust; </section><section prefix="4">Participate in any other way in any federal, state, or local governmental program for the benefit of the savings plan trust; </section><section prefix="5">Promulgate, impose, and collect administrative fees and charges in connection with transactions of the savings plan trust, and provide for reasonable service charges, including penalties for cancellations and late payments in respect of participation agreements; </section><section prefix="6">Procure insurance against any loss in connection with the property, assets or activities of the savings plan trust; </section><section prefix="7">Administer the funds of the savings plan trust; </section><section prefix="8">Procure insurance indemnifying any member of the board from personal loss or accountability arising from liability resulting from a member's action or inaction as a member of the board; and </section><section prefix="9">Promulgate reasonable rules and regulations for the administration of the savings plan trust. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4561</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>