<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.978</section_number><catch_line>Energy recovery road fund -- Uses -- Transfer of funds from coal recovery road fund. </catch_line><order_by>978</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All revenues generated from the purchase of decals pursuant to KRS 177.990(5) and KRS 177.9771(4) and no other taxes or fees normally assessed on motor carriers shall be credited to a special account within the road fund called the "energy recovery road fund" and any additional funds obtained through state appropriation, gifts, grants and federal funds may be credited to the special account, and shall be used, in addition to those road funds normally used for said highways, exclusively by the Transportation Cabinet for those costs attendant to highway purposes for roads designated as part of the extended weight coal haul road system. All funds in the account shall be carried forward at the end of each year. </section><section prefix="2">All funds credited to the "coal recovery road fund" shall be transferred to the "energy recovery road fund." </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 14, effective August 1, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 498, sec. 2, effective April 1, 1987. --Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by 1986 Acts, ch. 331, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1986, and ch. 498, sec. 2, effective April 1, 1987, part of which are in conflict and cannot be codified together. Pursuant to KRS 7.136(3), ch. 498, sec. 2, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5410</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>