<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-080</section_number><catch_line>Health Insurance Advisory Council -- Powers -- Duties -- Members -- Expenses and supplies. </catch_line><order_by>17A-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created and established a Health Insurance Advisory Council whose duties shall be to review and discuss with the commissioner any issues which impact the provision of health insurance in the state. The advisory council shall consist of nine (9) members: the commissioner plus eight (8) persons appointed by the Governor with the advice of the commissioner to serve two (2) year terms. The commissioner shall serve as chair of the advisory council. </section><section prefix="2">The eight (8) persons appointed by the Governor with the advice of the commissioner shall be: <section prefix="a">Two (2) representatives of insurers currently offering health benefit plans in the state; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) practicing health care providers; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) representatives of purchasers of health benefit plans; and </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) representatives of agents. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall: <section prefix="a">Review and discuss the design of the standard health benefit plan; </section><section prefix="b">Review and discuss the rate-filing process for all health benefit plans; </section><section prefix="c">Review and discuss the administrative regulations concerning this subtitle to be promulgated by the department; </section><section prefix="d">Make recommendations on high-cost conditions as provided in KRS 304.17B-033; </section><section prefix="e">Advise the Department of Insurance concerning the Department of Insurance's separation plan for the division of duties and responsibilities between the operation of the Department of Insurance and the operation of Kentucky Access; </section><section prefix="f">Review and discuss issues that impact Kentucky Access; and </section><section prefix="g">Review and discuss other issues at the request of the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="4">The advisory council shall be a budgetary unit of the department which shall pay all of the advisory council's necessary operating expenses and shall furnish all office space, personnel, equipment, supplies, and technical or administrative services required by the advisory council in the performance of the functions established in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1211, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 521, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 49, effective April 10, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17355</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>