<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-951</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963. </catch_line><order_by>2-951</order_by><text>As used in KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Constituent limited partnership" means a constituent organization that is a limited partnership; </section><section prefix="2">"Constituent organization" means an organization that is party to a merger; </section><section prefix="3">"Converted limited partnership" means the limited partnership into which a converting organization converts pursuant to KRS 362.2-952, 362.2-953, 362.2-954, and 362.2-955; </section><section prefix="4">"Converted organization" means an organization into which another organization has been converted; </section><section prefix="5">"Converting limited partnership" means a converting organization that is a limited partnership; </section><section prefix="6">"Converting organization" means an organization that converts into another organization pursuant to KRS 362.2-952; </section><section prefix="7">"General partner" means a general partner of a limited partnership; </section><section prefix="8">"Governing statute" of an organization means the statute that governs the organization's internal affairs; </section><section prefix="9">"Organization" means a general partnership, including a limited liability partnership; limited partnership, including a limited liability limited partnership; limited liability company; business trust; corporation; or any other entity having a governing statute. The term includes domestic and foreign entities regardless of whether organized for profit; </section><section prefix="10">"Organizational documents" means: <section prefix="a">For a domestic or foreign general partnership, its partnership agreement; </section><section prefix="b">For a limited partnership or foreign limited partnership, its certificate of limited partnership and partnership agreement; and </section><section prefix="c">For a domestic or foreign limited liability company, its articles of organization and operating agreement, or comparable records as provided in its governing statute; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Person dissociated as a general partner" means a person dissociated as a general partner of a limited partnership; </section><section prefix="12">"Personal liability" means personal liability for a debt, liability, or other obligation of an organization which is imposed on a person that co-owns, has an interest in, or is a member of the organization: <section prefix="a">By the organization's governing statute solely by reason of the person co-owning, having an interest in, or being a member of the organization; or </section><section prefix="b">By the organization's organizational documents under a provision of the organization's governing statute authorizing those documents to make one (1) or more specified persons liable for all or specified debts, liabilities, and obligations of the organization solely by reason of the person or persons co-owning, having an interest in, or being a member of the organization; and </section></section><section prefix="13">"Surviving organization" means an organization into which one (1) or more other organizations are merged. A surviving organization may preexist the merger or be created by the merger. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 19, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 176, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><former-codification>KRS 362.2-1101. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>