<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.060</section_number><catch_line>Executive Branch Ethics Commission -- Membership -- Officers -- Compensation -- Removal -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Executive Branch Ethics Commission is hereby established. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the commission shall serve staggered terms of four (4) years. Of the initial members appointed as provided in this section, one (1) member shall serve a term of one (1) year, one (1) member shall serve a term of two (2) years, one (1) member shall serve a term of three (3) years, and two (2) members shall be appointed for terms of four (4) years. Thereafter, all appointments shall be for four </section><section prefix="4">years. </section>(4) The commission shall elect from its membership a chairman and vice chairman. In the absence of the chairman or in the event of a vacancy in that position, the vice chairman shall serve as chairman. <section prefix="5">A member of the commission shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for attending meetings and shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of duties. </section><section prefix="6">All members shall be registered voters of the state. </section><section prefix="7">Members of the commission shall be removed by the Governor for cause only, including substantial neglect of duty and inability to discharge the powers and duties of office. </section><section prefix="8">A quorum shall consist of three (3) or more members. An affirmative vote of three (3) or more members shall be necessary for commission action. </section><section prefix="9">The commission shall meet at the call of the chairman or a majority of its members. </section><section prefix="10">The commission shall be attached to the Finance and Administration Cabinet for administrative purposes only. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 17, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 602, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=598</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>