<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.500</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Spinal Cord and Head Injury Research Board. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Spinal Cord and Head Injury Research Board is hereby created for the purpose of administering the spinal cord and head injury research trust fund created pursuant to KRS 211.504. The board shall be composed of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members representing the University of Kentucky College of Medicine; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members representing the University of Louisville School of Medicine; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member who has a spinal cord or head injury or who has a family member with a spinal cord or head injury; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Medical Association; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) at-large member. </section></section><section prefix="2">Board members shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of duties incident to the provisions of KRS 211.500 to 211.504. </section><section prefix="3">The terms of board members shall be four (4) years, except that of the members appointed after July 15, 1998, two (2) members appointed to fill the terms ending on June 30, 1999, shall serve until January 31, 2000; two (2) members appointed to fill the terms expiring on June 30, 2000, shall serve until January 31, 2001; two (2) members appointed to fill the terms expiring on June 30, 2001, shall serve until January 31, 2002; and one (1) member appointed to fill the term expiring June 30, 2002, shall serve until January 31, 2003; and subsequent appointments shall be for four (4) year terms ending on January 31. </section><section prefix="4">At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member who is appointed after a term has begun shall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. </section><section prefix="5">A majority of the full authorized membership of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall elect, by a majority vote, a chairman who shall be the presiding officer of the board, preside at all meetings, and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The chairman shall be elected or reelected for each calendar year. The board shall have such other organization as deemed necessary and approved by the board. </section><section prefix="7">Meetings of the board shall be held at least twice a year but may be held more frequently as deemed necessary, subject to call by the chairman or by request of a majority of the board members. Board meetings shall concern, among other things, policy matters relating to spinal cord and head injury research projects and programs, research progress reports, authorization of projects and financial plans, and other matters necessary to carry out the intent of KRS 211.500 to 211.504. </section><section prefix="8">No member of the board shall be subject to any personal liability or accountability for any loss sustained or damage suffered on account of any action or inaction of the board. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall be attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 361, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 21, effective August 1, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 305, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8425</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>