<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.147</section_number><catch_line>Education Management Selection Commission -- Selection of first commissioner of education. </catch_line><order_by>147</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created an Education Management Selection Commission. The commission shall consist of six (6) members to be appointed as follows: Three (3) by the Governor, one (1) by the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, one (1) by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and one (1) jointly by the President Pro Tempore and the Speaker. The commission is temporary in nature and shall terminate after the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education has signed a contract of employment with the first commissioner of education. The members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for their reasonable and necessary actual expenses. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall conduct a national search to identify the best qualified individual for the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education to appoint as the first commissioner of education to carry out the duties of the chief state school officer. The individual shall be agreed upon by a unanimous vote of all of the members of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall meet as soon as practicable after it is constituted. The members shall elect a chairperson, who shall be responsible for convening future meetings. The Governor's office and the Legislative Research Commission shall provide staff support to the commission. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 36, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/96).  Notwithstanding 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, the reference to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education in subsections (1) and (2) of this statute has been left unchanged because that reference is historical in nature. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3138</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>