<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.440</section_number><catch_line>Funds available to recognized and certified fire department -- Rights and responsibilities of department -- Fire chief. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Only fire departments recognized and certified by the commission shall be eligible to receive volunteer fire department aid pursuant to KRS 95A.262(2), to receive low interest loans pursuant to KRS 95A.262(14), or to participate in the Professional Firefighters Foundation Program, pursuant to KRS 95A.200 to 95A.290. </section><section prefix="2">A fire department created pursuant to KRS Chapter 273 which has been recognized and certified by the commission shall have the following rights and responsibilities: <section prefix="a">Designation as the only fire department authorized to protect property within its geographic area as filed with the commission and the county clerk, but the department may seek the assistance of other departments, and may make reciprocal aid contracts pursuant to KRS 75.050; </section><section prefix="b">Authority to secure water immediately for purposes of fighting a fire from any source, public or private. Upon request, the department shall compensate the owner in a reasonable amount for water used within six (6) months of use; and </section><section prefix="c">All rights identified in the Kentucky Revised Statutes for fire departments. </section></section><section prefix="3">The officers and firefighters, whether paid or unpaid, of each fire department created pursuant to KRS Chapter 273 and recognized and certified by the commission shall select a chief. The appointment of the chief shall be subject to the approval of the governing board of the department. The chief shall establish a chain of command within the department. The chief, or the highest person available in the chain of command if the chief cannot be present, shall, subject to all state statutes as applicable, have the following rights and responsibilities: <section prefix="a">Authority to order the immediate evacuation of areas endangered by fire, a hazardous materials incident, or other impending disaster that constitutes a threat to life or property; </section><section prefix="b">Authority to be in charge of all fire ground operations at the scene of a fire or other emergency; </section><section prefix="c">Control of all department personnel while on duty; and </section><section prefix="d">Control of all equipment of the department. </section></section><section prefix="4">The chief of each fire department created pursuant to KRS Chapter 273 and recognized and certified by the commission shall perform necessary actions to maintain recognition and certification of the department by the commission. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24468</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>