<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.030</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions to KRS 322.020. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>KRS 322.020 shall not apply to: <section prefix="1">The work of an employee or subordinate of: <section prefix="a">A professional engineer if the work is done under the direct supervision of and verified by the professional engineer; or </section><section prefix="b">A professional land surveyor if the work is done under the direct supervision of and verified by the professional land surveyor; </section></section><section prefix="2">The practice of engineering or land surveying by officers and employees of the United States government while engaged in engineering or land surveying for the government; </section><section prefix="3">The practice of engineering or land surveying by a person on property he or she leases or owns unless: <section prefix="a">The practice involves the public safety, health, or welfare; or </section><section prefix="b">The land surveying relates to the location or determination of any existing or proposed land boundaries; </section></section><section prefix="4">An engineer or land surveyor engaged solely as an officer or employee of a privately owned public utility or of a business entity engaged in interstate commerce as defined in the Interstate Commerce Act (24 Stat. 379) as amended; </section><section prefix="5">A licensed architect who engages in the practice of engineering incident to the practice of architecture; or </section><section prefix="6">The practice of engineering related solely to the design or fabrication of manufactured products. This exemption does not extend to site-specific engineering work for Kentucky locations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599e-18, 1599e-22. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>