<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.130</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.130 to 211.160. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.130 to 211.160, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" shall mean the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" shall mean the secretary for health and family services; </section><section prefix="3">"An individual with a severe physical disability" shall mean a person who has a severe physical disability as a result of cerebral palsy, poliomyelitis, muscular dystrophy, or spina bifida; </section><section prefix="4">"Educable person" shall mean an individual with a severe physical disability, as defined above, who is determined by the cabinet to be capable of receiving and benefiting from the services and facilities provided by KRS 211.130 to 211.160; </section><section prefix="5">"Funds" shall mean all moneys received by the cabinet from all persons, corporations, associations, organizations, and state or federal government agencies, specifically designated to be used for furnishing facilities and services for educable persons; provided, however, that no moneys appropriated to the cabinet by the General Assembly of this Commonwealth shall be considered to have been appropriated for establishing, providing, or maintaining services or facilities for educable persons, unless the act appropriating such moneys expressly so provides. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 340, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 284, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 72, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (2), (11) and (21). -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>