<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.7505</section_number><catch_line>Certification standards for mental health professionals providing court-mandated treatment -- List of certified providers to Administrative Office of the Courts -- Submission of data to cabinet -- Distribution of compiled data. </catch_line><order_by>7505</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall, by administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, establish certification standards for mental health professionals providing court-mandated treatment services for domestic violence offenders. </section><section prefix="2">The standards created by the cabinet shall be based on the following principles: <section prefix="a">Domestic violence is a pattern of coercive control which includes physical, sexual, psychological, and environmental abuse, and is considered to be criminal conduct; </section><section prefix="b">The primary goal of treatment programs for domestic violence offenders shall be the cessation of violence which will provide for the safety of victims and their children; and </section><section prefix="c">Domestic violence offenders are responsible and shall be held accountable for the violence which they choose to perpetrate. </section></section><section prefix="3">The standards created by the cabinet shall address the following: <section prefix="a">Qualifications of providers of court-mandated domestic violence offender treatment services which shall include appropriate requirements for degree, experience, training, and continuing education; </section><section prefix="b">Procedures for application by providers to receive certification which shall include methods of appeal if certification is denied, and sanctions for noncompliance with the standards which may include revocation of certification; </section><section prefix="c">Admittance and discharge criteria for domestic violence offenders to enter court-mandated treatment services provided pursuant to this section; </section><section prefix="d">Written protocols for referral by a court to certified providers and for progress reports to be made to the court by providers; </section><section prefix="e">Contracts for domestic violence offenders to sign prior to entering court-ordered treatment services provided pursuant to this section. The contract shall specify that certified providers may contact the victims of the offender if the victim chooses to be contacted. The contract shall authorize the provider to release information regarding the offender's progress in treatment to the court, victims, probation and parole officers, and other individuals authorized by the court to receive the information; </section><section prefix="f">Written procedures in compliance with KRS 202A.400, 209.030, and 620.030; </section><section prefix="g">Payment protocols which require the offender to pay the actual cost for any court-mandated evaluation or treatment pursuant to this section, subject to the offender's ability to pay; and </section><section prefix="h">Other provisions which shall further the availability and quality of court-mandated domestic violence offender services. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain a list of providers certified pursuant to this section and regularly submit the list to the Administrative Office of the Courts; and </section><section prefix="b">Collect data from certified providers, which shall include demographic information and clinical characteristics on offenders served, number of offenders admitted into treatment and discharge conditions, total clinical services provided to offenders, and other information necessary to monitor the safety and effectiveness of services provided, to be compiled annually and submitted to the Governor, the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court, and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></section><section prefix="5">No person, association, or organization shall conduct, operate, maintain, advise, or advertise any program that provides court-ordered treatment services for domestic violence offenders without first obtaining or maintaining valid certification under this chapter. If the cabinet has cause to believe that court-ordered treatment services for domestic violence offenders are being provided by a person or entity that does not possess valid certification under this chapter, the cabinet may institute proceedings, in the Circuit Court of the county in which the person or entity is located or in Franklin Circuit Court, for injunctive relief to terminate the provision of those services. </section><section prefix="6">Any person certified under this section shall submit quarterly to the cabinet: <section prefix="a">Demographic information and clinical characteristics on offenders served; </section><section prefix="b">Number of offenders admitted into treatment and discharge conditions; </section><section prefix="c">Total clinical services provided to offenders; and </section><section prefix="d">Other information as required by administrative regulation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 627, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 581, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17472</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>