<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9145</section_number><catch_line>Alteration of units. </catch_line><order_by>9145</order_by><text>Subject to the provisions of the declaration and other provisions of law, a unit owner: <section prefix="1">May make any improvements or alterations to his or her unit that do not impair the structural integrity, utility components, or mechanical systems or lessen the support of any portion of the condominium; </section><section prefix="2">Shall not change the appearance of the common elements, or the exterior appearance of a unit or any other portion of the condominium, without the written permission of the association; and </section><section prefix="3">After acquiring an adjoining unit or an adjoining part of an adjoining unit, may remove or alter any intervening partition or create apertures therein, even if the partition in whole or in part is a common element, if those acts do not impair the structural integrity, utility components, or mechanical systems or lessen the support of any portion of the condominium. Removal of partitions or creation of apertures under this subsection is not an alteration of boundaries and neither creates a merged unit nor modifies the basis for the calculation and collection of assessments. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 23, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40010</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>