<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.1921</section_number><catch_line>Refusal to make anatomical gift -- Effect of refusal. </catch_line><order_by>1921</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual may refuse to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part by: <section prefix="a">A record signed by: <section prefix="1">The individual; or </section><section prefix="2">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, another individual acting at the direction of the individual if the individual is physically unable to sign; </section></section><section prefix="b">The individual's will, whether or not the will is admitted to probate or invalidated after the individual's death; or </section><section prefix="c">Any form of communication made by the individual during the individual's terminal illness or injury addressed to at least two (2) adults, at least one (1) of whom is a disinterested witness. </section></section><section prefix="2">A record signed pursuant to subsection (1)(a)2. of this section shall: <section prefix="a">Be witnessed by at least two (2) adults, at least one (1) of whom is a disinterested witness, who have signed at the request of the individual; and </section><section prefix="b">State that it has been signed and witnessed as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">An individual who has made a refusal may amend or revoke the refusal: <section prefix="a">In the manner provided in subsection (1) of this section for making a refusal; </section><section prefix="b">By subsequently making an anatomical gift pursuant to KRS 311.1917 that is inconsistent with the refusal; or </section><section prefix="c">By destroying or canceling the record evidencing the refusal, or the portion of the record used to make the refusal, with the intent to revoke the refusal. </section></section><section prefix="4">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 311.1923(8), in the absence of an express, contrary indication by the individual set forth in the refusal, an individual's unrevoked refusal to make an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part bars all other persons from making an anatomical gift of the individual's body or part. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>