<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.765</section_number><catch_line>Salary of county attorney -- Expense allowance -- Compensation adjustment -- Private practice of law permitted. </catch_line><order_by>765</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county attorney shall receive for prosecutorial duties an annual salary to be paid out of the State Treasury which shall be the total compensation as county attorney which he received during the calendar year 1976, but which in no event shall be less than twenty thousand dollars ($20,000); except, however, the annual salary of each county attorney shall be equal to that of each Commonwealth's attorney who is not prohibited from the private practice of law as provided in KRS 15.755(5), effective January 1, 1990. </section><section prefix="2">Each county attorney shall be paid each month the sum of five hundred dollars ($500), which sum is declared to be the equivalent of the minimum sum that each county attorney will expend each month in the performance of his official duties directed to be performed for the Commonwealth. The aforementioned sum shall be paid out of the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="3">In order to equate the compensation of county attorneys with the purchasing power of the dollar, the Department for Local Government shall compute by the second Friday in February of every year the annual increase or decrease in the consumer price index of the preceding year by using 1949 as the base year in accordance with Section 246 of the Constitution of Kentucky which provides that the above elected officials shall be paid at a rate no greater than twelve thousand dollars ($12,000) per annum. The Department for Local Government shall notify the appropriate governing bodies charged by law to fix the compensation of the above elected officials of the annual rate of compensation to which the elected officials are entitled pursuant to the increase or decrease in the consumer price index. Upon notification from the Department for Local Government, the appropriate governing body may set the annual compensation of the above elected officials at a rate no greater than that stipulated by the Department for Local Government. </section><section prefix="4">The county attorney shall not be prohibited from engaging in the private practice of law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 9, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 421, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 579, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 17. sec. 14, effective January 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1007</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>