<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-305</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and goals on pollution prevention. </catch_line><order_by>46-305</order_by><text>In the interest of protecting public health and the environment, the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby finds that it is the policy of the Commonwealth to encourage environmental leadership in pollution prevention by source reduction when technically feasible and economically practicable, without shifting risks from one part of a process or environmental medium to another. It shall be the goal of the Commonwealth to reduce the amount by weight of hazardous waste and of toxic chemicals regulated under Title III, Section 313 of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 generated by each Kentucky facility in 1987 by twenty-five percent (25%) by January 1, 1997, and by fifty percent (50%) by January 1, 2002. It shall also be the goal of the Commonwealth to reduce the amount by weight of hazardous waste, and of toxic chemicals regulated under Title III, Section 313 of the Superfund Amendments and Reauthorization Act of 1986 generated by each Kentucky facility which began operating after December 31, 1987, by twenty-five percent (25%) within ten (10) years after beginning the operation, and by fifty percent (50%) within fifteen (15) years after beginning the operation. The General Assembly finds that the best means to achieve environmental leadership through pollution prevention are by: <section prefix="1">Providing facilities generating hazardous waste or releasing toxic chemicals with technical assistance to reduce the release of toxic chemicals and the generation of hazardous waste; </section><section prefix="2">Encouraging facilities generating hazardous waste or releasing toxic chemicals to adopt policies to prevent pollution, to prepare comprehensive plans and to develop measurable performance goals; </section><section prefix="3">Providing economic incentives to reduce the amount of hazardous waste generated and toxic chemicals released in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="4">Using cabinet incentives to acknowledge the environmental leadership of facilities meeting the pollution prevention goal. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>