<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.150</section_number><catch_line>Board of review -- Appointment -- Only three members to act in any matter -- Compensation -- Dissolution. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a board of review consisting of nine (9) persons who are residents and qualified voters of the Commonwealth, appointed by the Governor without limitation as to political affiliation, religion, race, sex, or past or present service in the Armed Forces, except that six (6) members of this board shall be veterans. The name of said board shall be "The Kentucky Veterans' Bonus Board of Review." The Governor shall designate a chairman and a secretary from among the membership. </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) members and no more shall constitute a board of review, and shall by concurrence of two (2) members decide any claim which comes before the board in the manner provided in this chapter. The chairman of the board shall designate three </section><section prefix="3">members to consider and decide each claim, having due regard for availability </section>for service so that delay may be avoided. (3) (a) Members of the board shall be compensated twenty-five dollars ($25) per diem, but only for actual time served in considering and deciding claims for veterans' bonus pursuant to designation by the Governor. (b) All members of the board shall be reimbursed for necessary travel to and from their places of residence, and in performance of duties pursuant to assignment, at the rate of eight cents ($0.08) per mile. <section prefix="4">Each claim coming before the board shall promptly be considered and decided by the three (3) members designated for that purpose. In every case the board shall either (a) affirm the decision of the administrator, or (b) determine that a veterans' bonus should be paid, and to what persons and in what amounts. No written opinions or recitations of reasons for any decision need be made. A statement of the decision made shall be signed by at least two (2) of the three (3) members designated to decide the claim; and upon concurrence of two (2) members a decision shall be final and not subject to reconsideration. </section><section prefix="5">The Governor shall, upon notification by the administrator that the last notice of a disapproval claim has been mailed, notify the chairman of the board of review that it shall complete its work within sixty (60) calendar days from date of notification. On the sixtieth day the Governor shall thereupon declare that the board of review is dissolved and shall so notify the members, and the functions and duties of the board shall be deemed to have been fully performed. </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 2. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 15. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21835</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>