<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.041</section_number><catch_line>Registered nurse license -- Jurisprudence examination -- Use of "R.N.A." by provisional licensee -- Use of "R.N." -- Special license -- Reinstatement -- Limited license.   </catch_line><order_by>041</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for a license to practice as a registered nurse shall file with the board a written application for a license and submit evidence, verified by oath, that the applicant: <section prefix="a">Has completed the basic curriculum for preparing registered nurses in an approved school of nursing and has completed requirements for graduation therefrom; </section><section prefix="b">Is able to understandably speak and write the English language and to read the English language with comprehension; and </section><section prefix="c">Has passed the jurisprudence examination approved by the board as provided by subsection (4) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant shall be required to pass a licensure examination in any subjects as the board may determine. Application for licensure by examination shall be received by the board at the time determined by the board by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="3">Upon request, an applicant who meets the requirements of subsection (1) of this section shall be issued a provisional license that shall expire no later than six (6) months from the date of issuance. </section><section prefix="4">The jurisprudence examination shall be prescribed by the board and be conducted on the licensing requirements under this chapter and board regulations and requirements applicable to the nursing profession in this Commonwealth. The board shall promulgate an administrative regulation in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A establishing the provisions to meet this requirement. </section><section prefix="5">An individual who holds a provisional license shall have the right to use the title "registered nurse applicant" and the abbreviation "R.N.A." An R.N.A. shall only work under the direct supervision of a registered nurse and shall not engage in independent nursing practice. </section><section prefix="6">Upon the applicant's successful completion of all requirements for registered nurse licensure, the board may issue to the applicant a license to practice nursing as a registered nurse, if in the determination of the board the applicant is qualified to practice as a registered nurse in this state. </section><section prefix="7">The board may issue a license to practice nursing as a registered nurse to any applicant who has passed the licensure examination and the jurisprudence examination prescribed by the board or their equivalent and been licensed as a registered nurse under the laws of another state, territory, or foreign country, if in the opinion of the board the applicant is qualified to practice as a registered nurse in this state. </section><section prefix="8">The applicant for licensure to practice as a registered nurse shall pay a licensure application fee, and licensure examination fees if applicable, as set forth in a regulation by the board promulgated pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who holds a license to practice as a registered nurse in this state shall have the right to use the title "registered nurse" and the abbreviation "R.N." No other person shall assume the title or use the abbreviation or any other words, letters, signs, or figures to indicate that the person using the same is a registered nurse. No person shall practice as a registered nurse unless licensed under this section. </section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">On November 1, 2006, and thereafter, a registered nurse who is retired, upon payment of a one-time fee, may apply for a special license in recognition of the nurse's retired status. A retired nurse may not practice nursing but may use the title "registered nurse" and the abbreviation "R.N." </section><section prefix="b">A retired registered nurse who wishes to return to the practice of nursing shall apply for reinstatement. </section><section prefix="c">The board shall promulgate an administrative regulation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to specify the fee required in paragraph (a) of this subsection and reinstatement under paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="11">Any person heretofore licensed as a registered nurse under the licensing laws of this state who has allowed the license to lapse by failure to renew may apply for reinstatement of the license under the provisions of this chapter. A person whose license has lapsed for one (1) year or more shall pass the jurisprudence examination approved by the board as provided in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="12">A license to practice registered nursing may be limited by the board in accordance with regulations promulgated by the board and as defined in this chapter. </section><section prefix="13">A person who has completed a prelicensure registered nurse program and holds a current, active licensed practical nurse license from another jurisdiction may apply for licensure by endorsement as a licensed practical nurse in this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 117, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 113 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44650</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>