<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.360</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of construction permit -- Refusal of application -- Resubmission -- Changes in plan or facilities -- Application of local building codes and zoning laws. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may issue a permit to construct upon receipt of an application for a permit to construct a new community or alter an existing community. </section><section prefix="2">If the application is refused, the cabinet shall give the reasons therefor in writing to the applicant; and if the objections can be corrected the applicant may resubmit his or her application for approval. </section><section prefix="3">Each person issued a permit to construct a new community or alter an existing community, upon completion and prior to occupancy, shall make application for a permit to operate. </section><section prefix="4">No change in sanitary facilities, including the water supply, sanitary sewer, waste disposal system, sanitary station, watering station, or service building, and no change in the plan of any existing community or in any proposed community for which a permit to construct has been issued, shall be made without having first obtained a construction permit therefor except that a change from a private water supply or private sewage disposal system to a public water supply or public sewage system shall not require a construction permit. The application shall be made in the manner prescribed for an original application. The change or changes shall comply with all applicable public health laws and regulations. </section><section prefix="5">A permit to construct, alter, or operate a community does not relieve the applicant from securing a local building permit if required, or from complying with any local zoning or other legal requirements. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>