<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.050</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service -- "The Administrative Register" -- Publication dates -- Certificate of compiler -- Fees.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Legislative Research Commission shall compile, publish, and distribute the administrative regulations filed by administrative bodies. This compilation shall be known as the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service. The Legislative Research Commission shall maintain the official version of the administrative regulations in an electronic database that shall be made available to the public as provided by KRS 7.500. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">There is hereby created a publication known as "The Administrative Register" to be published on a monthly basis by the Legislative Research Commission for the purpose of giving notice of administrative regulations filed in accordance with this chapter. </section><section prefix="b">Every administrative regulation forwarded to the Legislative Research Commission shall have its complete text published in the Administrative Register along with the accompanying statements required by KRS 13A.190, 13A.210, 13A.2251(1), 13A.240, 13A.245, 13A.250, and 13A.270. </section><section prefix="c">Within five (5) workdays of the publication of an administrative regulation in the Administrative Register, an administrative body shall: <section prefix="1">Review the text and accompanying statements of the administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="2">Notify the regulations compiler in writing or by e-mail of errors. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Register shall be published the first day of each month and shall include all administrative regulations received by the Legislative Research Commission by 12 noon, eastern time, on the fifteenth day of the preceding month. When the fifteenth day falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or holiday the deadline is the workday which immediately precedes the Saturday, Sunday, or holiday. </section><section prefix="4">The compiler shall cause to be prepared a certificate to the effect that the text of the administrative regulations as published in this service is correct. One (1) copy of the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service with the original certificate therein shall be provided to the Office of the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="5">The Commission shall prescribe reasonable fees for subscription to the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service and the Administrative Register. All fees paid to the Commission for these publications shall be placed in the State Treasury to the credit of a revolving trust or agency fund account, for use by the Legislative Research Commission in carrying out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Copies of administrative regulations or other items required to be filed by this chapter shall be made available to any interested party upon request to the Legislative Research Commission. The Commission may prescribe reasonable fees for duplication services and all fees paid to the Commission for duplication services shall be placed in the State Treasury to the credit of a revolving trust or agency fund account, for use by the Legislative Research Commission in carrying out the provisions of this subsection. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 5, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40709</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>