<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.155</section_number><catch_line>Development of quality assurance standards for health care facilities. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All health care facilities and services licensed under this chapter, with the exception of personal care homes, family care homes, and boarding homes, shall develop comprehensive quality assurance or improvement standards adequate to identify, evaluate, and remedy problems related to the quality of health care facilities and services. These standards shall be made available upon request to the public during regular business hours and shall include: <section prefix="a">An ongoing written internal quality assurance or improvement program; </section><section prefix="b">Specific, written guidelines for quality care studies and monitoring; </section><section prefix="c">Performance and clinical outcomes-based criteria; </section><section prefix="d">Procedures for remedial action to correct quality problems, including written procedures for taking appropriate corrective action; </section><section prefix="e">A plan for data gathering and assessment; </section><section prefix="f">A peer review process; and </section><section prefix="g">A summary of process outcomes and follow-up actions related to the overall quality improvement program for the health care facility or service. </section></section> Current federal or state regulations which address quality assurance and quality improvement requirements for nursing facilities, intermediate care facilities, and skilled care facilities shall suffice for compliance with the standards in this section. <section prefix="2">All health care facilities licensed, with the exception of personal care homes, family care homes, and boarding homes, under this chapter, shall use the application form and guidelines established pursuant to KRS 304.17A-545(5) for assessing the credentials of those applying for privileges. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9228</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>