<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.456</section_number><catch_line>Accessible parking placard for person with a disability -- Display. </catch_line><order_by>456</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On the application of any person who has a severe visual, audio, or physical impairment, including partial paralysis, lower limb amputation, chronic heart condition, emphysema, arthritis, rheumatism, or other debilitating condition which limits or impairs one's personal mobility or ability to walk, the county clerk in the county of the person's residence shall issue the person with a disability an accessible parking placard. In addition, any agency or organization which transports persons with a disability as a part of the service provided by that agency or organization shall receive an accessible parking placard upon application to the county clerk for each vehicle used in the transportation of persons with a disability. The accessible parking placard issued shall be a two (2) sided hanger style placard and shall on each side bear the international symbol of access adopted by Rehabilitation International in 1969, the date of expiration of the placard, a seal or other identification of the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet, and shall contain the accessible parking placard identification number and other information the Transportation Cabinet may by regulation require. The international symbol of access shall be at least three (3) inches in height, be centered on the placard and in a white color on a blue shield. Any information contained on the placard shall be written in indelible ink or inscribed in other permanent fashion so as to prevent tampering with or the changing of information contained on the placard. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall issue an accessible parking placard at no charge that shall be valid for a period of two (2) years and which may be twice renewed for a period of two (2) years, without any fee being charged to the applicant. The application shall be made on a form prepared by the Transportation Cabinet. Placards shall be printed at cabinet expense and distributed to the county clerk of each county who shall keep a record of applications filed and placards issued. </section><section prefix="3">For every person seeking an accessible parking placard, proof of the disability shall be required by: <section prefix="a">Evidence that the individual has a license plate for a person with a disability as provided by KRS 186.041 or 186.042; </section><section prefix="b">The county clerk issuing the permit ascertaining that the applicant is obviously disabled; or </section><section prefix="c">A statement from a licensed physician, chiropractor, or advanced practice registered nurse that the applicant is a person whose mobility, flexibility, coordination, respiration, or perceptiveness is significantly reduced by a permanent disability to that person's arms, legs, lungs, heart, ears, or eyes. </section></section><section prefix="4">For every agency or organization seeking an accessible parking placard for a person with a disability, application for the placard shall include: <section prefix="a">Name of the agency or organization requesting use of an accessible parking placard; </section><section prefix="b">Number of vehicles being used in the transportation of persons with a disability; and </section><section prefix="c">A statement from the director of the agency or organization verifying the need for the parking placard. </section></section><section prefix="5">The accessible parking placard shall, when the vehicle is parked in a parking space identified as accessible to a person with a disability, be displayed so that it may be viewed from the front and rear of the vehicle by hanging the placard from the front windshield rear view mirror. When there is no rear view mirror, the placard shall be displayed on the dashboard. </section><section prefix="6">A person who has not been issued a license plate for a person with a disability under the provisions of KRS 186.041 or 186.042 may be issued a second parking placard at no charge. </section><section prefix="7">A person with a disability who has been issued a parking placard pursuant to this section may make application for a replacement placard by swearing in an affidavit that the original placard has been lost, stolen, or destroyed. The replacement parking placard shall be issued at no charge by the county clerk. </section><section prefix="8">The Transportation Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement or administer this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 4, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 405 and 416. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 416, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43312</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>