<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.115</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of the secretary -- Rules and regulations -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall have the power and authority to adopt, amend, or rescind such rules and regulations as he deems necessary or suitable for the proper administration of this chapter. The commission shall determine its own organization and methods of procedure. </section><section prefix="2">General and special rules may be adopted, amended, or rescinded by the secretary only after public hearing or opportunity to be heard thereon, of which proper notice has been given. General rules shall become effective ten (10) days after filing with the Secretary of State and publication in the manner which the commission prescribes. Special rules shall become effective ten (10) days after notification of or mailing to the last known address of the individuals or concerns affected thereby. Regulations shall become effective in the manner and at the time prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall serve as an appeals board to hear and decide appeals filed in accordance with the provisions of KRS 341.430 and shall adopt regulations governing the manner of filing appeals and the conduct of hearings and appeals consistent with the provisions of this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 97. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>