<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.588</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations -- Reports to Governor and Legislative Research Commission. </catch_line><order_by>588</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall, by administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A: <section prefix="a">Develop a method to score applications for the bluegrass turns green private sector loan fund established in KRS 42.586 and the bluegrass turns green public sector grant fund established in KRS 42.584; </section><section prefix="b">Develop a list of companies qualified to perform energy audits for the purposes of determining a baseline of energy consumption and any subsequent projected energy cost savings for: <section prefix="1">Private sector recipients of low-interest loans provided from the bluegrass turns green private sector loan fund established in KRS 42.586; and </section><section prefix="2">Public sector recipients of grants awarded from the public sector turns green grant fund established in KRS 42.584; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Establish a process for the collection of loan payments from the private sector to repay amounts that were made available under the bluegrass turns green loan private sector fund. </section></section> The cabinet shall also promulgate any other administrative regulations necessary to administer the provisions of KRS 42.580 to 42.588. <section prefix="2">The cabinet shall report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission on or before November 1, 2009, and on or before each November 1 thereafter, the following for the bluegrass turns green private sector loan fund and the bluegrass turns green public sector grant fund for the immediately preceding fiscal year: <section prefix="a">The number of applicants; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the engineered demand-side management projects on which loans or grants were provided; </section><section prefix="c">The total amount loaned to the private sector and the total amount of grants provided to the public sector; </section><section prefix="d">The projected private sector energy cost savings; </section><section prefix="e">The projected public sector energy cost savings; </section><section prefix="f">The number of applicants and the amount of loan and grants for which funding was not available; and </section><section prefix="g">Based upon the energy audits performed, the amount of increased energy capacity realized. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 24, effective February 25, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 25, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> February 25, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22073</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>