<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.520</section_number><catch_line>Information available to program directors and CASA volunteers. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The clerk of the court shall: <section prefix="a">Notify and provide a copy of all dependency, abuse, and neglect petitions to the program director, as soon as the court makes a referral to the program director for assignment of a CASA volunteer to the case; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a copy of all court orders issued pursuant to this section; and </section><section prefix="c">Notify the program director of all scheduled court hearings for cases to which a CASA volunteer has been assigned. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon appointment by the court to represent a child, the CASA volunteer shall have access to all information and records pertaining to the child including, but not limited to, the records of the following entities: the cabinet; child-caring facilities operated or licensed by the cabinet; public and private schools; physical and mental health care providers; law enforcement agencies; and other entities deemed appropriate by the court. </section><section prefix="3">With court approval, the CASA volunteer may have access to information and records pertaining to the parents or persons exercising custodial control or supervision of the child assigned to the CASA volunteer, including information and records of the court, the cabinet, public and private child care facilities, private and public schools, and the medical and psychological records of the child assigned to the volunteer. The volunteer shall have access to the medical and psychological records of parents when the court determines that the information is essential to the welfare of the child and the court orders it. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20231</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>