<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.830</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 171.830 to 171.849. </catch_line><order_by>830</order_by><text>As used in KRS 171.830 to 171.849, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Loan" means a deposit of property in a museum not accompanied by a transfer of title to the property, whether or not such deposit is accompanied by an oral or written agreement or other documentation; </section><section prefix="2">"Museum" means an institution located in Kentucky and operated by a nonprofit corporation, the Commonwealth of Kentucky, a city, a county, an urban-county, or a charter county, primarily for educational, scientific, aesthetic, historic, or preservation purposes, and which owns, cares for, exhibits, studies, archives, or catalogues property. Museums shall include, but not be limited to, traditional museums, historical societies, historic sites or landmarks, parks, monuments, and libraries; </section><section prefix="3">"Museum records" means documents created or held by a museum in its regular course of business; </section><section prefix="4">"Property" means a tangible object, under a museum's care, which has intrinsic historic, artistic, scientific, or cultural value; and </section><section prefix="5">"Tangible objects" shall include, but not be limited to, manuscripts, letters, correspondence, writings, notes, ledgers, accounts, charts, maps, photographs, drawings and similar renderings, and personal property, regardless of the medium in which an object is held. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4871</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>