<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.050</section_number><catch_line>Duties of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The secretary in person or by representative shall: <section prefix="1">Investigate and ascertain the wages of all employees employed in this state; </section><section prefix="2">Enter the place of business or employment of any employer of employees to examine and inspect all books, registers, payrolls, and other records that have a bearing upon the question of wages of employees and to ascertain whether the orders of the secretary are complied with; </section><section prefix="3">Require from the employer a full and correct statement in writing when the secretary or the secretary's representative considers it necessary, of the wages paid to all employees in his or her employment; and </section><section prefix="4">Upon complaint, prosecute any violation of any of the provisions of any law which it is his or her duty to administer or enforce. The secretary may enter into reciprocal agreements with the corresponding labor agency or official of any other state to collect in the other state claims assigned to the secretary. To the extent allowed by a reciprocal agreement, the secretary may maintain actions in the courts of another state to collect claims and judgments for wages and assign claims and judgments to the agency or official of another state for collection. If a reciprocal agreement extends a like comity to cases arising in the Commonwealth, the secretary may maintain actions in the courts of the Commonwealth to collect claims and judgments for wages arising in the other state in the same manner and to the same extent that actions are authorized when arising in the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1704, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1; and ch. 386, sec. 59. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599c-39, 4767a-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31994</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>