<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.425</section_number><catch_line>Bounty on beaver. </catch_line><order_by>425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon adoption of a resolution by the fiscal court that beaver exist within the county in such quantities that they present a threat to the preservation of farmland, trees, and other property, the fiscal court may request the department to pay a bounty on beaver. Upon receipt of the resolution, a bounty on beaver of ten dollars ($10) for each beaver shall be paid in the following manner. Upon the presentation of the tail of any beaver, any conservation officer of the department shall issue a receipt, in the form as prescribed by the commission, to the person presenting the tail. The department shall redeem the receipts by paying to such person the sum of ten dollars ($10) for each receipt as bounty. The redemption of receipts shall be paid only from funds especially appropriated for this purpose and it is expressly provided that no bounty shall be paid from any regular receipts, funds, or appropriations of the department. However, the department may charge a maximum of one dollar ($1) against the appropriation for bounties for each bounty paid as reimbursement for the expense of administering the bounty program. </section><section prefix="2">No bounty shall be paid when funds, personnel, or equipment of any governmental unit are used in capturing and killing beaver. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receipt of an adopted resolution from a fiscal court stating that beaver no longer present a threat to property within the county, the department shall cease paying the bounty. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>