<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">CITY CLASSIFICATION, BOUNDARIES, AND ALTERNATIVE METHOD OF CONSOLIDATING GOVERNMENTAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>81.430</section_number><catch_line>Legislative bodies of merged cities. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The members of the legislative bodies of the merging cities shall continue to hold their offices in the new city, until their respective terms of office expire, and shall constitute a combined legislative body of the new city. </section><section prefix="2">At the expiration of the terms of office of the combined legislative body members, which in no case shall be greater than two (2) years, an election shall be held to elect the correct member of legislative body members as required by the organizational structure of the city pursuant to KRS 83A.030. The election shall be governed by the general election laws and shall be held at the same time as other city elections. </section><section prefix="3">If any member of the combined legislative body resigns his office prior to the expiration of the term of the office, the resignation shall be subject to one (1) of the following provisions: <section prefix="a">If after the resignation, the total number of combined legislative body members is greater than will be required by the organizational structure for the legislative body of the newly merged city, the vacancy shall not be filled and the provisions of KRS 83A.040 shall not apply; or </section><section prefix="b">If after the resignation, the total number of combined legislative body members is less than will be required by the organizational structure for the legislative body of the newly merged city, the vacancy shall be filled as provided by KRS 83A.040. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 5, effective March 25, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24995</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>