<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.100</section_number><catch_line>Time of filing reports -- Period covered -- Change of period. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the corporation operates on a calendar year basis, the reports required under KRS 136.090 shall be filed on or before April 15 in each year. If the corporation operates on a fiscal year basis, the reports shall be filed on or before the fifteenth day of the fourth month following the close of each fiscal year. The reports shall cover operations for the preceding calendar or fiscal year, as the case may be. Domestic corporations hereafter incorporated, and foreign corporations hereafter becoming the owners of property or transacting business in this state, shall make their reports to the Department of Revenue on or before the first filing date succeeding their incorporation or succeeding their becoming the owners of property or transacting business in this state, and shall in all respects be subject to the provisions of KRS 136.070 to 136.100 the same as corporations already in existence. </section><section prefix="2">A corporation may change its reporting period from a calendar year to a fiscal year, or from a fiscal year to a calendar year, by securing written permission from the department. If a corporation so changes its basis of reporting, the first report filed on the new filing date shall cover operations for the period between the close of the old accounting period and the close of the new accounting period. The assessment of value shall be computed in the same manner as on any other return, but the tax due shall be computed on that proportionate part of the assessment that the period between the close of the old accounting period and the close of the new accounting period bears to the entire twelve (12) month period. </section><section prefix="3">In any case where two (2) or more corporations merge, consolidate or otherwise combine into a single corporation after the close of the taxable year, but before the beginning of the succeeding taxable year, all factors used to determine the corporation license tax assessment shall be computed on the basis of the consolidated accounting records of such corporations. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 300, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4189-5, 4189-7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28507</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>