<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.205</section_number><catch_line>Reports of improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing of controlled substances -- Administrative regulations for prescribing and dispensing protocols and licensure actions and requirements -- Complaint procedure -- Criminal record check. </catch_line><order_by>205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Reporting agency" includes: <section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="2">The Office of the Attorney General; </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services; and </section><section prefix="4">The applicable state licensing board; and </section></section><section prefix="b">"State licensing board" means: <section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Nursing; </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Dentistry; </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Board of Optometric Examiners; </section><section prefix="5">The State Board of Podiatry; and </section><section prefix="6">Any other board that licenses or regulates a person who is entitled to prescribe or dispense controlled substances to humans. </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">When a reporting agency or a law enforcement agency receives a report of improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing of a controlled substance it may, to the extent otherwise allowed by law, send a copy of the report within three (3) business days to every other reporting agency. </section><section prefix="b">A county attorney or Commonwealth's attorney shall notify the Office of the Attorney General and the appropriate state licensing board within three (3) business days of an indictment or a waiver of indictment becoming public in his or her jurisdiction charging a licensed person with a felony offense relating to the manufacture of, trafficking in, prescribing, dispensing, or possession of a controlled substance. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each state licensing board shall establish the following by administrative regulation for those licensees authorized to prescribe or dispense controlled substances: <section prefix="a">Mandatory prescribing and dispensing standards related to controlled substances, the requirements of which shall include the diagnostic, treatment, review, and other protocols and standards established for Schedule II controlled substances and Schedule III controlled substances containing hydrocodone under KRS 218A.172 and which may include the exemptions authorized by KRS 218A.172(4); </section><section prefix="b">A prohibition on a practitioner dispensing greater than a forty-eight (48) hour supply of any Schedule II controlled substance or a Schedule III controlled substance containing hydrocodone unless the dispensing is done as part of a narcotic treatment program licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="c">A procedure for temporarily suspending, limiting, or restricting a license held by a named licensee where a substantial likelihood exists to believe that the continued unrestricted practice by the named licensee would constitute a danger to the health, welfare, or safety of the licensee's patients or of the general public; </section><section prefix="d">A procedure for the expedited review of complaints filed against their licensees pertaining to the improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing of controlled substances that is designed to commence an investigation within seven (7) days of a complaint being filed and produce a charging decision by the board on the complaint within one hundred twenty (120) days of the receipt of the complaint, unless an extension for a definite period of time is requested by a law enforcement agency due to an ongoing criminal investigation; </section><section prefix="e">The establishment and enforcement of licensure standards that conform to the following: <section prefix="1">A permanent ban on licensees and applicants convicted after July 20, 2012, in this state or any other state of any felony offense relating to controlled substances from prescribing or dispensing a controlled substance; </section><section prefix="2">Restrictions short of a permanent ban on licensees and applicants convicted in this state or any other state of any misdemeanor offense relating to prescribing or dispensing a controlled substance; </section><section prefix="3">Restrictions mirroring in time and scope any disciplinary limitation placed on a licensee or applicant by a licensing board of another state if the disciplinary action results from improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing of controlled substances; and </section><section prefix="4">A requirement that licensees and applicants report to the board any conviction or disciplinary action covered by this subsection with appropriate sanctions for any failure to make this required report; </section></section><section prefix="f">A procedure for the continuous submission of all disciplinary and other reportable information to the National Practitioner Data Bank of the United States Department of Health and Human Services; </section><section prefix="g">If not otherwise required by other law, a process for submitting a query on each applicant for licensure to the National Practitioner Data Bank of the United States Department of Health and Human Services to retrieve any relevant data on the applicant; and </section><section prefix="h">Continuing education requirements beginning with the first full educational year occurring after July 1, 2012, that specify that at least seven and one-half percent (7.5%) of the continuing education required of the licensed practitioner relate to the use of the electronic monitoring system established in KRS 218A.202, pain management, or addiction disorders. </section></section><section prefix="4">A state licensing board shall employ or obtain the services of a specialist in the treatment of pain and a specialist in drug addiction to evaluate information received regarding a licensee's prescribing or dispensing practices related to controlled substances if the board or its staff does not possess such expertise, to ascertain if the licensee under investigation is engaging in improper, inappropriate, or illegal practices. </section><section prefix="5">Any statute to the contrary notwithstanding, no state licensing board shall require that a grievance or complaint against a licensee relating to controlled substances be sworn to or notarized, but the grievance or complaint shall identify the name and address of the grievant or complainant, unless the board by administrative regulation authorizes the filing of anonymous complaints. Any such authorizing administrative regulation shall require that an anonymous complaint or grievance be accompanied by sufficient corroborating evidence as would allow the board to believe, based upon a totality of the circumstances, that a reasonable probability exists that the complaint or grievance is meritorious. </section><section prefix="6">Every state licensing board shall cooperate to the maximum extent permitted by law with all state, local, and federal law enforcement agencies, and all professional licensing boards and agencies, state and federal, in the United States or its territories in the coordination of actions to deter the improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing of a controlled substance. </section><section prefix="7">Each state licensing board shall require a fingerprint-supported criminal record check by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation of any applicant for initial licensure to practice any profession authorized to prescribe or dispense controlled substances. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 4, effective March 4, 2013. -- Created 2012 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective July 20, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> March 4, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41652</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>