<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.810</section_number><catch_line>Redress of injuries to property.   </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever complaint is made to any commanding officer that willful damage has been done to the property of any person or that the person's property has been wrongfully taken by members of the state military forces, that person may, under such regulations prescribed, convene a board to investigate the complaint. The board shall consist of from one (1) to three (3) commissioned officers and, for the purpose of that investigation, it has power to summon witnesses and examine them upon oath, to receive depositions or other documentary evidence, and to assess the damages sustained against the responsible parties. The assessment of damages made by the board is subject to the approval of the commanding officer, and in the amount approved by that officer shall be charged against the pay of the offenders. The order of such commanding officer directing charges herein authorized is conclusive on any disbursing officer for the payment to the injured parties of the damages so assessed and approved. </section><section prefix="2">If the offenders cannot be ascertained, but the organization or detachment to which they belong is known, charges totaling the amount of damages assessed and approved may be made in such proportion as may be considered just upon the individual members thereof who are shown to have been present at the scene at the time the damages complained of were inflicted, as determined by the approved findings of the board. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 143, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 78, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013</effective><former-codification>KRS 35.395. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42033</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>