<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.629</section_number><catch_line>Interagency Technical Advisory Committee on Groundwater -- Duties and responsibilities. </catch_line><order_by>629</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established an Interagency Technical Advisory Committee on Groundwater to assist the KGS in the development, coordination, and implementation of a groundwater monitoring network for the Commonwealth. The committee shall consist of one (1) representative from each of the following agencies, to be appointed by that agency: <section prefix="a">Division of Conservation of the Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="b">Division of Public Health Protection and Safety of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="c">Division of Forestry of the Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="d">Division of Environmental Services of the Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="e">Division of Waste Management of the Department for Environmental Protection; </section><section prefix="f">Division of Water of the Department for Environmental Protection; </section><section prefix="g">Department for Environmental Protection; </section><section prefix="h">Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="i">Kentucky Geological Survey; </section><section prefix="j">University of Kentucky College of Agriculture; and </section><section prefix="k">University of Kentucky Water Resources Research Institute. </section></section><section prefix="2">The committee shall have two (2) nonvoting legislative liaisons who shall be members of the General Assembly. One (1) liaison shall be a House member appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and one (1) liaison shall be a Senate member appointed by the President of the Senate. The chair of the committee shall be the director of the University of Kentucky Water Resources Research Institute. The duties and responsibilities of the committee shall include: <section prefix="a">Developing a plan to coordinate agencies for the overall characterization of the state's groundwater, including occurrence, flow systems, water quantity, and water quality; </section><section prefix="b">Reviewing the data entry process to ensure that all data collected is placed into the Kentucky Groundwater Data Repository; </section><section prefix="c">Establishing a long-term groundwater monitoring plan for the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">Making recommendations for prioritization of the state's groundwater research needs; and </section><section prefix="e">Annually reviewing and evaluating groundwater data collection and analysis. </section></section><section prefix="3">In addition to the members identified in subsection (1) or (2) of this section, the committee may have, as one (1) of its members, one (1) nonvoting representative from the United States Geological Survey, appointed by that agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 122, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 123, sec. 18, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 99 and 123, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. (6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>