<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.730</section_number><catch_line>Permits to hold captive cervids -- Amendments to existing holding and fencing requirements -- Duties of department. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within sixty (60) days of July 12, 2006, the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources shall promulgate administrative regulations amending existing requirements for a permit to hold captive cervids in accordance with the provisions of KRS 150.725 to 150.735. All other fencing and holding requirements specified in existing administrative regulation for a permit to hold captive cervids adopted on January 5, 2004, shall not be amended in a manner that is in conflict with KRS 150.725 to 150.735 or that increases the stringency of those requirements, except when as ordered by the state veterinarian for disease control and as provided by law or in administrative regulations for the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources to control emergency conditions that detrimentally affect wildlife. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall have thirty (30) days from the date it receives a completed application to either issue or deny captive permits for propagation and taking of captive cervids by any legal hunting or slaughter methods. If an application demonstrates that the applicant complies with the statutory and administrative requirements for a permit and the applicant removes all wild cervids from the facility, the department shall issue the permit. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2063</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>