<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.710</section_number><catch_line>Granting or denial of construction certificate -- Policy of General Assembly -- Transfer of rights and obligation. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within one hundred twenty (120) days of receipt of an administratively complete application, or within one hundred eighty (180) days of receipt of an administratively complete application if a hearing is requested, the board shall, by majority vote, grant or deny a construction certificate, either in whole or in part, based upon the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Impact of the facility on scenic surroundings, property values, the pattern and type of development of adjacent property, and surrounding roads; </section><section prefix="b">Anticipated noise levels expected as a result of construction and operation of the proposed facility; </section><section prefix="c">The economic impact of the facility upon the affected region and the state; </section><section prefix="d">Whether the facility is proposed for a site upon which existing generating facilities, capable of generating ten megawatts (10MW) or more of electricity, are currently located; </section><section prefix="e">Whether the proposed facility will meet all local planning and zoning requirements that existed on the date the application was filed; </section><section prefix="f">Whether the additional load imposed upon the electricity transmission system by use of the merchant electric generating facility will adversely affect the reliability of service for retail customers of electric utilities regulated by the Public Service Commission; </section><section prefix="g">Except where the facility is subject to a statewide setback established by a planning and zoning commission as provided in KRS 278.704(3) and except for a facility proposed to be located on a site of a former coal processing plant and the facility will use on-site waste coal as a fuel source, whether the exhaust stack of the proposed merchant electric generating facility and any wind turbine is at least one thousand (1,000) feet from the property boundary of any adjoining property owner and all proposed structures or facilities used for generation of electricity are two thousand (2,000) feet from any residential neighborhood, school, hospital, or nursing home facility, unless a different setback has been requested and approved under KRS 278.704(4). If a planning and zoning commission has established setback requirements that differ from those under KRS 278.704(2), the applicant shall provide evidence of compliance. If the facility is proposed to be located on site of a former coal processing plant and the facility will use on-site waste coal as a fuel source, the applicant shall provide evidence of compliance with the setback requirements provided in KRS 278.704(5); </section><section prefix="h">The efficacy of any proposed measures to mitigate adverse impacts that are identified pursuant to paragraph (a), (b), (e), or (f) of this subsection from the construction or operation of the proposed facility; and </section><section prefix="i">Whether the applicant has a good environmental compliance history. </section></section><section prefix="2">When considering an application for a construction certificate for a merchant electric generating facility, the board may consider the policy of the General Assembly to encourage the use of coal as a principal fuel for electricity generation as set forth in KRS 152.210, provided that any facility, regardless of fuel choice, shall comply fully with KRS 224.10-280, 278.212, 278.216, and 278.700 to 278.716. </section><section prefix="3">A person that has received a construction certificate for a merchant electric generating facility shall not transfer rights and obligation under the certificate without having first applied for and received a board determination that: <section prefix="a">The acquirer has a good environmental compliance history; and </section><section prefix="b">The acquirer has the financial, technical, and managerial capacity to meet the obligations imposed by the terms of the approval or has the ability to contract to meet these obligations. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 5, effective April 10, 2014. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 6, effective April 24, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 10, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42956</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>