<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.165</section_number><catch_line>Landing strips for personal use -- Limitation on regulation by local government -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All statutes to the contrary notwithstanding, any property owner who resides in a county with a population of thirty-five thousand (35,000) or greater, and who owns at least one thousand (1,000) contiguous acres, may construct a landing strip for their personal use that is capable of handling two (2) private aircraft. The landing strip shall not be used for public or commercial purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The landing strip authorized under this section shall meet all regulations or standards promulgated by the Federal Aviation Administration concerning areas regulated for the safe maneuvering approach and landing of aircraft. </section><section prefix="3">All local governments shall be prohibited from regulating landing strips authorized under this section and shall be prohibited from enacting planning and zoning ordinances contrary to the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="4">For the purposes of this section, roadways or railroad rights-of-way shall not be considered a separation of contiguous acres. </section><section prefix="5">The property owner may be required to pay a fee of one hundred dollars ($100) per year to the county in which the airport is located. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 361, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  This section was created by 2002 Ky. Acts chs.306 and 361. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 361, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails.  See KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>