<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">B LONG-TERM POLICY RESEARCH </unit></structure><section_number>7B.050</section_number><catch_line>Term and powers of executive director -- Employees. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive director of the Kentucky Long-Term Policy Research Center shall serve at the pleasure of the center's board. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director may employ staff, incur travel and other miscellaneous expenses, and authorize staff travel as necessary to carry out the duties of the center, within the limits of funds appropriated or otherwise made available to it. </section><section prefix="3">Employees of the center shall be employees of the legislative department and shall be exempted from classified service, but entitled to the same benefits as other employees of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">With approval of the board, the executive director may enter into agreements with any state agency or political subdivision of the state, any institution of higher education, or any other person or entity to enlist staff assistance to implement the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The executive director shall supervise the allocation of the work and activities of all employees of the center. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (3) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=509</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>