<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.327</section_number><catch_line>Venue and process. </catch_line><order_by>327</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every action for the involuntary dissolution of a corporation shall be commenced by the attorney general in the circuit court of the county in which the registered office of the corporation is situated.  </section><section prefix="2">Summons shall issue and be served as in other civil action. If process is returned not found, the attorney general shall have the defendant constructively served as provided in CR 4.05, and shall cause publication to be made in some newspaper published in the county where the registered office of the corporation is situated, containing a notice of the pendency of such action, the title of the court, the title of the action, and the date on or after which default may be entered. The attorney general shall cause a copy of such notice to be mailed, by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the corporation at its registered office within ten (10) days after the first publication thereof. The certificate of the attorney general of the mailing of such notice shall be prima facie evidence thereof. Such notice shall be published at least once each week for two (2) successive weeks, and the first publication thereof may begin at any time after the summons has been returned. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 64, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 42. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 52. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13694</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>