<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.770</section_number><catch_line>Notification to warehousemen, manufacturers and dealers of assessment -- Remittance of assessment. </catch_line><order_by>770</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event a majority of the eligible producers in the referendum who vote therein shall vote in favor of the assessment, then the Commissioner shall notify forthwith, by certified mail, every person licensed to operate a tobacco warehouse in the state, as well as every person who operates a tobacco manufacturing establishment and every tobacco dealer who buys burley tobacco directly from the producer, that on and after the date designated in the notice, which shall be not less than thirty (30) days nor more than sixty (60) days after the mailing of the notice by the Commissioner, the amount of the assessment shall be deducted by all sales markets or purchasers of burley tobacco or by their agents or representatives, from the purchase price paid the seller of burley tobacco. </section><section prefix="2">On or before the fifteenth day of each month all assessments deducted shall be remitted to the association certified by the assessment referendum. </section><section prefix="3">The books and records of all tobacco warehouses, tobacco manufacturers and tobacco dealer operators shall at reasonable times be open for inspection by the Commissioner or his duly authorized agents for the purpose of ascertaining the accuracy of the amounts remitted. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 51, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>