<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.260</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Horse Park Commission -- Members -- Terms -- Meetings -- Reimbursement for expenses -- Bylaws -- Advisory committee. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created and established an agency of state government to be known as the Kentucky Horse Park Commission, which shall constitute a separate administrative body of state government within the meaning of KRS 12.010(8) and under the provisions of KRS 12.015 shall be attached to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall be composed of seventeen (17) members who possess the ability to provide broad management expertise and direction in the operation of the Kentucky Horse Park and shall, to the extent possible, represent the diverse interest of the Kentucky horse industry. Of these, fifteen (15) members shall be appointed by the Governor. Two (2) of these appointed members of the commission shall represent the equine industry; and two (2) members shall be active in industry and commerce. The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development and the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall serve as ex officio members with full voting rights. Any vacancy on the commission shall be filled by the Governor for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="3">The appointed members of the commission shall hold their offices for a term of four </section><section prefix="4">years, except that for the initial appointment to the commission, two (2) </section>members shall serve a term of two (2) years, two (2) members shall serve a term of three (3) years, and three (3) members shall serve a term of four (4) years. (4) The commission shall meet quarterly and shall be headed by a chairman appointed by the Governor. The chairman shall preside over the commission meetings. The chairman may call special meetings of the commission upon a request of the majority of the members of the commission. <section prefix="5">Members shall be reimbursed only for expenses incurred in the discharge of official business, subject to regulations established by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. All expenses reimbursed to members shall be paid from operating funds of the Kentucky Horse Park. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall establish and maintain an office at the Kentucky State Horse Park for the transaction of its business and shall not establish any branch office. The commission may hold meetings at any other place when the convenience of the commission requires. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall be authorized to adopt bylaws providing for the call of its meetings, which shall be held at least quarterly, and for its operating procedures. A quorum of the commission shall consist of eight (8) members, and a quorum of members present at any duly-called meeting may act upon any matter before it for consideration. Each member shall have one (1) vote. </section><section prefix="8">The Governor may establish an advisory committee to advise in the administration, development and operation of the horse park or other functions, activities, and programs provided for or authorized by KRS 148.260 to 148.320. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 17, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 16, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 9. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1739</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>