<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.496</section_number><catch_line>Family resource and youth services centers -- Design -- Core components -- Location -- Grant program -- Prohibition on abortion counseling and referrals. </catch_line><order_by>496</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Family resource and youth services centers shall be designed to meet the needs of children and their families by providing services to enhance a student's ability to succeed in school. If resources are limited, students and families who are the most economically disadvantaged shall receive priority status for receiving services. </section><section prefix="2">Family resource centers shall be located in or near each elementary school in the Commonwealth in which twenty percent (20%) or more of the student body are eligible for free or reduced-price school meals. Family resource centers shall promote identification and coordination of existing resources and shall include but not be limited to the following core components for each site: <section prefix="a">Full-time preschool child care for children two (2) and three (3) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">After-school child care for children ages four (4) through twelve (12), with the child care being full-time during the summer and on other days when school is not in session; </section><section prefix="c">Families in training, which shall consist of an integrated approach to home visits, group meetings, and monitoring child development for new and expectant parents; </section><section prefix="d">Family literacy services as described in KRS 158.360 or a similar program designed to provide opportunities for parents and children to learn together and promote lifelong learning; and </section><section prefix="e">Health services or referrals to health services, or both. </section></section><section prefix="3">Youth services centers shall be located in or near each school in the Commonwealth, except elementary schools, in which twenty percent (20%) or more of the student body are eligible for free or reduced-price school meals. Youth services centers shall promote identification and coordination of existing resources and shall include but not be limited to the following core components for each site: <section prefix="a">Referrals to health and social services; </section><section prefix="b">Career exploration and development; </section><section prefix="c">Summer and part-time job development for high school students; </section><section prefix="d">Substance abuse education and counseling; and </section><section prefix="e">Family crisis and mental health counseling. </section></section><section prefix="4">A grant program is hereby established to provide financial assistance to eligible school districts to establish or maintain family resource or youth services centers. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall award grants pursuant to KRS 156.4977. Funding provided to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for the grant program and agency administrative costs shall include an increase that is equal to or greater than the general fund growth factor provided in agency budget instructions. </section><section prefix="5">A family resource or youth services center that receives funding for one (1) year or more shall not be considered ineligible for funding based solely on the percent of the student body eligible for free or reduced-price school meals unless the percent of the student body eligible for free or reduced-price school meals is below twenty percent (20%) for five (5) consecutive years. </section><section prefix="6">A school district shall not operate a family resource center or a youth services center that provides abortion counseling or makes referrals to a health care facility for the purpose of seeking an abortion. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3207</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>