<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.065</section_number><catch_line>School breakfast program -- Annual report by schools not offering -- Annual report by commissioner on status of program. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any school that does not offer a school breakfast program shall submit an annual report no later than September 15 to the Kentucky Board of Education indicating the reasons for not offering the program. The report shall include the number of children enrolled at the school and the number of children who are eligible for free or reduced priced meals under the federal program. </section><section prefix="2">The state board shall inform the school of the value of the school breakfast program, its favorable effects on student attendance and performance, and the availability of funds to implement the program. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner of education shall submit an annual report no later than December 1 to the Interim Joint Committee on Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare regarding the status of the school breakfast program including, but not limited to, information describing the schools that do not offer the program, the reasons given by the schools for not offering the program, the number of children enrolled in each school, the number of children in each school who are eligible for free or reduced priced meals under the federal program, and the action taken by the state board to encourage schools to implement the program. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3270</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>