<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.650</section_number><catch_line>Authority created -- Purposes -- Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The West Fork Drakes Creek Dam and Reservoir Interstate Authority is hereby created. The West Fork Drakes Creek Dam and Reservoir Interstate Authority shall be a public body corporate and politic and shall be referred to as the "authority" in KRS 151.650 to 151.664. The authority shall develop the resources of the region embracing the Tennessee county of Sumner and the Kentucky county of Simpson by means of the construction and maintenance of a dam across the West Fork Drakes Creek and the reservoir created by this dam. The water impounded within this reservoir shall be utilized by the areas encompassing the authority to provide a source of water for both recreation and economic development to be used in industrial, commercial, agricultural, and residential activities. The authority may develop this dam and reservoir for these stated purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly hereby finds that the need for the purposes for which this authority is created is evidenced by the effects which the recent droughts have had and continue to have on this area. The General Assembly also finds that an adequate supply of potable water is essential for the continued growth of this area. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2151</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>