<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="527" order_by="527">OFFENSES RELATING TO FIREARMS AND WEAPONS </unit></structure><section_number>527.040</section_number><catch_line>Possession of firearm by convicted felon -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of possession of a firearm by a convicted felon when he possesses, manufactures, or transports a firearm when he has been convicted of a felony, as defined by the laws of the jurisdiction in which he was convicted, in any state or federal court and has not: <section prefix="a">Been granted a full pardon by the Governor or by the President of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Been granted relief by the United States Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to the Federal Gun Control Act of 1968, as amended. </section></section><section prefix="2">Possession of a firearm by a convicted felon is a Class D felony unless the firearm possessed is a handgun in which case it is a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall apply to any youthful offender convicted of a felony offense under the laws of this Commonwealth. The exceptions contained in KRS 527.100 prohibiting possession of a handgun by a minor shall not apply to this section. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of this section with respect to handguns, shall apply only to persons convicted after January 1, 1975, and with respect to other firearms, to persons convicted after July 15, 1994. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 396, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 237, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 30 and 396 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19959</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>