<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.8-040</section_number><catch_line>Winding up.   </catch_line><order_by>8-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After dissolution, a statutory trust continues its existence as a statutory trust, but may not carry on any activities except as is appropriate to wind up and liquidate its activities and affairs, including: <section prefix="a">Collecting the assets of the trust; </section><section prefix="b">Disposing of the properties of the trust that will not be distributed in kind to beneficial owners of the trust; </section><section prefix="c">Discharging or making provision for discharging the liabilities of the trust, including entering into agreements with creditors for the satisfaction thereof; </section><section prefix="d">Distributing the remaining property of the trust in accordance with KRS 386A.8-080; and </section><section prefix="e">Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate the trust’s activities and affairs. </section></section><section prefix="2">In winding up a statutory trust’s activities, a trust may: <section prefix="a">Preserve the trust’s activities and property as a going concern for a reasonable time; </section><section prefix="b">Prosecute, defend, or settle actions or proceedings whether civil, criminal, or administrative, including by mediation or arbitration; and </section><section prefix="c">Transfer the property of the trust. </section></section><section prefix="3">The dissolution of a statutory trust does not: <section prefix="a">Prevent the commencement of a proceeding by or against the trust in its name; </section><section prefix="b">Abate or suspend a proceeding by or against the trust pending on the effective date of dissolution; </section><section prefix="c">Transfer title to the trust’s property; </section><section prefix="d">Terminate the authority of the registered agent of the statutory trust; </section><section prefix="e">Abate or suspend KRS 386A.3-040; or </section><section prefix="f">Abate or suspend KRS 386A.4-020. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 67, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40409</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>