<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.526</section_number><catch_line>Members to file statement of facts at retirement office -- Procedures for verification. </catch_line><order_by>526</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each employee on becoming a member of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System shall have on file in the retirement office, in the form as the board may prescribe, a statement of facts pertaining to the member. The statement shall include a record of military service, previous employment with the employer, and such other information as the system may require. </section><section prefix="2">If the records of the Personnel Cabinet or the department employing the member during the time the service was rendered do not substantiate the statement of service, the member shall be notified of any discrepancy. The member shall be advised that he has the responsibility of supplying verification of any unsubstantiated service. </section><section prefix="3">At the request of the member, or the beneficiary if the member is deceased, the executive director shall arrange a time and place to receive additional information in regard to the unverified service. After filing the request, the member or the beneficiary if the member is deceased, shall have a reasonable time but no more than six (6) months to present the additional information to substantiate the unverified service. </section><section prefix="4">The system may at any time conduct an audit of the employing department pursuant to KRS 61.675. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 7, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 65, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 14, effective March 26, 1974. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 24. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22960</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>