<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.260</section_number><catch_line>Purposes for which assistance by fund may be used. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Funds made available to local governments shall be received, held, and expended in accordance with the provisions of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300, any rules and regulations issued by the commission, and the following specific restrictions: <section prefix="a">Funds provided shall be used only as a supplemental distribution to firefighters, and for payments to the defined benefit pension plan to which the firefighter belongs to cover retirement costs on the supplemental distribution. </section><section prefix="b">Funds provided shall be distributed only to firefighters who have complied with subsections (3) and (4) of KRS 95A.230. </section><section prefix="c">Each firefighter shall receive distribution of the state supplement which his or her qualifications brought to the local government. </section><section prefix="d">Funds shall not be used to supplement existing salaries or as a substitute for normal salary increases periodically due to firefighters. </section></section><section prefix="2">This section shall not apply to funds expended pursuant to KRS 95A.240(3). </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 3, effective March 20, 2009. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> March 20, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>