<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.520</section_number><catch_line>Recordation of mortgages -- Effect thereof. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text>Any mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument executed by a cooperative or foreign corporation doing business in this state pursuant to KRS 279.310 to 279.600, which affects real and personal property and which is recorded in the real property records in any county in which such property is located or is to be located, shall have the same force and effect as if the mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument were also recorded, filed or indexed as provided by law in the proper office in such county as a mortgage of personal property. All after-acquired property of such cooperative or foreign corporation described or referred to as being mortgaged or pledged in any such mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument, shall become subject to the lien thereof immediately upon the acquisition of such property by such cooperative or foreign corporation, whether or not such property was in existence at the time of the execution of such mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument. Recordation of any such mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument shall constitute notice and otherwise have the same effect with respect to such after-acquired property as it has under the laws relating to recordation, with respect to property owned by such cooperative or foreign corporation at the time of the execution of such mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument and therein described or referred to as being mortgaged or pledged thereby. The lien upon personal property of any such mortgage, deed of trust or other instrument shall, after recordation thereof, continue in existence and of record for the period of time specified therein without the refiling thereof or the filing of any renewal certificate, affidavit or other supplemental information required by the laws relating to the renewal, maintenance or extension of liens upon personal property. </text><history>Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 21, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1950 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14228</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>