<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">A UNIFORM MILITARY AND OVERSEAS VOTERS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>117A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Covered voter" means: <section prefix="a">A uniformed-service voter or an overseas voter who is registered to vote in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">A uniformed-service voter defined in subsection (9)(a) of this section whose voting residence is in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and who otherwise satisfies the Commonwealth of Kentucky’s voter eligibility requirements; </section><section prefix="c">An overseas voter who, before leaving the United States, was last eligible to vote in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and, except for his or her absence from the state, otherwise satisfies the Commonwealth of Kentucky’s voter eligibility requirements; </section><section prefix="d">An overseas voter who, before leaving the United States, would have been last eligible to vote in the Commonwealth of Kentucky had the voter then been of voting age and, except for his or her absence from the state, otherwise satisfies the Commonwealth of Kentucky's voter eligibility requirements; or </section><section prefix="e">An overseas voter who was born outside the United States, is not described in paragraph (c) or (d) of this subsection, and, except for his or her absence from the state, otherwise satisfies the Commonwealth of Kentucky's voter eligibility requirements, if: <section prefix="1">The last place where a parent or legal guardian of the voter was, or under this chapter would have been, eligible to vote before leaving the United States is within the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="2">The voter has not previously registered to vote in any other state; </section></section></section><section prefix="2">"Dependent" means an individual recognized as a dependent by a uniformed service; </section><section prefix="3">"Federal postcard application" means the application prescribed under Section 101(b)(2) of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 42 U.S.C. sec. 1973ff(b)(2); </section><section prefix="4">"Federal write-in absentee ballot" means the ballot described in Section 103 of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act, 42 U.S.C. sec. 1973ff-2; </section><section prefix="5">"Military-overseas ballot" means: <section prefix="a">A federal write-in absentee ballot; </section><section prefix="b">A ballot specifically prepared or distributed for use by a covered voter in accordance with this chapter; or </section><section prefix="c">A ballot cast by a covered voter in accordance with this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Overseas voter" means a United States citizen who is outside the United States; </section><section prefix="7">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States; </section><section prefix="8">"Uniformed service" means: <section prefix="a">Active and reserve components of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">The Merchant Marine, the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, or the commissioned corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the United States; or </section><section prefix="c">The National Guard and state militia; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Uniformed-service voter" means an individual who is qualified to vote and is: <section prefix="a">A member of the active or reserve components of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard of the United States who is on active duty; </section><section prefix="b">A member of the Merchant Marine, the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, or the commissioned corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the United States; </section><section prefix="c">A member on activated status of the National Guard or state militia; or </section><section prefix="d">A spouse or dependent of a member referred to in this subsection; and </section></section><section prefix="10">"United States," used in the territorial sense, means the several states, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, and any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42722</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>