<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.47-030</section_number><catch_line>Required statements for applications and claims forms. </catch_line><order_by>47-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All applications shall contain a statement in a form approved by the Department of Insurance that clearly states in substance the following: "Any person who knowingly and with intent to defraud any insurance company or other person files an application for insurance containing any materially false information or conceals, for the purpose of misleading, information concerning any fact material thereto commits a fraudulent insurance act, which is a crime." </section><section prefix="2">All claim forms shall contain a statement in a form approved by the Department of Insurance that clearly states in substance the following: "Any person who knowingly and with intent to defraud any insurance company or other person files a statement of claim containing any materially false information or conceals, for the purpose of misleading, information concerning any fact material thereto commits a fraudulent insurance act, which is a crime." </section><section prefix="3">Fraud warning statements shall not be required on applications or claim forms used by reinsurers. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1584, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30184</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>