<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.905</section_number><catch_line>Subsidy for personal care assistance. </catch_line><order_by>905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall provide a subsidy for personal care assistance services to any adult who:  <section prefix="a">Has a severe physical disability;  </section><section prefix="b">Needs not less than fourteen (14) hours a week of personal care assistance services as defined by the secretary or needs an attendant at night, which services are necessary to prevent or remove the adult from inappropriate placement in an institutional setting; and  </section><section prefix="c">Qualifies under KRS 205.910.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The adult shall be responsible for:  <section prefix="a">Recruiting, hiring, firing and supervising the persons who provide personal care assistance services; and  </section><section prefix="b">Obtaining an evaluation of his eligibility for personal care services from a qualified agency or organization which employs evaluation teams to:  <section prefix="1">Determine the eligibility of the adult for personal care assistance services;  </section><section prefix="2">Reevaluate the adult at least biennially to determine the adult's continuing need for services; and  </section><section prefix="3">Report its findings and recommendations to the cabinet.  </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall follow the recommendations of the evaluation team or shall give notice to the adult within twenty (20) days of receipt of the recommendations of its reasons for not acting on the team's recommendations.  </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may maintain a list of qualified agencies and organizations.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7871</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>