<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.703</section_number><catch_line>Collection of benefit less than $1,000 by surviving relative. </catch_line><order_by>703</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the death of a member, retiree, or recipient who has an existing account or other benefit in a retirement system administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems that totals no more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), the surviving spouse, or if none, a surviving child, or if none, a surviving parent, or if none, a surviving brother or sister, may without formal administration of the estate collect the account subject to the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The surviving spouse, child, parent, or brother or sister who makes demand for the deceased member, retiree, or recipient account shall file with the retirement office an affidavit stating that he or she is entitled to payment of the account. The affidavit shall conform to the requirements of the administrative regulation promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="3">After having paid the account to the surviving spouse, child, parent, or brother or sister, the retirement system shall be discharged and held harmless to the same extent as if conducting business with a personal representative. The retirement system shall not be required to inquire into the truth or veracity of any statement made in the affidavit. In the event any person or entity establishes a superior right to the account, the surviving spouse, child, parent, or brother or sister, and not the Kentucky Retirement Systems, shall be answerable and accountable to any appointed personal representative for the estate. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23027</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>