<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.135</section_number><catch_line>Torture of dog or cat. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires, "torture" means the intentional infliction of or subjection to extreme physical pain or injury, motivated by an intent to increase or prolong the pain of the animal. </section><section prefix="2">A person is guilty of torture of a dog or cat when he or she without legal justification intentionally tortures a domestic dog or cat. </section><section prefix="3">Torture of a dog or cat is a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense if the dog or cat suffers physical injury as a result of the torture, and a Class D felony if the dog or cat suffers serious physical injury or death as a result of the torture. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall apply to the killing or injuring of a dog or cat: <section prefix="a">In accordance with a license to hunt, fish, or trap; </section><section prefix="b">For humane purposes; </section><section prefix="c">For veterinary, agricultural, spaying or neutering, or cosmetic purposes; </section><section prefix="d">For purposes relating to sporting activities including but not limited to training for organized dog or cat shows, or other animal shows in which a dog or a cat, or both, participate; </section><section prefix="e">For bona fide animal research activities, using dogs or cats, of institutions of higher education; or a business entity registered with the United States Department of Agriculture under the Animal Welfare Act or subject to other federal laws governing animal research; </section><section prefix="f">In defense of self or another person against an aggressive or diseased dog or cat; </section><section prefix="g">In defense of a domestic animal against an aggressive or diseased dog or cat; </section><section prefix="h">For animal or pest control; or </section><section prefix="i">For any other purpose authorized by law. </section></section><section prefix="5">Activities of animals engaged in hunting, field trials, dog training other than training a dog to fight for pleasure or profit, and other activities authorized either by a hunting license or by the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources shall not constitute a violation of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The acts specified in this section shall not constitute cruelty to animals under KRS 525.125 or 525.130. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2003).  In subsection (4)(e) of this section, the redundant words "activities of" have been deleted before the phrase "bona fide animal research activities." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19937</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>