<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.844</section_number><catch_line>Regulatory authority of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>844</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide by administrative regulation for the registration and licensing of the possession or use of any source of ionizing or electronic product radiation and the handling and disposal of radioactive waste. The cabinet may prescribe specific conditions or means for the disposal and volume and source reduction of radioactive materials including radioactive waste. These administrative regulations shall include but need not be limited to specification of the form of applications for registration and licenses, the qualifications therefor, grounds for revocation, appeal pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, and other matters necessary to carry out the intent of KRS 211.842 to 211.852 and to protect the public from unnecessary radiation exposure. </section><section prefix="2">All administrative regulations adopted prior to June 17, 1978, by the Cabinet for Human Resources and on file with the Legislative Research Commission shall continue in full force and effect unless subsequently amended or repealed pursuant to the provisions of KRS 211.842 to 211.852. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 375, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 316, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 110, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8488</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>