<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.160</section_number><catch_line>First responders -- Permitted activities -- Reasonable control by employers -- Utilization of first responders in medical care facilities. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A first responder may, subject to the provisions of this section, perform any procedure: <section prefix="a">Specified in the most recent curriculum of the United States Department of Transportation training course for first responders; and </section><section prefix="b">Any additional procedure authorized by the board by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">When there is a change in the United States Department of Transportation curriculum for first responders or the board approves an additional skill or procedure by administrative regulation, no person who was not trained under that curriculum shall perform any activity or procedure authorized by the new curriculum or administrative regulation unless the person has been trained according to the new curriculum or administrative regulation and demonstrates competency in the new knowledge or skill. Competency in a new skill shall be demonstrated through a return demonstration to a competent evaluator. If the board adopts the new procedure or skill, the board shall promulgate an administrative regulation specifying the new procedure, training requirements, examination requirements, and a time period during which the first responder shall successfully complete the new material or lose his or her certification as a first responder. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, nothing in this section shall prevent an employer from exercising reasonable fiscal control over the costs of providing emergency medical services to its citizens nor to prevent the employer from exercising any reasonable control over first responders providing emergency medical care on behalf of a licensed entity or other provider. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit utilization of any certified first responder for the purpose of such individual working with primary responsibility and duties limited to hospitals, physician's offices, clinics, or other definitive care facilities, except as a first responder trainee or as a full-time instructor of first responders. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 29, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30749</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>