<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.502</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on possession and use of alcohol vaporizing device. </catch_line><order_by>502</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, a person shall not sell, purchase, deliver, give away, possess, use, or offer for sale or use an alcohol vaporizing device or assist another in selling or using an alcohol vaporizing device. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">A hospital that operates primarily for the purpose of conducting scientific research; </section><section prefix="b">A public institution that is a member of the postsecondary education system or an independent institution as defined in KRS 164.001 that is conducting bona fide research; </section><section prefix="c">A pharmaceutical or biotechnology company conducting bona fide research; </section><section prefix="d">A manufacturer or distributor that sells an alcohol vaporizing device to one (1) of the entities set out in this subsection; or </section><section prefix="e">A device used by a manufacturer in the manufacturing process. </section></section><section prefix="3">Persons holding an alcohol vaporizing device in accordance with subsection (2)(a) to (d) of this section shall retain the alcohol vaporizing device in a secure location such that it is used only for research purposes. They shall not transfer the device to an entity or institution other than one covered by subsection (2) of this section and shall destroy the device when it is no longer of use. The department may promulgate administrative regulations authorizing additional reports if the department deems the reports reasonably necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 579, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11373</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>