<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="625" order_by="625">TERMINATION OF PARENTAL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>625.043</section_number><catch_line>Termination orders. </catch_line><order_by>043</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the Circuit Court determines that parental rights are to be voluntarily terminated in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, it shall make an order terminating all parental rights and obligations of the parent and releasing the child from all legal obligations to the parent and vesting care and custody of the child in the person, agency, or cabinet the court believes is best qualified to receive custody. </section><section prefix="2">Upon consent by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the child may be declared a ward of the state and custody vested in the cabinet or in any child-placing agency or child-caring facility licensed by the cabinet or in another person if all persons with parental rights to the child under the law have had their rights terminated voluntarily or involuntarily. If the other person is not excepted by KRS 199.470(4) or (5), a grant of permanent custody shall be made only if the proposed custodian has received the written approval of the secretary or the secretary's designee for the child's placement. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 670, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 621, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 66, effective April 10, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>