<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0203</section_number><catch_line>Strategic agenda -- Strategic implementation plan -- Benchmarks -- Review of goals and plan. </catch_line><order_by>0203</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall adopt a strategic agenda that identifies specific short-term objectives in furtherance of the long-term goals established in KRS 164.003(2). </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The purpose of the strategic agenda is to further the public purposes under KRS 164.003 by creating high-quality, relevant, postsecondary education and adult education opportunities in the Commonwealth. The strategic agenda shall: <section prefix="1">Serve as the public agenda for postsecondary education and adult education for the citizens of the Commonwealth, providing statewide priorities and a vision for long-term economic growth; </section><section prefix="2">State those important issues and aspirations of the Commonwealth's students, employers, and workforce reflecting high expectations for their performance and the performance of the educational institutions and providers that serve them; and </section><section prefix="3">Sustain a long-term commitment for constant improvement, while valuing market-driven responsiveness, accountability to the public, technology-based strategies, and incentive-based motivation. </section></section><section prefix="b">The council shall develop a strategic implementation plan, which may be periodically revised, to achieve the strategic agenda. The strategic agenda shall serve as a guide for institutional plans and missions. </section></section><section prefix="3">The framework for the strategic implementation plan of the strategic agenda shall include the following elements: <section prefix="a">A mission statement; </section><section prefix="b">Goals; </section><section prefix="c">Principles; </section><section prefix="d">Strategies and objectives; </section><section prefix="e">Benchmarks; and </section><section prefix="f">Incentives to achieve desired results. </section></section><section prefix="4">The implementation plan for the strategic agenda shall take into consideration the value to society of a quality liberal arts education and the needs and concerns of Kentucky's employers. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall develop benchmarks using criteria that shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Use of the statistical information commonly provided by governmental and regulatory agencies or specific data gathered by authorization of the council; </section><section prefix="b">Comparison of regions and areas within the Commonwealth and comparisons of the Commonwealth to other states and the nation; and </section><section prefix="c">Measures of educational attainment, effectiveness, and efficiency, including but not limited to those set forth in KRS 164.095. </section></section><section prefix="6">The council shall review the goals established by KRS 164.003(2) at least every four (4) years and shall review its implementation plan at least every two (2) years. </section><section prefix="7">In developing the strategic agenda, the council shall actively seek input from the Department of Education and local school districts to create necessary linkages to assure a smooth and effective transition for students from the elementary and secondary education system to the postsecondary education system. Upon completion of the strategic agenda and strategic implementation plan, the council shall distribute copies to each local school district. </section><section prefix="8">The strategic agenda shall include a long-term strategy, developed in partnership with the Kentucky Adult Education Program, for raising the knowledge and skills of Kentucky's adult population, and ensuring lifelong learning opportunities for all Kentucky adults, drawing on the resources of all state government cabinets and agencies, business and civic leadership, and voluntary organizations. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 102, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 6, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4169</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>