<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.132</section_number><catch_line>Office for Education and Workforce Statistics -- Purpose -- Kentucky Longitudinal Data System -- Collection of education and workforce data -- Certification and ownership of data -- Funding.   </catch_line><order_by>132</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office for Education and Workforce Statistics is hereby established and attached to the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, Office of the Secretary. </section><section prefix="2">The office’s purpose is to collect accurate education data and workforce data in the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System in order to link the data and generate timely reports about student performance through employment to be used to guide decision makers in improving the Commonwealth of Kentucky’s education system and training programs. </section><section prefix="3">The office shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the Governor pursuant to KRS 12.050. The executive director shall be appointed from nominations made to the Governor by the board. The office may employ additional staff necessary to carry out the office’s duties consistent with available funding and state personnel laws. </section><section prefix="4">The public agencies providing education data and workforce data to the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System shall be: <section prefix="a">The Council on Postsecondary Education; </section><section prefix="b">The Department of Education; </section><section prefix="c">The Early Childhood Advisory Council; </section><section prefix="d">The Education Professional Standards Board; </section><section prefix="e">The Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority; </section><section prefix="f">The Kentucky Commission on Proprietary Education; and </section><section prefix="g">Other agencies of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Longitudinal Data System, upon approval of the board, may include education data and workforce data from any additional public agency. </section><section prefix="6">Any private institution of higher education, private school, or parochial school, upon approval of the board, may provide education data and workforce data to the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System. </section><section prefix="7">Any education data or workforce data provided to the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System shall be certified to be accurate by the providing agency, institution, or school. Ownership of data provided shall be retained by the providing entity. </section><section prefix="8">The office may receive funding for its operation of the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System from the following sources: <section prefix="a">State appropriations; </section><section prefix="b">Federal grants; </section><section prefix="c">User fees; and </section><section prefix="d">Any other grants or contributions from public agencies or other entities. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 90, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). This statute was created with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 18 and 90, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>