<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.110</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary actions. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department may, following a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, impose sanctions specified in KRS 227A.040 upon proof that the licensee has: <section prefix="a">Misrepresented or concealed a material fact in obtaining a license, or in the reinstatement thereof; </section><section prefix="b">Been incompetent or negligent in the practice of performing electrical work; </section><section prefix="c">Failed to comply with an order issued by the department or an assurance of voluntary compliance; or </section><section prefix="d">Violated any provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">One (1) year from the date of a revocation, any former licensee whose license has been revoked may petition the department for reinstatement. The department shall investigate the petition and may reinstate the license upon a finding that the applicant has complied with any terms prescribed by the department and is again able to competently engage in the practice of performing electrical work. </section><section prefix="3">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the department may enter into an agreed order or accept an assurance of voluntary compliance with the license holder which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="4">The department may reconsider, modify, or reverse its probations, suspensions, or other disciplinary actions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 437, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>