<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.474</section_number><catch_line>Duties and functions of council. </catch_line><order_by>474</order_by><text>In addition to the duties relating to equine health and welfare matters set forth in KRS 257.472(1), the duties and functions of the council include but are not limited to: <section prefix="1">Undertaking research, conducting public hearings, and collecting data to determine the prevalent equine health and welfare issues; </section><section prefix="2">Striving to develop regional centers of care for unwanted, abused, neglected, or confiscated equines. The development of the centers may be undertaken in cooperation with state and local governments, private entities, universities, or other groups; </section><section prefix="3">Creating a system of voluntary certification of equine rescue and retirement operations that includes, at a minimum, industry-accepted standards of care for equines; </section><section prefix="4">Researching and offering suggestions to the commission for statutory changes affecting equine health, welfare, abuse, and neglect issues; </section><section prefix="5">Assisting veterinarians and others in maintaining the health and welfare of equines by identifying and referring to the appropriate authorities critical areas of need; and </section><section prefix="6">Submitting a written report annually to the Governor, the Department of Agriculture, and the Legislative Research Commission regarding its administrative, financial, and programmatic activities. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>