<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.390</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 177.390 to 177.570. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text>As used in KRS 177.390 to 177.570, the following words and terms shall have the following meanings, unless the context shall indicate another or different meaning or intent: <section prefix="1">The word "department" shall mean the Department of Highways, or, if said department shall be abolished, the department, board, body, or commission succeeding to the principal functions thereof or to whom the powers given by KRS 177.390 to 177.570 to the department shall be given by law; </section><section prefix="2">The word "project" or the words "turnpike project" shall mean any express highway or superhighway or such part or parts thereof as may be constructed under the provisions of KRS 177.390 to 177.570 by the department, including all bridges, tunnels, overpasses, underpasses, interchanges, entrance plazas, approaches, connecting highways, tollhouses, service stations, garages, restaurants, and administration, storage, and other buildings and facilities which the department may deem necessary for the operation of such project, together with all property, rights, easements, and interests which may be acquired by the department for the construction or the operation of such project; </section><section prefix="3">The word "cost" as applied to a turnpike project shall embrace the cost of construction, the cost of the acquisition of all land, rights of way, property, rights, easements, and interests acquired by the department for such construction, the cost of demolishing or removing any buildings or structures on land so acquired, including the cost of acquiring any lands to which such buildings or structures may be moved, the cost of all machinery and equipment, financing charges, provision for working capital in such amount as the department shall determine to be reasonable, interest prior to and during construction, and, if deemed advisable by the department, for a period not exceeding two (2) years after completion of construction, cost of traffic estimates and of engineering and legal expenses, plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of cost and of revenues, other expenses necessary or incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing any such project, administrative expense, and such other expense as may be necessary or incident to the construction of the project, the financing of such construction, and the placing of the project in operation. Any obligation or expense heretofore or hereafter incurred by the department for traffic surveys, borings, preparation of plans and specifications, engineering, and other services in connection with the construction of a project shall be regarded as a part of the cost of such project and may be reimbursed to the Commonwealth out of the proceeds of turnpike revenue bonds hereinafter authorized in KRS 177.400 to 177.570; </section><section prefix="4">The words "public highways" shall include all public highways, roads, and streets in the Commonwealth, whether maintained by the Commonwealth or by any county, city, town, or other political subdivision; </section><section prefix="5">The word "bonds" or the words "turnpike revenue bonds" shall mean revenue bonds of the Commonwealth authorized under the provisions of KRS 177.390 to 177.570; </section><section prefix="6">The word "owner" shall include all individuals, copartnerships, associations, or corporations having any title or interest in any property, rights, easements, and interests authorized to be acquired by KRS 177.390 to 177.570. </section></text><history>Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective March 25, 1960. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1960 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5325</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>