<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.838</section_number><catch_line>Temporary permit for nonresident not covered by reciprocal agreement.   </catch_line><order_by>838</order_by><text>Any person who is a nonresident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and who operates any motor vehicle as defined in KRS 281.010 not entitled to exemption from the payment of the fees imposed by KRS 186.050 by reason of the terms of a reciprocal agreement existing between the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the state in which such vehicle is licensed, may, in lieu of the payment of the fees imposed by KRS 186.050, obtain from the Department of Vehicle Regulation a temporary permit. Under regulations adopted by the Department of Vehicle Regulation application for such a temporary permit shall be made and such permits shall be issued for a specified period not exceeding ten (10) days, and for a specific vehicle. The fee for each permit shall be twenty-five ($25) dollars for any vehicle subject to the fees in KRS 186.050 for a vehicle and any towed unit with a declared gross weight of fifty-five thousand (55,000) pounds or less; or forty dollars ($40) for any vehicle subject to the fees in KRS 186.050 for a vehicle and any towed unit with a declared gross weight of fifty-five thousand one (55,001) pounds or more. </text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 30, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 12, effective April 1, 1988. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec  31. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44179</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>