<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="163" order_by="163">VOCATIONAL EDUCATION AND REHABILITATION </unit></structure><section_number>163.032</section_number><catch_line>Salary schedule for teachers and administrators in schools for deaf and blind -- Employment status and benefits -- Hiring process -- Work location assignments -- Accrued leave. </catch_line><order_by>032</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Department of Education, with assistance from the Kentucky Personnel Cabinet, shall adopt a salary schedule for teachers in the Kentucky School for the Deaf and the Kentucky School for the Blind. The salary schedule shall be the same as salary schedules in effect in local school districts in counties containing a city of the first class and shall conform to the requirements for a single salary schedule as defined in KRS 157.320, except the salary schedule shall not limit the number of years of experience for a certified employee who transfers to the school. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Certified teachers in the Kentucky School for the Deaf and the Kentucky School for the Blind shall have the same statutory employment status and benefits as certified teachers in the public schools. </section><section prefix="b">If a teacher qualifies for and requests a tribunal under KRS 161.790, the Attorney General shall appoint the members. </section></section><section prefix="3">Once a teacher has been selected for hiring at the Kentucky School for the Blind or the Kentucky School for the Deaf, the Department of Education and the Personnel Cabinet shall complete the hiring process within two (2) weeks. </section><section prefix="4">A certified teacher employed at one (1) of the schools on July 12, 2006, whose job description does not include outreach responsibilities shall not be involuntarily assigned to work on a permanent basis outside the county in which the employing school is located. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 18A.115 or 163.032 shall result in a loss of any leave accrued by a certified teacher employed prior to July 12, 2006, by one (1) of the schools. Accrued leave may be taken in accordance with the policy of the school. </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Department of Education, with assistance from the Kentucky Personnel Cabinet, shall adopt a salary schedule for administrators for the Kentucky School for the Deaf and the Kentucky School for the Blind. In considering the rate of pay and the requirements of KRS 18A.110(7)(b), the department and the cabinet shall consider rates that are based upon the duties and responsibilities of the positions and that are competitive with rates for similar or comparable services in Kentucky school districts. The salary schedule, which shall be computed prior to September 1 of each year, shall be based on two hundred sixty (260) days per year. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 80, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 470, sec. 55, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 263, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was amended by three 1990 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails, pursuant to KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39922</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>