<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.805</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 61.805 to 61.850. </catch_line><order_by>805</order_by><text>As used in KRS 61.805 to 61.850, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Meeting" means all gatherings of every kind, including video teleconferences, regardless of where the meeting is held, and whether regular or special and informational or casual gatherings held in anticipation of or in conjunction with a regular or special meeting; </section><section prefix="2">"Public agency" means: <section prefix="a">Every state or local government board, commission, and authority; </section><section prefix="b">Every state or local legislative board, commission, and committee; </section><section prefix="c">Every county and city governing body, council, school district board, special district board, and municipal corporation; </section><section prefix="d">Every state or local government agency, including the policy-making board of an institution of education, created by or pursuant to state or local statute, executive order, ordinance, resolution, or other legislative act; </section><section prefix="e">Any body created by or pursuant to state or local statute, executive order, ordinance, resolution, or other legislative act in the legislative or executive branch of government; </section><section prefix="f">Any entity when the majority of its governing body is appointed by a "public agency" as defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (g), or (h) of this subsection, a member or employee of a "public agency," a state or local officer, or any combination thereof; </section><section prefix="g">Any board, commission, committee, subcommittee, ad hoc committee, advisory committee, council, or agency, except for a committee of a hospital medical staff or a committee formed for the purpose of evaluating the qualifications of public agency employees, established, created, and controlled by a "public agency" as defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), or (h) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="h">Any interagency body of two (2) or more public agencies where each "public agency" is defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), or (g) of this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Action taken" means a collective decision, a commitment or promise to make a positive or negative decision, or an actual vote by a majority of the members of the governmental body; and </section><section prefix="4">"Member" means a member of the governing body of the public agency and does not include employees or licensees of the agency. </section><section prefix="5">"Video teleconference" means one (1) meeting, occurring in two (2) or more locations, where individuals can see and hear each other by means of video and audio equipment. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>