<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.0802</section_number><catch_line>Sale or other disposition of county property. </catch_line><order_by>0802</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county may sell or otherwise dispose of any of its real or personal property. </section><section prefix="2">Before selling or otherwise disposing of any real or personal property, the county shall make a written determination setting forth and fully describing: <section prefix="a">The real or personal property; </section><section prefix="b">Its intended use at the time of acquisition; </section><section prefix="c">The reasons why it is in the public interest to dispose of it; and </section><section prefix="d">The method of disposition to be used. </section></section><section prefix="3">Real or personal property may be: <section prefix="a">Transferred, with or without compensation, to another governmental agency; </section><section prefix="b">Sold at public auction following publication of the auction in accordance with KRS 424.130(1)(b); </section><section prefix="c">Sold by electronic auction following publication of the auction, including the uniform resource link (URL) for the site of the electronic auction, in accordance with KRS 424.130(1)(b); or </section><section prefix="d">Sold by sealed bids in accordance with the procedure for sealed bids under KRS 45A.365(3) and (4). </section></section><section prefix="4">If a county receives no bids for the real or personal property, either at public or electronic auction or by sealed bid, the property may be disposed of, consistent with the public interest, in any manner deemed appropriate by the county. In those instances, a written description of the property, the method of disposal, and the amount of compensation, if any, shall be made. </section><section prefix="5">Any compensation resulting from the disposal of this real or personal property shall be transferred to the general fund of the county. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23688</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>