<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-135</section_number><catch_line>Uniform health insurance claim forms. </catch_line><order_by>14-135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall prescribe the following uniform health insurance claim forms which shall be used by all insurers transacting health insurance in this state and by all state agencies that require health insurance claim forms for their records as the sole instrument for reimbursement: <section prefix="a">The uniform health insurance claim form for an institutional provider shall consist of the UB-92 data set or its successor submitted on the designated paper or electronic format as adopted by the National Uniform Billing Committee; </section><section prefix="b">The uniform health insurance claim form for a dentist shall consist of a data set and form approved by the American Dental Association; </section><section prefix="c">The uniform health insurance claim form for all other health care providers shall consist of the HCFA 1500 data set or its successor submitted on the designated paper or electronic format as adopted by the National Uniform Claims Committee; and </section><section prefix="d">A clean claim for pharmacists shall consist of a universal claim form or data set approved by the National Council on Prescription Drug Program. </section></section><section prefix="2">An insurer shall not require a provider to: <section prefix="a">Use a claim form that is different than the uniform claim form for the provider type as set out in subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Modify the uniform claims form or its content; or </section><section prefix="c">Submit additional claims forms. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1152, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17133</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>