<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.245</section_number><catch_line>Procedure when voter's right to vote disputed. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fact that a person is registered constitutes only prima facie evidence of his right to vote and does not prevent the officers of any election from refusing to allow him to vote for cause. </section><section prefix="2">When the officers of an election disagree as to the qualifications of a voter or if his right to vote is disputed by a challenger, the voter shall sign a written oath as to his qualifications before he is permitted to vote. The oath shall be in such form as prescribed by the State Board of Elections and twenty (20) printed copies shall be included in the election supplies of each precinct. </section><section prefix="3">The subscribed oaths shall be returned to the county clerk who shall deliver them to the Commonwealth's attorney. </section><section prefix="4">The Commonwealth's attorney and county attorney shall investigate each of the oaths and cause to be summoned before the grand jury the witnesses they or either of them, deem proper, and the grand jury shall make a thorough investigation of all votes so cast, and return indictments against all persons illegally voting. The foreman of the grand jury shall return to the county clerk all of the oaths upon which no indictments are found. The clerk shall safely keep them as a part of the records of his office, and shall produce any or all of them, when required, to any subsequent grand jury. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 130, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 38, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>