<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.014</section_number><catch_line>Organization of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>014</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the cabinet the: <section prefix="a">Office of the Secretary; </section><section prefix="b">Commonwealth Office of Technology, and the Office of the Controller, each of which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor; and </section><section prefix="c">Department of Revenue and the Department for Facilities and Support Services, each of which shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the secretary, upon the approval of the Governor, and responsible to the secretary. Each of these departments may have at least one (1) major assistant not in the classified service. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall establish the internal organization and assignment of functions which are not established by statute, and shall divide the cabinet into the offices, bureaus, divisions, or other units the secretary deems necessary to perform the functions, powers, and duties of the cabinet, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 12. </section><section prefix="3">All appointments under this chapter to positions not in the classified service shall be made pursuant to KRS 12.050, and such appointees shall be major assistants to the secretary and shall assist in the development of policy. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 95, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 506, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 83, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 216, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 508, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 340, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 393, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 44, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 7. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 95, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>