<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.450</section_number><catch_line>Fees for services -- Exemptions -- Response to all fires in jurisdiction required -- Mission statement -- Inclusion of fees on property tax bills -- Collection and distribution -- Collection fee for sheriff.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A fire department which collects membership charges or subscriber fees for combatting fires or serving in other emergencies shall base its annual fee or charge on the level of protection offered. </section><section prefix="2">A fire department that responds to a fire or other emergency on the property of a nonmember or nonsubscriber may charge the following fees for services rendered: <section prefix="a">Up to five hundred dollars ($500) for single family residential units; utility occupancies of two thousand (2,000) or fewer square feet; assembly and business occupancies having a capacity which does not exceed one hundred (100) persons; equipment; vehicles; and grass or woods fires; and </section><section prefix="b">Up to one thousand dollars ($1,000) for multifamily residential units; assembly and business occupancies having a capacity exceeding one hundred (100) persons; storage occupancies; utility occupancies of more than two thousand (2,000) square feet; and all industrial, educational, or institutional occupancies; and </section><section prefix="c">Up to five hundred dollars ($500) for responding to emergencies not covered in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection, including response to high hazard occupancies as defined in KRS 198B.010. The department may be entitled to recover necessary and reasonable costs in excess of the five hundred dollar ($500) limit based upon submission of a written itemized claim for the total costs incurred. Disputes involving fees in excess of the five hundred dollar ($500) limit shall be submitted to arbitration by the commission. </section></section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of subsection (2)(a) and (b) of this section, the meaning of assembly, business, industrial, educational, and institutional occupancies shall be as defined in KRS 198B.010. The meaning of storage and utility occupancies shall be as defined in the Kentucky Building Code, Sections 311.1 and 312.1 respectively, promulgated pursuant to KRS 198B.050. </section><section prefix="4">Property owned by the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the federal government shall be exempt from charges. </section><section prefix="5">If more than one (1) department responds to a fire or other emergency, the fee shall be paid only to the department which is authorized to protect the property pursuant to KRS 75.440(2)(a). </section><section prefix="6">A fire department shall respond within its jurisdiction to all fires and to other emergencies for which it is responsible as set forth in its mission statement. A copy of each fire department mission statement shall be filed with the commission. A new department shall file its statement when it is incorporated. A department in existence on July 15, 1994, shall file its mission statement by July 1, 1995. A copy of the mission statement shall be posted in a conspicuous location in each station of the department, and shall be filed with the county clerk of each county in which the department has jurisdiction pursuant to KRS 75.440(2)(a). The mission statement shall remain in effect until amended, and filed and posted by the fire department in the locations as required by this subsection. </section><section prefix="7">If a fire department collects membership charges or subscriber fees, the fiscal court may adopt an ordinance to require the annual membership charges or subscriber fees to be added to property tax bills. In any county where the fiscal court has adopted such an ordinance, the county clerk shall add the annual membership charges or subscriber fees to the tax bills of the affected property owners in a place separate from the bill of the fire district tax or fire subdistrict tax so that ratepayers can ascertain the amount of the membership charges or subscriber fees apart from the fire district tax. </section><section prefix="8">The membership charges or subscriber fees shall be collected and distributed by the sheriff to the appropriate fire departments in the same manner as the other taxes on the bill and unpaid fees or charges shall bear the same penalty as general state and county taxes. This shall be a lien on the property against which it is levied from the time of the levy. The fiscal court shall, in the ordinance set forth in subsection (7) of this section and in consultation with the sheriff and the fire department, set a collection fee for the sheriff to retain an amount not to exceed four and one-fourth percent (4.25%) of the membership charges or subscriber fees collected. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>