<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.366</section_number><catch_line>Training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>366</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Social Work, Kentucky Board of Licensure of Marriage and Family Therapists, Kentucky Board of Licensed Professional Counselors, Kentucky Board of Licensure for Pastoral Counselors, Kentucky Board of Alcohol and Drug Counselors, Kentucky Board of Examiners of Psychology, and Kentucky Board of Licensure for Occupational Therapy; and </section><section prefix="b">"Training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management" means an empirically supported training program approved by the boards that contains suicide assessment including screening and referral, suicide treatment, and suicide management. A board may approve a training program that excludes one (1) of the elements if the element is inappropriate for the profession in question or inappropriate for the level of licensure or credentialing of that profession based on the profession's scope of practice. A training program that includes only screening and referral elements shall be at least three (3) hours in length. All other training programs approved under this section shall be at least six (6) hours in length. </section></section><section prefix="2">Beginning January 1, 2015, each of the following professionals certified or licensed under KRS Title XXVI shall, at least once every six (6) years, complete a training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management that is approved, in administrative regulations, by the respective boards: <section prefix="a">A social worker, marriage and family therapist, professional counselor, or pastoral counselor certified or licensed under KRS Chapter 335; </section><section prefix="b">An alcohol and drug counselor licensed or certified under KRS Chapter 309, and an alcohol and drug peer support specialist registered under KRS Chapter 309; </section><section prefix="c">A psychologist licensed or certified under KRS Chapter 319; and </section><section prefix="d">An occupational therapist licensed under KRS Chapter 319A. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, a professional listed in subsection (2) of this section must complete the first training required by this section by July 2016. </section><section prefix="b">A professional listed in subsection (2) of this section applying for initial licensure, registration, or certification on or after June 25, 2013, may delay completion of the first training required by this section for six (6) years after initial licensure, registration, or certification if he or she can demonstrate successful completion of a six (6) hour academic training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management that: <section prefix="1">Was completed no more than six (6) years prior to the application for initial licensure, registration, or certification; and </section><section prefix="2">Is listed on the best practices registry of the American Foundation for Suicide Prevention and the Suicide Prevention Resource Center. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The hours spent completing a training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management under this section count toward meeting any applicable continuing education requirements for each profession. </section><section prefix="5">A board may, by administrative regulation, specify minimum training and experience that is sufficient to exempt a professional from the training requirements in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">The cabinet shall develop a model list of training programs in suicide assessment, treatment, and management. </section><section prefix="b">When developing the model list, the cabinet shall: <section prefix="1">Consider suicide assessment, treatment, and management training programs of at least six (6) hours in length listed on the best practices registry of the American Foundation for Suicide Prevention and the Suicide Prevention Resource Center; and </section><section prefix="2">Consult with the boards, public and private institutions of higher education, experts in suicide assessment, treatment, and management, and affected professional associations. </section></section><section prefix="c">The cabinet shall report the model list of training programs to the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare no later than December 15, 2014. </section></section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this section may be interpreted to expand or limit the scope of practice of any profession regulated under KRS Title XXVI. </section><section prefix="8">The cabinet and the boards affected by this section shall adopt any administrative regulations necessary to implement this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 18, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>