<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.540</section_number><catch_line>Enlargement of district. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text>Any drainage district organized under the provisions of this chapter may be enlarged and the boundaries extended so as to include other contiguous land, in the manner set forth in this section. The board may present a petition to the county judge/executive who organized the district, asking that the boundaries of the district be extended and such outlying land be included in the district, particularly describing the land and giving the name of the owner. When such petition is filed, the owner of any land to be included in the district shall be brought before the county judge/executive in the same manner as an original party to the proceeding, with the same right to protest against the proposed action or file exceptions thereto. If no objection is made to the petition, the county judge/executive shall order the land included and the boundaries enlarged or extended as prayed. If any objection is made, the county judge/executive shall hear the objection and shall order all or any part of the land included as appears just, and the boundaries shall be ordered changed accordingly. The land so included shall be subject to all dues, assessments and liabilities and entitled to all the benefits and privileges of the district the same as the land originally incorporated. The owner of any land contiguous to any such district may by petition to the county judge/executive and with the consent of the board have his land annexed to the district on such terms as the county judge/executive may deem just, and thereafter his land shall be part of the district the same as the other land in the district.  </text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 413, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380-23. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12919</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>