<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.814</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 217.815 to 217.826. </catch_line><order_by>814</order_by><text>The following words and phrases, as used in KRS 217.815 to 217.826, shall have the following meanings, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Brand name" means the name that a manufacturer of a drug or pharmaceutical places on the container thereof at the time of packaging. </section><section prefix="2">"Generic name" means the chemical or established name of a drug or pharmaceutical. </section><section prefix="3">"Practitioner" has the same meaning as in KRS 217.015. </section><section prefix="4">"Pharmacist" means any person licensed as such by the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. </section><section prefix="5">"Equivalent drug product" means a product with the same generic name, active ingredients, strength, quantity and dosage form as the drug product identified in a prescription. </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. </section><section prefix="7">"Nonequivalent drug product formulary" means a formulary of drugs, drug products, and dosage formulations for which there are no equivalent drugs, drug products, or dosage formulations and which have been determined to be noninterchangeable or to have actual or potential bioequivalency problems by the United States Food and Drug Administration and are contained in a drug bioequivalence problems list as published in the United States Food and Drug Administration publication entitled "Approved prescription drug products with therapeutic equivalence evaluations" with supplements. </section><section prefix="8">"Dosage formulation" shall include, but not be limited to, those specific dosage forms which, by the nature of their physical manufacture are deemed to be nonequivalent to other similar formulations such as controlled release tablets, aerosol-nebulizer drug delivery systems and enteric coated oral dosage forms. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 399, sec. 1. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>