<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="57" order_by="57">PUBLIC PRINTING AND DISTRIBUTION OF PUBLIC DOCUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>57.390</section_number><catch_line>Unsolicited mailings by state agencies -- Publications to be submitted to Legislative Research Commission and General Assembly online. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Publication" means any annual or biennial report, book, pamphlet, newsletter, bulletin, map, calendar, or brochure, of a documentary or informational nature, whether or not required by statute. The term does not include news releases; notices, agendas, or minutes of meetings; or budgets and budget recommendations; and </section><section prefix="b">"State agency" means any executive branch organizational unit or administrative body, as defined in KRS 12.010, or any agency of the legislative branch of state government. </section></section><section prefix="2">A state agency shall not mail a publication to any person who has not requested a copy of the publication unless the unsolicited mailing is: <section prefix="a">Used to market or advertise an agency, event, site, program, or service; or </section><section prefix="b">Determined, in writing, to be essential to the performance of the agency's statutory mission by: <section prefix="1">The Governor, if the state agency is in the executive branch; or </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly or the Legislative Research Commission, if the state agency is in the legislative branch. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Governor may delegate responsibility under subsection (2) of this section to the secretaries of the program cabinets for publication of state agencies within or attached to their respective cabinets. </section><section prefix="4">If any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes requires a state agency to submit a publication annually or biennially to the Legislative Research Commission or to the General Assembly, the state agency shall submit that publication online rather than on paper or by means of any other printed medium. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39689</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>