<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.736</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Kentucky Diabetes Research Board. </catch_line><order_by>736</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Diabetes Research Board is created for the purpose of administering the diabetes research trust fund. The board shall be composed of the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the secretary's designee and seven (7) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members representing the University of Kentucky College of Medicine; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members representing the University of Louisville School of Medicine; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member who has diabetes or who has a family member with diabetes; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member who is a physician with experience with research or treatment of diabetes; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) at-large member who has a health care policy perspective on diabetes issues as a patient, health care provider, consultant, or in business. </section></section><section prefix="2">The term of each appointed board member shall be four (4) years. A board member shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of his or her duties. </section><section prefix="3">At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed. A member who is appointed after a term has begun shall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed. A member who serves two (2) consecutive full four (4) year terms shall not be reappointed for four (4) years after completion of those terms. </section><section prefix="4">A simple majority of the full membership of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall elect, by a majority vote, a chairperson who shall be the presiding officer of the board, preside at all meetings, and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The chairperson shall be elected or reelected for each calendar year. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall meet at least two (2) times each year but may meet more frequently, subject to call by the chairperson or by request of a majority of the board members. Each board meeting shall include but not be limited to programs relating to diabetes, research progress reports, authorization of projects, and financial plans. </section><section prefix="7">No member of the board shall be subject to any personal liability or personal accountability for any loss sustained or damage suffered on account of any action or inaction of the board. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall be attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide sufficient staff for the proper administration of the board. </section><section prefix="9">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall promulgate any necessary administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of KRS 211.735 to 211.739. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 369, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/2004). When this statute was enacted (2004 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2), the phrase "of the secretary" was erroneously included in the first sentence of subsection (1). This manifest typographical error, which occurred during the preparation of a committee substitute, has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>