<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.4113</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations to allow sale and purchase of mounted wildlife specimens -- Recording of sales.   </catch_line><order_by>4113</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "mounted wildlife specimen" means: <section prefix="a">A legally taken animal, including the skin of the head, cape, or the entire skin, mounted in a lifelike representation of the animal or any part thereof; or </section><section prefix="b">A European mount in which the horns or antlers and the skull or a portion of the skull are mounted for display. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 150.180 and no later than January 1, 2014, the department shall promulgate administrative regulations to allow any person or entity to sell or buy mounted wildlife specimens, except as prohibited by federal law. </section><section prefix="3">The administrative regulations promulgated under this section shall establish a means by which each transaction for the sale of mounted wildlife specimens for white-tailed deer, elk, bears, turkeys, and bobcats shall be recorded by the department. The department shall make the recording of each transaction as reasonably convenient for all parties to the transaction as possible, which may include but not be limited to allowing telephone and Internet recording of sales. </section><section prefix="4">Mounted wildlife specimens purchased from or sold to a licensed taxidermist under KRS 150.4111 shall be exempt from the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42349</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>