<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.32-090</section_number><catch_line>Annual and quarterly statements. </catch_line><order_by>32-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Corporations subject to the provisions of this subtitle doing business in this state on June 18, 1970, or which thereafter do business in this state, shall make and file annually with the commissioner, on or before the first day of March of each year, a statement under oath upon a form to be prescribed by the commissioner, stating the amount of all membership dues, or subscriber fees, collected in this state by the corporation during the year ending the last day of December next preceding; the amounts actually paid during the year for hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and other health services for the subscribers or members of the corporation, and the amounts placed in established reserves for cases billed but not yet paid, unreported and unbilled cases, retroactive cost adjustments, and membership dues or fees paid in advance but not yet earned. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall require that domestic companies subject to this subtitle file quarterly statements according to the form and instructions approved by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1415, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 32, sec. 9, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>