<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.210</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>As used in KRS 153.210 to 153.235: <section prefix="1">The term "the arts" means endeavors which involve the application of skills or practice of esthetic principles or theories in the expression of beauty in form, color, sound, speech, or movement with a desired end of creating objects of imagination or taste for their own sake and without relation to the utility of the object produced. If the above stated criteria are met, the term "the arts" may include, but is not limited to, the following specific activities: music (all forms, and instrumental or vocal), dance, drama, folk art, creative writing, painting, sculpture, photography, graphic and craft arts, costume and fashion design, motion pictures, television, radio, tape and sound recording, and the arts related to the presentation, performance, execution, and exhibition of major art forms. </section><section prefix="2">The term "production" means plays (with or without music), ballet, dance and choral performances, concerts, recitals, operas, exhibitions, readings, motion pictures, television, radio, tape and sound recordings, and any other activities involving the execution or rendition of the arts in the Commonwealth, and meeting the standards that may be approved by the council hereinafter established by KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </section><section prefix="3">The term "project" means any programs organized to carry out the purposes of KRS 153.210 to 153.235, including programs to foster Kentucky's artistic creativity, to commission works of art with a pertinence to Kentucky, to create opportunities for residents of the Commonwealth to develop artistic talents when carried on as a part of a program otherwise included in this definition, and to develop and enhance public knowledge and understanding in the Commonwealth of the arts. It also includes, where appropriate, the rental, purchase, or other acquisition of real property or any interest therein, and the rental, purchase, or other acquisition of equipment, supplies, materials, and other personal property. </section><section prefix="4">The term "workshop" means a production, the primary purpose of which is to encourage the artistic development of amateur, student, or other nonprofessional participants who are residents of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="5">The term "group" may include any state or other public agency, and any nonprofit society, institution, organization, association, museum, or establishment in Kentucky, whether or not incorporated. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2(1). </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2458</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>