<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.055</section_number><catch_line>Duty of county judge/executives and mayors to distribute information to local officials and board members -- Electronic distribution permitted. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">County judge/executives and mayors, or their respective designees, shall distribute the written information provided by the Office of the Attorney General and the Department for Libraries and Archives under KRS 15.257 and 171.223 to each elected official and each member, whether elected or appointed, of every county and city legislative body, local government board, commission, authority, and committee, including boards of special districts, located within their respective jurisdictions. In the case of a board, commission, or authority created by joint action of a county or city, the county judge/executive and mayor, or their respective designees, shall distribute the written information to the members appointed by their respective jurisdictions. Distribution shall be accomplished within sixty (60) days of receiving the written information from the Office of the Attorney General and the Department for Libraries and Archives. The distribution may be by electronic means. </section><section prefix="b">The distribution of materials to members who have been elected or appointed after the most recent distribution of materials as required in paragraph (a) of this subsection has occurred shall be accomplished within sixty (60) days of the day their term of office begins. The distribution may be by electronic means. </section></section><section prefix="2">County judge/executives and mayors shall require signatory proof that each person identified in subsection (1) of this section has received the written information, shall maintain documentation of receipt on file, and shall certify to the Office of the Attorney General that the written information has been distributed as required. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42981</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>