<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.168</section_number><catch_line>Certified employee granted leave of absence for active military service -- Medical insurance -- Contribution to retirement system to be retroactive -- Credit given -- Exclusions. </catch_line><order_by>168</order_by><text>Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, a certified employee of a local board of education who is a member of a state National Guard or a Reserve component ordered to active military duty by the President of the United States shall be granted a leave of absence for this purpose and shall be considered to be rendering service to the state. <section prefix="1">A local board of education that has granted military leave to a certified employee and has a commitment from the employee to return to work upon the conclusion of military leave may provide the employer's contribution toward the purchase of the state's medical insurance program during the period of military leave as long as the employee or spouse pays the additional cost of dependent coverage. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the employee’s return to work, the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall pay the member contribution and any accrued interest that is required to be paid under KRS 161.507(4)(b) in order for the member to receive retirement service credit for the period of active military duty. Under no circumstances shall a member be entitled to service credit under this paragraph that is in violation of the provisions of KRS 161.500. The provisions of this subsection shall be retroactive to January 1, 2003, for employees who have been deployed to active combat service. </section><section prefix="3">For each year of military service or each year of combined military and school service within a school year, the certified employee shall receive a year of service credit for purposes of the district's single salary schedule defined in KRS 157.320. </section><section prefix="4">No provisions of this section shall be construed to provide disability benefits under KRS 161.611 or 161.663, survivorship benefits under KRS 161.520, life insurance benefits under KRS 161.555 or any other benefit available from the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System as a result of active military service, or conditions or injuries resulting from active military service, except for the accrual of service credit which shall be acknowledged by the retirement system subject to the relevant conditions set forth in KRS 161.507. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3886</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>