<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.060</section_number><catch_line>Application of chapter and KRS 236.005 to 236.150.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This chapter applies to all boilers, pressure vessels, and related piping in the Commonwealth unless statutorily exempted. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 236.005 to 236.150 shall not apply to boilers or pressure vessels or related piping under federal control. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 236.005 to 236.150 shall not apply to the following: <section prefix="a">Portable boilers or pressure vessels located on land dedicated to agricultural use, as defined in KRS 100.111, and used solely for agricultural purposes; </section><section prefix="b">Boilers or pressure vessels located at any oil refineries; </section><section prefix="c">Steam or vapor boilers used for heating purposes carrying a pressure of not more than fifteen (15) pounds per square inch gauge, and which are located in private residences; </section><section prefix="d">Hot water heating boilers carrying a pressure of not more than thirty (30) pounds per square inch gauge or hot water heaters which are located in private residences; </section><section prefix="e">Any pressure vessels used as containers for liquefied petroleum gases and subject to the jurisdiction of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction under KRS Chapter 234; </section><section prefix="f">Pressure vessels used for transportation of compressed gases if constructed and operated in compliance with specifications and regulations of another state or federal authority; </section><section prefix="g">Pressure vessels containing air located on vehicles operating under the regulations of another state or federal authority; </section><section prefix="h">Pressure vessels having an internal or external operating pressure of fifteen (15) PSI or less; </section><section prefix="i">Single wall pressure vessels having an inside diameter, width, height, or cross-section diagonal not exceeding six (6) inches; </section><section prefix="j">Any combination unit having an internal or external pressure in each chamber not exceeding fifteen (15) PSI and differential pressure on the common element not exceeding fifteen (15) PSI; </section><section prefix="k">Pressure vessels with a nominal water containing capacity of one hundred twenty (120) gallons or less, to be used for domestic supply purposes, for containing water under pressure, including those containing air, the compression of which serves only as a cushion; </section><section prefix="l">Pressure vessels not exceeding the design pressure at the top of the vessel and with no limitation in size, not exceeding the following: <section prefix="1">Vessels having an internal or external pressure of fifteen (15) PSI (100 kilopascals); or </section><section prefix="2">Combination units having an internal or external pressure in each chamber of fifteen (15) PSI (100 kilopascals) and differential pressure on the common elements not exceeding fifteen (15) PSI (100 kilopascals); </section></section><section prefix="m">Pressure vessels containing water heated by steam or other indirect means when none of the following are exceeded: <section prefix="1">Heat input of two hundred thousand (200,000) BTU/Hr.; </section><section prefix="2">Water temperature of two hundred ten (210) degrees Fahrenheit; </section><section prefix="3">Water storage capacity of one hundred twenty (120) gallons; </section></section><section prefix="n">Coil type hot water boilers without a steam space and where no steam is generated within the confines of the unit but where water flashes into steam when released to atmospheric pressure by the operation of a manually operated nozzle, unless one (1) of the following is exceeded: <section prefix="1">Three quarter (3/4) inch inside diameter tubing or pipe size with no drum or header attached; </section><section prefix="2">Six (6) gallon water containing capacity; </section><section prefix="3">Three hundred fifty (350) degrees Fahrenheit water temperature; </section></section><section prefix="o">Water heaters, hot water supply boilers, or hot water storage tanks, which are directly fired with oil, gas, or electricity, when none of the following limitations are exceeded: <section prefix="1">Heat input of two hundred thousand (200,000) BTU/Hr.; </section><section prefix="2">A water temperature of two hundred ten (210) degrees Fahrenheit; </section><section prefix="3">A water containing capacity of one hundred twenty (120) gallons; </section></section><section prefix="p">Pressure vessels which may be classified as: <section prefix="1">Pressure containers which are integral parts of components of rotating or reciprocating mechanical devices such as pumps, compressors, turbines, generators, engines, and hydraulic or pneumatic cylinders where the primary design considerations, stresses, or both are derived from the functional requirements of the device; or </section><section prefix="2">Structures whose primary function is the transport of fluids from one location to another within a system of which it is an integral part, that is, piping system; or </section></section><section prefix="q">Pressure vessels ASME "UM" stamped, registered with the national board, and which do not exceed the following: <section prefix="1">One and one-half (1-1/2) cubic feet in volume and six hundred (600) PSI MAWP; </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) cubic feet in volume and three hundred fifty (350) PSI MAWP; or </section><section prefix="3">Five (5) cubic feet in volume and two hundred fifty (250) PSI MAWP. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">This chapter shall apply only to piping associated with boilers and pressure vessels operating in the Commonwealth in the following applications and fluid services: <section prefix="a">All boiler external piping, conforming to ASME B31.1; </section><section prefix="b">Non-boiler external piping, including steam, boiler feedwater, blowdown, vents, drains, and chemical injection outside the boiler boundary conforming to ASME B31.1 or B31.3; </section><section prefix="c">All building services piping conforming to ASME B31.9; </section><section prefix="d">All compressed air piping emanating from a pressure vessel conforming to ASME B31.1, B31.3, or B31.9; </section><section prefix="e">All hot oil piping conforming to ASME B31.1 or B31.3; </section><section prefix="f">All anhydrous ammonia piping conforming to ASME B31.3 or B31.5; </section><section prefix="g">All cryogenic service piping conforming to ASME B31.3 or B31.5; </section><section prefix="h">All hydrogen piping used for vehicle transportation fuel conforming to ASME B31.12; </section><section prefix="i">All piping associated with a pressure vessel for human occupancy conforming with ASME B31.1 or B31.3; and </section><section prefix="j">Refrigeration service piping in safety group A3, B1, B2, and B3 fluids as defined by ASME and conforming to ASME B31.5. </section></section><section prefix="5">Piping associated with boilers and pressure vessels exempted in subsection (2) of this section shall conform to the appropriate ASME piping code. The owner of the piping shall assume all oversight and responsibilities as established in the appropriate ASME piping code. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 519, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 34, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V., sec. 24(11). -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 4. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40109</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>