<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.658</section_number><catch_line>Oversight committee -- Creation and duties. </catch_line><order_by>658</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Local Distribution Fund Oversight Committee is hereby created and administratively attached to and staffed by the department. The oversight committee shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor and shall be representative of local government and state government officials. The Governor shall receive recommendations for four (4) members each from the Kentucky Association of Counties and the Kentucky League of Cities from which the Governor shall select two (2) members each. The Governor shall receive recommendations for two (2) members each from the Kentucky School Board Association, the Kentucky Superintendents Association, and the Kentucky School Administrators Association from which the Governor shall select one (1) member each. One (1) member shall be appointed by the Governor to represent the interests of special districts other than school districts. The remaining member shall be the commissioner of the Department for Local Government, who shall serve as chairperson of the oversight committee. The members shall serve for a term of three (3) years. Five (5) members of the oversight committee shall constitute a quorum. A member may be removed for cause in accordance with procedures established by the oversight committee and shall serve without salary but shall be reimbursed for expenses in the same manner as state employees. Any vacancy occurring on the oversight committee shall be filled by the Governor for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="2">The duties of the oversight committee shall be: <section prefix="a">To monitor the department's implementation and distribution of funds from the gross revenues and excise tax fund and the state baseline and local growth fund and to report its findings to the commissioner of the department; and </section><section prefix="b">To act as a finder of fact for the commissioner of the department in disputes in and between political subdivisions, school districts, special districts, and sheriff departments, and between political subdivisions, school districts, special districts, and sheriff departments, and the department regarding the implementation and distribution of funds from the gross revenues and excise tax fund and the state baseline and local growth fund. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department shall provide the oversight committee with an annual report reflecting the amounts distributed to each participating political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff department. </section><section prefix="4">Any political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff department may file a complaint and request a hearing with the oversight committee on a form prescribed by the committee. The oversight committee shall give notice to any political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff department that may be affected by the complaint. Any political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff department intending to respond to the complaint shall do so in writing within thirty (30) days of notice of the complaint. </section><section prefix="5">In conducting its business: <section prefix="a">The oversight committee shall give due notice of the times and places of its hearings; </section><section prefix="b">The parties shall be entitled to be heard, to present evidence, and to examine and cross-examine witnesses; </section><section prefix="c">The oversight committee shall act by majority vote; </section><section prefix="d">The oversight committee shall adopt and publish rules of procedure and practice regarding its hearings; and </section><section prefix="e">The oversight committee shall make written findings and recommendations to the commissioner of the department. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the department shall review the findings and recommendations of the oversight committee and issue a final ruling within sixty (60) days of receipt of the recommendations. </section><section prefix="7">The parties in the dispute shall have the rights and duties to appeal any final ruling to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals under KRS 131.340. </section><section prefix="8">Nothing contained in this section shall prevent at any time a written compromise of any matter or matters in dispute, if otherwise lawful, by the parties to the hearing process. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 71, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 65, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 117, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>