<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.354</section_number><catch_line>Final discharge of paroled prisoner -- Conditions. </catch_line><order_by>354</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, when any paroled prisoner has performed the obligations of his or her parole during his or her period of active parole supervision the board may, at the termination of such period to be determined by the board, issue a final discharge from parole to the prisoner. Unless ordered earlier by the board, a final discharge shall be issued when the prisoner has been out of prison on parole a sufficient period of time to have been eligible for discharge from prison by minimum expiration of sentence had he or she not been paroled, provided before this date he or she had not absconded from parole supervision or that a warrant for parole violation had not been issued by the board. </section><section prefix="2">When any paroled prisoner classified as a violent offender pursuant to KRS 439.3401, or registered as a sex offender pursuant to KRS 17.500 to 17.580, has performed the obligations of his or her parole, the board shall issue a final discharge from parole to the prisoner when the prisoner has been out of prison on parole a sufficient period of time to have been eligible for discharge from prison by maximum expiration of sentence had he or she not been paroled, provided before this date he or she had not absconded from parole supervision or that a warrant for parole violation had not been issued by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19181</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>