<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="413" order_by="413">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>413.120Actions</section_number><catch_line>to be brought within five years.   </catch_line><order_by>120Actions</order_by><text>The following actions shall be commenced within five (5) years after the cause of action accrued: <section prefix="1">An action upon a contract not in writing, express or implied. </section><section prefix="2">An action upon a liability created by statute, when no other time is fixed by the statute creating the liability. </section><section prefix="3">An action for a penalty or forfeiture when no time is fixed by the statute prescribing it. </section><section prefix="4">An action for trespass on real or personal property. </section><section prefix="5">An action for the profits of or damages for withholding real or personal property. </section><section prefix="6">An action for an injury to the rights of the plaintiff, not arising on contract and not otherwise enumerated. </section><section prefix="7">An action upon a bill of exchange, check, draft or order, or any endorsement thereof, or upon a promissory note, placed upon the footing of a bill of exchange. </section><section prefix="8">An action to enforce the liability of a steamboat or other vessel. </section><section prefix="9">An action upon a merchant's account for goods sold and delivered, or any article charged in such store account. </section><section prefix="10">An action upon an account concerning the trade of merchandise, between merchant and merchant or their agents. </section><section prefix="11">An action for relief or damages on the ground of fraud or mistake. </section><section prefix="12">An action to enforce the liability of bail. </section><section prefix="13">An action for personal injuries suffered by any person against the builder of a home or other improvements. This cause of action shall be deemed to accrue at the time of original occupancy of the improvements which the builder caused to be erected. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2515, 2518. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44670</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>