<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="384" order_by="384">CONTROL OF PROPERTY AND EXERCISE OF RIGHTS OF PERSONS IN ARMED FORCES -- CONTRACTS OF INFANT WAR VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>384.050</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of conservator for property of member of Armed Forces or Merchant Seaman. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>Whenever a person (hereinafter referred to as an absentee) serving in or with the Armed Forces of the United States, or serving as a merchant seaman, has been reported or listed as missing, or missing in action, or interned in a neutral country, or beleaguered, besieged, or captured by an enemy, and such person has an interest in any form of property in this state or is a legal resident of this state and has not provided an adequate power of attorney authorizing another to act in his behalf in regard to such property or interests, the District Court of the county of such absentee's legal domicile or of the county where such property is situated, upon petition alleging the foregoing facts and showing the necessity for providing care of the property of such absentee, made by any person who would have an interest in the property of the absentee were such absentee deceased, or on the court's own motion, after notice to, or on receipt of proper waivers from, the heirs and next of kin of the absentee as provided by law for the administration of an estate, and upon good cause being shown, may, after finding the facts to be as aforesaid, appoint a conservator to take charge of the absentee's estate, under the supervision and subject to the further orders of the court. </text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 324, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35765</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>