<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.290</section_number><catch_line>Construction of sidewalks along public roads -- School bus turn-around areas. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may build a sidewalk composed of gravel, concrete, or other suitable material along the side of any public road in this state. The sidewalk shall not exceed sixty (60) inches in width and the construction and repair and the use of the sidewalk shall be without expense of any kind to any other person who may want to use it. All persons who desire shall be permitted to use the sidewalk, and it shall be so constructed as not to interfere with the traveling public on any public road. The governing body of each city, county, urban-county, consolidated local government, and charter county may build and repair sidewalks along public roads where the need exists for the safety of school children. Before the beginning of construction of the sidewalk, written approval must be obtained from the governmental agency having jurisdiction over the public road. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court may, where needed, build and maintain suitable areas for the safe turning around of school buses. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4318. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5450</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>