<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-305</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Innovation and Commercialization Center Program. </catch_line><order_by>12-305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Kentucky Innovation and Commercialization Center Program within the Department of Commercialization and Innovation. The goal of the ICC program is to create products, new companies, and value-added jobs in communities throughout the Commonwealth. Strategies to achieve this goal include: <section prefix="a">Increasing quality deal flow of technology-based firms in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Increasing understanding of start-up process and investment practices; and </section><section prefix="c">Providing value-added services to the start-up and investment community. </section></section><section prefix="2">The duties of the ICC program shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Identifying and linking entrepreneurs, faculty, scientists, venture capitalists, and other key individuals from the business sector, universities, community and technical colleges, local leaders, and government for the creation and expansion of knowledge-based companies; </section><section prefix="b">Establishing a uniform protocol for assembling and communicating project concepts and opportunities; </section><section prefix="c">Supporting high-quality projects through the concept and development phases including services such as market research, prototype development, business plan and strategies development, grant and contract capabilities, and capital and management resource identification; and </section><section prefix="d">Identifying, in the area of technology development, potential partners, strategic opportunities, training and educational needs, and issues that inhibit the growth of technology sectors and business clusters in the state. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 12, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>