<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.470</section_number><catch_line>Allocation of funds among counties. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text>Moneys in the local government economic assistance fund shall be allocated among the counties as follows: <section prefix="1">Funds allocated under KRS 42.4585: <section prefix="a">Sixty percent (60%) shall be distributed to each coal producing county on the basis of the ratio of tax collected on coal severed in each respective county to the tax collected statewide. </section><section prefix="b">Thirty percent (30%) shall be distributed to each coal producing county on the basis of per capita income (inverse order), ton miles of resource roads and population, equally weighted. </section><section prefix="c">Ten percent (10%) shall be distributed to non-coal producing counties impacted by the transport of coal on the basis of geographic area, ton miles of resource roads, and per capita income (inverse order), weighted on a basis of 30/100, 40/100, and 30/100, respectively. The expenditure of such funds shall be limited to the categories of projects set out in KRS 42.455(2)(c). All counties shall receive an annual payment based on the average of total ton miles within the county during the most recent three (3) year period. To qualify for the funds distributed under the provisions of this paragraph, a county must have within its geographic boundaries in any single year twenty-five hundredths of one percent (0.25%) of the total ton miles within coal impact counties during the most recent three (3) year period. </section></section><section prefix="2">All funds allocated under KRS 42.450(2) shall be distributed among the mineral producing counties on the basis of the tax collected on minerals severed in each respective county. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1992. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22042</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>