<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="523" order_by="523">PERJURY AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>523.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Material false statement" means any false statement, regardless of its admissibility under the rules of evidence which could have affected the outcome of the proceeding. Whether a falsification is material in a given factual situation is a question of law. </section><section prefix="2">"Oath" means an affirmation or other legally authorized manner of attesting to the truth of a statement. A written statement shall be treated as if made under oath when: <section prefix="a">The statement was made on or pursuant to a form bearing notice, authorized by law, that false statements made therein are punishable; or </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The document recites that the statement was made under oath, and </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The declarant was aware of such recitation at the time he made the statement; </section><section prefix="b">The declarant intended that the statement be represented as sworn; and </section><section prefix="c">The statement was in fact so represented by its delivery or utterance with the signed jurat of an officer, authorized to administer oaths appended thereto. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="3">"Official proceeding" means a proceeding heard before any legislative, judicial, administrative or other governmental agency or official authorized to hear evidence under oath, including any referee, hearing examiner, commissioner, notary or other person taking testimony or depositions in any such proceedings. </section><section prefix="4">"Required or authorized by law" means the oath is provided for by statute, regulation, court rule, or otherwise by law. </section><section prefix="5">"Statement" means any representation, but includes a representation of opinion, belief or other state of mind only if the representation clearly relates to state of mind apart from or in addition to any facts which are the subject of the representation. </section><section prefix="6">"Public servant" means: <section prefix="a">Any public officer or employee of the state or of any political subdivision thereof or of any governmental instrumentality within the state; or </section><section prefix="b">Any person exercising the functions of any such public officer or employee; or </section><section prefix="c">Any person participating as advisor, consultant or otherwise in performing a governmental function, but not including witnesses; or </section><section prefix="d">Any person elected, appointed or designated to become a public servant although not yet occupying that position. </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 190, effective January 1, 1975.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><lrc-note> (12/12/94).  To make its numbering consistent with standard practice, subsection (2) of this statute has been renumbered under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19892</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>