<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.200</section_number><catch_line>Required equipment -- Prohibition against operation without required equipment. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every vessel shall have aboard: <section prefix="a">Personal floatation devices of the type and quantity as prescribed by the United States Coast Guard; </section><section prefix="b">When in operation during hours of darkness, or during times of poor visibility, such lights as prescribed by administrative regulations of the department; </section><section prefix="c">If carrying or using any inflammable or toxic fluid in any inclosure for any purpose, and if not an entirely open motorboat, an efficient natural or mechanical ventilation system which shall be capable of removing resulting gases prior to and during the time such motorboat is occupied by any person; </section><section prefix="d">Such additional equipment designed to promote the safety of navigation and of persons as the department may find to be appropriate and for which it has provided in its administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="e">If such motorboat is equipped with toilet facilities, a storage container or a treatment or disposal system of size and construction sufficient to protect and preserve the waters of this state from pollution. The storage container or treatment or disposal system shall conform to the construction, performance, and utilization criteria as may be established by regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">The certificate number. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except during an authorized race or regatta, which shall include trial runs in preparation for such race or regatta to be conducted at a time and place designated by the department, it shall be illegal to operate any motorboat without an effective exhaust muffling system, or in any manner which renders the exhaust muffling system ineffective in muffling the sound of engine exhaust. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall operate or give permission for the operation of a motorboat which is not equipped as required by this section or modification thereof or which is not safe for operation as a motorboat. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978, sec. 263, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 15. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 2. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 22. </history><metadata><effective>: July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11065</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>