<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.635</section_number><catch_line>Optional retirement plans.   </catch_line><order_by>635</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each member shall have the right to elect to have his retirement allowance payable under any one (1) of the options set forth in this section in lieu of the retirement allowance otherwise payable to him upon retirement under any of the provisions of KRS 16.505 to 16.652, 61.510 to 61.705, and 78.510 to 78.852. The amount of any optional retirement allowance shall be actuarially equivalent to the amount of retirement allowance otherwise payable to him. </section><section prefix="2">Survivorship one hundred percent (100%). The member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime and have the retirement allowance continued after his death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. </section><section prefix="3">Survivorship sixty-six and two-thirds percent (66-2/3%). The member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime and have two-thirds (2/3) of the retirement allowance continue after his death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. </section><section prefix="4">Survivorship fifty percent (50%). The member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime and have one-half (1/2) of the retirement allowance continued after his death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. </section><section prefix="5">Life with ten (10) years certain. The member less than age seventy-six (76) may elect to receive a monthly retirement allowance during his lifetime which shall guarantee payments for one hundred twenty (120) months. If the member dies before receiving payments for one hundred twenty (120) months, his beneficiary shall receive the remaining payments monthly, for the duration of the one hundred twenty (120) months' period. However, if the trust is designated as beneficiary, the trustee of the trust may elect to receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments, or the trustee may elect to continue the remaining monthly payments to the trust of the member. If the estate is designated as beneficiary, the estate shall receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments. </section><section prefix="6">Life with fifteen (15) years certain. The member less than age sixty-eight (68) may elect to receive a monthly retirement allowance during his lifetime which shall guarantee payments for one hundred and eighty (180) months. If the member dies before receiving payments for one hundred and eighty (180) months, his beneficiary shall receive the remaining payments monthly for the duration of the one hundred and eighty (180) months' period. However, if the trust is designated as beneficiary, the trustee of the trust may elect to receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments, or the trustee may elect to continue the remaining payments to the trust of the member. If the estate is designated as beneficiary, the estate shall receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments. </section><section prefix="7">Life with twenty (20) years certain. The member less than age sixty-two (62) may elect to receive a monthly retirement allowance during his lifetime which shall guarantee payments for two hundred and forty (240) months. If the member dies before receiving payments for two hundred and forty (240) months, his beneficiary shall receive the remaining payments for the duration of the two hundred and forty (240) months period. However, if the trust is beneficiary, the trustee of the trust may elect to receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments, or the trustee may elect to continue the remaining payments to the trust of the member. If the estate is designated as beneficiary, the estate shall receive a lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent to the remaining payments. </section><section prefix="8">Social Security adjustment options. These options shall be available to any member who has not attained age sixty-two (62) as follows: <section prefix="a">No survivor rights. The member may elect to receive an increased retirement allowance from his effective retirement date through the month he attains age sixty-two (62) at which time his retirement allowance shall be decreased for the remainder of his lifetime; </section><section prefix="b">Survivor rights. The member may elect to receive an increased retirement allowance from his effective retirement date through the month he attains age sixty-two (62) based on the option payable under subsection (2) of this section, if the retirement allowance shall be decreased in the month following the month he attains age sixty-two (62), or the month following the month he would have attained age sixty-two (62), in event of his death, and have the retirement allowance continue after his death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. </section></section><section prefix="9">Beneficiary Social Security adjustment option. This option is available to the beneficiary of a deceased member if the beneficiary, who is a person, has not attained age sixty (60), and is eligible to receive Social Security payments at age sixty (60). The beneficiary may elect to receive during his lifetime an increased retirement allowance based on his annual benefit payable for life. The payment shall begin on his effective retirement date and continue through the month he attains age sixty (60) at which time his retirement allowance shall be decreased for the remainder of his lifetime. </section><section prefix="10">Pop-up option. The member may elect to receive a decreased retirement allowance during his lifetime and have the retirement allowance continued after his death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. If the beneficiary dies prior to the member, or if the beneficiary is the member's spouse and they divorce, the member's retirement allowance shall increase to the amount that would have been payable as a single life annuity. </section><section prefix="11">Actuarial equivalent refund. A member who began participating in the system prior to January 1, 2014, may elect to receive a one (1) time lump-sum payment which shall be the actuarial equivalent of the amount payable for a period of sixty (60) months under KRS 61.595 (1). </section><section prefix="12">Partial lump-sum option. <section prefix="a">No survivor rights. A member retiring on or before January 1, 2009, may elect to receive a one-time lump-sum payment equal to twelve (12), twenty-four (24), or thirty-six (36) monthly retirement allowances payable under the applicable retirement formula for the system and receive a reduced monthly retirement allowance payable for his or her lifetime. The lump-sum payment shall be paid in the month the first monthly retirement allowance is payable. </section><section prefix="b">Survivor rights. A member retiring on or before January 1, 2009, may elect to receive a one-time lump-sum payment equal to twelve (12), twenty-four (24), or thirty-six (36) monthly retirement allowances payable under subsection (2) of this section and receive a reduced monthly retirement allowance payable for his or her lifetime. The lump-sum payment shall be paid in the month the first monthly retirement allowance is payable. The reduced retirement allowance shall be continued after the member's death to his beneficiary during the lifetime of the person. </section></section><section prefix="13">The other provisions of this section notwithstanding, the beneficiary of a retired member of the General Assembly shall, after the member's death, receive sixty-six and two-thirds percent (66-2/3%) of the member's retirement allowance during his or her lifetime if the member of the General Assembly began participating in the system prior to January 1, 2014, and has elected this option and has made contributions in accordance with subsection (14) of this section and of KRS 61.560. The retirement allowance of the retired member of the General Assembly shall not be actuarially reduced to provide for this survivor benefit. </section><section prefix="14">A member of the General Assembly who began participating in the system prior to January 1, 2014, who wishes to obtain the survivorship option specified in subsection (13) of this section shall so notify the Kentucky retirement systems: <section prefix="a">Within thirty (30) days after first becoming a member of the General Assembly if he is not a member of the General Assembly on July 15, 1980; or </section><section prefix="b">Within thirty (30) days after July 15, 1980, if he is a member of the General Assembly on July 15, 1980. </section></section><section prefix="15">The system shall forward to members of the General Assembly a form on which a member who began participating in the system prior to January 1, 2014, may elect the option provided for in subsections (13) and (14) of this section. </section><section prefix="16">The options described in subsections (2), (3), (4), (8)(b), (10), (12)(b), and (13) of this section shall be extended to the member only if the designated beneficiary is a person. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 63, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 19, effective June 27, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 37, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 186, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 553, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, secs. 26 and 40. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 23. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 45. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 4. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 5. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 17. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 165, Part II, sec. 12. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 26. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>