<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.025</section_number><catch_line>Application for appointment as guardian, limited guardian, or conservator. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any interested person or entity may petition the District Court for the appointment of a guardian or limited guardian for an unmarried minor. </section><section prefix="2">Any interested person or entity may petition the District Court for appointment of a conservator for a minor who owns real or personal property, or both, requiring management or protection or who has or may have business interests that may be jeopardized or prevented by minority, or who needs a conservator to settle or compromise claims. </section><section prefix="3">The petition for appointment shall set forth the following: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the minor; </section><section prefix="b">The date of birth of the minor; </section><section prefix="c">The name and address of the minor's spouse, if any; </section><section prefix="d">The names and addresses of the minor's parents, or if the minor has no living parent, the names and addresses of the minor's adult next of kin; </section><section prefix="e">The name and address of the individual or facility having custody of the minor; </section><section prefix="f">The facts and reasons supporting the need for a guardianship, limited guardianship, or conservatorship for the minor; </section><section prefix="g">A description and approximation of the value of the minor's real and personal property and other financial resources, including government benefits, insurance entitlements, and anticipated yearly income; </section><section prefix="h">The name and address of the petitioner; </section><section prefix="i">The name and address of the petitioner's attorney, if any; and </section><section prefix="j">The name and address of the person or entity desiring appointment as guardian, limited guardian, or conservator. </section></section><section prefix="4">The petition shall be accompanied by a verified application of the person or entity desiring appointment as guardian, limited guardian, or conservator. The application shall set forth the following: <section prefix="a">Name, address, and age of the applicant; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant's relationship to the minor, if any; </section><section prefix="c">Whether or not the applicant has ever been convicted of a crime; and </section><section prefix="d">The applicant's qualifications to serve as guardian, limited guardian, or conservator. </section></section><section prefix="5">The District Court shall appoint a time for hearing the petition and application. Notice of the time and place of the hearing shall be given not less than five (5) days prior to the hearing to the minor, if the minor is more than fourteen (14) years of age, and to each of the persons or entities required to be named in the petition. Proof of notice shall be made in accordance with the provisions of KRS 395.016. Notice may be waived as provided in KRS 395.016. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 695, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 101, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 41. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 110 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35988</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>