<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.530</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees of pension fund established under KRS 95.520 -- Members -- Officers.   </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In cities with a pension fund established under KRS 95.520 where there are fewer than six (6) active members of the pension fund, the board of trustees of the policemen's and firefighter's pension fund is composed of the mayor, city treasurer, and one (1) retired member each from the police and fire departments. The retired members from the police and fire departments shall be elected by the respective retired members of those departments annually by ballot, one (1) from each department, and shall serve for one (1) year and until their respective successors are elected and qualified. The board shall select from their number a president and a secretary. </section><section prefix="2">If there are six (6) or more active members of the fund, there shall be two (2) additional board members who shall be one (1) active member of the fund from each department elected by the active members of the fund from the respective departments and who shall serve for one (1) year and until their respective successors are elected and qualified. If all of the six (6) or more active members or all of the retired members are from one (1) department, then both of the active member board members or both of the retired board members, as the case may be, shall be elected from that department. </section><section prefix="3">The board of trustees' membership shall be restructured according to the provisions of this section at the time of the next scheduled election of board members after July 15, 1990. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 122, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 24, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 103. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3142b-3, 3351a-3. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>