<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.430</section_number><catch_line>Employment manual -- Administrative regulations -- Expiration of pilot program. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The pilot agency shall develop a comprehensive employment manual establishing conditions of employment for employees in each organizational unit. Each manual shall be approved by the Personnel Steering Committee prior to the implementation of its pilot personnel program. It shall specify the terms and conditions of employment for employees of each organizational unit. </section><section prefix="b">The employment manual shall be promulgated by administrative regulation pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A and shall contain a clear explanation of the statutes governing employee actions relating to dismissal, suspension, disciplinary fine, lay-off, or status, and the reasons employee actions may be taken. </section><section prefix="c">The head of the agency in which the pilot program is located shall be responsible for preparing and submitting the administrative regulations required by this section to the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet for promulgation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="d">Policies relating to specific implementation of the pilot personnel program, other than conditions of employment, shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A and shall be explained in detail in the reports required by KRS 18A.410. </section><section prefix="e">For purposes of the approved pilot programs, only those sections of this chapter relating to the subject of the pilot programs shall be suspended and in no event shall the following sections be suspended: KRS 18A.095 relating to the rights of executive department employees and the prohibition of ex parte communications, KRS 18A.113 relating to general lay-off rules, KRS 18A.1131 relating to lay-off rules applicable to classified employees only, KRS 18A.1132 relating to lay-off rules applicable to both classified and unclassified employees, KRS 18A.130 relating to reemployment of career employees terminated on or after January 1, 1980, and KRS 18A.135 relating to the reemployment of career employees. </section></section><section prefix="2">A pilot personnel program shall: <section prefix="a">Become effective upon completion of the administrative regulatory procedure established by KRS Chapter 13A and subsection 1 of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">Expire no later than July 15, 1998, unless the expiration date is extended by statute. </section></section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>