<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person or entity who violates any of the provisions of KRS 100.201 to 100.347 or any of the regulations adopted pursuant thereto for which no other penalty is provided, shall upon conviction, be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) but not  more than five hundred dollars ($500) for each conviction. Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person, owner or agent who violates this chapter shall, upon conviction, be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100)  nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for each lot or parcel which was the subject of sale or transfer, or a contract for sale or transfer. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who intentionally violates any provision of KRS 100.3681 to 100.3684 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor punishable by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="4">A commission may appoint enforcement officers who shall have authority to issue citations for violations of this chapter which the officer has observed, but shall not have powers of peace officers to make arrests or carry deadly weapons. The defendant shall appear within a designated time pursuant to the citation. </section><section prefix="5">The procedure for citations issued by an enforcement officer shall be as provided in KRS 431.015. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, secs. 68 (1st sentence) and 83. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26891</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>