<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.220</section_number><catch_line>Grant of funds to local fairs for premiums and facilities -- Fair Council -- Meetings -- Members. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commissioner of Agriculture shall make grants of state funds to qualified local agricultural fairs on a matching basis, to be used by them to pay premium awards for exhibits and displays of domestic livestock, poultry, harness horse racing, other horse events, and agricultural products. The premiums actually awarded shall conform to those appearing on the premium list issued by the fair. </section><section prefix="2">The state may provide funds for use in the establishment of new facilities and improvement of existing facilities for use in conducting events at local agricultural fairs as provided by this section. No grant for buildings shall be made until the local fair board has complied with the local fair program and qualified for the state grant as provided in subsection (5) of this section. Grants for facilities shall be made under regulations promulgated by the Fair Council and the Commissioner of Agriculture. In no event shall the allocation for facilities result in a decrease in the number of approved agricultural classes or premiums. </section><section prefix="3">There shall be a Fair Council in the Department of Agriculture. The council shall act in an advisory capacity to the Commissioner in all matters pertaining to the administration of the department's fair program. It shall be called into session when there are matters for its consideration. It shall meet at least twice each calendar year at Frankfort or at any other place that may be determined. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The council shall be composed of the: <section prefix="1">Commissioner as chairman ex officio; </section><section prefix="2">Presidents or their designated representatives of the following state groups: <section prefix="a">Kentucky Livestock Improvement Association; </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation; </section><section prefix="c">Kentucky Association of Fairs and Horse Shows, Inc.; </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky Harness Horse Association; </section><section prefix="e">American Saddlebred Horse Association; and </section><section prefix="f">Kentucky Walking Horse Association; </section></section><section prefix="3">Director of Vocational Agriculture Education; </section><section prefix="4">Dean of the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="5">Co-chairs of the Interim Joint Committee on Agriculture. </section></section><section prefix="b">The Commissioner may, with the concurrence of a majority of the members of the council, appoint additional members to the council. </section></section><section prefix="5">To qualify for a grant of state funds, a fair shall meet standards set by the Commissioner and his advisory council whose approval may be given only if the fair: <section prefix="a">Provides in its bylaws for holding an annual fair running for at least three (3) days; </section><section prefix="b">Presents, through the medium of youth organizations such as 4-H clubs, Future Farmers of America, and other similar organizations, an educational program concerning the production and marketing of the livestock, poultry, and horse industries; </section><section prefix="c">Complies with all administrative regulations which the Department of Agriculture is hereby authorized to promulgate; and </section><section prefix="d">Appoints one (1) or more members to its fair board from local livestock associations, horsemen's associations, and county farm bureaus, and selects one (1) or more county extension agents and vocational agriculture teachers for counties served by the fair as members of the board. Wherever local livestock associations, horsemen's associations, and farm bureaus are in existence, appointees are to be nominated to the fair board by these organizations. Where fairs serve an area, appointments may be made from all counties within the particular area. It shall be the responsibility of the appointees to aid in establishing premium lists and planning agricultural exhibits. </section></section><section prefix="6">Any fair receiving a grant of state funds shall file with the director of the Division of Show and Fair Promotion in the Department of Agriculture, by December 1 of the year in which the grant is received, satisfactory proof that all state premium awards have been paid and a certified notarized financial report submitted by the treasurer of the local fair association. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 39-1, 39-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>