<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.460</section_number><catch_line>Use of certain substances and devices in public waters prohibited -- Use of explosives and firearms prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, firm or corporation, whether acting in a private or public capacity, shall place or cause to be placed in any public waters any substance that might injure, interfere with, or cause the waters to be unfit for the support of wildlife. When any employee of a person, firm or corporation, in the course of his employment, places or causes to be placed any such substance in any public waters, his act shall be prima facie evidence of the guilt of both the employee and the employer, and either one (1) or both may be punished as provided in subsection (7) of KRS 150.990. Each day that this section is violated shall constitute a separate offense. This section does not apply to employees or agents of the department acting in an official capacity. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall use, or attempt to use any electrical device, fish-finding devices excepted, of any type, such as telephone, or electrical leads from a magneto, or battery, or motor, or any other type of electrical equipment, in any stream or body of water. This does not prevent the authorized employees or agents of the department from using this or any devices in research or investigational work. </section><section prefix="3">No person, except employees or agents of the department, shall willfully place or attempt to place in any of the public waters of the state any substance which has a poisonous or intoxicating effect upon wildlife. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall kill, injure, shock, or stun or attempt to kill, injure, shock, or stun any fishes by any explosive agent, firearm, or other device. This provision shall not apply to employees or agents of the department acting in an official capacity. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 474, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 37, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 24. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 19. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 64. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 14. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 47. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1253, 1954d-29, 1954d-38, 1954d-39. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2029</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>