<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.456</section_number><catch_line>Autologous or directed donations -- Surcharges -- Conditions. </catch_line><order_by>456</order_by><text>The following policies shall apply to autologous and directed blood donations: <section prefix="1">Any otherwise qualified donor who wishes to direct a donation of blood to that person or to another particular individual may do so. The surcharge for any autologous or directed donation of blood shall not exceed twenty percent (20%) of the charge for a regular unit of blood. </section><section prefix="2">If the donation is to another particular individual, the requirements of KRS 214.454 shall be met if the recipient and the recipient's attending physician have requested the donation. </section><section prefix="3">Blood collected as a directed donation may be used for someone other than, or in addition to, the designated recipient if the donor's blood is not compatible with that of the designated recipient or if any part of the donation is not needed by the designated recipient. </section><section prefix="4">Each blood establishment shall advise prospective donors of the opportunity for autologous and directed donations and of the provisions of this section and of KRS 214.452 to 214.466. </section><section prefix="5">Autologous blood donation programs shall be exempt from KRS 214.454. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8824</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>