<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.7992</section_number><catch_line>Program to promote instruction in the arts and foreign languages. </catch_line><order_by>7992</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Education shall establish a program that promotes the integration of the arts and foreign languages in the elementary school program. A school shall submit an application through the district superintendent, with the agreement of the school council or of the principal, if a council does not exist. The department shall award a grant to at least one (1) school per region based on the quality of the application in meeting the criteria established in subsection (2) of this section. Special consideration shall be given, but not limited to, a school that does not have an existing comprehensive arts and foreign language program. </section><section prefix="2">School programs under subsection (1) of this section shall include, but not be limited to, the following components: <section prefix="a">Instruction in each of the four (4) disciplines of dance, drama, music, and the visual arts that includes the core content skills and knowledge taught in a sequential manner and includes all students in the elementary school; </section><section prefix="b">Intense instruction in at least one (1) foreign language that includes skills and knowledge related to communicative language and culture and includes all students in the elementary school; </section><section prefix="c">Integration of arts and foreign language instruction across the curriculum; </section><section prefix="d">Coordination of the programs by teachers with appropriate arts and foreign language certification; </section><section prefix="e">Professional development for teachers and administrators designed to facilitate the effective teaching of arts and foreign languages; </section><section prefix="f">An effective monitoring and evaluation system that includes student performance assessment; </section><section prefix="g">Partnerships with parents, local cultural agencies, individual artists, and native speakers of the foreign language who work in collaboration with classroom teachers; </section><section prefix="h">Support from the local school board, the school council, and teachers; and </section><section prefix="i">Student attendance at one (1) or more live performance or visual art exhibition each school year. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Department of Education shall report annually by July 1 of each year on the implementation of the program to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>