<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.936</section_number><catch_line>Refund to persons making payments. </catch_line><order_by>936</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the giving of fifteen (15) days' written notice, sent to the agent and the trustee, any person, partnership, or corporation who has paid funds for a preneed funeral service may demand a refund of the entire amount actually paid, together with all interest, dividends, increases or accretions, of any kind whatsoever, which have been earned on such funds. If the trustee is unknown, the written notice sent to the agent shall constitute compliance with this section. Upon receipt of notice, the agent shall immediately forward notice to the trustee. </section><section prefix="2">The financial institutions shall be relieved from further liability, after making payment to the person making payment of said funds, to the agent upon receipt of the foregoing written notice. Notice of payment of funds under this section shall be given by the financial institution to the agent. </section><section prefix="3">The trustee may rely upon all certifications and affidavits made pursuant to or required by the provisions of KRS 367.932 to 367.974 and 367.991, and shall not be liable to any person for such reliance. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 367.936, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 316.330. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>