<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.798</section_number><catch_line>Program to encourage studies in mathematics, science, and related technologies -- Role of Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc. </catch_line><order_by>798</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intention of the General Assembly to generate a substantial increase in the number of mathematicians, scientists, and engineers in the Kentucky workforce in order to foster economic growth in the business sector and to provide high quality jobs for Kentuckians. A program shall be established to encourage studies in math, science, and related technologies, beginning with middle school and continuing through advanced college level work, leading to sustained job placements in Kentucky's technological and innovative businesses and industries. Principal activities for developing, coordinating, and implementing this program shall be conducted by the Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc., a private, nonprofit corporation comprised of leaders from education, government, and the private sector. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc., may solicit, accept, receive, invest, and expend funds from any public or private source for the purpose of implementing the provisions in this section. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc., shall coordinate, promote, and support activities designed to: <section prefix="a">Recognize Kentucky middle school students with a high interest, aptitude, or achievement in math, science, and technology related courses, events, and activities; and </section><section prefix="b">Develop additional learning experiences outside the traditional classroom courses, to enhance interest in math and science for middle and high school students, including summer and weekend institutes, skills, application in real world situations, business and industry internships and mentorships, and career awareness exploration. </section><section prefix="c">Solicit program support, cooperation, and funds from private businesses, industries, and government entities with an interest and need for technological innovation; </section><section prefix="d">Develop a college-level academic scholarship program for students in math, science, engineering, and other technology related disciplines, soliciting contributions from private businesses and industries; </section><section prefix="e">Develop internship and post-degree placement commitment plans for industries and those students participating in internships or receiving scholarships; and </section><section prefix="f">Submit an annual report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission concerning: <section prefix="1">Activities related to achieving the program's objectives for the preceding year; </section><section prefix="2">Factual information about Kentucky students' progress in math, science, and related technologies and business and industries' changing technological needs; and </section><section prefix="3">Recommendations to improve the program in achieving its purposes. </section></section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3594</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>