<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7051</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of development plan for a development area -- Public hearing. </catch_line><order_by>7051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city or county seeking to establish a development area shall adopt a development plan. The development plan may be developed by a city, a county, or a city and county jointly, or may be proposed by an agency or by a private entity. The plan shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Assurances that the proposed development area meets the requirements of KRS 65.7049(1) and (2), identification of the conditions in the proposed development area that meet the criteria set forth in KRS 65.7049(3), and, if applicable, confirmation that the requirements of KRS 65.7049(4) have been met; </section><section prefix="b">A detailed description of the existing uses and conditions of real property in the development area; </section><section prefix="c">A map showing the boundaries of the proposed development area, a legal description of the development area, and geographic reference points; </section><section prefix="d">A map showing proposed improvements and uses therein, including the identification of any proposed projects, along with a narrative description of the proposed improvements, projects, and uses within the development area; </section><section prefix="e">A description of the redevelopment assistance proposed to be employed in the development area, including the manner and location of such assistance; </section><section prefix="f">A detailed financial plan containing projections of the cost of the proposed redevelopment assistance to be provided, proposed projects to be funded, proposed sources of funding for these costs, projected incremental revenues, and the projected time frame during which financial obligations will be incurred; </section><section prefix="g">Proposed changes of any zoning ordinance, comprehensive plan, master plan, map, building code, or ordinance anticipated to be required to implement the development plan; and </section><section prefix="h">If the city or county is a member of a planning unit, certification of review by the planning commission for compliance with the comprehensive plan of the planning unit pursuant to KRS Chapter 100 after any necessary changes identified in paragraph (g) of this subsection are made. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to adoption of a development plan, the city or county shall hold a public hearing to solicit input from the public regarding the plan. The city or county shall advertise the hearing by causing to be published, in accordance with KRS 424.130, notice of the time, place, and purpose of the hearing and a general description of the boundaries of the proposed development area. The notice shall include a summary of the redevelopment assistance proposed to be employed, identification of projects proposed for the development area, and a statement that a copy of the development plan is available for inspection at the business office of the city or county. </section><section prefix="3">Prior to publication of a hearing notice pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, a copy of the development plan shall be filed with the city clerk of each city having jurisdiction within the proposed development area, and with the county fiscal court. </section><section prefix="4">A city or county having jurisdiction within the proposed development area not initially participating in a proposed development plan shall have the opportunity to determine whether it will participate in the plan. The city or county shall determine and notify the entity proposing the development plan in writing within thirty (30) days after the public hearing whether it will participate in the plan. </section><section prefix="5">At the end of the time period established in subsection (4) of this section, the city or county may adopt an ordinance establishing a development area in accordance with KRS 65.7053. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 6, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>