<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.040</section_number><catch_line>Malt beverage licenses -- Kinds -- Fees.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>The following kinds of malt beverage licenses may be issued by the director of the Division of Malt Beverages, the fees for which shall be: <section prefix="1">Brewer's license, per annum  .........................................................................$2,580.00 </section><section prefix="2">Microbrewery license, per annum  ...................................................................$520.00 </section><section prefix="3">Distributor's license, per annum  ......................................................................$520.00 </section><section prefix="4">Nonquota retail malt beverage package license, per annum ............................$210.00 </section><section prefix="5">Brew-on-premises license, per annum  ............................................................$520.00 </section><section prefix="6">Out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license, </section> per annum  ....................................................................................................$1,550.00 <section prefix="7">Malt beverage storage license, per annum  ......................................................$260.00 </section><section prefix="8">Replacement or duplicate license, per annum  ...................................................$25.00 </section><section prefix="9">Limited out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license, </section> per annum  .......................................................................................................$260.00 <section prefix="10">Nonquota type 4 malt beverage drink license  ................................................$210.00 </section><section prefix="11">The holder of a nonquota retail malt beverage package license may obtain a Nonquota type 4 malt beverage drink license for a fee of fifty dollars ($50). The holder of a Nonquota type 4 malt beverage drink license may obtain a nonquota retail malt beverage package license for a fee of fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="12">A nonrefundable fee of sixty dollars ($60) shall be charged to process each new transitional license pursuant to KRS 243.045. </section><section prefix="13">Other special licenses as the state board finds to be necessary for the administration of KRS Chapters 241, 242, 243, and 244 and for the proper regulation and control of the trafficking in malt beverages, as provided for by administrative regulations promulgated by the state board. </section>Applicants for special licenses provided for under the authority granted in subsection (9) of this section may be exempt from so much of the provisions of subsection (1)(f) of KRS 243.100 set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. A nonrefundable application fee of fifty dollars ($50) shall be charged to process each new application for a license under this section. The application fee shall be applied to the licensing fee if the license is issued, or otherwise the fee shall be retained by the department. </text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 51, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 564, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 518, sec. 2, effective April 13, 1998; and ch. 522, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 18. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>