<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.450</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of Department of Military Affairs -- Administration of veterans' program trust fund by Department of Veterans' Affairs. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>The Department of Military Affairs, Commonwealth of Kentucky, shall administer the provisions of KRS 40.410 to 40.560 and shall: <section prefix="1">Prepare and make available forms on which applications for the bonus shall be made; </section><section prefix="2">Employ such additional personnel as may be required for orderly and expeditious administration; </section><section prefix="3">Promulgate all administrative regulations required for the effective administration of KRS 40.410 to 40.560, except as it relates to the veterans' program trust fund established in KRS 40.460(2), which shall be administered by the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs. The Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs shall have authority to promulgate administrative regulations for the administration of the veterans' program trust fund; </section><section prefix="4">Report annually to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission within sixty (60) days after the end of each fiscal year during its administration of KRS 40.410 to 40.560; and </section><section prefix="5">Report to the Governor and to the Legislative Research Commission not later than the thirtieth day prior to the beginning of the 1990 Regular Session of the General Assembly, and each thirty (30) days thereafter until adjournment of the 1990 Regular Session of the General Assembly, concerning the following: <section prefix="a">The number of claims which have been submitted; </section><section prefix="b">The number of claims which have been approved for payment; </section><section prefix="c">The number of claims which are subject to further review; and </section><section prefix="d">An accounting for the funds which have been spent in the administration of KRS 40.410 to 40.560. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>