<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="346" order_by="346">COMPENSATION OF CRIME VICTIMS </unit></structure><section_number>346.080</section_number><catch_line>Filing of claim -- Investigation -- Examination -- Hearing -- Order -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A claim, when accepted for filing, shall be assigned by the clerk of the board to an investigator for investigation. All claims arising from the death of an individual as a direct result of a crime shall be considered together. </section><section prefix="2">The investigator to whom such claim is assigned shall examine the papers filed in support of the claim and the validity of the claim. The investigation shall include, but not be limited to, an examination of police, court, and official records and reports concerning the crime. </section><section prefix="3">If the mental, physical, or emotional condition of a victim or claimant is material to a claim, the board may order the victim or claimant to submit to a mental or physical examination by a physician or psychiatrist, and may order an autopsy of a deceased victim. A report upon an examination shall be filed with the investigator setting out findings, including results of all tests made, diagnosis, prognosis, and other conclusions. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this chapter, there is no privilege, except privileges arising from the attorney-client relationship, as to communications or records relevant to an issue of the physical, mental, or emotional condition of the claimant or victim in a proceeding under this chapter in which that condition is an element. </section><section prefix="5">Claims shall be investigated and determined, regardless of whether the alleged criminal has been apprehended or prosecuted for or convicted of any crime based upon the same incident, or has been acquitted, or found not guilty of the crime in question owing to criminal irresponsibility or other legal exemption. </section><section prefix="6">Upon completion of the investigator's report, the claim shall be assigned to a board member who may decide the claim in favor of a claimant in the amount claimed on the basis of the papers filed in support thereof and the report of the investigation of the claim within thirty (30) days of the assignment of the claim. If the board member is unable to decide the claim upon the basis of the papers and the report, he shall order a hearing. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="7">After examining the papers filed in support of the claim and the report of investigation, and after a hearing, if any, the board member to whom the claim was assigned shall issue a recommended order either granting an award pursuant to KRS 346.130 or deny the claim. The board shall review the recommended order and any exceptions filed to it, and shall by majority vote issue a final order. </section><section prefix="8">A final order of the board may be appealed by the Attorney General or a claimant by filing a petition for judicial review in Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 329, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32700</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>