<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="411" order_by="411">RIGHTS OF ACTION AND SURVIVAL OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>411.550</section_number><catch_line>Determination of private nuisance. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In determining whether a defendant's use of property constitutes a private nuisance, the judge or jury, whichever is the trier of fact, shall consider all relevant facts and circumstances including the following: <section prefix="a">The lawful nature of the defendant's use of the property; </section><section prefix="b">The manner in which the defendant has used the property; </section><section prefix="c">The importance of the defendant's use of the property to the community; </section><section prefix="d">The influence of the defendant's use of property to the growth and prosperity of the community; </section><section prefix="e">The kind, volume, and duration of the annoyance or interference with the use and enjoyment of claimant's property caused by the defendant's use of property; </section><section prefix="f">The respective situations of the defendant and claimant; and </section><section prefix="g">The character of the area in which the defendant's property is located, including, but not limited to, all applicable statutes, laws, or regulations. </section></section><section prefix="2">A defendant's use of property shall be considered as a substantial annoyance or interference with the use and enjoyment of a claimant's property if it would substantially annoy or interfere with the use and enjoyment of property by a person of ordinary health and normal sensitivities. </section></text><history>Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 6, effective May 24, 1991. </history><metadata><effective>May 24, 1991 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17829</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>