<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.095</section_number><catch_line>Brake linings, sale when not of approved type prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On and after January 1, 1967, it shall be unlawful to sell, or to display for sale, any brake lining unless of a type which has been submitted to the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet for approval and for which a certificate of approval has been issued by the secretary and is then in effect; provided, however, that no owner of a motor vehicle shall be required to replace brake linings which were installed before June 16, 1966 solely because such linings have not been approved in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall, in order to insure safe operation of motor vehicles, prescribe uniform specifications as to the stopping ability, pedal force, lining integrity, stability, fade and recovery characteristic requirements of brake linings and shall determine whether any brake lining submitted complies with such rules and uniform standards; provided, however, that in order to promote uniformity between the states and thereby avoid increased costs to the people of this state, due to the necessity of complying with diverse requirements in the distribution and sale of brake linings, the secretary is hereby authorized to adopt and maintain the standards and specifications which are adopted by the several states pursuant to the procedures of the Vehicle Equipment Safety Compact, or those of the Society of Automotive Engineers, whichever in the discretion of the secretary will better protect the safety of the people of this state. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 113, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6307</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>