<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.767</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees of pension fund -- Membership -- Officers -- Treasurer. </catch_line><order_by>767</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be organized in connection with the police and fire departments a board to be known as the board of trustees of the policemen's and firefighter's pension fund. If there are six (6) or more active members of the fund, the board shall be composed of the mayor of the city, city treasurer, one (1) member of the city legislative body appointed by the mayor, one (1) retired member each from the police and fire departments elected by the respective retired members of those departments annually by ballot, and one (1) active member of the fund from each department elected by the active members of the fund from the respective departments annually. If all of the six (6) or more active members or all of the retired members are from one (1) department, then both of the active member board members or both of the retired board members, as the case may be, shall be elected from that department. If there are fewer than six (6) active members of the fund, no active members of the departments shall be elected to the board. The trustees shall select from their number a president and secretary. The city treasurer shall be ex officio treasurer of the board and custodian of its funds. </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees membership shall be restructured according to the provisions of this section at the time of the next scheduled election of board members after July 15, 1990. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 36, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>