<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.280</section_number><catch_line>Bond, powers and compensation of railroad policemen. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each railroad policeman shall, before he enters upon the discharge of the duties of his office, execute bond, with good security, conditioned for the faithful performance of his duty as such policeman, and take and subscribe an oath of office. The bond shall be executed in the county in which the policeman resides, or in which the railroad has its registered process agent, if any, within the state, or in which the policeman performs any duties as a railroad policeman, and the bond shall be approved, and the oath administered, by the county judge/executive. The bond and oath shall be entered of record by the county clerk, and the execution of the bond and the taking of the oath shall be indorsed upon the commission of the person so qualifying. Each policeman so appointed and commissioned shall, throughout the counties through which the railroad operates, have and exercise the powers of sheriffs and constables in making arrests for public offenses committed upon or about railroad property, and in serving process in criminal and penal prosecutions for such offenses, and shall be subject to all the liabilities of sheriffs or constables. </section><section prefix="2">The compensation of railroad policemen shall be fixed and paid by the railroad company for which they are appointed. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 456, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 779a-3, 779a-5. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14019</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>