<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.654</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>654</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors of the Kentucky Natural History Museum shall establish the Kentucky Natural History Museum. The board shall implement KRS 146.650 to 146.666 to the extent practical prior to operation of the museum. Working to achieve the public purposes that are the goals of implementation of KRS 146.650 to 146.666 shall not be dependent on the existence and operation of the museum in a physical place. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall be administratively linked to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">To accomplish the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666, the board is authorized to: <section prefix="a">Acquire and hold property by deed, gift, devise, bequest, lease, exchange, purchase, or transfer; </section><section prefix="b">Plan for, develop, construct, and maintain buildings; </section><section prefix="c">Enter into agreements with state, federal, or local agencies; </section><section prefix="d">Employ and contract with individuals, corporations, or other business entities to accomplish the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666; </section><section prefix="e">Accept and administer appropriations, gifts, grants, devises, and bequests of money, securities, or other items of value; and </section><section prefix="f">Carry out any other functions necessary to accomplish the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666. </section></section><section prefix="4">To accomplish the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666, the board may provide and administer grants to public and private entities. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1550</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>