<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29">A JURIES </unit></structure><section_number>29A.040</section_number><catch_line>Master list of prospective jurors for county -- Annual update. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A list of all persons over the age of eighteen (18) and holding valid driver's licenses which were issued in the county, of the names and addresses of all persons filing Kentucky resident individual income tax returns which show an address in the county, and of all persons registered to vote in the county shall constitute a master list of prospective jurors for a county. </section><section prefix="2">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall at least annually acquire an electronic copy of the driver's license list from the Transportation Cabinet, an electronic copy of the tax roll described in subsection (1) of this section from the Department of Revenue, and an electronic copy of the voter registration lists from the State Board of Elections. In addition, the Administrative Office of the Courts shall at least annually acquire a listing of deceased persons from the Vital Statistics Branch in the Department of Public Health. The Transportation Cabinet, the Department of Revenue, the State Board of Elections, and the Vital Statistics Branch and those public officers or employees having custody, possession, or control of any of the lists required under this section shall annually furnish a copy of the list to the Administrative Office of the Courts without charge. </section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall merge the lists required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section in a manner designed to create an accurate listing of all persons eligible for jury service. The Administrative Office of the Courts may purge names from the master list upon reasonable evidence of death, change of state residence, change of county residence, or any other reason causing a person to be ineligible for jury service as found in KRS 29A.080. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who comes into possession of the Kentucky income tax names and addresses as provided in this section shall be bound by the confidentiality provisions of KRS 131.190. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 44, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449, sec. 6, effective October 1, 1982. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 15, effective September 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21121</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>