<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.305</section_number><catch_line>Possession of wildlife or raw fur out of season -- Inspection of commercial frozen food lockers. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to regulations adopted under this chapter and except as otherwise provided in this section, no person shall have in his possession any wildlife protected by this chapter, or any raw fur, except during the open season for the particular species, unless such person be the holder of a valid permit issued pursuant to the provisions of KRS 150.275 or 150.280. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has legally taken any wildlife may possess same in cold storage. If possessed in a commercial locker plant, the name of the taker, his license number, the date of taking, and the number and species of wildlife must be marked on the package in which the same is stored. Legally imported wildlife from other states or countries may be similarly held. </section><section prefix="3">Federal regulations shall govern the possession of migratory wild birds. </section><section prefix="4">To facilitate the enforcement of subsection (2) of this section, the commissioner, or such agents and employees of the department as may be designated by him, shall have authority to inspect all commercial frozen food lockers within the State of Kentucky at such periods and intervals as the commissioner shall, in the exercise of a reasonable discretion, fix and determine. No search warrant or other legal process shall be required of any properly authorized person as a condition precedent to the making of the inspections herein authorized. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 14. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 42. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 15. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1997</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>