<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.357</section_number><catch_line>Governmental Services Center at Kentucky State University -- Authority to direct -- Duties and responsibilities of center -- Executive director of authority. </catch_line><order_by>357</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established as a separate administrative body of state government the Governmental Services Center at Kentucky State University which shall be attached to the Personnel Cabinet for administrative purposes. The center shall be governed by the Governmental Services Center Authority. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall consist of the president of Kentucky State University, who shall be chairman, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet, two (2) members appointed by the Governor, each of whom shall serve as ex officio voting members of the authority, and two (2) other voting members to be appointed by the chairman of the authority. Appointed members shall be citizens and residents of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The initial term of one (1) of the members appointed by the chairman shall be for two (2) years, and the initial term of the other appointed member shall be for a term of four (4) years; thereafter, all appointments shall be for terms of four (4) years, but appointed members shall be removable at will by the chairman of the authority. </section><section prefix="3">The Governmental Services Center at Kentucky State University, under direction of the authority, shall be responsible for the development, coordination, content, approval, and implementation of all training, employee development, and related programs conducted for and on behalf of all program cabinets, departments, administrative bodies, and program managers of the state government. The center shall conduct, or cause to be conducted, ongoing management training programs for all program managers and supervisors within the executive branch of state government. The organizational units whose supervisors and managers received training at the center shall share the cost of the training on a pro rata basis. The center shall encourage the enrollment of state employees in academic courses and programs at Kentucky State University. If desired academic courses are not available at the university, and cannot feasibly be developed by the university, other universities and community colleges within the Commonwealth shall be utilized. The authority shall determine the appropriateness of all such programs. </section><section prefix="4">The authority may employ an executive director and other employees necessary to perform the functions of the center in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 18A. The executive director or any staff member of the center may hold concurrently with their employment by the center, and subject to the provisions of KRS 164.360 and 164.365, faculty appointments of appropriate rank at Kentucky State University. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the authority who are not either state or university employees shall be reimbursed for their actual expenses in attending meetings for the authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 599, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 81, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4272</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>