<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="165" order_by="165">A PROPRIETARY EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>165A.330</section_number><catch_line>License required -- Applications.   </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall conduct, operate, maintain, or establish a proprietary school as herein defined or use any words which designate or tend to designate to the public that the operator of the school is qualified to conduct, operate, and maintain the school, unless he holds a valid current license from the commission. </section><section prefix="2">Completed applications for a license shall be filed with the commission thirty (30) working days prior to being considered by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Renewal applications shall be filed with the commission by May 15, prior to the June 30 expiration date. </section><section prefix="4">The school owner shall notify the commission if any personnel involved in the applicant school has ever been associated as owner, partner, director, or other administrator with a school that has had its license revoked or that has closed and caused students a loss of money. The commission may consider this information in granting, renewing, or revoking a license. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall in any way solicit any person or group of persons in this state to enroll at or attend any such school unless the person holds a valid license as agent of the school for which he is soliciting. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>