<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.250</section_number><catch_line>Participation by Governor-elect in executive branch and Transportation Cabinet budget recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor-elect or a delegate appointed by him or her shall be entitled to examine the budget recommendations of the executive branch of government, and the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall provide him or her with every practicable facility for reviewing and familiarizing himself or herself with the recommendations. The Governor-elect shall be entitled to a seat in all hearings thereon. He or she shall be furnished a copy of the budget request of each executive branch budget unit. The budget director shall make available to the Governor-elect so much as he or she requests of the information upon which the executive branch budget recommendations are based. </section><section prefix="2">After a review of the executive branch and Transportation Cabinet draft budget bills, the Governor-elect may prepare revisions and additions thereto. The budget director shall assist, upon request, in the preparation of such revisions and additions. </section><section prefix="3">The budget director shall have as many copies of the revised budget recommendations of the executive branch of government printed as the Governor-elect requests. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 24, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 50, effective July 1, 1983. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=556</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>