<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.085</section_number><catch_line>Quarantine of animals suspected of having rabies -- Destruction of animal in lieu of quarantine -- Exceptions -- Head of animal suspected of being rabid to be sent to laboratory. </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A health officer or his agent shall have the authority to quarantine for a period not to exceed: <section prefix="1">One hundred eighty (180) days any animal bitten by another animal known or suspected to have rabies; </section><section prefix="2">Ten (10) days any dog, cat, or ferret which has bitten a human being; or </section><section prefix="3">Ten (10) days any dog, cat, or ferret which exhibits symptoms of rabies. </section></section><section prefix="b">In lieu of the quarantines provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection, a health officer or his agent may order an animal to be destroyed and tested for rabies. </section><section prefix="c">If a wild or exotic animal bites a human being or exhibits symptoms of rabies, that animal shall be destroyed and tested for rabies. </section><section prefix="d">Service animals, as defined in KRS 525.010, and service animals in training, that are vaccinated in accordance with KRS 258.015, are under the control of a law enforcement agency, and are acting in the line of duty, shall be exempt from the quarantine described in paragraph (a)2. of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">If an animal dies with rabies, is suspected of having died with rabies, or is destroyed because of having been suspected of being rabid, the owner, if known, whether the animal had been previously quarantined or not, shall send the head of the animal to a laboratory approved by the secretary for health and family services to be tested for rabies. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The owner of any animal quarantined or tested under this section shall be liable for any expenses incurred as a result of the quarantine or testing. </section><section prefix="b">Any owner who destroys or disposes of an animal that has bitten a human being shall be liable for any rabies postexposure treatment if the animal is destroyed or disposed of in a manner that does not allow for rabies testing or quarantine. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 573, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 520, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12426</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>