<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-257</section_number><catch_line>Coverage under health benefit plan for colorectal cancerexaminations and laboratory tests.  </catch_line><order_by>17A-257</order_by><text>(1)A health benefit plan issued or renewed on or after January 1, 2016, shallprovide coverage for all colorectal cancer examinations and laboratory testsspecified in current American Cancer Society guidelines for complete colorectalcancer screening of asymptomatic individuals as follows:(a)Coverage or benefits shall be provided for all colorectal screeningexaminations and tests that are administered at a frequency identified inthe most recent version of the American Cancer Society guidelines forcomplete colorectal cancer screening; and(b)The covered individual shall be:1.Fifty (50) years of age or older; or2.Less than fifty (50) years of age and at high risk for colorectalcancer according to current colorectal cancer screening guidelinesof the American Cancer Society.(2)Coverage under this section shall not be subject to a deductible or coinsurancefor services received from participating providers under the health benefit plan.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2016; and ch.56, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2016. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1,effective July 15, 2008.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2016). This statute was amended by2015 Ky. Acts chs. 10 and 56, which do not appear to be in conflict and havebeen codified together.</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44718</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>