<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.350</section_number><catch_line>Forestry Best Management Practices Board. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a Forestry Best Management Practices Board consisting of thirteen (13) members for the purposes of updating Kentucky's forest practice guidelines for water quality management and the Division of Forestry's administrative regulations regarding timber harvesting operations, and supervising the implementation of forestry best management practices and timber harvesting operations regulations by the Division of Forestry. The offices of the board shall be maintained at a place designated by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The initial appointments to the board shall be made within one (1) year of July 15, 1998, and the appointments shall be for staggered terms to assure continuity. The Governor shall appoint members to the board representing the following: <section prefix="a">Five (5) members who are farmers or woodland owners with at least fifty (50) acres of woodland and who are actively engaged in woodland management: <section prefix="1">One (1) of these members from a list of three (3) persons nominated by the Kentucky Woodland Owners Association; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) of these members from a list of three (3) persons nominated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) of these members from a list of three (3) persons nominated by the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation; and </section><section prefix="4">Two (2) of these members shall be farmers at large; </section></section><section prefix="b">One (1) logger in good standing; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member of the Department of Forestry of the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member of the Kentucky Division of Forestry; </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) members of a Kentucky wood industry; and </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) members at large who are woodland owners. </section></section><section prefix="3">Except for initial staggered appointments, board memberships shall be for a period of four (4) years, and members may be appointed to no more than two (2) full consecutive terms. Appointments to the board shall be made consistent with subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The chair of the board shall be chosen from the members selected to meet the criteria in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall review existing forestry best management practices within one (1) year after establishment of the board and shall conduct periodic reviews for rewriting the best management practices regulations no sooner than every five (5) years thereafter. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall oversee implementation of best management practice education and enforcement by the Division of Forestry. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall meet at least once a year for the purpose of conducting its oversight responsibilities. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall be attached to the division for administrative purposes. The division shall provide funds necessary for board meetings, travel expenses, and other administrative support, including but not limited to staff assistance at meetings, report preparation, and record keeping. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall present its findings and recommendations to the Office of the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission when the board deems appropriate or when the Office of the Governor specifically requests a report. The board shall provide a summary report of its findings and recommendations to the Office of the Governor every five (5) years and to the Legislative Research Commission, if deemed appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 555, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1888</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>