<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.085Continuing</section_number><catch_line>education requirements -- Post-licensure educationrequirements -- Qualifications of instructors -- Administrative regulations.</catch_line><order_by>085Continuing</order_by><text>(1)All actively licensed agents except those licensees exempt under KRS324.046(5), shall successfully complete six (6) classroom or online hours ofcontinuing education each year. Three (3) of the six (6) hours shall be in realestate law.(2)A licensee who is issued an initial sales associate license after January 1,2016, shall complete forty-eight (48) classroom or online hours ofcommission-approved post-license education:(a)Provided by one (1) or a combination of the following:1.An accredited institution; or2.A commission-approved:a.Real estate school; orb.Broker-affiliated training program; and(b)Within two (2) years of receiving or activating his or her license unlessextended by the commission for good cause shown.(3)The license held by any licensee failing to complete his or her sales associatepost-license education requirements in accordance with subsection (2) of thissection shall be automatically canceled, in accordance with administrativeregulations establishing compliance and delinquency procedures.(4)The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations to establishprocedures for implementing the requirements in this section.(5)In order to qualify to teach continuing education or post-license courses, allcontinuing education and post-license instructors shall maintain a minimumrating as prescribed by the commission by the promulgation of administrativeregulations.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44748</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>