<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.744</section_number><catch_line>Addition of nonlicensed raster-based datasets of publicly funded Kentucky locations to the Geospatial Data Warehouse -- Exceptions -- Confidentiality.   </catch_line><order_by>744</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All entities in Kentucky that create or purchase digital ortho-rectified aerial imagery, remotely sensed imagery, LiDAR, digital elevation models, or any other form of nonlicensed raster-based datasets of locations in Kentucky using public funds, in whole or in part, shall provide a copy of the information to the Commonwealth Office of Technology, Division of Geographic Information Systems, without cost, in order to allow the Commonwealth Office of Technology to effectively discharge its statutory responsibility to maintain an accurate and complete central statewide geographic information clearinghouse for official state use. The imagery provided to the Commonwealth Office of Technology shall be added to Kentucky's secure Geospatial Data Warehouse for official government use only. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to roads, land parcels, structure locations, or other vector-based datasets acquired with public funding. </section><section prefix="3">The Commonwealth Office of Technology shall not disclose to the general public or make available for distribution, download, or purchase any data that an entity providing data under subsection (1) of this section has requested remain confidential. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.518. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>