<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.314</section_number><catch_line>Renewal and reinstatement of license -- Continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>314</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each person licensed as an interpreter shall annually, on or before July 1, submit to the board current proof of nationally recognized certification and pay a fee for the renewal of the interpreter license. The amount of the fee shall be promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. All licenses not renewed by July 1 of each year shall expire. </section><section prefix="2">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed after July 1, during which time individuals may continue to practice and may renew their licenses upon payment of the renewal fee plus a late renewal fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. </section><section prefix="3">All licenses not renewed by August 31 shall terminate based on the failure of the individual to renew in a timely manner. Upon termination, the licensee is no longer eligible to practice in the Commonwealth.  </section><section prefix="4">After the sixty (60) day grace period, but before five (5) years from the date of termination, individuals with a terminated license may have their licenses reinstated upon payment of the renewal fee plus a reinstatement fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. </section><section prefix="5">A suspended license is subject to expiration and termination and may be renewed as provided in KRS 309.300 to 309.319. Renewal shall not entitle the licensee to engage in the practice of interpreting until the suspension has ended or is otherwise removed by the board and the right to practice is restored by the board. </section><section prefix="6">A revoked license is subject to expiration and termination but shall not be renewed. If it is reinstated, the licensee shall pay the reinstatement fee as set forth in subsection (4) of this section and the renewal fee as set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">The board may require that a person applying for renewal or reinstatement of licensure show evidence of completion of continuing education as prescribed by the board by administrative regulation. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>