<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">A MASS TRANSIT AUTHORITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96A.320</section_number><catch_line>Submission of proposal to establish program -- Voters -- Program financing. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 96A.310 to 96A.370, the term "mass transportation program" shall mean the provision of necessary funds by public bodies to transit authorities created pursuant to KRS Chapter 96A with which to acquire, operate, and preserve mass transportation facilities. A "mass transportation program" may also include a method for the public body or public bodies to finance principal and interest payments on any general obligation bonds issued pursuant to KRS 96A.120, or to finance transportation-related facilities to promote the movement of vehicles and people. Urban-county governments which initiate a "mass transportation program" may include in this program the improvement of existing roads and the construction of new roads. </section><section prefix="2">Public bodies which have been parties to the creation and establishment of transit authorities, or who constitute the membership of such transit authorities, may, acting either individually or jointly, submit to either the electorates of such public bodies, or the electorate of the transit area encompassed by any such transit authority, but only in the manner and pursuant to the procedures set forth in KRS 96A.310 to 96A.370, one (1) or more proposals for the approval of a mass transportation program to be financed by additional voted levies of ad valorem taxes upon all taxable property in such public body or public bodies. Such additional voted levies of ad valorem taxes upon all taxable property in any such public body shall never exceed in the aggregate the limits prescribed by the Constitution of Kentucky for any such public body. </section><section prefix="3">Public bodies which have been parties to the creation and establishment of transit authorities, or who constitute the membership of such transit authorities, may, acting either individually or jointly, submit to either the electorates of such public bodies, or the electorate of the transit area encompassed by any such transit authority, but only in the manner and pursuant to the procedures set forth in KRS 96A.310 to 96A.370, one (1) or more proposals for the approval of a mass transportation program to be financed by voted levies of occupational license fees. Such voted levies of occupational license fees shall not exceed one percent (1%) of: <section prefix="a">Salaries, wages, commissions, and other compensation earned by persons for work done and services performed or rendered; and </section><section prefix="b">The net profits of businesses, trades, professions, or occupations from activities conducted in the public body, or the transit area, except public service companies, banks, trust companies, combined banks and trust companies, combined trust, banking and title companies, any savings and loan association whether state or federally chartered, and in all other cases where a public body is prohibited by law from imposing a license fee. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Public bodies which have been parties to the creation and establishment of transit authorities, or who constitute the membership of such transit authorities, may, acting either individually or jointly, submit to either the electorates of such public bodies, or the electorate of the transit area encompassed by any such transit authority, but only in the manner and pursuant to the procedures set forth in KRS 96A.310 to 96A.370, one (1) or more proposals for the approval of a mass transportation program to be financed by the voted levy of a sales tax upon all retailers at a rate not to exceed one-half of one percent (0.5%) of the gross receipts of any retailer derived from "retail sales" or "sales at retail" made within the public body or public bodies, provided, however, that public transit sales tax shall not be levied on those retail sales which are exempted from the state sales tax by KRS Chapter 139 on June 19, 1976, or hereafter exempted. </section><section prefix="b">Any sales tax levied for said purpose shall be in addition to the sales tax authorized by Chapter 139 of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. Said public transportation sales tax shall be collected and administered under the provisions of Chapter 139 of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and the rules and regulations of the Kentucky Department of Revenue. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Department of Revenue shall refund that portion of the sales tax collected as a public transportation tax to the public body or bodies imposing said tax. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any other provision contrary hereto, a mass transportation program financed by a public body or public bodies from said sales tax shall be restricted by the following order of priorities, to wit: <section prefix="a">First, the annual payment of principal, interest, and sinking fund requirements on any general obligation bonds issued pursuant to KRS 96A.120; </section><section prefix="b">Second, appropriations to the transit authority to provide local matching funds for any available federal or state capital, operating, or planning and demonstration grant projects in accordance with the annual approved budget; and </section><section prefix="c">Third, any excess funds in the control of each public body receiving said tax shall be transferred to the general fund of each such public body for public transportation and traffic improvement projects at any location within a city or county, in any manner which said public body or public bodies determine will improve transportation, road or traffic conditions, or in general will promote the movement of people and vehicles. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 105, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 560, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 6; and ch. 350, sec. 1. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26348</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>