<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Alcohol" means: <section prefix="a">Beer, ale, port, or stout and other similar fermented beverages, including sake or similar products, of any name or description containing one-half of one percentum (0.5%) or more of alcohol by volume, brewed or produced from malt, wholly or in part, or from any substitute therefor; </section><section prefix="b">Wine of not less than one-half of one percentum (0.5%) of alcohol by volume; </section><section prefix="c">Distilled spirits, which means that substance known as ethyl alcohol, ethanol, or spirits of wine in any form, including all dilutions and mixtures thereof from whatever source or by whatever process produced; or </section><section prefix="d">Any substance containing ethyl alcohol, hydrated oxide of ethyl, spirit of wine, or any distilled spirits including but not limited to ethanol, methanol, propanol, and isopropanol. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Alcohol concentration" means: <section prefix="a">The number of grams of alcohol per one hundred (100) milliliters of blood; </section><section prefix="b">The number of grams of alcohol per two hundred ten (210) liters of breath; or </section><section prefix="c">The number of grams of alcohol per sixty-seven (67) milliliters of urine. </section></section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Transportation Cabinet of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">"Commerce" means: <section prefix="a">Any trade, traffic, or transportation within the jurisdiction of the United States between a place in a state and a place outside of the state, including a place outside of the United States; and </section><section prefix="b">Trade, traffic, and transportation in the United States that affects any trade, traffic, and transportation described in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Commercial driver's license," or "CDL," means a license issued to an individual in accordance with the requirements of this chapter or, if the license is issued by another state in accordance with the Federal Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act, to an individual that authorizes the individual to drive any class of commercial motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="6">"Commercial driver's license information system" or CDLIS means the national information system established to serve as a clearinghouse for locating information related to the licensing and identification of commercial motor vehicle drivers. </section><section prefix="7">"Commercial driver's instruction permit" means a permit issued pursuant to KRS 281A.120. </section><section prefix="8">"Commercial motor vehicle," or "CMV," means a motor vehicle or combination motor vehicle used in commerce that is: <section prefix="a">Designed to carry property and has a gross vehicle weight rating as determined by federal regulation which has been adopted into cabinet administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="b">Designed to transport sixteen (16) or more passengers, including the driver; </section><section prefix="c">Transporting hazardous materials and is required to be placarded in accordance with Title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 172; or </section><section prefix="d">Any other vehicle that is required by cabinet administrative regulation, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, to be operated by a licensed commercial driver. </section></section><section prefix="9">"Controlled substance" means any substance so classified under Section 102(6) of the Controlled Substances Act, 21 U.S.C. sec. 802(6), and includes all substances listed on Schedules I through V, of Title 21, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 1308, as adopted by the Transportation Cabinet by administrative regulation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. It shall also include those substances defined or listed in KRS Chapter 218A. </section><section prefix="10">"Conviction" means an unvacated adjudication of guilt, or a determination that a person has violated or failed to comply with the law in a court of original jurisdiction or an authorized administrative tribunal, an unvacated forfeiture of bail or collateral deposited to secure the person's appearance in court, a plea of guilty, a plea of nolo contendere, or Alford plea entered and accepted by the court, the payment of a fine or court cost, or violation of a condition of release without bail, regardless of whether or not the penalty is rebated, suspended, or probated. </section><section prefix="11">"Disqualification" means any of the following actions: <section prefix="a">The suspension, revocation, or cancellation of a CDL by the Commonwealth or the jurisdiction of issuance; </section><section prefix="b">Any withdrawal of a person's privilege to drive a commercial motor vehicle by the Commonwealth or another jurisdiction as a result of a violation of state or local law relating to motor vehicle traffic control, other than parking, vehicle weight, or vehicle defect violations; or </section><section prefix="c">A determination by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration that a person is not qualified to operate a commercial motor vehicle under 49 C.F.R. pt. 391. </section></section><section prefix="12">"Drive" means to drive, operate, or be in physical control of a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="13">"Driver" means any person who drives, operates, or is in physical control of a commercial motor vehicle, or who is required to hold a commercial driver's license. </section><section prefix="14">"Driver's license" means a license issued by a state to an individual that authorizes the individual to drive a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="15">"Employee" means any operator of a commercial motor vehicle, including full-time, regularly employed drivers; casual, intermittent, or occasional drivers; leased drivers and independent, owner-operator contractors while in the course of operating a commercial motor vehicle who are either directly employed by, under lease to, or operating in a manner indicating employment to an employer. </section><section prefix="16">"Employer" means any person, including the United States, a state, or a political subdivision of a state, who owns or leases a commercial motor vehicle, or assigns a person to drive a commercial motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="17">"Felony" means any offense under state or federal law that is punishable by death or imprisonment for a term exceeding one (1) year. </section><section prefix="18">"Gross combination weight rating," or "GCWR," is the gross vehicle weight rating of power unit plus the gross vehicle weight rating of any towed unit. In the absence of a value specified by the manufacturer, GCWR shall be determined by adding the gross vehicle weight rating of the power unit and the total weight of the towed unit and load therein. </section><section prefix="19">"Gross vehicle weight rating," or "GVWR," means the value specified by the manufacturer as the maximum loaded weight of a single, a combination or an articulated vehicle. </section><section prefix="20">"Hazardous materials" has the same meaning as in 49 C.F.R. sec. 383.5. </section><section prefix="21">"Highway" shall include any way or place of any nature when any part of it is open to the use of the public as a matter of right, license, or privilege for the use of vehicular traffic. </section><section prefix="22">"Imminent hazard" means a condition that presents a substantial likelihood that death, serious illness, severe personal injury, or a danger to health, property, or the environment exists. </section><section prefix="23">"Moped" shall have the same meaning as in KRS 186.010(5). </section><section prefix="24">"Motor vehicle" means a vehicle, machine, tractor, trailer, or semitrailer propelled or drawn by mechanical power used on highways, or any other vehicle required to be registered under the laws of this state, but shall not include any vehicle, machine, tractor, trailer, or semitrailers operated exclusively on a rail. </section><section prefix="25">"NDR" means the national driver register. </section><section prefix="26">"Out-of-service order" means a declaration by an authorized enforcement officer of a federal, state, Canadian, Mexican, or local jurisdiction that a driver, commercial motor vehicle, or a motor carrier operation is out of service pursuant to 49 C.F.R. sec. 386.72, 392.5, 395.13, or 396.9; comparable laws or regulations; or the North American Uniform Out-of-Service Criteria. </section><section prefix="27">"Resident" means a person who has established Kentucky as his or her state of domicile. Proof of residency shall include but not be limited to a deed or property tax bill, utility agreement or utility bill, or rental housing agreement. </section><section prefix="28">"School bus" means a vehicle that meets the specification of KRS 156.153 used to transport preprimary, primary, or secondary school students between school and home, or to and from school-sponsored events. A school bus shall not include a bus used as a common carrier. </section><section prefix="29">"Serious traffic violation" means a conviction when operating a commercial motor vehicle of: <section prefix="a">Excessive speeding, involving a single charge of any speed fifteen (15) miles per hour or more, above the specified speed limit; </section><section prefix="b">Reckless driving, as defined under state or local law, including conviction of driving a commercial motor vehicle in willful or wanton disregard for the safety of persons or property; </section><section prefix="c">Improper or erratic traffic lane changes; </section><section prefix="d">Following the vehicle ahead too closely; </section><section prefix="e">A violation of any state or local law related to motor vehicle traffic control, other than a parking violation, arising in connection with a fatal accident; </section><section prefix="f">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without a CDL; </section><section prefix="g">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without a CDL in one's possession or refusing to display a CDL upon request; </section><section prefix="h">Driving a commercial motor vehicle without the proper class of CDL or endorsements, or both, for the specific vehicle type or types being operated or for the passengers or type or types of cargo being transported; or </section><section prefix="i">Any conviction of an offense that requires mandatory suspension under KRS 186.560 or a serious violation as defined by Title 49 of the Code of Federal Regulations Part 383 or as amended by the Federal Highway Administration. </section></section><section prefix="30">"State" means a state of the United States and the District of Columbia. </section><section prefix="31">"State police" means the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="32">"Vehicle" means every device in, upon, or by which any person or property is or may be transported or drawn along a public highway, except devices moved by human or animal power, used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks, or which derives its power from overhead wires. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 285, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 1, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 1, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>