<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.020</section_number><catch_line>Scope of chapter -- Licensure requirements.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in the practice of cosmetology or nail technology for other than cosmetic purposes nor shall any person engage in the practice of cosmetology or nail technology for the treatment of physical or mental ailments. The provisions of this chapter do not apply to: <section prefix="a">Persons authorized by the law of this state to practice medicine, podiatry, optometry, dentistry, chiropractic, nursing, or embalming who perform incidental practices of cosmetology and nail technology in the normal course of the practice of their profession; </section><section prefix="b">Commissioned medical or surgical personnel of the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Hospital Service who perform incidental practices of cosmetology or nail technology in the course of their duties; and </section><section prefix="c">Cosmetology or nail technology services performed at an institution operated or under contract to the Department of Corrections or the Department of Juvenile Justice. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (1) of this section, no person shall engage in the practice of cosmetology or nail technology for the public, generally, or for consideration without the appropriate license required by this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">No person unless duly and properly licensed pursuant to this chapter shall: <section prefix="a">Teach cosmetology or nail technology; </section><section prefix="b">Operate a beauty salon; </section><section prefix="c">Engage in a cosmetology apprenticeship; </section><section prefix="d">Operate a nail salon; </section><section prefix="e">Act as a nail technician; or </section><section prefix="f">Conduct or operate a school for cosmetologists or nail technicians. </section></section><section prefix="4">No person shall aid or abet any person in violating the provisions of this section, nor shall any person engage or employ for consideration any person to perform any practice licensed by this chapter unless the person to perform the practice holds and displays the appropriate license. </section><section prefix="5">No licensed cosmetology instructors, licensed cosmetologists, or licensed nail technicians shall hold clinics for teaching or demonstrating for personal profit, either monetary or otherwise, if the clinics are not sponsored by a recognized professional hairdresser's, cosmetologist's, or nail technician's group. </section><section prefix="6">Whenever a person engages in different practices separately licensed, certified, or permitted by the provisions of this chapter, that person shall procure a separate license, certificate, or permit for each of the practices in which the person engages. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>