<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.160</section_number><catch_line>Testing of knowledge and skills -- Fees -- State Police CDL skills-testing fund -- Contract examiners -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, the State Police shall be responsible for administering both the knowledge and skills test required by KRS 281A.130. </section><section prefix="b">Applicants who fail the written knowledge test shall be permitted to retake the written test on the next day the tests are administered. Applicants who fail the written test six (6) times shall be required to wait three (3) days before taking the knowledge test again. Applicants who subsequently fail the written test three (3) additional times shall be required to wait three (3) days prior to retaking the test. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided for in subsection (3) of this section, at the time a CDL permit is issued: <section prefix="1">An applicant who has held a Kentucky operator's license for thirty (30) days or longer shall pay a skills-testing fee of fifty dollars ($50); and </section><section prefix="2">An applicant who has held a Kentucky operator's license for less than thirty (30) days shall pay a skills-testing fee of one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section></section><section prefix="b">There is created within the State Treasury a trust fund to be known as the State Police CDL skills-testing fund. The fund shall be administered by the State Police and shall receive all skills-testing and retesting fees collected under subsections (2)(a) and (6)(c) of this section, in addition to any grants, gifts, or appropriations of state or federal moneys and any interest earned on moneys in the fund. Moneys in the fund shall not lapse and shall be carried forward to the next succeeding fiscal year. The State Police CDL skills-testing fund shall be used by the State Police to contract with and train civilian CDL skills examiners and to improve the logistics of the CDL skills-testing process. </section><section prefix="c">The State Police, upon request of an applicant who has passed both the vision and knowledge tests, may schedule the applicant for the skills test at the first available test date at a test site designated by the State Police but not less than ten (10) days after the applicant has filed the application and been issued a CDL permit. Except in extenuating circumstances, a retest for a failed portion of the skills test shall be given within three (3) days of a request of a retest. </section><section prefix="d">An applicant shall provide a class representative commercial vehicle, for the class of CDL for which the applicant is testing, in which to take the skills test. Unless the State Police grant an exemption at the time the application for testing is made, the vehicle supplied under this paragraph shall be unloaded. Upon arrival for the skills test, the applicant shall have in his or her possession a valid Kentucky operator's license, a valid CDL permit, and a current U.S. Department of Transportation physical card. A CDL-licensed driver who is at least twenty-one (21) years old shall accompany the applicant at all times the applicant is in operation of a commercial vehicle. </section></section><section prefix="3">A testing fee shall not be charged to an individual applying for a CDL with an "S" endorsement as defined in KRS 281A.170. </section><section prefix="4">The State Police may authorize a third party to administer the skills test specified by this section if: <section prefix="a">The test is the same that would otherwise be administered by the state; and </section><section prefix="b">The third party has entered into an agreement with this Commonwealth which complies with requirements of Title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 383.75, as adopted by the Transportation Cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="5">The State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A that establish procedures that ensure an arm's-length relationship is maintained between a third-party tester and any owner, officer, or employee of any program offering commercial truck driving under the Kentucky Community and Technical College System or a proprietary school licensed under KRS Chapter 165A. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Applicants shall be permitted to take the skills test for a particular class vehicle an unlimited number of times; however, an applicant shall not retest more than one (1) time in any twenty-four (24) hour period. </section><section prefix="b">The skills test shall consist of three (3) separate portions: pre-trip inspection, basic maneuvering, and road skills. An applicant must achieve a score of at least eighty percent (80%) on each portion of the skills test before a CDL may be issued to the applicant. An applicant who passes one (1) or more portions of the skills test but does not pass all portions of the skills test shall retest only on those portions of the skills test the applicant failed. </section><section prefix="c">An applicant who fails any portion of the skills test four (4) times shall be notified by the State Police that the applicant is required to wait one (1) week and pay a retest fee of fifty dollars ($50) before retaking a portion of this skills test again. </section><section prefix="d">Failure of an applicant to notify the State Police prior to missing an appointment for a skills test shall be considered a failure, on all parts of the skills test scheduled to be given, for the purposes of determining number of failures, waiting periods, and retesting fees under paragraph (c) of this subsection for individual applicants. A missed appointment failure under this paragraph shall not be reported as a failure to the board. </section><section prefix="e">The provisions of KRS 281A.150 notwithstanding, an application fee shall not be charged for each test that is retaken as a result of a failing score. </section></section><section prefix="7">An applicant who seeks reinstatement of a commercial driver's license after a suspension, withdrawal, revocation, or disqualification of less than one (1) year shall pay the reinstatement fee as prescribed by KRS 281A.150(6) and shall receive his or her commercial driver's license with all endorsement and restrictions that were in effect at the time of suspension. An applicant who seeks reinstatement of a commercial driver's license after a suspension, withdrawal, revocation, or disqualification of one (1) year or more shall submit to the skills, knowledge, and vision tests. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Within ninety (90) days of April 22, 2006, the State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to set forth the qualifications for contract examiners retained under subsection (2)(b) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 288, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, effective April 22, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 8, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective February 20, 1992; and ch. 274, sec. 10, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 16, effective January 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 4, (3) at 649.</budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 28 and 85, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (4/22/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, made reference to "Department of Transportation" as shown in subsection (2)(d) of this statute. After consulting the drafter of that Act, to avoid confusion with the State Transportation Cabinet, in codification the Reviser of Statutes has changed the reference to read "U.S. Department of Transportation." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>