<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.570</section_number><catch_line>Egg marketing board -- Functions -- Membership -- Appointment -- Terms -- Qualifications -- Meetings -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be an egg marketing board in the Department of Agriculture. The board shall act in an advisory capacity to the Commissioner in all matters pertaining to the administration of the egg marketing law. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall be composed of the Commissioner, chairman ex officio, and six (6) members appointed by the Governor from lists of names submitted by egg producing and marketing organizations within the Commonwealth approved by the Commissioner for the purpose of submitting such lists. Appointments shall be for three (3) years, except that in the case of the members first appointed, two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) members for two (2) years, and two (2) members for three (3) years. All members shall be residents of the Commonwealth and not more than three (3) shall be of the same political party. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall meet at least once each calendar year and at such other times as the Commissioner, acting chairman, or a quorum of the board may deem necessary. The chairman shall serve without additional compensation, but the members shall receive reimbursement for their necessary traveling expenses and the sum of fifty dollars ($50) per day for each day they attend board meetings, payable out of funds derived from administration of the egg marketing law. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 31, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1957. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12598</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>