<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">A ANNEXATION </unit></structure><section_number>81A.060</section_number><catch_line>Public hearings -- Authority of board of aldermen. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After the preparation of the report required by KRS 81A.050, any city of the first class proposing annexation shall hold at least two (2) public hearings on the proposed annexation prior to the enactment of the first ordinance.  Additional hearings may be held.  Notice of such hearings shall be published in accordance with KRS Chapter 424.  </section><section prefix="2">The hearings held pursuant to this section shall provide an opportunity to be heard to all persons residing or owning property in the area described in the notice of the public hearing, and to all residents of the city.  </section><section prefix="3">At each public hearing, a representative of the city shall make an explanation of the report required in KRS 81A.050.  Such explanation shall be as detailed as necessary so as to convey an accurate and definitive report.  </section><section prefix="4">The board of aldermen shall take into consideration facts presented at the public hearings and shall have authority to amend the report required by KRS 81A.050 and to make changes in the plans for serving the area proposed to be annexed.  If any amendment or change is approved by the board, another hearing shall be held to provide any person residing or owning property in the area to be annexed or any resident of the city an opportunity to be heard on the amendment or amendments.  Such hearing shall be held not later than thirty (30) days after the board approves the amendment.  Notice of such hearing shall be published in accordance with KRS Chapter 424.  </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25004</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>