<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-606</section_number><catch_line>Power to bind and liability to partnership before dissolution of person dissociated as general partner. </catch_line><order_by>2-606</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After a person is dissociated as a general partner and before the limited partnership is dissolved, converted under KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963, or merged out of existence under KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963, the limited partnership is bound by an act of the person only if: <section prefix="a">The act would have bound the limited partnership under KRS 362.2-402 before the dissociation; and </section><section prefix="b">At the time the other party enters into the transaction: <section prefix="1">Less than two (2) years has passed since the dissociation; and </section><section prefix="2">The other party does not have notice of the dissociation and reasonably believes that the person is a general partner. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If a limited partnership is bound under subsection (1) of this section, then the person dissociated as a general partner is liable: <section prefix="a">To the limited partnership for any damage caused to the limited partnership arising from that obligation; and </section><section prefix="b">If a general partner or another person dissociated as a general partner is liable for that obligation, to that general partner or other person for any damage caused to that general partner or other person arising from that liability. </section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 143, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>