<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272">COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>272.261</section_number><catch_line>Removal of officers or directors -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>261</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any member may bring charges against an officer or director by filing them in writing with the secretary of the association, together with a petition signed by ten percent (10%) of the membership, requesting the officer's or director's removal. The removal shall be voted upon at the next regular or special meeting of the association. By an affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds (2/3) of the votes entitled to be cast by members present in person, or by proxy (if permitted by the bylaws), and voting, the association may remove such officer or director. The director or officer against whom such charges have been brought shall be informed in writing of the charges prior to the meeting, and shall have an opportunity at the meeting to be heard in person or by counsel, and to present witnesses; and, the person, or persons, bringing the charges shall have the same opportunity. </section><section prefix="2">If an association's bylaws provide for election of directors by districts, the petition for removal of a director must be signed by not less than twenty percent (20%) of the members residing in the district from which the director was elected. The board may call a special meeting of the members residing in that district to consider the removal of the director. By an affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds (2/3) of the votes entitled to be cast by members present in person, or by proxy (if permitted by the bylaws), and voting, at such meeting duly called and held, the director in question shall be removed from office; except that this section does not apply to directors appointed under subsection (3) of KRS 272.171. </section></text><history>Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 5. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 14. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>