<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.170</section_number><catch_line>Paramedics -- Permitted activities -- Employment by hospitals -- Reasonable control by employers. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the provisions of this section, a paramedic may perform any procedure: <section prefix="a">Specified in the most recent curriculum of the United States Department of Transportation training course for paramedics; and </section><section prefix="b">Any additional procedure specified by the board by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">When there is a change in the United States Department of Transportation curriculum for paramedics, or the board approves an additional skill or procedure by administrative regulation, or approves a protocol differing from the curriculum or administrative regulations, no person who was not trained under that curriculum or administrative regulation shall perform any activity or procedure in the new curriculum, administrative regulation, or protocol unless the person has been trained according to the new curriculum, administrative regulation, or protocol and demonstrates competency in the new knowledge or skill. Competency in a new skill shall be demonstrated through a return demonstration to a competent evaluator. If the board adopts the new procedure or skill, the board shall promulgate an administrative regulation specifying the new procedure, training requirements, examination requirements, and a time period during which the paramedic shall successfully complete the material or lose his or her license as a paramedic. </section><section prefix="3">A paramedic may draw blood samples from a criminal defendant upon the request of a peace officer and the consent of the defendant, or without the consent of the defendant upon receipt of a court order requiring the procedure, if the paramedic is authorized to do so by his or her employer. The authorization shall be in writing and may be by general written policy of the employer and the service's medical director. The paramedic who drew the blood sample shall deliver the sample to the peace officer or other person specified by the court in a court order and shall testify in court with regard thereto upon service of a proper subpoena. </section><section prefix="4">A paramedic shall be permitted to render services only under the supervision of an emergency medical services medical director. </section><section prefix="5">Any provision of this chapter other than this section relating to the requirement for additional training, requirement for skill examination, or approval of standing orders, protocols, or medical procedures to the contrary notwithstanding, a paramedic may be employed by a hospital to work as a licensed paramedic in the emergency department of the hospital subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The hospital in collaboration with the medical staff shall provide operating procedures and policies under which the paramedic shall operate consistent with the paramedic's scope of practice; </section><section prefix="b">A paramedic shall provide patient care services under the orders of a physician, physician assistant, advanced practice registered nurse, or as delegated by a registered nurse; </section><section prefix="c">Subject to the provisions relating to the scope of practice of a paramedic, a hospital may require a paramedic to take additional training on any subject or skill which the paramedic may be required to perform in a hospital and demonstrate competency in the skill or subject to a competent evaluator; and </section><section prefix="d">The paramedic does not violate the provisions of KRS 311A.175 or any other statute or administrative regulation relating to a paramedic. </section></section> No provision of this section shall prevent a paramedic from being employed in any other section of the hospital where the paramedic's job duties do not require certification or licensure by the board and do not otherwise constitute the unlawful practice of medicine. <section prefix="6">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, nothing in this section shall prevent an employer from exercising reasonable fiscal control over the costs of providing medical services to its citizens nor prevent the employer from exercising any reasonable control over paramedics providing care on behalf of the licensed entity. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 50, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 31, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>