<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.874</section_number><catch_line>Abstracts, memoranda, copies -- Agency may prescribe fee -- Use of nonexempt public records for commercial purposes -- Online access. </catch_line><order_by>874</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon inspection, the applicant shall have the right to make abstracts of the public records and memoranda thereof, and to obtain copies of all public records not exempted by the terms of KRS 61.878. When copies are requested, the custodian may require a written request and advance payment of the prescribed fee, including postage where appropriate. If the applicant desires copies of public records other than written records, the custodian of the records shall duplicate the records or permit the applicant to duplicate the records; however, the custodian shall ensure that such duplication will not damage or alter the original records. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Nonexempt public records used for noncommercial purposes shall be available for copying in either standard electronic or standard hard copy format, as designated by the party requesting the records, where the agency currently maintains the records in electronic format. Nonexempt public records used for noncommercial purposes shall be copied in standard hard copy format where agencies currently maintain records in hard copy format. Agencies are not required to convert hard copy format records to electronic formats. </section><section prefix="b">The minimum standard format in paper form shall be defined as not less than 8 1/2 inches x 11 inches in at least one (1) color on white paper, or for electronic format, in a flat file electronic American Standard Code for Information Interchange (ASCII) format. If the public agency maintains electronic public records in a format other than ASCII, and this format conforms to the requestor's requirements, the public record may be provided in this alternate electronic format for standard fees as specified by the public agency. Any request for a public record in a form other than the forms described in this section shall be considered a nonstandardized request. </section></section><section prefix="3">The public agency may prescribe a reasonable fee for making copies of nonexempt public records requested for use for noncommercial purposes which shall not exceed the actual cost of reproduction, including the costs of the media and any mechanical processing cost incurred by the public agency, but not including the cost of staff required. If a public agency is asked to produce a record in a nonstandardized format, or to tailor the format to meet the request of an individual or a group, the public agency may at its discretion provide the requested format and recover staff costs as well as any actual costs incurred. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Unless an enactment of the General Assembly prohibits the disclosure of public records to persons who intend to use them for commercial purposes, if copies of nonexempt public records are requested for commercial purposes, the public agency may establish a reasonable fee. </section><section prefix="b">The public agency from which copies of nonexempt public records are requested for a commercial purpose may require a certified statement from the requestor stating the commercial purpose for which they shall be used, and may require the requestor to enter into a contract with the agency. The contract shall permit use of the public records for the stated commercial purpose for a specified fee. </section><section prefix="c">The fee provided for in subsection (a) of this section may be based on one or both of the following: <section prefix="1">Cost to the public agency of media, mechanical processing, and staff required to produce a copy of the public record or records; </section><section prefix="2">Cost to the public agency of the creation, purchase, or other acquisition of the public records. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">It shall be unlawful for a person to obtain a copy of any part of a public record for a: <section prefix="a">Commercial purpose, without stating the commercial purpose, if a certified statement from the requestor was required by the public agency pursuant to subsection (4)(b) of this section; or </section><section prefix="b">Commercial purpose, if the person uses or knowingly allows the use of the public record for a different commercial purpose; or </section><section prefix="c">Noncommercial purpose, if the person uses or knowingly allows the use of the public record for a commercial purpose. A newspaper, periodical, radio or television station shall not be held to have used or knowingly allowed the use of the public record for a commercial purpose merely because of its publication or broadcast, unless it has also given its express permission for that commercial use. </section></section><section prefix="6">Online access to public records in electronic form, as provided under this section, may be provided and made available at the discretion of the public agency. If a party wishes to access public records by electronic means and the public agency agrees to provide online access, a public agency may require that the party enter into a contract, license, or other agreement with the agency, and may charge fees for these agreements. Fees shall not exceed: <section prefix="a">The cost of physical connection to the system and reasonable cost of computer time access charges; and </section><section prefix="b">If the records are requested for a commercial purpose, a reasonable fee based on the factors set forth in subsection (4) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>