<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.776</section_number><catch_line>Energy audit training program -- Additional programs on energy awareness. </catch_line><order_by>776</order_by><text>The cabinet, with the assistance of the Department for Energy Development and Independence, shall institute an energy audit training program to identify energy saving techniques for state-owned building maintenance staff. Additional programs shall be developed to educate state employees and other building occupants on energy awareness and practices to reduce energy use in state-owned buildings. Local government employees may be included in training and educational programs. </text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 6, effective February 25, 2010; and amended ch. 24, sec. 53, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 30, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 53, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24 and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5. Notwithstanding KRS 446.260, these Acts do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22688</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>