<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.470</section_number><catch_line>Purposes for which assistance funds may be used.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text>Law Enforcement Foundation Program funds made available to local units shall be received, held, and expended in accordance with the provisions of KRS 15.410 to 15.510, including the administrative regulations promulgated by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet and the following specific restrictions: <section prefix="1">Funds provided shall be used only as a cash salary supplement to police officers, for payments to the defined benefit pension plan to which the officer belongs to cover employer retirement costs on the cash salary supplement, and for administrative costs as provided in KRS 15.450; </section><section prefix="2">Funds provided shall be used only to compensate police officers who have complied with KRS 15.440(1)(c), (d), and (e); </section><section prefix="3">Each police officer shall be entitled to receive the state supplement which his qualifications brought to the local unit; </section><section prefix="4">Funds provided shall not be used to supplant existing salaries or as a substitute for normal salary increases periodically due to police officers; </section><section prefix="5">Each police officer receiving the state supplement who is also a member of the Kentucky National Guard or any reserve component of the United States Armed Forces shall continue to receive the state supplement during any period of military activation, as provided in KRS 15.460(2); and </section><section prefix="6">Funds distributed or received pursuant to subsection (5) of this section shall be excluded from all aspects of the Kentucky Retirement Systems or any other retirement system. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 25, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(10). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 2, (3) at 648. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>