<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.177</section_number><catch_line>Sale and disposal of hypodermic syringes or needles. </catch_line><order_by>177</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person engaged in sales at retail shall display hypodermic syringes or needles in any portion of the place of business which is open or accessible to the public. </section><section prefix="2">Every person engaged in sales of hypodermic syringes or needles at retail shall maintain a bound record in which shall be kept: <section prefix="a">The name of the purchaser; and </section><section prefix="b">The address of the purchaser; and </section><section prefix="c">The quantity of syringes or needles purchased; and </section><section prefix="d">The date of the sale; and </section><section prefix="e">Planned use of such syringes or needles. </section></section><section prefix="3">Said record shall be maintained for a period of two (2) years from the date of the sale and shall be available for inspection during business hours by any law enforcement officer, agent or employee of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or Board of Pharmacy engaged in the enforcement of KRS Chapter 218A. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall present false identification or give a false or fictitious name or address in obtaining or attempting to obtain any hypodermic syringe or needle. </section><section prefix="5">No person engaged in the retail sale of hypodermic syringes or needles shall: <section prefix="a">Fail to keep the records required by this section; or </section><section prefix="b">Fraudulently alter any record required to be kept by this section; or </section><section prefix="c">Destroy, before the time period required by this section has elapsed, any record required to be kept by this section; or </section><section prefix="d">Sell, or otherwise dispose of, any hypodermic syringe to any person who does not present the identification required by this section; or </section><section prefix="e">Disclose the names in said book except to those required by this section. </section></section><section prefix="6">Any physician, other licensed medical person, hospital, or clinic disposing of hypodermic syringes or needles shall crush the barrel of same or otherwise render the instrument incapable of further use. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 513, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 458, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9307</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>