<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.297</section_number><catch_line>Sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, or pledge of assets. </catch_line><order_by>297</order_by><text>A sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition of all, or substantially all, property and assets of a corporation may be made upon such terms and conditions and for such consideration, which may consist in whole or in part of money or property, real or personal, including shares of any corporation for profit, domestic or foreign, as may be authorized in the following manner:  <section prefix="1">If there are members entitled to vote thereon, the board of directors shall adopt a resolution recommending such sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition and directing that it be submitted to a vote at a meeting of members entitled to vote thereon, which may be either an annual or a special meeting, written notice stating that the purpose, or one of the purposes, of such meeting is to consider the sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition of all, or substantially all, the property and assets of the corporation shall be given to each member entitled to vote at such meeting, within the time and in the manner provided by KRS 273.161 to 273.390 for the giving of notice of meetings of members. At such meeting the members may authorize such sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition and may fix, or may authorize the board of directors to fix, any or all of the terms and conditions thereof and the consideration to be received by the corporation therefor. Such authorization shall require at least two-thirds (2/3) of the votes which members present at such meeting or represented by proxy are entitled to cast. After such authorization by a vote of members, the board of directors, nevertheless, in its discretion, may abandon such sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition of assets, subject to the rights of third parties under any contracts relating thereto, without further action or approval by members.  </section><section prefix="2">If there are no members, or no members entitled to vote thereon, a sale, lease, exchange, mortgage, pledge or other disposition of all, or substantially all, the property and assets of a corporation shall be authorized upon receiving the vote of a majority of the directors in office. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 43. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13680</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>