<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.650</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 158.680 to 158.710.  (Expired) </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>As used in KRS 158.680 to 158.710, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="2">"Competencies" means the possession of skills, knowledge, and understandings to the degree they can be demonstrated or measured; </section><section prefix="3">"Performance goals" means expected student and school district outcomes as approved by the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education; </section><section prefix="4">"Interim performance goal" means the specified amount of improvement the district shall achieve toward meeting the performance goal agreed upon in the district improvement plan; </section><section prefix="5">"Process goals" means systematic and orderly procedures, including specific actions and time frames to be followed in achieving performance goals; </section><section prefix="6">"Standards" means acceptable levels of attainment school districts shall meet in student, program, service, and operational performance as established in administrative regulations adopted by the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education; </section><section prefix="7">"Educationally deficient school district" means a school district which does not meet minimum standards in student, program, service, or operational performance; </section><section prefix="8">"Education development district" means an educationally deficient district which fails to meet all process goals or to achieve all interim performance goals according to the timelines established in the district improvement plan; </section><section prefix="9">"Annual performance report" means the report published annually by each local board of education that presents the district's performance with regard to performance goals as established by State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education administrative regulations; and </section><section prefix="10">"District improvement plan" means the plan developed by a local school district in consultation with the Department of Education, that establishes the process goals and timelines for correcting identified deficiencies in the achievement of performance goals and the interim performance goals. The plan shall be approved by the local board of education and the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education. </section></text><history>Expired 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. 1, sec. 11, effective June 30, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I. sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 347, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978.</history><metadata><lrc-note>(7/15/96).  Because this statute has expired as of June 30, 1996, under KRS 158.710(6), references to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education within the statute have not been changed to the Kentucky Board of Education as required by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3566</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>