<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.730</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition by certain employees prohibited -- Disclosure of previous interest required -- Payment under eminent domain proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text>No officer or employee of a city of any class, county containing a city of the first class, or consolidated local government, or of the vacant property review commission, who in the course of his or her duties is required to participate in the determination of property blight or deterioration or the issuance of notices on code violations which may lead to a determination of blight or deterioration, shall acquire any interest in any property declared to be blighted or deteriorated. If any such officer or employee owns or has financial interest, direct or indirect, in any property certified to be blighted or deteriorated, he or she shall immediately disclose, in writing, such interest to the commission and to the legislative body and such disclosure shall be entered in the minutes of the commission and of the legislative body. Failure to so disclose such interest shall constitute misconduct in office. No payment shall be made to any officer or employee for any property or interest therein acquired by the city of any class, consolidated local government, or county containing a city of the first class from such officer or employee unless the amount of such payment is fixed by court order in eminent domain proceedings, or unless payment is unanimously approved by the legislative body. </text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 8, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 131, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>