<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78">COUNTY EMPLOYEES' CIVIL SERVICE AND RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>78.545</section_number><catch_line>Matters not specified in KRS 78.510 to 78.852.   </catch_line><order_by>545</order_by><text>The following matters shall be administered in the same manner subject to the same limitations and requirements as provided for the Kentucky Employees Retirement System as follows: <section prefix="1">Cessation of membership, conditions, as provided for by KRS 61.535; </section><section prefix="2">Statement of member and employer, as provided for by KRS 61.540; </section><section prefix="3">Beneficiary to be designated by member, change, rights, as provided for by KRS 61.542; </section><section prefix="4">Service credit determination, as provided for by KRS 61.545; </section><section prefix="5">Cessation of membership, loss of benefits, as provided for by KRS 61.550; </section><section prefix="6">Service credit, Armed Forces, as provided for by KRS 61.555; </section><section prefix="7">Normal and early retirement eligibility requirements, as provided for by KRS 61.559; </section><section prefix="8">Retirement allowance increases as provided for by KRS 61.691; </section><section prefix="9">Retirement application procedure, effective retirement date, as provided for by KRS 61.590; </section><section prefix="10">Disability retirement, conditions, as provided for by KRS 61.600; </section><section prefix="11">Disability retirement, allowance, as provided for by KRS 61.605; </section><section prefix="12">Medical examination after disability retirement, as provided for by KRS 61.610; </section><section prefix="13">Disability retirement allowance, reduction, as provided for by KRS 61.615; </section><section prefix="14">Determination of retirement allowance, as provided for by KRS 61.595; </section><section prefix="15">Refund of contributions, conditions, as provided for by KRS 61.625; </section><section prefix="16">Refund of contributions, death after retirement, as provided for by KRS 61.630; </section><section prefix="17">Optional retirement plans, as provided for by KRS 61.635; </section><section prefix="18">Suspension of retirement payments on reemployment, reinstatement, as provided for by KRS 61.637; </section><section prefix="19">Death before retirement, beneficiary's options, as provided for by KRS 61.640; </section><section prefix="20">Board of trustees, conflict of interest, as provided for by KRS 61.655; </section><section prefix="21">Custodian of funds, payments made, when, as provided for by KRS 61.660; </section><section prefix="22">Medical examiners and hearing procedures, as provided for by KRS 61.665; </section><section prefix="23">Actuarial bases, as provided for by KRS 61.670; </section><section prefix="24">Employer's administrative duties, as provided for by KRS 61.675; </section><section prefix="25">Correction of errors in records, as provided for by KRS 61.685; </section><section prefix="26">Exemptions of retirement allowances, and qualified domestic relations orders, as provided for by KRS 61.690; </section><section prefix="27">Credit for service prior to membership date, as provided for by KRS 61.526; </section><section prefix="28">Creditable compensation of fee officers, as provided for by KRS 61.541; </section><section prefix="29">Members' account, confidential, as provided for by KRS 61.661; </section><section prefix="30">Retirement plan for employees determined to be in a hazardous position, as provided for by KRS 61.592; </section><section prefix="31">Maximum disability benefit, as provided for by KRS 61.607; </section><section prefix="32">Consent of employees to deductions and reciprocal arrangement between systems, as provided for by KRS 61.680; </section><section prefix="33">Employer contributions, as provided for by KRS 61.565; </section><section prefix="34">Recontribution and delayed contribution payments, purchase of service credit, interest, and installment payments, as provided for by KRS 61.552; </section><section prefix="35">Hospital and medical insurance plan, as provided by KRS 61.702; </section><section prefix="36">Death benefit, as provided by KRS 61.705; </section><section prefix="37">Reinstated employee, contributions on creditable compensation, as provided for by KRS 61.569; </section><section prefix="38">Statement to be made under oath, good faith reliance, as provided for in KRS 61.699; </section><section prefix="39">Disability procedure for members in hazardous positions as provided for in KRS 16.582; </section><section prefix="40">Direct deposit of recipient's retirement allowance as provided for in KRS 61.623; </section><section prefix="41">Death or disability from a duty-related injury as provided in KRS 61.621; </section><section prefix="42">Purchase of service credit effective July 1, 2001, as provided in KRS 61.5525; </section><section prefix="43">Payment of small accounts upon death of member, retiree, or recipient without formal administration of the estate as provided in KRS 61.703; </section><section prefix="44">Hybrid cash balance plan provided to new members as provided by KRS 61.597; </section><section prefix="45">Employer payment of increases in creditable compensation during the last five (5) years of employment as provided by KRS 61.598; </section><section prefix="46">Calculation of retirement allowance, as provided by KRS 61.599; and </section><section prefix="47">Voluntary and involuntary cessation of participation by a participating agency as provided by KRS 61.522. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 75, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 29, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 35, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 485, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 55, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 23, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, secs. 33 and 40. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 34, effective March 26, 1974. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2; and ch. 116, sec. 64. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44283</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>