<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.32-060</section_number><catch_line>Rehabilitation, replacement, or expansion of existing facilities -- Criteria for approval as economic development project. </catch_line><order_by>32-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall not approve an economic development project that otherwise meets the requirements of this subchapter if the economic development project will result in the replacement of facilities existing in the state except as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The authority may approve an economic development project that: <section prefix="a">Rehabilitates an existing facility used for manufacturing, agribusiness, or nonretail service or technology, or as a national or regional corporate headquarters, if: <section prefix="1">The facility has not been in operation for a period of ninety (90) or more consecutive days; or </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The current occupant of the facility has advertised a notice of closure; and </section><section prefix="b">The eligible company proposing the economic development project is not an affiliate of the current occupant of the facility; or </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The facility is sold or transferred pursuant to a foreclosure ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction or an order of a bankruptcy court of competent jurisdiction; and </section><section prefix="b">The title to the facility prior to the sale is not vested in the eligible company or an affiliate of the eligible company; </section></section></section><section prefix="b">Replaces an existing manufacturing, agribusiness, nonretail service or technology, or national or regional corporate headquarters facility if: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Title to the facility: </section> i. Is held by exercise of the power of eminent domain; or  ii. May be taken pursuant to a nonappealable judgment  granting authority to exercise the power of eminent  domain; and <section prefix="b">Normal operations at the facility cannot be resumed within twelve (12) months; or </section></section><section prefix="2">The facility has been damaged or destroyed by fire or other casualty to the extent that normal operations cannot be resumed at the facility within twelve (12) months; or </section></section><section prefix="c">Replaces an existing facility located in the same county if the existing facility cannot be expanded due to the unavailability of real estate at or adjacent to the facility to be replaced. Any economic development project satisfying the requirements of this paragraph shall be eligible for incentives under this subchapter only to the extent of the expansion. No incentives shall be available for the equivalent of the facility to be replaced or rehabilitated. </section></section><section prefix="3">The authority shall not approve an economic development project under this section which results in a lease abandonment or lease termination by the approved company without the consent of the lessor. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 14, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>