<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.365</section_number><catch_line>Crisis intervention team (CIT) training -- Curriculum -- Individual and aggregate reports -- Telephonic behavioral health jail triage system.   </catch_line><order_by>365</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Crisis intervention team (CIT) training" means a forty (40) hour training curriculum based on the Memphis Police Department Crisis Intervention Team model of best practices for law enforcement intervention with persons who may have a mental illness, substance abuse disorder, an intellectual disability, developmental disability, or dual diagnosis that meets the requirements of subsections (2) to (5) of this section and is approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council; </section><section prefix="b">"Department" means the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="c">"Prisoner" has the same meaning as set out in KRS 441.005; and </section><section prefix="d">"Qualified mental health professional" has the same meaning as set out in KRS 202A.011. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall, in collaboration with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the regional community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability, and representatives of the Kentucky statewide affiliate of the National Alliance on Mental Illness, coordinate the development of CIT training designed to train law enforcement officers to: <section prefix="a">Effectively respond to persons who may have a mental illness, substance abuse disorder, intellectual disability, developmental disability, or dual diagnosis; </section><section prefix="b">Reduce injuries to officers and citizens; </section><section prefix="c">Reduce inappropriate incarceration; </section><section prefix="d">Reduce liability; and </section><section prefix="e">Improve risk management practices for law enforcement agencies. </section></section><section prefix="3">The CIT training shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">An introduction to crisis intervention teams; </section><section prefix="b">Identification and recognition of the different types of mental illnesses, substance abuse disorders, intellectual disabilities, developmental disabilities, and dual diagnoses; </section><section prefix="c">Interviewing and assessing a person who may have a mental illness, substance abuse disorder, intellectual disability, developmental disability, or dual diagnosis; </section><section prefix="d">Identification and common effects of psychotropic medications; </section><section prefix="e">Suicide prevention techniques; </section><section prefix="f">Community resources and options for treatment; </section><section prefix="g">Voluntary and involuntary processes for hospitalization of a person with a mental illness, substance abuse disorder, intellectual disability, developmental disability, or dual diagnosis; and </section><section prefix="h">Hostage or other negotiations with a person with a mental illness, intellectual disability, substance abuse disorder, developmental disability, or dual diagnosis. </section></section><section prefix="4">The curriculum shall be presented by a team composed of, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">A law enforcement training instructor who has completed a forty (40) hour CIT training course and a CIT training instructor's course which has been approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, and at least forty (40) hours of direct experience working with a CIT; </section><section prefix="b">A representative from the local community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability serving the region where CIT training is conducted; </section><section prefix="c">A consumer of mental health services; and </section><section prefix="d">A representative of the Kentucky statewide affiliate of the National Alliance on Mental Illness. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The department shall submit the CIT training curriculum and the names of available instructors approved by the department to conduct or assist in the delivery of CIT training to the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council no later than July 1, 2007. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Law Enforcement Council shall notify the department of approval or disapproval of the CIT training curriculum and trainers within thirty (30) days of submission of the curriculum and the names of instructors. </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Law Enforcement Council may waive instructor requirements for non-law enforcement trainers whose names are submitted by the department. </section><section prefix="d">If the curriculum or trainers are not approved, the department shall have an opportunity to revise and resubmit the curriculum and to submit additional names of instructors if necessary. </section></section><section prefix="6">If the curriculum is approved, the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council shall: <section prefix="a">Notify the Department of Kentucky State Police and all law enforcement agencies employing peace officers certified under KRS 15.380 to 15.404 of the availability of the CIT training; and </section><section prefix="b">Notify all instructors and entities approved for law enforcement training under KRS 15.330 of the availability of the CIT training. </section></section><section prefix="7">Any law enforcement training entity approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council may use the CIT training model and curriculum in law enforcement in-service training as specified by subsection (1) of this section that is consistent with the Memphis CIT national model for best practices. </section><section prefix="8">No later than one (1) year after June 26, 2007, the department shall submit to the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council a CIT training instructors' curriculum and the names of available instructors approved by the department to conduct or assist in the delivery of CIT training instructors' training. Additional instructors may be submitted on a schedule determined by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="9">All CIT-trained law enforcement officers shall report to his or her agency on forms provided with the CIT curriculum on encounters with persons with mental illness, substance abuse disorders, intellectual disabilities, developmental disabilities, and dual diagnoses. The law enforcement agency shall aggregate reports received and submit nonidentifying information to the department on a monthly basis. Except for information pertaining to the number of law enforcement agencies participating in CIT training, the reports to the department shall include the information specified in subsection (10) of this section. </section><section prefix="10">The department shall aggregate all reports from law enforcement agencies under subsection (9) of this section and submit nonidentifying statewide information to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the Criminal Justice Council, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare by December 1, 2008, and annually thereafter. The report shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">The number of law enforcement officers trained per agency; </section><section prefix="b">Law enforcement responses to persons with mental illness, substance abuse disorders, intellectual disabilities, developmental disabilities, and dual diagnoses; </section><section prefix="c">Incidents of harm to the law enforcement officer or to the citizen; </section><section prefix="d">The number of times physical force was required and the type of physical force used; and </section><section prefix="e">The outcome of the encounters that may include but not be limited to incarceration or hospitalization. </section></section><section prefix="11">To implement the requirements of subsections (2) to (5) and (8) to (10) of this section, the department may use public or private funds as available and may develop a contract with a nonprofit entity that is a Kentucky statewide mental health advocacy organization that has a minimum of five (5) years of experience in implementation of the CIT training program in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="12">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall create a telephonic behavioral health jail triage system to screen prisoners for mental health risk issues, including suicide risk. The triage system shall be designed to give the facility receiving and housing the prisoner an assessment of his or her mental health risk, with the assessment corresponding to recommended protocols for housing, supervision, and care which are designed to mitigate the mental health risks identified by the system. The triage system shall consist of: <section prefix="a">A screening instrument which the personnel of a facility receiving a prisoner shall utilize to assess inmates for mental health, suicide, intellectual disabilities, and acquired brain injury risk factors; and </section><section prefix="b">A continuously available toll-free telephonic triage hotline staffed by a qualified mental health professional which the screening personnel may utilize if the screening instrument indicates an increased mental health risk for the assessed prisoner. </section></section><section prefix="13">In creating and maintaining the telephonic behavioral health jail triage system, the cabinet shall consult with: <section prefix="a">The Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Jailers Association; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with Mental Illness, Alcohol and Other Drug Abuse Disorders, and Dual Diagnoses; and </section><section prefix="d">The regional community services programs for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability created under KRS 210.370 to 210.460. </section></section><section prefix="14">The cabinet may delegate all or a portion of the operational responsibility for the triage system to the regional community services programs for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability created under KRS 210.370 to 210.460 if the regional program agrees and the cabinet remains responsible for the costs of delegated functions. </section><section prefix="15">The cabinet shall design into the implemented triage system the ability to screen and assess prisoners who communicate other than in English or who communicate other than through voice. </section><section prefix="16">The cost of operating the telephonic behavioral health jail triage system shall be borne by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="17">Records generated under this section shall be treated in the same manner and with the same degree of confidentiality as other medical records of the prisoner. </section><section prefix="18">Unless the prisoner is provided with an attorney during the screening and assessment, any statement made by the prisoner in the course of the screening or assessment shall not be admissible in a criminal trial of the prisoner, unless the trial is for a crime committed during the screening and assessment. </section><section prefix="19">The cabinet may, after consultation with those entities set out in subsection (13) of this section, promulgate administrative regulations for the operation of the telephonic behavioral health jail triage system and the establishment of its recommended protocols for prisoner housing, supervision, and care. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 75, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 37, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 326, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 335, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the reorganization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (6/26/2007).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes in codification has changed the internal numbering system of subsection (2) of this statute. The meaning of the text was not altered. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40803</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>