<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.150</section_number><catch_line>Criminal gang activity or recruitment -- Actions not constituting defenses. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To establish the existence of a "criminal gang" as defined in KRS 506.140, any competent evidence that is probative of the existence of or membership in a criminal gang shall be admissible, including the following: <section prefix="a">Self-proclamation; </section><section prefix="b">A common name, insignia, flag, or means of recognition; </section><section prefix="c">Common identifying hand or body signs, signals, or code; </section><section prefix="d">A common identifying mode, style, or color of dress; </section><section prefix="e">An identifying tattoo or body marking; </section><section prefix="f">Membership, age, or other qualifications; </section><section prefix="g">Creed of belief; </section><section prefix="h">An organizational or command structure, overt or covert; </section><section prefix="i">A de facto claim of territory or jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="j">An initiation ritual; </section><section prefix="k">A concentration or specialty; or </section><section prefix="l">A method of operation or criminal enterprise. </section></section><section prefix="2">It is no defense to prosecution under KRS 506.140 that: <section prefix="a">One (1) or more members of the gang are not criminally responsible for the offense; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) or more members of the gang have been acquitted, have not been prosecuted or convicted, have been convicted of a different offense, or are under prosecution; </section><section prefix="c">A person has been charged with, acquitted, or convicted of any offense under KRS 506.140; </section><section prefix="d">The participants may not know each other's identity; </section><section prefix="e">The membership in the criminal gang may change from time to time; or </section><section prefix="f">The participants may stand in a wholesaler-retailer or other arm's length arrangement in the conduct of illicit distribution or other operations. </section></section><section prefix="3">Once the initial combination of five (5) or more persons is formed, the number or identity of persons remaining in the gang is immaterial as long as four (4) or more persons in the gang, excluding the defendant, are involved in a continuing pattern of criminal activity as defined in KRS 506.140 constituting a violation of KRS 506.140. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 84, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>