<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="143" order_by="143">COAL TAX </unit></structure><section_number>143.024</section_number><catch_line>Tax incentive for purchase or severance of coal used in alternative fuel or gasification facility. </catch_line><order_by>024</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Alternative fuel facility" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="b">"Approved company" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="c">"Authority" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="d">"Base amount" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="e">"Capital investment" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="f">"Eligible project" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="g">"Energy-efficient alternative fuel facility" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="h">"Gasification facility" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; and </section><section prefix="i">"Tax incentive agreement" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other provision of KRS 134.580 or this chapter, an approved company that purchases or severs coal that is subject to the tax imposed under KRS 143.020 and that is specifically used by the approved company as feedstock for an alternative fuel facility, energy-efficient alternative fuel facility, or gasification facility may be eligible for an incentive under KRS 154.27-060. </section><section prefix="3">A company approved for incentives under KRS 154.27-060 shall file a request for the incentive with the department within sixty (60) days of the completion of the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the facility. In subsequent years, the approved company shall file a request for the incentive within sixty (60) days following the end of each calendar year. The request for incentives shall be in the form prescribed by the department through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. The request for incentives shall include but not be limited to the following information: <section prefix="a">Verification of the base amount; </section><section prefix="b">Verification of the tons of coal purchased and used or severed and used by the approved company as feedstock for an alternative fuel facility, energy-efficient alternative fuel facility, or gasification facility during the calendar year for which the request for incentives is being made; </section><section prefix="c">Verification that the minimum capital investment as set forth in the tax incentive agreement has been made; </section><section prefix="d">Verification of the output of coal-derived alternative transportation fuels, coal-derived synthetic natural gas, coal-derived liquid fuels, coal-derived energy-efficient alternative fuels, or other coal-derived chemicals or chemical feedstocks; and </section><section prefix="e">Any other information that the department may require. </section></section><section prefix="4">To assist in determining the amount of coal purchased and used or severed and used that is eligible for the incentive, the department shall obtain from the University of Kentucky Center for Applied Energy Research a reasonable and typical estimate of the tons of coal needed to produce a given output of coal-derived alternative transportation fuels, coal-derived synthetic natural gas, coal-derived liquid fuels, coal-derived energy-efficient alternative fuels, or other coal-derived chemicals or chemical feedstocks, considering: <section prefix="a">The type of coal to be used; </section><section prefix="b">Equipment to be employed; </section><section prefix="c">Size and output of the facility; </section><section prefix="d">Slate of products produced; and </section><section prefix="e">Other characteristics of the alternative fuel facility, energy-efficient alternative fuel facility, or gasification facility. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The department and the authority shall review the request for incentives jointly and shall verify that the request for incentives meets all requirements established by statute and administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="b">The department shall verify the tax paid pursuant to KRS 143.020 on the coal purchased or severed by the approved company and used as feedstock for an alternative fuel facility, energy-efficient alternative fuel facility, or gasification facility during the calendar year for which the application was submitted and shall determine the amount of the tax paid that qualifies for distribution to the approved company pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="c">The incentive amount shall be distributed to the approved company in quarterly installments beginning on July 1 of the year following the calendar year for which the request for incentives required under this section was submitted. </section></section><section prefix="6">The approved company seeking incentives shall execute information-sharing agreements prescribed by the department with vendors from which it purchased coal to verify the value of coal purchased by the approved company and used as feedstock for an alternative fuel facility, energy-efficient alternative fuel facility, or gasification facility and the amount of tax paid under KRS 143.020 on such coal. </section><section prefix="7">The department shall notify the authority of the incentive distributed to each approved company upon request. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 11, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (8/30/2007).  A manifest clerical or typographical error in subsection (4) of this section has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes during codification pursuant to the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29236</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>