<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="635" order_by="635">PUBLIC OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>635.505</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">The "treatment program" means a continuum of services provided in community and institutional settings designed to provide early intervention and treatment services for juvenile sexual offenders. </section><section prefix="2">A "juvenile sexual offender" as used in this chapter means an individual who was at the time of the commission of the offense under the age of eighteen (18) years who is not actively psychotic or an individual with an intellectual disability and who has been adjudicated guilty of or has been convicted of or pled guilty to: <section prefix="a">A felony under KRS Chapter 510; </section><section prefix="b">Any other felony committed in conjunction with a misdemeanor described in KRS Chapter 510; </section><section prefix="c">Any felony under KRS 506.010 when the crime attempted is a felony or misdemeanor described in KRS Chapter 510; </section><section prefix="d">An offense under KRS 530.020; </section><section prefix="e">An offense under KRS 530.064(1)(a); </section><section prefix="f">An offense under KRS 531.310; or </section><section prefix="g">A misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 510. </section></section><section prefix="3">A "juvenile sexual offender assessment" means an assessment of the child's adolescent social development, medical history, educational history, legal history, family history, substance abuse history, sexual history, treatment history, and recent behaviors, which shall be prepared in order to assist the courts in determining whether the child should be declared a juvenile sexual offender, and to provide information regarding the risk for reoffending and recommendations for treatment. </section><section prefix="4">"Individual with an intellectual disability" as used in this section means a juvenile with a full scale intelligent quotient of seventy (70) or below. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 143, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 66, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 538, sec. 14, effective April 13, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>