<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.270</section_number><catch_line>Use of publicly owned resources at impending, happening, or response phase of disaster or emergency. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">During the threatened or impending happening of a disaster or emergency, the Governor, the Adjutant General, or the Director may authorize the use of public employees, equipment, supplies, materials, funds, or any other publicly owned or supported resources to assist in the mitigation of the potential effects of the disaster or emergency, regardless of whether the use is on public or private property. </section><section prefix="2">During the actual happening of and any part of the response phase of a disaster or emergency the Governor, the Adjutant General, or the Director, shall, when necessary or desirable, authorize the use of public employees, equipment, supplies, materials, funds, or any other publicly owned or supported resource to assist in the operations of government, or the private sector, necessary to deal with the disaster or emergency, regardless of whether the use is on public or private property. </section><section prefix="3">After the active or response phase of the disaster or emergency has passed and the recovery phase has begun, the Governor, the Adjutant General, or the Director may authorize the use of public employees, equipment, supplies, funds, or any other publicly owned or supported resources to assist in the recovery phase of the disaster or emergency, regardless of whether the use is on public or private property. </section><section prefix="4">A formal declaration of disaster or emergency shall not be necessary to invoke the provisions of subsection (1) or (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21721</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>