<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.042</section_number><catch_line>Status of student teachers -- Responsibility to administrative staff and supervising teachers -- Professional competency requirement for supervising teachers. </catch_line><order_by>042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Education Professional Standards Board shall provide through administrative regulation for the utilization of the common schools for the preparation of teacher education students from the colleges and universities. </section><section prefix="2">Within the provisions established by the Education Professional Standards Board, local boards of education are authorized to enter into cooperative agreements, including financial arrangements, with colleges and universities for the purpose of providing professional laboratory experiences and student teaching experiences for students preparing for the education profession. </section><section prefix="3">The Education Professional Standards Board shall promulgate administrative regulations defining the professional requirements and general duties of a supervising teacher and requirements for a local school district and school to be used for this purpose. </section><section prefix="4">A student teacher who is jointly assigned under agreement by a teacher education institution and a local board of education shall have the same legal status and protection as a certified teacher employed within the school district and shall be responsible to the administrative staff of the school district and the supervising teacher to whom he or she is assigned. All student teachers shall be subject to the state and national criminal records checks required of certified hires under provisions of KRS 160.380. </section><section prefix="5">Teacher education students, other than student teachers, may be permitted through cooperative agreements between the local school district and the teacher education institution, to engage in supplementary instructional activities with pupils under the direction and supervision of the professional administrative and teaching staff of the school district. Teacher education students shall not be subject to the criminal records checks required under KRS 160.380 or 161.148. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001; and ch. 137, sec. 9, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 67, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><lrc-note> (6/21/2001).  This section was amended by 2001 Ky. Acts chs. 60 and 137, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3834</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>