<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-336</section_number><catch_line>Commingled goods. </catch_line><order_by>9-336</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "commingled goods" means goods that are physically united with other goods in such a manner that their identity is lost in a product or mass. </section><section prefix="2">A security interest does not exist in commingled goods as such. However, a security interest may attach to a product or mass that results when goods become commingled goods. </section><section prefix="3">If collateral becomes commingled goods, a security interest attaches to the product or mass. </section><section prefix="4">If a security interest in collateral is perfected before the collateral becomes commingled goods, the security interest that attaches to the product or mass under subsection (3) of this section is perfected. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (6) of this section, the other provisions of this part of this article determine the priority of a security interest that attaches to the product or mass under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">If more than one (1) security interest attaches to the product or mass under subsection (3) of this section, the following rules determine priority: <section prefix="a">A security interest that is perfected under subsection (4) of this section has priority over a security interest that is unperfected at the time the collateral becomes commingled goods. </section><section prefix="b">If more than one (1) security interest is perfected under subsection (4) of this section, the security interests rank equally in proportion to the value of the collateral at the time it became commingled goods. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 76, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>