<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="187" order_by="187">FINANCIAL RESPONSIBILITY LAW </unit></structure><section_number>187.440</section_number><catch_line>Installment payment of judgment -- Default. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A judgment debtor upon due notice to the judgment creditor may apply to the court in which such judgment was rendered for the privilege of paying such judgment in installments and the court, in its discretion and without prejudice to any other legal remedies which the judgment creditor may have, may so order and fix the amounts and times of payment of the installments. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall not suspend a license, registration or a nonresident's operating privilege, and shall restore any license, registration or nonresident's operating privilege suspended following nonpayment of a judgment, when the judgment debtor gives proof of financial responsibility and obtains such an order permitting the payment of such judgment in installments, and while the payment of any said installment is not in default. </section><section prefix="3">In the event the judgment debtor fails to pay any installment as specified by such order, then upon notice of such default, the cabinet shall forthwith suspend the license, registration or nonresident's operating privilege of the judgment debtor until such judgment is satisfied as provided in KRS 187.290 to 187.620. </section></text><history>Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 16, effective January 1, 1947. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1947</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6261</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>