<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.472</section_number><catch_line>Exemption for certain medical items. </catch_line><order_by>472</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the taxes imposed by this chapter shall not apply to the sale or purchase of: <section prefix="a">A drug purchased for the treatment of a human being for which a prescription is required by state or federal law, whether the drug is dispensed by a licensed pharmacist, administered by a physician or other health care provider, or distributed as a free sample to or from a physician's office; </section><section prefix="b">An over-the-counter drug purchased for the treatment of a human being for which a prescription is issued; </section><section prefix="c">Medical oxygen and oxygen delivery equipment purchased for home use. Oxygen delivery equipment includes: <section prefix="1">High pressure cylinders, cryogenic tanks, oxygen concentrators, or similar medical oxygen delivery equipment including repair and replacement parts for the equipment; and </section><section prefix="2">Tubes, masks, and similar items required for the delivery of oxygen to the patient; </section></section><section prefix="d">Insulin and diabetic supplies, including hypodermic syringes, needles, and sugar (urine and blood) testing materials purchased by an individual for private use; </section><section prefix="e">Colostomy, urostomy, or ileostomy supplies purchased by an individual for private use; </section><section prefix="f">Prosthetic devices purchased by any health care provider for use in the treatment of a specific individual or purchased by an individual as prescribed by a person authorized under the laws of the Commonwealth to issue prescriptions; </section><section prefix="g">Prosthetic devices that are individually designed or created for an individual regardless of the purchaser; </section><section prefix="h">Mobility enhancing equipment for which a prescription is issued; and </section><section prefix="i">Durable medical equipment, including hospital beds for which a prescription is issued. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as specifically provided in subsection (1) of this section, supplies or equipment used to deliver a drug to a patient are taxable. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Drug" means a compound, substance, or preparation and any component of a compound, substance, or preparation, other than food and food ingredients, dietary supplements, or alcoholic beverages as defined in KRS 139.485, that is recognized in the official United States Pharmacopoeia, official Homeopathic Pharmacopoeia of the United States, or official National Formulary, or a supplement to any of them, or is: <section prefix="1">Intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in humans; or </section><section prefix="2">Intended to affect the structure or any function of the human body; </section></section><section prefix="b">"Grooming and hygiene products" means soaps and cleaning solutions, shampoo, toothpaste, mouthwash, antiperspirants, and suntan lotions, regardless of whether the items meet the definition of an over-the-counter drug; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">"Over-the-counter drug" means a drug that contains a label that identifies the product as a drug as required by 21 C.F.R. sec. 201.66. The "over-the-counter drug" label shall include: <section prefix="a">A "Drug Facts" panel; or </section><section prefix="b">A statement of the active ingredients with a list of those ingredients contained in the compound, substance, or preparation. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Over-the-counter drug" shall not include grooming and hygiene products; </section></section><section prefix="d">"Prescription" means an order, formula, or recipe issued in any form of oral, written, electronic, or other means of transmission by a person authorized under the laws of the Commonwealth to prescribe a drug; </section><section prefix="e"><section prefix="1">"Prosthetic device" means a replacement, corrective, or supportive device, including repair and replacement parts for the device, worn on or in the body to: <section prefix="a">Artificially replace a missing portion of the body; </section><section prefix="b">Prevent or correct a physical deformity or malfunction; or </section><section prefix="c">Support a weak or deformed portion of the body. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Prosthetic device" shall not include any of the following: <section prefix="a">Corrective eyeglasses; </section><section prefix="b">Contact lenses; or </section><section prefix="c">Dental prosthesis; </section></section></section><section prefix="f"><section prefix="1">"Mobility enhancing equipment" means equipment, including repair and replacements part for same, which: <section prefix="a">Is primarily and customarily used to provide or increase the ability to move from one place to another and which is appropriate for use either in a home or a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="b">Is not generally used by persons with normal mobility; and </section><section prefix="c">Does not include any motor vehicle or equipment on a motor vehicle normally provided by a motor vehicle manufacturer. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Mobility enhancing equipment" shall not include durable medical equipment; and </section></section><section prefix="g"><section prefix="1">"Durable medical equipment" means equipment, including repair and replacement parts for same, which: <section prefix="a">Can withstand repeated use; </section><section prefix="b">Is primarily and customarily used to serve a medical purpose; </section><section prefix="c">Generally is not useful to a person in the absence of illness or injury; and </section><section prefix="d">Is not worn in or on the body. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Durable medical equipment" shall not include mobility enhancing equipment or oxygen delivery equipment that is not worn in or on the body. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this paragraph, "repair and replacement parts" includes all components or attachments used in connection with durable medical equipment. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 17, effective July 1, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective August 1, 2008; and ch. 95, sec. 1, effective August 1, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 9, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 21, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1971. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (8/1/2008).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has inserted subparagraph and subdivision designations in subsection (3)(f) of this statute during codification. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28892</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>