<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.210</section_number><catch_line>Powers of chief state school officer. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief state school officer shall have access to the papers, books and records of all teachers, trustees, superintendents, or other public school officials. </section><section prefix="2">He may administer oaths and may examine witnesses under oath in any part of the state in any matter pertaining to the public schools, and may cause the testimony to be reduced to writing. He may issue process to compel attendance of witnesses before him and compel witnesses to testify in any investigation he is authorized to make. </section><section prefix="3">When he or his assistants find any mismanagement, misconduct, violation of law, or wrongful or improper use of any district or state school fund, or neglect in the performance of duty on the part of any official, he shall report the same, and any other violation of the school laws discovered by him, to the Kentucky Board of Education, which shall, through the chief state school officer or one (1) of his assistants, call in the county attorney or the Commonwealth's attorney in the county or district where the violation occurs, and the attorney so called in shall assist in the indictment, prosecution, and conviction of the accused. If prosecution is not warrantable, the Kentucky Board of Education may rectify and regulate all such matters. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 137, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4384-12, 4384-15. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3151</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>