<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.392</section_number><catch_line>Report on separation from service -- Placement of certification on inactive status -- Lapse or retirement of certification -- Action by council. </catch_line><order_by>392</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within ten (10) working days from separation from service, the chief executive officer of the employing agency or his designee shall file with the council a summary report that provides the relevant information about the person's separation from service. </section><section prefix="2">If the person separated from service has successfully completed basic training at a school certified or recognized by the council, the council shall place the certification on inactive status. Placement of certification on inactive status shall not prevent the council from subsequently instituting an action to revoke an officer's certification in appropriate cases in accordance with KRS 15.391 for any reason justifying revoked or denied status pursuant to KRS 15.386, the council shall revoke the person's certification. </section><section prefix="3">If the person has been separated from service or has not successfully completed basic training at a school certified or recognized by the council and fails to meet the requirements of KRS 15.400(1), the certification shall lapse. </section><section prefix="4">If the person has been separated due to death, the certification shall be retired. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 139, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 105, effective December 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> ((6/26/2007).  The amendment to this section in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007, is retroactive to July 1, 2004. See 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5.  ((6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 76 and 139. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 139, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>