<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.420</section_number><catch_line>Administrative functions of secretary -- Personnel -- Compensation and other benefits -- Administrative costs. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary may promulgate administrative regulations authorized by statute for the proper administration of the functions of the cabinet, including qualification for the receipt of federal funds and for cooperation with other state and federal agencies. </section><section prefix="2">In the administration of KRS 199.420 to 199.670, the secretary shall cooperate to the fullest extent possible with any agency of this state or any other state of the United States. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary is authorized, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapters 12, 18A, 42, 45, and 64, to appoint, fix the compensation, and prescribe the duties and powers of any officers and employees as are necessary in the performance of the secretary's duties under KRS 199.420 to 199.670. All positions shall be filled by persons selected and appointed on a nonpartisan merit basis, in accordance with merit standards established by law. The secretary shall not employ or pay any person who is an officer or committee member of any political party organization. The secretary may delegate to any person so appointed that power and authority as the secretary deems reasonable and proper for the effective administration of KRS 199.420 to 199.670. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall have the power and authority to elect coverage for the workers in the cabinet, under the provisions of KRS Chapter 341, and may elect coverage for these workers under the workers' compensation law of this state. In the event the coverage is elected the payment of contributions under KRS Chapter 341 and premiums under the workers' compensation law shall be deemed a proper cost of administration. </section><section prefix="5">The salaries and expenses of the secretary and the secretary's staff shall be considered a proper cost of administration and charged to the funds allocated to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 173, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 20, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 135, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (13) and (21). -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 2. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 4. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch.  125, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7159</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>