<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.400</section_number><catch_line>Sentencing level relating to sentence imposed. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text>The sentencing level of the system shall consist of at least the following information as relates to the sentence imposed: <section prefix="1">Sentencing date; </section><section prefix="2">Sentence for each offense; </section><section prefix="3">If sentenced to imprisonment: <section prefix="a">Place of imprisonment; </section><section prefix="b">Sentence minimum for each offense; </section><section prefix="c">Sentence maximum for each offense; </section><section prefix="d">Consecutive multiple incarceration; </section><section prefix="e">Concurrent multiple incarceration; </section><section prefix="f">Was the defendant sentenced without privilege of parole for twenty-five (25) years; and </section><section prefix="g">If answer to paragraph (f) of this subsection is yes, which aggravating circumstance or circumstances were found; </section></section><section prefix="4">If sentenced to a fine: <section prefix="a">The amount of the fine; </section><section prefix="b">Is the fine to be paid in installments; </section><section prefix="c">If answer to paragraph (b) of this subsection is yes, amount of each installment; </section><section prefix="d">Was the fine paid in full upon conviction; </section><section prefix="e">If not, what amount was paid; and </section><section prefix="f">How much of money held for bail was used in payment of the fine; </section></section><section prefix="5">If any other sentence was imposed: <section prefix="a">The nature of the sentence; </section><section prefix="b">Was conditional discharge imposed and what were the conditions of the discharge; </section><section prefix="c">Was restitution imposed; </section><section prefix="d">If restitution was imposed, what were the conditions of restitution; </section><section prefix="e">If monetary restitution was imposed, what was the amount; </section><section prefix="f">Was the amount paid in full upon conviction; </section><section prefix="g">If restitution was to be paid in installments, what is the amount of each installment and to whom is it to be paid; and </section><section prefix="h">List any other type of sentence imposed; </section></section><section prefix="6">Were court costs imposed: <section prefix="a">The amount of the costs; </section><section prefix="b">Are the costs to be paid in installments; </section><section prefix="c">If answer to paragraph (b) of this subsection is yes, the amount of each installment; </section><section prefix="d">Were the costs paid in full upon conviction; and </section><section prefix="e">If not, how much was paid; </section></section><section prefix="7">Was a crime victim compensation fund cost imposed: <section prefix="a">The amount imposed; </section><section prefix="b">Is this amount to be paid in installments; </section><section prefix="c">If answer to paragraph (b) of this subsection is yes, the amount of each installment; </section><section prefix="d">Was the crime victim compensation fund cost paid in full upon conviction; and </section><section prefix="e">If not, how much was paid; </section></section><section prefix="8">List all other fees, costs, and similar monetary penalties which were imposed but not listed above: <section prefix="a">List separately the amount of each; </section><section prefix="b">List separately each to be paid in installments; </section><section prefix="c">List separately the amount of each installment; </section><section prefix="d">Were these costs paid in full upon conviction; list each; and </section><section prefix="e">If not, list the amount paid on each. </section></section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20960</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>