<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.033</section_number><catch_line>License for speech-language pathology assistant -- Requirements for licensure -- Supervision requirements. </catch_line><order_by>033</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may issue a license to practice as a speech-language pathology assistant under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The practice shall be limited to the public schools and shall be under the supervision of an appropriately qualified supervisor; </section><section prefix="b">The requirements for supervision shall be set forth in administrative regulations promulgated by the board and shall include requirements that: <section prefix="1">A person holding an interim license as a speech-language pathology assistant shall receive no less than three (3) hours per week of documented direct supervision and three (3) hours per week of indirect supervision from an appropriate supervisor as determined by the board; </section><section prefix="2">A person holding a license as a speech-language pathology assistant with less than three (3) years of full-time experience shall receive no less than two (2) hours per week of documented direct supervision and two (2) hours per week of indirect supervision from an appropriate supervisor as determined by the board; </section><section prefix="3">A person holding a license as a speech-language pathology assistant with three (3) or more years of full-time experience shall receive no less than one (1) hour per week of documented direct supervision and one (1) hour per week of indirect supervision, unless, in the professional judgment of the supervisor, the ability of the speech-language pathology assistant requires a higher level of supervision in order to avoid compromising the quality of services provided to students; and </section><section prefix="4">Supervision shall be adjusted proportionally for less than full-time employment; </section></section><section prefix="c">An individual shall not supervise or be listed as the supervisor for more than two (2) speech-language pathology assistants; and </section><section prefix="d">The supervisor shall delegate to the assistant the appropriate tasks pursuant to KRS 334A.020 and the supervisor and assistant shall work together to provide the appropriate services to all assigned pupils taking into account the severity and complexity of the needs of individual students and the respective workloads of the supervisor and assistant. The maximum number of pupils served by each speech-language pathology assistant shall not exceed the direct service caseload of the speech-language pathologist as established in KRS 334A.190. </section></section><section prefix="2">To be eligible for licensure by the board as a speech-language pathology assistant, the applicant shall meet the following requirements: <section prefix="a">A baccalaureate degree in the area of speech-language pathology as defined by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">Completion of postgraduate professional experience deemed appropriate by the board by administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="c">List on the application the name of the appropriately qualified supervisor who has agreed to provide supervision as set forth by the board by administrative regulation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>