<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.432</section_number><catch_line>Petition for 60-day and 360-day involuntary treatment -- Contents -- Guarantee for costs. </catch_line><order_by>432</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Proceedings for sixty (60) days or three hundred sixty (360) days of treatment for an individual suffering from alcohol and other drug abuse shall be initiated by the filing of a verified petition in District Court. </section><section prefix="2">The petition and all subsequent court documents shall be entitled: "In the interest of (name of respondent)." </section><section prefix="3">The petition shall be filed by a spouse, relative, friend, or guardian of the individual concerning whom the petition is filed. </section><section prefix="4">The petition shall set forth: <section prefix="a">Petitioner's relationship to the respondent; </section><section prefix="b">Respondent's name, residence, and current location, if known; </section><section prefix="c">The name and residence of respondent's parents, if living and if known, or respondent's legal guardian, if any and if known; </section><section prefix="d">The name and residence of respondent's husband or wife, if any and if known; </section><section prefix="e">The name and residence of the person having custody of the respondent, if any, or if no such person is known, the name and residence of a near relative or that the person is unknown; and </section><section prefix="f">Petitioner's belief, including the factual basis therefor, that the respondent is suffering from an alcohol and other drug abuse disorder and presents a danger or threat of danger to self, family, or others if not treated for alcohol or other drug abuse. </section></section> Any petition filed pursuant to this subsection shall be accompanied by a guarantee, signed by the petitioner or other person authorized under subsection (3) of this section, obligating that person to pay all costs for treatment of the respondent for alcohol and other drug abuse that is ordered by the court. </text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>