<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.075</section_number><catch_line>Dishonor of financial instrument in payment of license fee -- Emergency hearing. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a licensee issues payment for a license to the board by a check, draft, order, or electronic funds transfer that is dishonored by the bank or financial institution upon which it is drawn, and the licensee fails to reimburse the board for the amount of the check, draft, order, or electronic funds transfer and any applicable fee within thirty (30) days of written notice from the board, the board may initiate action for the immediate temporary suspension of the license under KRS 314.089 until the licensee pays the required fee and meets all requirements for reinstatement of the license. The board shall mail written notice that the check, draft, order, or electronic funds transfer has been dishonored to the licensee's address on record with the board. </section><section prefix="2">A licensee whose license is suspended under subsection (1) of this section may request an emergency hearing under the provisions of KRS 13B.125. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall supersede the provisions of KRS 314.091. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30903</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>