<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.250</section_number><catch_line>Powers of department of public parks and recreation in first-class cities -- Employees -- Director of parks and recreation. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department of public parks and recreation of any city of the first class shall exercise all of the powers and perform all of the functions and duties of any former board of park commissioners of the city, except as otherwise provided by law or by KRS 97.250 to 97.257. The agents and employees of the department of public parks and recreation, except as provided herein, shall be employed and governed in accordance with the merit system, as provided by any law or amendments thereof, and any rules and regulations issued pursuant thereto, authorizing, creating and governing any city board or commission empowered to administer and enforce civil service laws, rules and regulations in and for the city. </section><section prefix="2">The department of public parks and recreation of any city of the first class shall be under the supervision and direction of a director to be designated director of parks and recreation, and shall have exclusive direction, supervision and control of all park property, as herein defined, except as otherwise provided by law or by KRS 97.250 to 97.257 or by ordinance of the legislative body of said city; and shall provide for and supervise all public amusements and recreation in parks, playgrounds, and community centers. The director of the department may adopt rules and regulations for the reasonable and proper use, management and control of public park, playground and community center property, and may organize the department for administrative purposes into the divisions necessary for the proper conduct of the business of said department, and appoint heads or chiefs of the divisions, who, under the supervision and control of the director, shall have the direction of such divisions. </section></text><history>Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 79. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2840, 2841, 2844, 2847. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26381</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>