<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.145</section_number><catch_line>Absent and additional members.   </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No member of a general or special court-martial shall be absent or excused after the court has been assembled for the trial of the accused unless excused as a result of a challenge, excused by the military judge for physical disability or other good cause, or excused by order of the convening authority for good cause. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever a general court-martial, other than a general court-martial composed of a military judge only, is reduced below five (5) members, the trial may not proceed unless the convening authority details new members sufficient in number to provide not less than the applicable minimum number of five (5) members. The trial may proceed with the new members present after the recorded evidence previously introduced before the members of the court has been read to the court in the presence of the military judge, the accused, and counsel for both sides. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever a special court-martial, other than a special court-martial composed of a military judge only, is reduced below three (3) members, the trial may not proceed unless the convening authority details new members sufficient in number to provide not less than three (3) members. The trial shall proceed with the new members present as if no evidence has been introduced previously at the trial, unless a verbatim record of the evidence previously introduced before the members of the court or a stipulation thereof is read to the court in the presence of the military judge, the accused, and counsel for both sides. </section><section prefix="4">If the military judge of a court-martial composed of a military judge only is unable to proceed with the trial because of physical disability, as a result of a challenge, or for other good cause, the trial shall proceed, subject to any applicable conditions in KRS 35.075(1)(b) or (2)(b), after the detail of a new military judge as if no evidence had previously been introduced, unless a verbatim record of the evidence previously introduced or a stipulation thereof is read in court in the presence of the new military judge, the accused, and counsel for both sides. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 30, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 19. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>