<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">A PROFESSIONAL GEOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>322A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Geology" means the science which treats the earth as a whole; the investigation, analysis, classification, and location of the rocks and other materials which compose the earth's crust; the study of minerals, gases, and liquids composing and contained within the earth's crust; and the study of geologic materials and processes; </section><section prefix="2">"Geologist" means a person who is qualified by reason of his or her knowledge of the principles of geology, acquired by professional education and practical experience, to engage in the public practice of geology; </section><section prefix="3">"Public practice of geology" means the performance of service to the public in connection with the geological description, location, or evaluation of earth materials, liquids, and gases and the natural processes acting upon them. The "public practice of geology" does not include: <section prefix="a">The practice of engineering or land surveying as defined in KRS Chapter 322; or </section><section prefix="b">Design recommendations, design, or plans related to the practice of engineering or land surveying as defined in KRS Chapter 322; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Registered geologist" means a person who is registered as a geologist under the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="5">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Registration for Professional Geologists; and </section><section prefix="6">"Geologist-in-training" means an individual who has met the academic qualifications established by the board, who has successfully passed a written examination approved by the board demonstrating knowledge of the fundamentals of geology, and who has been enrolled by the board as a geologist-in-training. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>