<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.787</section_number><catch_line>Statements of financial disclosure -- Form -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>787</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The statement of financial interests required by KRS 6.781 shall be filed on a form prescribed by the commission. The commission shall provide copies of the form without charge to any person required to file. </section><section prefix="2">The statement shall include the following information for the preceding calendar year: <section prefix="a">Name, business address, business telephone number, and home address of the filer; </section><section prefix="b">Title of the filer's public position or office sought; </section><section prefix="c">Any other occupations of filer and spouse; </section><section prefix="d">Positions held by the filer or his spouse in any business, partnership, corporation for profit, or corporation not for profit from which the filer receives compensation, and the name of that business, partnership, or corporation; </section><section prefix="e">Names and addresses of all businesses, investments, or securities in which the filer, his spouse, or children has or had at any time during the preceding year an interest of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) at fair market value or five percent (5%) ownership interest or more; </section><section prefix="f">Sources of gross income of the filer and his spouse, information concerning the source, and the form of the income; </section><section prefix="g">All positions of a fiduciary nature in a business; </section><section prefix="h">A designation as commercial, residential, or rural, and the location of all real property, other than the filer's primary residence, in which there is an interest of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more held by the filer, his spouse, or children; </section><section prefix="i">Sources of gifts of money or property with a retail value of more than two hundred dollars ($200) to the filer or the filer's immediate family, except those from a member of the filer's family; </section><section prefix="j">The name of any creditor owed more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), except debts arising from the purchase of consumer goods. As used in this paragraph, the term "consumer goods" has the same meaning as in KRS 355.9-102; </section><section prefix="k">The name of any legislative agent who is: <section prefix="1">A member of the filer's immediate family; </section><section prefix="2">A partner of the filer, or a partner of a member of the filer's immediate family; </section><section prefix="3">An officer or director of the filer's employer; </section><section prefix="4">An employer of the filer or an employer of a member of the filer's immediate family; or </section><section prefix="5">A business associate of the filer or a business associate of a member of the filer's immediate family; </section></section><section prefix="l">The names of any of the filer's clients who are legislative agents or employers; and </section><section prefix="m">An answer to the question, "If you have held a professional license during the filing period, has a properly licensed partner of yours engaged in the practice of cases or other matters which you are prohibited from practicing under KRS 6.744?" If the filer responds affirmatively, he shall also list the names of the clients represented and list the agencies before which the partner made an appearance. These lists shall be separate and need not identify which client was represented before a specific agency. </section></section><section prefix="3">Paragraphs (a) to (j) of subsection (2) of this section shall not require disclosure of specific dollar amounts. Paragraph (f) shall not require the disclosure of the names of clients or customers of business entities listed as sources of income. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 175, effective July 1, 2001. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 23, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=388</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>