<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.362</section_number><catch_line>Motorcycle Safety Education Commission -- Membership -- Terms -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>362</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Motorcycle Safety Education Commission is established as an independent body to help foster the growth and development of the motorcycle safety education program established under KRS 15A.350. </section><section prefix="2">The Motorcycle Safety Education Commission shall be composed of seven (7) members, appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) representative of the Department of Kentucky State Police, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) representative of the Transportation Cabinet's Division of Driver Licensing, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) instructor in the motorcycle safety education program, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) members of the Kentucky Motorcycle Association, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of five (5) nominees selected by the association; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees selected by the President of the Senate; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees selected by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the Motorcycle Safety Education Commission shall serve a term of four (4) years. Sitting members shall be eligible to succeed themselves. </section><section prefix="4">Commission members shall receive no compensation for their services and shall not be compensated for expenses incurred from travel or in connection with the performance of their duties as commission members. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall elect its chair and vice chair from its membership. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet quarterly or upon the call of the chair or the request of the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="7">The commission may take action only at meetings where a quorum is present. </section><section prefix="8">The commission shall keep a record of its meetings and recommendations. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 54, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 7, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1079</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>