<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.009</section_number><catch_line>Ex officio member of district governing body -- Designation by fiscal court. </catch_line><order_by>009</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except where the law provides that fiscal court members may serve as members of a district's governing body, the fiscal court of the county in which the greater portion of the district's population lies may, by resolution, designate one of its members to serve as an ex officio member of a district's governing body. Fiscal court members shall be eligible for ex officio membership on a district's governing body regardless of residency, political affiliation or other restrictions on board membership. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall notify the district of the designation of an ex officio member of the governing body and the district shall provide the ex officio member with notice of all regular and special meetings of the district's governing body. </section><section prefix="3">An ex officio member of a district's governing body designated pursuant to this section shall not be counted in determining a quorum nor shall he vote on matters before the district's governing body. </section><section prefix="4">An ex officio member of a district's governing body designated pursuant to this section shall receive no compensation or reimbursement for expenses for attending meetings of the district's governing body. </section><section prefix="5">An ex officio member of a district's governing body designated pursuant to this section shall serve in such capacity at the pleasure of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall not apply to a district established by a city or cities. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 84, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41764</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>