<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.542</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for Colon Cancer Screening Program -- Services provided -- Funding -- Affordability -- Data collection -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The program shall provide colon cancer screening for uninsured individuals who are age fifty (50) to sixty-four (64) and other uninsured individuals determined to be at high risk for developing colon cancer. </section><section prefix="2">Services provided under the program may be undertaken by private contract for services or operated by the department. The program may also provide referral services for the benefit of individuals for whom further examination or treatment is indicated by the colon cancer screening. </section><section prefix="3">The department may adopt a schedule of income-based fees to be charged for colon cancer screening. The schedule adopted shall be such that the screening is affordable and accessible to the largest possible number of individuals throughout the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The department may accept any grant or award of funds from federal or private sources for carrying out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall establish a data collection system to document the number of individuals screened, the demographic characteristics of the individuals screened, and the types of colon cancer screening tests performed under the program. </section><section prefix="6">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010)  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 3 provides that the addition of subsection (3) of this statute in Section 1 of that Act shall be in memory of Richard "Butch" Stewart. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8836</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>