<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="393" order_by="393">ESCHEATS </unit></structure><section_number>393.110</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations for reports by holders of abandoned property to report to department -- Posting and publication of notices. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>The department shall promulgate administrative regulations prescribing the reports which shall be filed with the department by persons holding property presumed abandoned, including the date for filing reports, the contents of the reports, the coverage period of the reports, identifying information concerning the property and presumptive owner if known, the manner in which property shall be transferred from the person holding it to the department, requirements for providing notice to a person who may be the owner of property presumed abandoned, legal actions that may be taken to claim property presumed abandoned, and any other necessary and relevant information needed by the department to carry out the responsibilities concerning unclaimed property prescribed in this chapter. The department shall, notwithstanding KRS 424.180 and 424.190, provide on an annual basis notice or published advertisement of property transferred to it. Any procedures prescribed by the department in accordance with this section shall employ the most cost-effective methods available for the submission of reports to the department and the notice or advertisement of property transferred to the department. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 173, Pt. I, A. 16, sec. 1, effective March 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 560, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 8, effective March 10, 1994; ch. 83, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 276, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 28, effective August 1, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 27. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 221. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 9. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 156, secs. 1, 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1611. </history><metadata><effective> March 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 58, 83, and 276. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between chs. 83 and 276, Acts ch. 276, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails, pursuant to KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>