<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.647</section_number><catch_line>Duty of commission on receipt of hearing risk certificate -- Standards for audiological assessment and diagnostic centers.   </catch_line><order_by>647</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission, on receipt of an auditory screening report of an infant from a hospital or alternative birthing center in accordance with KRS 216.2970 shall review each auditory screening report that indicates a potential hearing loss. The commission shall contact the parents to schedule follow-up evaluations or make a referral for evaluations within three (3) business days. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall secure information missing from birth certificates or hospital referral reports which is relevant to identifying infants with a hearing loss. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall establish standards for infant audiological assessment and diagnostic centers based on accepted national standards, including but not limited to the "Guidelines for the Audiologic Assessment of Children From Birth to 5 Years of Age" as published by the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association (ASHA) and the "Year 2007 Position Statement: Principles and Guidelines for Early Hearing Detection and Intervention Programs" as published by the Joint Committee on Infant Hearing (JCIH). The commission may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish the standards for the centers. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall maintain a list of approved infant audiological assessment and diagnostic centers that meet the standards established by the commission. An audiological assessment and diagnostic center included on the list shall meet the standards established by the commission. An approved center may voluntarily choose not to be included on the list. </section><section prefix="5">An approved audiology assessment and diagnostic center shall agree to provide requested data to the commission for each infant evaluated and on any newly identified children ages birth to three (3) years with a permanent childhood hearing loss within forty-eight (48) hours and make a referral to the Kentucky Early Intervention System point of entry in the service area of the child's residence for services under KRS 200.664. A center shall submit documentation to the commission of a referral made to the Kentucky Early Intervention System. A referral received by the Kentucky Early Intervention System from a center shall be considered a referral from the commission. </section><section prefix="6">If the audiological evaluation performed by the commission contains evidence of a hearing loss, within forty-eight (48) hours the commission shall: <section prefix="a">Contact the attending physician and parents and provide information to the parents in an accessible format as supplied by the Kentucky Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing; and </section><section prefix="b">Make a referral to the Kentucky Early Intervention System point of entry in the service area of the child's residence for services under KRS 200.664. </section></section><section prefix="7">The commission shall forward a report of an audiological evaluation that indicates a hearing loss, with no information that personally identifies the child, to: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing for census purposes; and </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Birth Surveillance Registry for information purposes. </section></section><section prefix="8">Cumulative demographic data of identified infants with a hearing loss shall be made available to agencies and organizations including but not limited to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Early Childhood Advisory Council, requesting the information for planning purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 366, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 308, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 489, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>