<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.240</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of board members. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each appointed member of the board shall: <section prefix="a">Be a citizen of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Have been a resident of this state for at least five (5) years; and </section><section prefix="c">Be a resident of this state at the time of appointment and for the term of the appointment. </section></section><section prefix="2">One (1) member of the board shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice of engineering or land surveying. </section><section prefix="3">Eight (8) members of the board shall be a professional engineer or a professional land surveyor engaged in the respective practice for at least twelve (12) years and shall have been in responsible charge of important engineering or land surveying work for at least five (5) years. <section prefix="a">At least five (5) members of the board shall be professional engineers licensed in Kentucky for at least four (4) years prior to the date of their appointment; </section><section prefix="b">At least three (3) members of the board shall be professional land surveyors licensed in Kentucky for at least four (4) years prior to the date of their appointment; and </section><section prefix="c">The eight (8) members shall remain professional engineers or professional land surveyors licensed in Kentucky during the term of their appointments. If a member's license is surrendered, suspended, revoked, or placed in inactive or retired status, that member shall automatically be removed from the board and the vacancy filled under KRS 322.250(5). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 21, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 17. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 17. --Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599e-3, 1599e-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31443</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>