<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.410</section_number><catch_line>Determination of insured status -- Notification of worker -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>The secretary acting through his duly authorized representatives shall, upon request, determine the insured status of a worker. If a worker is found to have fully insured status, as defined in KRS 341.090(3), the Division of Unemployment Insurance shall notify all interested parties. If found to be not fully insured, the division shall notify the worker. The secretary may, at any time, make further determinations as may affect the worker's eligibility for benefits or may set aside, reconsider, modify, or amend a determination at any time on the basis of additional information or to correct a clerical mistake. The secretary may by regulation prescribe what constitutes a determination as used in this section and KRS 341.420(2) and (3). Any further determination made pursuant to this section may be appealed pursuant to KRS 341.420. </text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 149, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(23),(31). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 28. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 15. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-11. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32302</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>