<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">C RESTRUCTURE OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT IN COUNTY CONTAINING CITY OF FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>67C.402</section_number><catch_line>Employees' right to organize for the purpose of collective bargaining -- Mayor to represent consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Police officers of a consolidated local government shall have, and shall be protected in the exercise of, the right of self-organization, to form, join, or assist any labor organization, to bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing on questions of wages, hours, and other conditions of employment free from interference, restraint, or coercion. </section><section prefix="2">Labor organizations designated by the cabinet as the representative of the majority of police officers in an appropriate unit or recognized by a consolidated local government as the representative of the majority of employees in an appropriate unit shall be the exclusive representative for the employees of that unit for the purpose of collective bargaining with respect to rates of pay, wages, hours, and other conditions of employment. </section><section prefix="3">Labor organizations recognized by a consolidated local government as the exclusive representative or so designated in accordance with the provisions of this section shall be responsible for representing the interest of all police officers in the unit without discrimination. </section><section prefix="4">When a labor organization has been designated in accordance with the provisions of this section as the exclusive representative of police officers in an appropriate unit, the mayor of a consolidated local government or his designated authorized representative shall represent the consolidated local government in collective bargaining with the labor organization. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 65, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24041</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>