<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.117</section_number><catch_line>Animal Control Advisory Board -- Purpose -- Promulgation of administrative regulations -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>117</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Animal Control Advisory Board is hereby created for the purposes of evaluating applications for and reviewing disbursements from the animal control and care fund, creating training programs, and other duties relating to animal control and care in the counties of the Commonwealth. The Animal Control Advisory Board shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The advisory board shall be attached to the Kentucky Department of Agriculture for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="3">The advisory board shall be composed of the following members appointed by the Governor as specified: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Animal Control Association; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Farm Bureau; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Association of Counties; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Houndsmen Association; and </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) members selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky League of Cities. </section></section><section prefix="4">Appointed members shall serve for a term of four (4) years. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment for the unexpired portion of the term. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the advisory board shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for attendance at meetings and shall be entitled to reimbursement for expenses incurred for travel. No per diem or travel expenses shall be paid except for meetings of the full advisory board. </section><section prefix="6">The advisory board shall elect one (1) of its members to serve as chair for a term of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="7">The advisory board shall meet quarterly or upon the call of the chair. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 608, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12434</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>