<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.2245</section_number><catch_line>Incorporation of code or uniform standard by reference.   </catch_line><order_by>2245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An administrative body may incorporate by reference a code or uniform standard if a federal or state statute: <section prefix="a">Requires or authorizes an administrative body to implement, or a regulated entity to comply with, the provisions of that code or uniform standard; and </section><section prefix="b">Does not set forth the code or uniform standard, or a comprehensive scheme of regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a code or uniform standard is changed by the administrative body, the administrative body shall: <section prefix="a">Clearly state the provisions in the body of the administrative regulation that are different than those included in the code or uniform standard; and </section><section prefix="b">File with the regulations compiler a: <section prefix="1">Copy of the code or uniform standard; </section><section prefix="2">Summary listing the pages upon which changes have been made; and </section><section prefix="3">Detailed summary of the changes and their effect. </section></section></section> The summaries shall be attached to the back of the proposed administrative regulation. <section prefix="3">If a federal regulation requires an administrative body to adopt, develop, or implement material of a scientific or technical nature that does not lend itself to the format requirements of KRS Chapter 13A, the administrative body may incorporate the material by reference in an administrative regulation as provided by KRS 13A.2251 and 13A.2255. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>