<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-080</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited interest, rewards. </catch_line><order_by>2-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner or any deputy, examiner, actuary, assistant or employee of the department, shall not be connected with the management of, or be financially interested, directly or indirectly, in any insurer, insurance agency or broker, or insurance transaction except as policyholder or claimant under a policy; except, that as to matters wherein a conflict of interest does not exist on the part of any such individual, the commissioner may employ or retain from time to time insurance actuaries, examiners, accountants, attorneys, or other technicians who are independently practicing their profession even though from time to time similarly employed or retained by insurers or others. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall directly or indirectly give or pay to the commissioner or any deputy, examiner, actuary, assistant, employee or technician retained by the department; and the commissioner, or any deputy, examiner, actuary, assistant, employee or technician retained by the department, shall not directly or indirectly receive or accept any fee, compensation, loan, gift or other thing of value in addition to the compensation and expense allowance provided by law, or by contract with the commissioner, for any service rendered or to be rendered, as such commissioner, deputy, examiner, actuary, assistant, employee or technician, or in connection therewith. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (1) of this section shall not be deemed to prohibit receipt by any such person of commissions or retirement benefits to which entitled by reason of services performed prior to becoming commissioner or prior to employment by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 922, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16654</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>