<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.240</section_number><catch_line>Application for retailer's or seller's permit to do business. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person presently engaged or desiring to engage in or conduct business as a retailer or seller within this state shall file with the department an application for a permit for each place of business. </section><section prefix="2">Every application for a permit shall: <section prefix="a">Be made upon a form prescribed by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Set forth the name under which the applicant transacts or intends to transact business and the location of the place or places of business; and </section><section prefix="c">Set forth other information as the department may require. </section></section><section prefix="3">The application shall be signed by: <section prefix="a">The owner, if he or she is a natural person; </section><section prefix="b">A member or partner, if the entity is an association, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or partnership; </section><section prefix="c">An executive officer, if the entity is a corporation, or some person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application, to which shall be attached written evidence of his or her authority; or </section><section prefix="d">A licensed certified public accountant, or an attorney licensed to practice law in the Commonwealth, specifically authorized by and acting on behalf of an owner, an association, a partnership, a limited liability company, a limited liability partnership, a corporation, or other business entity. </section></section><section prefix="4">A written signature shall not be required if the applicant registers electronically. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 8, effective August 1, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 411, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 12, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 24, effective February 5, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>