<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.800</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal reporting to branches of government -- Annual financial and program status reports. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text>The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall prepare and submit to each branch of government: <section prefix="1">Within ten (10) days after the close of each month copies of the accounts of the budget units of that branch of government with the appropriations and allotments in favor of its budget units and the balances as of the beginning and end of that month. </section><section prefix="2">Within ten (10) days after the close of each month, prepare and transmit to each branch of government a report embodying a summary statement of the actual financial condition of each fund of the major fund groups as of the close of the previous month, a summary statement showing the receipts and payments of each such fund for the previous month and for the current fiscal year to the close of the previous month, a summary budget statement for each such fund showing the available cash balance as of the end of the previous month, the amount of cash estimated to be realized from each source during the remaining months of the fiscal year, the total means of financing, the amount of the unallotted balances of all appropriations, the estimated amount of unliquidated commitments, and the estimated cash surplus or deficit. </section><section prefix="3">Within ninety (90) days of the close of a fiscal year, file with each branch of government a complete report of the financial transactions of the preceding fiscal year and of the financial condition of the Commonwealth as of the end of that fiscal year, with such comments and supplementary data necessary to make the report complete and easy to understand. </section><section prefix="4">Each branch of government shall publish a financial and program status report, within ninety (90) days of the close of a fiscal year, detailing for that period, activities, appropriations, allotments, expenditures, receipts, transfers, encumbrances and available balances of each budget unit of the branch, and an explanation of the programs and services provided by the branch. </section><section prefix="5">In order to effectuate the budget review function of the General Assembly, each branch of government shall make available, on a continuing basis, records which detail activities, appropriations, allotments, expenditures, receipts, transfers, encumbrances and available balances of each budget unit of the branch. Such records shall be made available in the form necessary to facilitate their read only accession by means of electronic data processing procedures employed by the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 30, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>