<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.575</section_number><catch_line>Procedure whereby adopted person may seek to locate preadoptive sibling. </catch_line><order_by>575</order_by><text>In situations where a preadoptive brother or sister relationship existed, and one (1) or more of these siblings was then adopted, the following procedures shall be followed on an inquiry by one (1) or more of the siblings to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services seeking information about his brother or sister: <section prefix="1">In all cases, an adopted person eighteen (18) years of age or older or a preadoptive sibling eighteen (18) years of age or older of an adopted person may file information concerning himself, his present location, and his known antecedents with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, stating his interest in being reunited with his preadoptive siblings and authorizing the cabinet to release such information to his preadoptive siblings who may make similar inquiry. </section><section prefix="2">In any case in which a person eighteen (18) years of age or older requests information about or expresses a desire in being reunited with a preadoptive sibling, the cabinet shall first determine whether such sibling has made similar inquiry pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. If the sibling has previously authorized release of information about himself, the cabinet shall release the information to the sibling making inquiry. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 184, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 147, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7194</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>