<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.672</section_number><catch_line>Sanctions -- Reasons for sanctions. </catch_line><order_by>672</order_by><text>Subject to a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the board may revoke, suspend, place on probation, or restrict the license or certificate of any licensee or certificate holder; refuse to issue or renew a license or certificate; or reprimand, censure, or fine a licensee or certificate holder for any of the following reasons: <section prefix="1">Fraud or deceit in obtaining licensure or certification; </section><section prefix="2">Transfer of the authority granted by the license or certificate to another person; </section><section prefix="3">Unfair or deceptive trade practices; </section><section prefix="4">Willful or deliberate disregard and violation of building codes, electrical codes, or related laws and ordinances of this Commonwealth or any city, county, or urban-county government; </section><section prefix="5">Aiding or abetting any person attempting to evade the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689; </section><section prefix="6">Conspiracy or knowingly combining with any person, to allow a license or certificate to be used by an unlicensed or uncertified person, firm, or corporation with intent to evade the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. Allowing a license or certificate to be used by more than one (1) person shall be prima facie evidence of intent to evade the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689; </section><section prefix="7">Willful or deliberate disregard of disciplinary actions taken by the board, or of a city, county, or urban-county government; </section><section prefix="8">Negligence or incompetence in compliance with applicable codes and standards of practice; </section><section prefix="9">Violation of any of the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689 or any administrative regulation promulgated by the board; or </section><section prefix="10">Conviction of a felony or of any crime an element of which is dishonesty or fraud, under the laws of any state or of the United States. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 88, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7069</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>