<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.148</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Department of Kentucky State Police regarding traffic safety -- Control of funds. </catch_line><order_by>148</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, Department of Kentucky State Police, shall: <section prefix="a">Coordinate all efforts of the state's various departments and agencies to promote traffic safety and make recommendations regarding the prevention of unnecessary duplications of these efforts; </section><section prefix="b">Cooperate with all organizations, public or private, in the encouragement and promotion of traffic safety education in all forms; and </section><section prefix="c">Receive, control, and expend, in accordance with the general provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes governing financial administration of all state agencies, grants and funds from either public or private sources. </section></section><section prefix="2">There are hereby transferred to and vested in the Department of Kentucky State Police all functions, powers, duties, funds, personnel, equipment, and supplies relating to the administration of the National Highway Safety Act of 1966 in Kentucky, which responsibility and authority have been conferred upon the Transportation Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 82, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1208</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>