<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 258.005 to 258.087. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in KRS 258.005 to 258.087, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Dog" means any canine three (3) months of age or older for which there exists a United States Department of Agriculture approved rabies vaccine; </section><section prefix="2">"Owner" means any person owning, keeping, or harboring a dog, cat, or ferret in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">"Veterinarian" means a licensed practitioner of veterinary medicine; </section><section prefix="4">"Qualified person" means a person granted a permit by the secretary for health and family services to vaccinate his own dog against rabies; </section><section prefix="5">"Vaccination" means the administration by a veterinarian or other qualified person of rabies vaccine approved by and administered in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary for health and family services; </section><section prefix="6">"Cat" means any feline three (3) months of age or older for which there exists a United States Department of Agriculture approved rabies vaccine; </section><section prefix="7">"Animal control officer" means an individual who is employed or appointed by, or has contracted with: <section prefix="a">A city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government to enforce the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes relating to cruelty, mistreatment, or torture of animals, and local animal control ordinances; or </section><section prefix="b">An entity that has contracted with a city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government to enforce the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes relating to cruelty, mistreatment, or torture of animals, and local animal control ordinances; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Ferret" means any musteline three (3) months of age or older for which there exists a United States Department of Agriculture approved rabies vaccine; and </section><section prefix="9">"Quarantine" means the confinement of an animal for observation of clinical signs of illness indicating rabies infection, and the prevention of escape or contact with any person or other animal. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 568, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 514, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12409</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>