<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="511" order_by="511">BURGLARY AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>511.085</section_number><catch_line>Domestic violence shelter trespass.  </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text>(1)As used in this section, "domestic violence shelter" means a residential facilityproviding protective shelter services for domestic violence victims.(2)A person is guilty of domestic violence shelter trespass when:(a)The person enters the buildings or premises of a domestic violenceshelter that the person knows or should know is a domestic violenceshelter or which is clearly marked on the building or premises as being adomestic violence shelter; and(b)At the time of the entering, the person is the subject of an order ofprotection as defined in KRS 403.720 and 456.010.(3)It shall be a defense to a prosecution under this section that the personentered the shelter with the permission of the operator of the shelter afterdisclosing to the operator that the person is the subject of an order ofprotection or a foreign protective order. Authority to enter under this subsectionmay not be granted by a person taking shelter at the facility.(4)A person shall not be convicted of a violation of this section and a violation ofKRS 511.060, 511.070, or 511.080 arising from the same act of trespass.(5)Domestic violence shelter trespass is a Class A misdemeanor.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 48, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2010.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44796</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>