<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-210</section_number><catch_line>Environmental Board. </catch_line><order_by>1-210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Environmental Board is established, which shall control and manage the environmental trust fund. The board shall be composed of eight (8) members as follows: the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the chairman of the Environmental Quality Commission, and six (6) members at large to be appointed by the Governor. The board members shall elect the chairman. </section><section prefix="2">The six (6) members at large shall be appointed for terms of four (4) years. The remaining members shall be permanent members. The six (6) members at large shall be appointed from the following: two (2) from manufacturers, mineral extraction industry, or agribusiness; two (2) from the state-supported university system; one (1) from public health or environmental citizen groups; and one (1) an educator specializing in environmental education. Vacancies in the members at large appointments shall be filled in the same manner as originally appointed, and appointments to fill these vacancies shall be for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall meet at least once each calendar quarter or more often on the call of the chairman. </section><section prefix="4">No member of the board shall receive any salary, fee, or other remuneration for services as a member of the board but each member shall be reimbursed for travel expenses incurred in the performance of duties as a board member. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary and the staff of the cabinet shall serve as staff for the board. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet may provide legal representation to the board or the board may enter into personal service contracts pursuant to KRS Chapter 45 to obtain legal counsel. </section><section prefix="7">Five (5) members of the board shall constitute a quorum for conducting business. Each member shall have one (1) vote and a majority vote of the members present shall control on all questions. </section><section prefix="8">The cabinet shall annually prepare a proposed program and a list of projects for public comment and review for the board's consideration. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 346, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.2115. KRS 224.01-210. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-210</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41556</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>