<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.050</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on persons not licensed or certified -- Activities prohibited to persons licensed or certified -- Reporting of prohibited activities -- Penalties and disciplinary action. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall: <section prefix="a">Call or hold himself or herself out as or use the title of emergency medical technician, first responder, paramedic, first responder instructor or instructor trainer, emergency medical technician instructor or instructor trainer, or paramedic instructor, paramedic instructor trainer, or paramedic course coordinator unless licensed or certified under the provisions of this chapter. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply if the board does not license or certify a person as an instructor, instructor trainer, or course coordinator in a particular discipline regulated by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Operate or offer to operate or represent or advertise the operation of a school or other educational program for first responders, emergency medical technicians, paramedics, or instructors or instructor trainers for first responders, emergency medical technicians, or paramedics unless the school or educational program has been approved under the provisions of this chapter. The provisions of this paragraph shall not apply to continuing education provided by a licensed ambulance service for anyone certified or licensed by the board given by an ambulance service for its employees or volunteers; or </section><section prefix="c">Knowingly employ a first responder, emergency medical technician, paramedic, or an instructor or instructor trainer for first responders, emergency medical technicians, or paramedics, or paramedic course coordinator unless that person is licensed or certified under the provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person licensed or certified by the board or who is an applicant for licensure or certification by the board shall: <section prefix="a">If licensed or certified, violate any provision of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Use fraud or deceit in obtaining or attempting to obtain a license or certification from the board, or be granted a license upon mistake of a material fact; </section><section prefix="c">If licensed or certified by the board, grossly negligently or willfully act in a manner inconsistent with the practice of the discipline for which the person is certified or licensed; </section><section prefix="d">Be unfit or incompetent to practice a discipline regulated by the board by reason of negligence or other causes; </section><section prefix="e">Abuse, misuse, or misappropriate any drugs placed in the custody of the licensee or certified person for administration, or for use of others; </section><section prefix="f">Falsify or fail to make essential entries on essential records; </section><section prefix="g">Be convicted of a misdemeanor which involved acts that bear directly on the qualifications or ability of the applicant, licensee, or certified person to practice the discipline for which the person is an applicant, licensee, or certified person; </section><section prefix="h">Be convicted of a misdemeanor which involved fraud, deceit, breach of trust, or physical harm or endangerment to self or others, acts that bear directly on the qualifications or ability of the applicant, licensee, or certificate holder to practice acts in the license or certification held or sought; </section><section prefix="i">Be convicted of a misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 510 involving a patient or be found by the board to have had sexual contact as defined in KRS 510.010(7) with a patient while the patient was under the care of the licensee or certificate holder; </section><section prefix="j">Have had his or her license or credential to practice as a nurse or physician denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in Kentucky or in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license to be denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="k">Have a license or certification to practice in any activity regulated by the board denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license or certification to be denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="l">Violate any lawful order or directive previously entered by the board; </section><section prefix="m">Have been listed on the nurse aide abuse registry with a substantiated finding of abuse, neglect, or misappropriation of property; or </section><section prefix="n">Be convicted of, have entered a guilty plea to, have entered an Alford plea to a felony offense, or completed a diversion program for a felony offense. </section></section><section prefix="3">It shall be unlawful for an employer of a person licensed or certified by the board having knowledge of the facts to refrain from reporting to the board any person licensed or certified by the board who: <section prefix="a">Has been convicted of, has entered a guilty plea to, has entered an Alford plea to a felony offense, or has completed a diversion program for a felony offense; </section><section prefix="b">Has been convicted of a misdemeanor or felony which involved acts that bear directly on the qualifications or ability of the applicant, licensee, or certified person to practice the discipline for which they are an applicant, licensee, or certified person; </section><section prefix="c">Is reasonably suspected of fraud or deceit in procuring or attempting to procure a license or certification from the board; </section><section prefix="d">Is reasonably suspected of grossly negligently or willfully acting in a manner inconsistent with the practice of the discipline for which they are certified or licensed; </section><section prefix="e">Is reasonably suspected of being unfit or incompetent to practice a discipline regulated by the board by reason of negligence or other causes, including but not limited to being unable to practice the discipline for which they are licensed or certified with reasonable skill or safety; </section><section prefix="f">Is reasonably suspected of violating any provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated under this chapter; </section><section prefix="g">Has a license or certification to practice an activity regulated by the board denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license or certification to be denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="h">Is practicing an activity regulated by the board without a current active license or certification issued by the board; </section><section prefix="i">Is reasonably suspected of abusing, misusing, or misappropriating any drugs placed in the custody of the licensee or certified person for administration or for use of others; or </section><section prefix="j">Is suspected of falsifying or in a grossly negligent manner making incorrect entries or failing to make essential entries on essential records. </section></section><section prefix="4">A person who violates subsection (1)(a), (b), or (c) of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for a first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of this section shall not preclude prosecution for the unlawful practice of medicine, nursing, or other practice certified or licensed by an agency of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="6">The filing of criminal charges or a criminal conviction for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the office of the board from instituting or imposing board disciplinary action authorized by this chapter against any person or organization violating this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="7">The institution or imposition of disciplinary action by the office of the board against any person or organization violating the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the filing of criminal charges against or a criminal conviction of any person or organization for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30726</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>