<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1415</section_number><catch_line>Possession of controlled substance in first degree -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>1415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of possession of a controlled substance in the first degree when he or she knowingly and unlawfully possesses: <section prefix="a">A controlled substance that is classified in Schedules I or II and is a narcotic drug; </section><section prefix="b">A controlled substance analogue; </section><section prefix="c">Methamphetamine; </section><section prefix="d">Lysergic acid diethylamide; </section><section prefix="e">Phencyclidine; </section><section prefix="f">Gamma hydroxybutyric acid (GHB), including its salts, isomers, salts of isomers, and analogues; or </section><section prefix="g">Flunitrazepam, including its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers. </section></section><section prefix="2">Possession of a controlled substance in the first degree is a Class D felony subject to the following provisions: <section prefix="a">The maximum term of incarceration shall be no greater than three (3) years, notwithstanding KRS Chapter 532; </section><section prefix="b">For a person's first or second offense under this section, he or she may be subject to a period of: <section prefix="1">Deferred prosecution pursuant to KRS 218A.14151; or </section><section prefix="2">Presumptive probation; </section></section><section prefix="c">Deferred prosecution under paragraph (b) of this subsection shall be the preferred alternative for a first offense; and </section><section prefix="d">If a person does not enter a deferred prosecution program for his or her first or second offense, he or she shall be subject to a period of presumptive probation, unless a court determines the defendant is not eligible for presumptive probation as defined in KRS 218A.010. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 12, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 65, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>