<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.040</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees -- Officers and employees. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As soon as practicable after the passage of the ordinance providing for a free public library, the mayor shall appoint twelve (12) trustees. The appointments shall be made for four (4) year terms except that the original appointees shall be so appointed that the terms of three (3) members shall expire each year. Each appointee must be, at the time of his appointment, a taxpayer and qualified voter in the city and must have resided therein for two (2) years prior to his appointment. The mayor shall continue to appoint all twelve (12) trustees unless the county judge/executive becomes authorized to appoint trustees under the provisions of KRS 173.105, after which the mayor shall appoint only the trustee positions not appointed by the county judge/executive. The trustees shall serve without compensation. The twelve (12) trustees, whether appointed under this subsection or under KRS 173.105, together with the mayor of the city, shall constitute the board of trustees of the free public library, and shall be a corporation with power to make such rules and regulations to govern itself and the property entrusted to its care as it deems proper. Absence of a trustee from four (4) regular monthly meetings of the board during any one (1) year of the trustee's term shall constitute automatic resignation from the board by the trustee. </section><section prefix="2">Vacancies in the office of trustee shall be reported by the board to the mayor, if the vacancy occurs in a trustee position filled by appointment of the mayor, or to the county judge/executive if the vacancy occurs in a trustee position which the county judge/executive has authority to fill under KRS 173.105. The vacancy shall be filled by the mayor if so authorized or the county judge/executive if so authorized under subsection (1) of this section and KRS 173.105, for the remainder of an unexpired term or for a full term if the vacancy results from the expiration of a term. The trustees shall, before entering upon the duties of office, make an oath or affirmation before a judicial officer that they will discharge their duties. </section><section prefix="3">At its first meeting and each year thereafter, the board shall select members of the board to serve as president and vice president, and it may choose other necessary officers and employees, fix their duties and compensation, and remove them at pleasure. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2801b-3, 2801b-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>