<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.535</section_number><catch_line>Title for classic motor vehicle project -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>535</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owner of a motor vehicle that meets the definition of a classic motor vehicle project may apply for a classic motor vehicle project certificate of title, which shall: <section prefix="a">Bear on the face of the title the words "CLASSIC MOTOR VEHICLE PROJECT--NOT FOR ROAD USE"; and </section><section prefix="b">Not bear the designation of "salvage," "junk," "rebuilt," or any other similar brand. </section></section><section prefix="2">The owner of a motor vehicle that meets the definition of a classic motor vehicle project as set forth in KRS 186A.510, has been issued a classic motor vehicle project certificate of title under subsection (1) of this section, and has been restored to roadworthy condition may make application for a new certificate of title pursuant to KRS 186A.115. The Transportation Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A governing the form of application. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receipt of a classic motor vehicle project certificate of title issued pursuant to subsection (1) of this section and proof of passing the inspection required by KRS 186A.115, the cabinet shall issue a new regular certificate of title with no special brand printed on the face of the title. </section><section prefix="4">The only time a vehicle with a classic motor vehicle project certificate of title may be operated upon the highways of the Commonwealth is when it is en route to or from an inspection by the certified inspector prior to obtaining a certificate of title after having been restored in accordance with KRS 186A.115. </section><section prefix="5">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, regarding the administration of the classic motor vehicle project certificate of title procedures. The administrative regulations shall include the manner in which classic motor vehicle project titles are differentiated from salvage titles and rebuilt brands. The administrative regulations may include designation of additional brands which provide significant information to the owner. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6213</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>