<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.792</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 158.792 and 164.0207 -- Reading diagnostic and intervention fund -- Grants for reading intervention programs -- Administrative regulations -- Annual reports on use of grant funds and costs of intervention programs. </catch_line><order_by>792</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section and KRS 164.0207, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Comprehensive reading program" means a program that emphasizes the essential components of reading: phonemic awareness, phonics, fluency, vocabulary, comprehension, and connections between writing and reading acquisition and motivation to read. </section><section prefix="b">"Reading diagnostic assessment" means an assessment that identifies a struggling reader and measures the reader's skills against established performance levels in the essential components of reading. The purpose is to screen for areas that require intervention in order for the student to learn to read proficiently. </section><section prefix="c">"Reading intervention program" means short-term intensive instruction in the essential skills necessary to read proficiently that is provided to a student by a highly trained teacher. This instruction may be conducted one-on-one or in small groups; shall be research-based, reliable, and replicable; and shall be based on the ongoing assessment of individual student needs. </section><section prefix="d">"Reliable, replicable research" means objective, valid, scientific studies that: <section prefix="1">Include rigorously defined samples of subjects that are sufficiently large and representative to support the general conclusions drawn; </section><section prefix="2">Rely on measurements that meet established standards of reliability and validity; </section><section prefix="3">Test competing theories, where multiple theories exist; </section><section prefix="4">Are subjected to peer review before their results are published; and </section><section prefix="5">Discover effective strategies for improving reading skills. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The reading diagnostic and intervention fund is created to help teachers and library media specialists improve the reading skills of struggling readers in the primary program. The Department of Education, upon the recommendation of the Reading Diagnostic and Intervention Grant Steering Committee, shall provide renewable, two (2) year grants to schools to support teachers in the implementation of reliable, replicable research-based reading intervention programs that use a balance of diagnostic tools and instructional strategies that emphasize phonemic awareness, phonics, fluency, vocabulary, comprehension, and connections between writing and reading acquisition and motivation to read to address the diverse learning needs of those students reading at low levels. Any moneys in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to be used for the purposes specified in this section. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations, based on recommendations from the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, the Reading Diagnostic and Intervention Grant Steering Committee established in KRS 158.794, and the Collaborative Center for Literacy Development established in KRS 164.0207 to: <section prefix="1">Identify eligible grant applicants, taking into consideration how the grant program described in this section will relate to other grant programs; </section><section prefix="2">Specify the criteria for acceptable diagnostic assessments and intervention programs; </section><section prefix="3">Specify the criteria for acceptable ongoing assessment of each child to determine his or her reading progress; </section><section prefix="4">Establish the minimum evaluation process for an annual review of each grant recipient's program and progress; </section><section prefix="5">Identify the annual data that must be provided from grant recipients; </section><section prefix="6">Define the application review and approval process; </section><section prefix="7">Establish matching requirements deemed necessary; </section><section prefix="8">Define the professional development and continuing education requirements for teachers, library media specialists, administrators, and staff of grant recipients; </section><section prefix="9">Establish the conditions for renewal of a two (2) year grant; and </section><section prefix="10">Specify other conditions necessary to implement the purposes of this section. </section></section><section prefix="b">The board shall require that a grant applicant provide assurances that the following principles will be met if the applicant's request for funding is approved: <section prefix="1">A research-based comprehensive schoolwide reading program will be available; </section><section prefix="2">Intervention services will supplement, not replace, regular classroom instruction; </section><section prefix="3">Intervention services will be provided to struggling primary program readers within the school based upon ongoing assessment of their needs; and </section><section prefix="4">A system for informing parents of struggling readers of the available family literacy services within the district will be established. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">In order to qualify for funding, the school council, or if none exists, the principal or the superintendent of schools, shall allocate matching funds required by grant recipients under subsection (3) of this section. Funding for professional development allocated to the school council under KRS 160.345 and for continuing education under KRS 158.070 may be used as part of the school's match. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Education shall make available to schools: <section prefix="a">Information concerning successful, research-based comprehensive reading programs, diagnostic tools for pre- and post-assessment, and intervention programs, from the Collaborative Center for Literacy Development created under KRS 164.0207; </section><section prefix="b">Strategies for successfully implementing early reading programs, including professional development support and the identification of funding sources; and </section><section prefix="c">A list of professional development providers offering teacher training related to reading that emphasizes the essential components for successful reading: phonemic awareness, phonics, fluency, vocabulary, comprehension, and connections between writing and reading acquisition and motivation to read. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Department of Education shall submit a report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education no later than September 1 of each year outlining the use of grant funds. The report shall also include comparisons of the overall costs and effectiveness of intervention programs. The annual report for an odd-numbered year shall include an estimate of the cost to expand the reading diagnostic and intervention grant program. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 50, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 3, effective March 18, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 580, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, which included an amendment to this section, KRS 158.792, provides that the Act shall be cited as the "Read to Achieve Act of 2005." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3589</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>