<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="248" order_by="248">TOBACCO </unit></structure><section_number>248.510</section_number><catch_line>Tobacco research board membership -- Compensation -- Meetings -- Quorum. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Tobacco Research Board is hereby created. The board shall be composed of thirteen (13) voting members and one (1) nonvoting member as follows: <section prefix="a">Ten (10) permanent members who shall be the following officeholders or shall be designated by the following organizations: the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation; the Kentucky Innovations Commission; the commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Agriculture; the dean of the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture; the Burley Growers Cooperative Association; the Council for Burley Tobacco; the Dark Fired Tobacco Association; the Kentucky Science and Technology Corporation; the chairman of the Senate Committee on Agriculture; and the chairman of the House Committee on Agriculture and Small Business. Each officeholder and organization shall designate an alternate who is authorized to serve when the member cannot be present at a meeting. </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members at large, at least one (1) of whom is a tobacco farmer in Kentucky and at least one (1) of whom has research and development experience in the public or private sector, who shall be appointed by the Governor with the advice and consent of the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="c">One (1) nonvoting member from the University of Kentucky, who shall be the University of Kentucky Vice President for Research, or the Vice President's designee. The nonvoting member of the board may be counted in determining a quorum, but the nonvoting member shall not vote on matters before the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">No member of the board shall receive any salary, fee, or other remuneration for his services as a member of the board but each member shall be reimbursed for his ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of his duties incident to implementation of the provisions of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="3">The term of the ten (10) members designated in paragraph (a) of subsection (1) of this section shall not change but they shall be permanent members in terms of the organizations and offices named. At-large members and the tobacco industry member shall serve two (2) year terms. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall elect, by a majority vote of the thirteen (13) voting members, a chairman and a vice chair. The chairman shall be the presiding officer of the board, shall preside at all meetings, and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The chairman shall be elected or reelected annually and shall be a permanent member or an at-large member of the board. The vice chair shall conduct meetings in the absence of the chairman. The board shall have such other organization as deemed necessary and approved by the board. </section><section prefix="5">Meetings of the board shall be held at least quarterly but may be held more frequently as deemed necessary subject to call by the chairman or by request of a majority of the board members. Board meetings shall concern, among other things, policy matters relating to research projects and programs, research progress reports, authorization of projects and financial plans, and such other matters as necessary to carry out the intent of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="6">Seven (7) members of the board shall constitute a quorum for doing business. Each member shall have one (1) vote and a majority vote of the members present shall control on all questions. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 1. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11950</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>