<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-240</section_number><catch_line>Annual report by investors. </catch_line><order_by>20-240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before February 1 of the calendar year succeeding the year in which a credit was awarded, and continuing for four (4) years thereafter, a qualified small business that has received a qualified investment shall file an annual report with the authority. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">This report shall demonstrate that the small business: <section prefix="1">Continues to have more than fifty percent (50%) of its assets, operations, and employees in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Has at no time received an aggregate amount of qualified investments that has allowed qualified investors to receive more than one million dollars ($1,000,000) in credits; and </section><section prefix="3">Continues to be actively and principally engaged in a qualified activity. </section></section><section prefix="b">The report shall also provide additional information related to the success of the small business attributable to the investment, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">New jobs created; </section><section prefix="2">Increased sales or other economic activity conducted; </section><section prefix="3">The degree of other private investment attracted; and </section><section prefix="4">Any other information requested by the authority. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">If a qualified small business either: <section prefix="a">Fails to submit the report mandated by this section in any year; or </section><section prefix="b">Fails to meet any of the criteria listed in subsection (2)(a) of this section at any time during any year of the reporting period; </section></section> the authority shall notify the department, which shall recapture any portion, or the full amount, of the credit awarded for qualified investments in that qualified small business from the qualified investor that received the credit award or any taxpayer receiving the credit through a valid transfer. Any amounts collected from the recapture shall be deposited in the general fund. <section prefix="4">If a qualified small business becomes insolvent and ceases operations at any time before the final required annual report is due, it shall file a written report with the authority attesting to that fact and shall thereafter be exempt from the annual report required by this section, and credits awarded for qualified investments in that qualified small business shall not be subject to any recapture. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 26, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43419</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>