<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 387.010 to 387.280. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 387.010 to 387.280, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Minor" means any person who has not reached the age of eighteen (18). </section><section prefix="2">"Interested person or entity" means an adult relative or friend of the minor, an official or representative of a public or private agency, corporation, or association concerned with the minor's welfare, or any other person found suitable by the District Court. </section><section prefix="3">"Guardian" means an individual, agency, or corporation appointed by the District Court to have care, custody, and control of a minor and to manage the minor's financial resources. </section><section prefix="4">"Limited guardian" means an individual, agency, or corporation appointed by the District Court to have care, custody, and control of a minor without the power to manage the minor's financial resources. </section><section prefix="5">"Conservator" means an individual, agency, or corporation appointed by the District Court to manage the financial resources of a minor. </section><section prefix="6">"Ward" means a person for whom a guardian, limited guardian, or conservator has been appointed. </section><section prefix="7">"Parent" means a mother or father whose parental rights have not been terminated or suspended by prior court order. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 138, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 39. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2149. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 150 would have repealed this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35986</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>