<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.060</section_number><catch_line>Enactment of ordinances. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each ordinance shall embrace only one (1) subject and shall have a title that shall clearly state the subject. </section><section prefix="2">Each ordinance shall be introduced in writing and shall have an enacting clause styled "Be it ordained by the City of ________:". </section><section prefix="3">No ordinance shall be amended by reference to its title only, and ordinances to amend shall set out in full the amended ordinance or section indicating any text being added by a single solid line drawn underneath it. Text that is intended to be removed shall be marked at the beginning with an opening bracket and at the end with a closing bracket. The text between the brackets shall be stricken through with a single solid line. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in subsection (7) of this section, no ordinance shall be enacted until it has been read on two (2) separate days. The reading of an ordinance may be satisfied by stating the title and reading a summary rather than the full text. </section><section prefix="5">A city legislative body may adopt the provisions of any local, statewide, or nationally recognized standard code and codifications of entire bodies of local legislation by an ordinance that identifies the subject matter by title, source, and date and incorporates the adopted provisions by reference without setting them out in full, if a copy accompanies the adopting ordinance and is made a part of the permanent records of the city. </section><section prefix="6">Unless otherwise provided by statute, a majority of a legislative body shall constitute a quorum and a vote of a majority of a quorum shall be sufficient to take action. </section><section prefix="7">In an emergency, upon the affirmative vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the membership, a city legislative body may suspend the requirements of second reading and publication to provide for an ordinance to become effective by naming and describing the emergency in the ordinance. Publication requirements of subsection (9) of this section shall be complied with within ten (10) days of the enactment of the emergency ordinance. </section><section prefix="8">Every action of the city legislative body shall be made a part of the permanent records of the city and on passage of an ordinance the vote of each member of the city legislative body shall be entered on the official record of the meeting. The legislative body shall provide by ordinance for the maintenance and safekeeping of the permanent records of the city. The person assigned this responsibility and the presiding officer shall sign the official record of each meeting. All ordinances adopted in a city shall, at the end of each month, be indexed and maintained in the following manner: <section prefix="a">The city budget, appropriations of money, and tax levies shall be maintained and indexed so that each fiscal year is kept separate from other years. </section><section prefix="b">All other city ordinances shall be kept in the minute book or an ordinance book in the order adopted and indexed in a composite index or maintained in a code of ordinances. </section></section><section prefix="9">Except in cities of the first class, a charter county government, and as provided in subsection (7) of this section, no ordinance shall be effective until published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. Ordinances may be published in full or in summary as designated by the legislative body. If the legislative body elects to publish an ordinance in summary, the summary shall be prepared or certified by an attorney licensed to practice law in the Commonwealth of Kentucky and shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The title of the ordinance; </section><section prefix="b">A brief narrative setting forth the main points of the ordinance in a way reasonably calculated to inform the public in a clear and understandable manner of the meaning of the ordinance; and </section><section prefix="c">The full text of each section that imposes taxes or fees. </section></section> Ordinances that include descriptions of real property may include a sketch, drawing, or map, including common landmarks, such as streets or roads in lieu of metes and bounds descriptions. <section prefix="10">A city may specify by ordinance additional requirements for adoption of ordinances in greater detail than contained herein, but a city shall not lessen or reduce the substantial requirements of this section or any other statute relating to adoption of ordinances. </section><section prefix="11">At least once every five (5) years, each city shall cause all ordinances in the composite index or code of ordinances to be examined for consistency with state law and with one another and to be revised to eliminate redundant, obsolete, inconsistent, and invalid provisions. </section><section prefix="12">The legislative body may adopt municipal orders. Orders shall be in writing and may be adopted only at an official meeting. Orders may be amended by a subsequent municipal order or ordinance. All orders adopted shall be maintained in an official order book. </section><section prefix="13">In lieu of an ordinance, a municipal order may be used for matters relating to the internal operation and functions of the municipality and to appoint or remove or approve appointment or removal of members of boards, commissions, and other agencies over which the city has control. </section><section prefix="14">All ordinances, and orders of the city may be proved by the signature of the city clerk; and when the ordinances are placed in a printed composite index or code of ordinances by authority of the city, the printed copy shall be received in evidence by any state court without further proof of the ordinances. </section><section prefix="15">For anything said in debate, legislative body members shall be entitled to the same immunities and protections allowed to members of the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42982</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>