<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.550</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 311.530 to 311.620 and KRS 311.990(4) to (6). </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>As used in KRS 311.530 to 311.620 and KRS 311.990(4) to (6): <section prefix="1">"Board" means the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="2">"President" means the president of the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="3">"Secretary" means the secretary of the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="4">"Executive director" means the executive director of the State Board of Medical Licensure or any assistant executive directors appointed by the board; </section><section prefix="5">"General counsel" means the general counsel of the State Board of Medical Licensure or any assistant general counsel appointed by the board; </section><section prefix="6">"Regular license" means a license to practice medicine or osteopathy at any place in this state; </section><section prefix="7">"Limited license" means a license to practice medicine or osteopathy in a specific institution or locale to the extent indicated in the license; </section><section prefix="8">"Temporary permit" means a permit issued to a person who has applied for a regular license, and who appears from verifiable information in the application to the executive director to be qualified and eligible therefor; </section><section prefix="9">"Emergency permit" means a permit issued to a physician currently licensed in another state, authorizing the physician to practice in this state for the duration of a specific medical emergency, not to exceed thirty (30) days; </section><section prefix="10">Except as provided in subsection (11) of this section, the "practice of medicine or osteopathy" means the diagnosis, treatment, or correction of any and all human conditions, ailments, diseases, injuries, or infirmities by any and all means, methods, devices, or instrumentalities; </section><section prefix="11">The "practice of medicine or osteopathy" does not include the practice of Christian Science, the domestic administration of family remedies, the rendering of first aid or medical assistance in an emergency in the absence of a person licensed to practice medicine or osteopathy under the provisions of this chapter, the use of automatic external defibrillators in accordance with the provisions of KRS 311.665 to 311.669, the practice of podiatry as defined in KRS 311.380, the practice of a midlevel health care practitioner as defined in KRS 216.900, the practice of dentistry as defined in KRS 313.010, the practice of optometry as defined in KRS 320.210, the practice of chiropractic as defined in subsection (2) of KRS 312.015, the practice as a nurse as defined in KRS 314.011, the practice of physical therapy as defined in KRS 327.010, the performance of duties for which they have been trained by paramedics licensed under KRS Chapter 311A, first responders, or emergency medical technicians certified under Chapter 311A, the practice of pharmacy by persons licensed and registered under KRS 315.050, the sale of drugs, nostrums, patented or proprietary medicines, trusses, supports, spectacles, eyeglasses, lenses, instruments, apparatus, or mechanisms that are intended, advertised, or represented as being for the treatment, correction, cure, or relief of any human ailment, disease, injury, infirmity, or condition, in regular mercantile establishments, or the practice of midwifery by women. KRS 311.530 to 311.620 shall not be construed as repealing the authority conferred on the Cabinet for Health and Family Services by KRS Chapter 211 to provide for the instruction, examination, licensing, and registration of all midwives through county health officers; </section><section prefix="12">"Physician" means a doctor of medicine or a doctor of osteopathy; </section><section prefix="13">"Grievance" means any allegation in whatever form alleging misconduct by a physician; </section><section prefix="14">"Charge" means a specific allegation alleging a violation of a specified provision of this chapter; </section><section prefix="15">"Complaint" means a formal administrative pleading that sets forth charges against a physician and commences a formal disciplinary proceeding; </section><section prefix="16">As used in KRS 311.595(4), "crimes involving moral turpitude" shall mean those crimes which have dishonesty as a fundamental and necessary element, including but not limited to crimes involving theft, embezzlement, false swearing, perjury, fraud, or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="17">"Telehealth" means the use of interactive audio, video, or other electronic media to deliver health care. It includes the use of electronic media for diagnosis, consultation, treatment, transfer of medical data, and medical education; </section><section prefix="18">"Order" means a direction of the board or its panels made or entered in writing that determines some point or directs some step in the proceeding and is not included in the final order; </section><section prefix="19">"Agreed order" means a written document that includes but is not limited to stipulations of fact or stipulated conclusions of law that finally resolves a grievance, a complaint, or a show cause order issued informally without expectation of further formal proceedings in accordance with KRS 311.591(6); </section><section prefix="20">"Final order" means an order issued by the hearing panel that imposes one (1) or more disciplinary sanctions authorized by this chapter; </section><section prefix="21">"Letter of agreement" means a written document that informally resolves a grievance, a complaint, or a show cause order and is confidential in accordance with KRS 311.619; </section><section prefix="22">"Letter of concern" means an advisory letter to notify a physician that, although there is insufficient evidence to support disciplinary action, the board believes the physician should modify or eliminate certain practices and that the continuation of those practices may result in action against the physician's license; </section><section prefix="23">"Motion to revoke probation" means a pleading filed by the board alleging that the licensee has violated a term or condition of probation and that fixes a date and time for a revocation hearing; </section><section prefix="24">"Revocation hearing" means a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B to determine whether the licensee has violated a term or condition of probation; </section><section prefix="25">"Chronic or persistent alcoholic" means an individual who is suffering from a medically diagnosable disease characterized by chronic, habitual, or periodic consumption of alcoholic beverages resulting in the interference with the individual's social or economic functions in the community or the loss of powers of self-control regarding the use of alcoholic beverages; </section><section prefix="26">"Addicted to a controlled substance" means an individual who is suffering from a medically diagnosable disease characterized by chronic, habitual, or periodic use of any narcotic drug or controlled substance resulting in the interference with the individual's social or economic functions in the community or the loss of powers of self-control regarding the use of any narcotic drug or controlled substance; </section><section prefix="27">"Provisional permit" means a temporary permit issued to a licensee engaged in the active practice of medicine within this Commonwealth who has admitted to violating any provision of KRS 311.595 that permits the licensee to continue the practice of medicine until the board issues a final order on the registration or reregistration of the licensee; </section><section prefix="28">"Fellowship training license" means a license to practice medicine or osteopathy in a fellowship training program as specified by the license; and </section><section prefix="29">"Special faculty license" means a license to practice medicine that is limited to the extent that this practice is incidental to a necessary part of the practitioner's academic appointment at an accredited medical school program or osteopathic school program and any affiliated institution for which the medical school or osteopathic school has assumed direct responsibility. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 585, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 211, sec. 35, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 376, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 537, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 251, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 90(9); and ch. 331, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 5. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 146. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 29. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30519</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>