<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.33-370</section_number><catch_line>Proof of claim. </catch_line><order_by>33-370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Contents of proof of claim. <section prefix="a">Proof of claim shall consist of a verified statement that includes all of the following that are applicable:  <section prefix="1">The particulars of the claim, including the consideration given for it.  </section><section prefix="2">The identity and amount of the security on the claim.  </section><section prefix="3">The payments made on the debt, if any.  </section><section prefix="4">That the sum claimed is justly owing and that there is no setoff, counterclaim or defense to the claim.  </section><section prefix="5">Any right of priority of payment or other specific right asserted by the claimant.  </section><section prefix="6">A copy of any written instrument which is the foundation of the claim.  </section><section prefix="7">In the case of any third-party claim based on a liability policy issued by the insurer, a conditional release of the insured pursuant to subsection (1) of KRS 304.33-390.  </section><section prefix="8">The name and address of the claimant and the attorney who represents him, if any.  </section></section><section prefix="b">No claim need be considered or allowed if it does not contain all the information under paragraph (a) of this subsection which may be applicable. The liquidator may require that a prescribed form be used and may require that other information and documents be included.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Supplementary information. At any time the liquidator may request the claimant to present information or evidence supplementary to that required under subsection (1) of this section, and may take testimony under oath, require production of affidavits or depositions or otherwise obtain additional information or evidence.  </section><section prefix="3">Conclusiveness of judgments. No judgment or order against an insured or the insurer entered after the filing of a successful petition for liquidation and no judgment or order against an insured or the insurer entered at any time by default or by collusion need be considered as evidence of liability or of quantum of damages. No judgment or order against an insured or the insurer entered within four (4) months before the filing of the petition need be considered as evidence of liability or of the quantum of damages.  </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 33, sec. 37, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29856</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>