<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.816</section_number><catch_line>Annual statewide analysis and report of academic achievement of technical education students -- Assistance plan -- Occupation skill standards and assessments.     </catch_line><order_by>816</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Education, with involvement of representatives from the local school districts and teacher preparation institutions, shall complete an annual statewide analysis and report of academic achievement of technical education students who have completed or are enrolled in a sequence of a technical program of at least three (3) high school credits. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The analysis shall include the previous year's results from the state assessment program described in KRS 158.6453. The data shall be disaggregated for all high school students by career cluster areas of agriculture, business and marketing, human services, health services, transportation, construction, communication, and manufacturing and by special populations. Where available, disaggregated data from other national assessments shall also be used. </section><section prefix="b">In addition to assessment scores required under paragraph (a) of this subsection, the analysis shall include: <section prefix="1">The number of students who took state or national assessments of skill standards and qualified for skills certificates; </section><section prefix="2">The number of senior concentrators as defined in the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act, Pub. L. No. 105-332, who have attained a high school diploma or equivalent; </section><section prefix="3">The number of students who made successful transitions to work, military, or postsecondary education. A successful transition to postsecondary education means a student enters directly into advanced training, a certificate program, or a degree program without having to take remedial academic courses; </section><section prefix="4">The number of students employed in nontraditional careers; and </section><section prefix="5">Other factors deemed appropriate by the state education agencies or required under federal law. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Department of Education shall coordinate the development of a statewide technical assistance plan to aid providers of programs in identifying areas for improvement for those schools that do not meet their school performance goal and for those schools where technical students as a group do not score equal to or better than the school average in each of the academic areas. The plan shall address methodologies for further analysis at each school including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">The academic course-taking patterns of the technical students; </section><section prefix="2">The rigor and intensity of the technical programs and expectations for student performance in reading, math, science, and writing and other academic skills as well as in technical skill development; </section><section prefix="3">The level of communication and collaboration between teachers in technical programs and academic programs, planning, and opportunity for analyzing student achievement, particularly between faculty in the comprehensive high schools with the faculty in state-operated or locally operated secondary area centers and vocational departments; </section><section prefix="4">The faculties' understanding of Kentucky's program of studies, academic expectations, and core content for assessment; </section><section prefix="5">The knowledge and understanding of academic teachers and technical teachers in integrating mutually supportive curricula content; </section><section prefix="6">The level of curricula alignment and articulation in grades eight (8) to sixteen (16); </section><section prefix="7">The availability of extra help for students in meeting higher standards; </section><section prefix="8">The availability and adequacy of school career and guidance counseling; </section><section prefix="9">The availability and adequacy of work-based learning; </section><section prefix="10">The availability and adequacy of distance learning and educational technology; </section><section prefix="11">The adequacy of involvement of business and industry in curricula, work-based learning, and program development; and </section><section prefix="12">The adequacy of teachers' preparation to prepare them for teaching both academic and technical skills to all students that are necessary for successful transition to postsecondary education, work, or the military. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The department and the office, in cooperation with the Education Professional Standards Board, teacher preparation programs, postsecondary education institutions, and other appropriate partners, shall ensure that academic core content is embedded or integrated within the performance requirements for teacher education students. </section><section prefix="2">Beginning with the 2013-2014 school year and thereafter, the Education Professional Standards Board shall, as a condition of program approval, require career and technical educator preparation programs to include instructional techniques for teacher education students to embed reading, mathematics, and science knowledge and skills into all career and technical education instruction at the secondary level. </section></section><section prefix="c">The department, in cooperation with the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, shall encourage postsecondary education and business and industry to provide professional development and training opportunities to engage technical faculty in continuous improvement activities to enhance their instructional skills. </section><section prefix="d">The department shall continue efforts with business and industry to develop occupation skill standards and assessments. All efforts shall be made with the involvement of business, industry, and labor. Skill standards and assessments, where available, shall be used as the focus of the curricula. </section></section><section prefix="4">The department shall consult with the Education Professional Standards Board in carrying out the requirements of this section as they relate to teacher preparation. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 43, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 7, effective April 19, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 83, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42222</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>