<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.49-222</section_number><catch_line>Duties of captive insurers. </catch_line><order_by>49-222</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A captive insurer shall engage a manager who is approved by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">The captive manager shall maintain the books and records of the captive insurer’s business, transactions, and affairs at a location that is in this state or shall make them available to the commissioner at a location that is in this state. </section><section prefix="3">The captive manager shall promptly notify the commissioner of any failure of the captive insurer to comply with this section. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner may require a captive insurer to discharge a captive manager for failure to substantively fulfill the captive manager’s duties under this subtitle. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1619, effective, July 15, 2010; and ch. 91, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXXIV, sec. 1, effective April 25, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "executive director" of insurance in subsection (1) of this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 12, has been changed in codification to the "commissioner" of insurance to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938.  (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 91, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>