<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.452</section_number><catch_line>Prepayment of fines subject to certain conditions. </catch_line><order_by>452</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An offense which is designated as subject to prepayment by specific statutory designation may be prepaid by the violator subject to the terms and conditions of the statute involved. </section><section prefix="2">When an offense that is not designated as subject to prepayment by specific statutory designation is cited on the same citation with another offense that is subject to prepayment, the officer shall cite the violator to court for all cited offenses. However, if the offense for which prepayment is not allowed is dismissed by the judge prior to the court date listed on the citation, the offense subject to prepayment by specific statutory designation may be prepaid by the violator, and the violator shall not be required to appear in court. </section><section prefix="3">An offense which is designated as subject to prepayment is subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">Designation as subject to prepayment does not preclude a physical arrest by a peace officer for that offense; </section><section prefix="b">Designation as subject to prepayment shall preclude a requirement that the defendant make a court appearance on a uniform citation; </section><section prefix="c">Except as provided for in KRS 189.990(26), for any offense designated as subject to prepayment, the defendant may elect to pay the minimum fine for the offense plus court costs to the circuit clerk before the date of his trial or be tried in the normal manner, unless the citation is marked for mandatory court appearance pursuant to KRS 431.015 or subsection (2) of this section, except that the fine for violations of KRS 189.221, 189.222, 189.226, 189.270, or 189.271 shall be in accordance with KRS 189.990(2)(a) and the defendant shall not be allowed to pay the minimum fine as otherwise allowed by this paragraph; and </section><section prefix="d">Prepayment of the fine and costs shown on the citation or accompanying schedule shall be considered as a plea of guilty for all purposes. </section></section><section prefix="4">When a peace officer issues a uniform citation and no physical arrest is made he or she shall, where the citation is designated as subject to prepayment, mark the citation as "PAYABLE", except as provided in KRS 431.015 or subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The Administrative Office of the Courts, after consultation with the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Transportation Cabinet, the Division of Forestry, the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, and a representative of law enforcement shall develop a prepayable fine and cost schedule and a uniform statewide instruction sheet for the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 313, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 5, effective March 3, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, relating to the creation and organization of the Commerce Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>