<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.905</section_number><catch_line>Duties -- Meetings -- Chairman -- Annual report.     </catch_line><order_by>905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The duties of the committee shall be to advise the executive and legislative branches of government of the Commonwealth on issues regarding industrial expansion, promotion of motor carrier development, safety training, and improvement of motor carrier taxation and regulation methods. </section><section prefix="2">The committee may request information and data from agencies of state government and may conduct studies to assist in the performance of its functions and duties. </section><section prefix="3">The committee shall meet no less than quarterly during each calendar year, but may meet more frequently, if required. Meetings may be held at any place within the Commonwealth as determined by the committee. The Transportation Cabinet shall provide meeting facilities and administrative assistance and support to the committee and the expense of operations of the committee shall be paid from the budget of the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="4">The chairman of the committee shall be the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, or his designee. The vice chairman shall be elected from the nine (9) appointed members of the committee. A majority of the membership of the committee shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business. </section><section prefix="5">The meetings of the committee shall be public and the board shall file annual reports of its activities, findings, and recommendations with the office of the Secretary of State and the Legislative Research Commission. The reports shall be a matter of public record. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 44, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44193</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>