<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.993</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>993</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates KRS 189.045 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="2">Any person convicted of violating any of the provisions of KRS 189.095 shall be fined sixty dollars ($60) and costs of prosecution. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 189.205 shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 189.375 shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates KRS 189.505 shall be fined not less than sixty dollars ($60) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200) or be imprisoned for not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section><section prefix="6">Any person found violating any provision of KRS 189.820 or 189.830 is guilty of a misdemeanor and shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than thirty-five dollars ($35). </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates KRS 189.920 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than thirty (30) days, or both. In the case of a private vehicle not authorized to use emergency lights under KRS 189.920, all lighting and other equipment used in violation of KRS 189.910 to 189.950 shall be confiscated and forfeited to the county in which the offense occurred. </section><section prefix="8">Any person who violates KRS 189.930 shall be fined not less than sixty dollars ($60) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or be imprisoned in the county jail for not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates KRS 189.940 shall be fined not less than sixty dollars ($60) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or be imprisoned in the county jail for not more than six (6) months, or both. In the case of a private vehicle, all lighting and other equipment used in violation of KRS 189.910 to 189.950 shall be confiscated and forfeited to the county in which the offense occurred. </section><section prefix="10">If a member of a regular or volunteer fire department, ambulance service, or rescue squad violates any provisions of subsection (6) of KRS 189.940, he shall, in addition to any other penalty provided under KRS 189.990 or this section, be immediately dismissed from his membership or employment with the fire department, ambulance service, or rescue squad and shall be disqualified from being employed by or being a member of any fire department, ambulance service, or rescue squad in the Commonwealth for a period of three (3) years. Upon conviction of a second offense he shall be permanently barred from employment or membership in any fire department, ambulance service, rescue squad, police department, or sheriff's office in the Commonwealth, nor shall he be permitted to operate any public safety vehicle as defined in KRS 189.910. </section><section prefix="11">Any person who violates KRS 189.950 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or be imprisoned in the county jail for not more than thirty (30) days, or both. In the case of a privately owned vehicle, all lighting and other equipment used or installed in violation of KRS 189.910 to 189.950 shall be confiscated and forfeited to the county in which the offense occurred. </section><section prefix="12">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter for which no penalty is otherwise provided shall, upon conviction, be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense, except that no penalty shall be assessed for a violation of KRS 189.580(1)(b) or (6)(b). </section><section prefix="13">No producer or processor of natural resources shall allow the transporting of natural resources over the highways of the Commonwealth in excess of the weight limits without possessing a resource recovery road hauling permit. Violation for hauling in excess of prescribed limits without possession of a permit or transporting natural resources over prescribed limits of the resource recovery road hauling permit shall be not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each violation and shall be deposited in the resource recovery road fund. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 110, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 173, sec. 33, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 12(5), effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1979. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978; Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 4; ch.  92, sec. 61; ch. 93, sec. 6; and ch. 117, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 123. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 2 and ch. 113, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 109, 110, and 173, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>