<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.610</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky finds and declares the following: <section prefix="a">Displacement as a direct result of programs or projects undertaken with federal financial assistance is caused by a number of activities, including rehabilitation, demolition, code enforcement, and acquisition; </section><section prefix="b">Relocation assistance policies shall provide for fair, uniform, and equitable treatment of all affected persons; </section><section prefix="c">The displacement of businesses often results in their closure; and </section><section prefix="d">Minimizing the adverse impact of displacement is essential to maintaining the economic and social well-being of communities. </section></section><section prefix="2">KRS 56.620, 56.690 and 56.740 establish a uniform policy for the fair and equitable treatment of persons displaced as a direct result of programs or projects undertaken with federal financial assistance. The primary purpose of the above-mentioned sections shall be to ensure that such persons shall not suffer disproportionate injuries as a result of programs and projects designed for the benefit of the public as a whole and to minimize the hardship of displacement on such persons. The provisions of the above-mentioned sections may be applied to programs and projects undertaken without federal financial assistance. </section><section prefix="3">The following is the intent of the Kentucky General Assembly: <section prefix="a">KRS 56.620, 56.690 and 56.740 shall be carried out in a manner which minimizes waste, fraud and mismanagement and reduces unnecessary administrative costs borne in providing relocation assistance; </section><section prefix="b">Uniform procedures for the administration of relocation assistance shall, to the maximum extent feasible, assure that the unique circumstances of any displaced person are taken into account and that persons in essentially similar circumstances are accorded equal treatment under the above-mentioned sections; and </section><section prefix="c">The improvement of housing conditions of economically disadvantaged persons under the above-mentioned sections shall be undertaken, to the maximum extent feasible, in coordination with existing federal, state and local government programs for accomplishing such goals. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 540, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22668</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>