<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="391" order_by="391">DESCENT AND DISTRIBUTION </unit></structure><section_number>391.105</section_number><catch_line>Determination of rights of intestate succession in the case of a person born out of wedlock. </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of intestate succession, if a relationship of parent and child must be established to determine succession by, through, or from a person, a person born out of wedlock is a child of the natural mother. That person is also a child of the natural father if: <section prefix="a">The natural parents participated in a marriage ceremony before or after the birth of the child, even though the attempted marriage is void; or </section><section prefix="b">In determining the right of the child or its descendants to inherit from or through the father: <section prefix="1">There has been an adjudication of paternity before the death of the father; or </section><section prefix="2">There has been an adjudication of paternity after the death of the father based upon clear and convincing proof; </section></section><section prefix="c">In determining the right of the father or his kindred to inherit from or through the child: <section prefix="1">There has been an adjudication of paternity before the death of the child; or </section><section prefix="2">There has been an adjudication of paternity after the death of the child based on clear and convincing proof and the evidence in such adjudication shall have demonstrated that the father openly treated the child as his, and the father did not follow a consistent policy of refusing to support the child on the ground of nonpaternity. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The terms and conditions set out in this section shall also apply in actions brought pursuant to KRS 411.130 and 411.135. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36142</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>