<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.060</section_number><catch_line>Sentence of imprisonment for felony -- Postincarceration supervision. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A sentence of imprisonment for a felony shall be an indeterminate sentence, the maximum of which shall be fixed within the limits provided by subsection (2), and subject to modification by the trial judge pursuant to KRS 532.070. </section><section prefix="2">Unless otherwise provided by law, the authorized maximum terms of imprisonment for felonies are: <section prefix="a">For a Class A felony, not less than twenty (20) years nor more than fifty (50) years, or life imprisonment; </section><section prefix="b">For a Class B felony, not less than ten (10) years nor more than twenty (20) years; </section><section prefix="c">For a Class C felony, not less than five (5) years nor more than ten (10) years; and </section><section prefix="d">For a Class D felony, not less than one (1) year nor more than five (5) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">For any felony specified in KRS Chapter 510, KRS 530.020, 530.064(1)(a), or 531.310, the sentence shall include an additional five (5) year period of postincarceration supervision which shall be added to the maximum sentence rendered for the offense. During this period of postincarceration supervision, if a defendant violates the provisions of postincarceration supervision, the defendant may be reincarcerated for: <section prefix="a">The remaining period of his initial sentence, if any is remaining; and </section><section prefix="b">The entire period of postincarceration supervision, or if the initial sentence has been served, for the remaining period of postincarceration supervision. </section></section><section prefix="4">In addition to the penalties provided in this section, for any person subject to a period of postincarceration supervision pursuant to KRS 532.400 his or her sentence shall include an additional one (1) year period of postincarceration supervision following release from incarceration upon expiration of sentence if the offender is not otherwise subject to another form of postincarceration supervision. During this period of postincarceration supervision, if an offender violates the provisions of supervision, the offender may be reincarcerated for the remaining period of his or her postincarceration supervision. </section><section prefix="5">The actual time of release within the maximum established by subsection (1), or as modified pursuant to KRS 532.070, shall be determined under procedures established elsewhere by law. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 38, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 65, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 70, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 278, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39556</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>