<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.155</section_number><catch_line>Reporting of specified incidents of student conduct -- Notation on school records -- Report to law enforcement of certain student conduct -- Immunity. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a student has been adjudicated guilty of an offense specified in this subsection or has been expelled from school for an offense specified in this subsection, prior to a student's admission to any school, the parent, guardian, principal, or other person or agency responsible for a student shall provide to the school a sworn statement or affirmation indicating on a form provided by the Kentucky Board of Education that the student has been adjudicated guilty or expelled from school attendance at a public or private school in this state or another state for homicide, assault, or an offense in violation of state law or school regulations relating to weapons, alcohol, or drugs. The sworn statement or affirmation shall be sent to the receiving school within five (5) working days of the time when the student requests enrollment in the new school. </section><section prefix="2">If any student who has been expelled from attendance at a public or private school in this state for homicide, assault, or an offense in violation of state law or school regulations relating to weapons, alcohol, or drugs requests transfer of his records, those records shall reflect the charges and final disposition of the expulsion proceedings. </section><section prefix="3">If any student who is subject to an expulsion proceeding at a public or private school in this state for homicide, assault, or an offense in violation of state law or school regulations relating to weapons, alcohol, or drugs requests transfer of his records to a new school, the records shall not be transferred until that proceeding has been terminated and shall reflect the charges and any final disposition of the expulsion proceedings. </section><section prefix="4">A person who is an administrator, teacher, or other employee of a public or private school shall promptly make a report to the local police department, sheriff, or the Department of Kentucky State Police, by telephone or otherwise, if: <section prefix="a">The person knows or has reasonable cause to believe that conduct has occurred which constitutes: <section prefix="1">A misdemeanor or violation offense under the laws of this Commonwealth and relates to: <section prefix="a">Carrying, possession, or use of a deadly weapon; or </section><section prefix="b">Use, possession, or sale of controlled substances; or </section></section><section prefix="2">Any felony offense under the laws of this Commonwealth; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The conduct occurred on the school premises or within one thousand (1,000) feet of school premises, on a school bus, or at a school-sponsored or sanctioned event. </section></section><section prefix="5">A person who is an administrator, teacher, supervisor, or other employee of a public or private school who receives information from a student or other person of conduct which is required to be reported under subsection (1) of this section shall report the conduct in the same manner as required by that subsection. </section><section prefix="6">Neither the husband-wife privilege of KRE 504 nor any professional-client privilege, including those set forth in KRE 506 and 507, shall be a ground for refusing to make a report required under this section or for excluding evidence in a judicial proceeding of the making of a report and of the conduct giving rise to the making of a report. However, the attorney-client privilege of KRE 503 and the religious privilege of KRE 505 are grounds for refusing to make a report or for excluding evidence as to the report and the underlying conduct. </section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this section shall be construed as to require self-incrimination. </section><section prefix="8">A person acting upon reasonable cause in the making of a report under this section in good faith shall be immune from any civil or criminal liability that might otherwise be incurred or imposed from: <section prefix="a">Making the report; and </section><section prefix="b">Participating in any judicial proceeding that resulted from the report. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 167, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  A comma has been added after the second use of the word "premises" in paragraph (b) of subsection (4) of this statute. The drafter of 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 471 advises and the context clearly establishes that the omission of this comma in that Act was a manifest clerical or typographical error. See KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3454</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>