<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.165</section_number><catch_line>Program for repayment of educational loans for primary health-care professionals who agree to serve in federally designated health professional shortage areas. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text>The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish a loan repayment program to repay educational loans for primary health-care professionals who agree to serve in federally designated health professional shortage areas. The program shall: <section prefix="1">Apply for federal funds for the program under the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. sec. 254g-1); </section><section prefix="2">Make payments of qualifying educational loans of health professionals agreeing to provide primary health services in federally designated health professional shortage areas; </section><section prefix="3">Assign health professionals only to public and private nonprofit entities; </section><section prefix="4">Enter into contracts with participants with remedies for breach of contract by the health professional; and </section><section prefix="5">Make available nonfederal contributions towards contracts with individual health professionals in an amount not less than one dollar ($1) for each one dollar ($1) of federal funds provided. In meeting this matching fund requirement, the state shall provide fifty percent (50%) of the state's share from state funds, and the remaining fifty percent (50%) shall be provided from local governments or other community-based resources from the area in which the health professional will be serving. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 342, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 286, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, Part 1., sec. 115, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>