<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.230</section_number><catch_line>Survey, plat and certificate -- Issue of patent. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The surveyor shall survey the entries in the order in which they are made, bounding each entry by plainly marked trees, stones or stakes, noting where it binds on a watercourse or the marked line of another survey, and giving names. The survey shall be made in the presence of two (2) disinterested housekeepers as chainmen, whose names shall be placed at the bottom of the plat and certificate. Each survey must be made within six (6) months after the date of the entry. A plat and certificate of the survey shall be made out by the surveyor and recorded in his books, and the original thereof and a copy of the order of court under which it is made shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State within six (6) months after the survey is made. </section><section prefix="2">When the survey is carried into grant, the Secretary of State shall write across the face of the order on which the survey was made "satisfied," and sign his name to it. The legal title to the land shall vest in the patentee as of the time the survey is made, unless the plat and certificate of survey are filed more than six (6) months after the survey is made, in which case the legal title shall vest in the patentee as of the date of the patent. </section><section prefix="3">Plats and certificates are assignable, regardless of when made or when assigned, and the assignment authorizes a patent to issue to the assignee. Land warrants are not assignable. </section><section prefix="4">No patent shall be issued for more than two hundred (200) acres to any one (1) person in any one (1) county. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4015, 4016, 4704. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>