<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.435</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 141.435 to 141.437. </catch_line><order_by>435</order_by><text>As used in KRS 141.435 to 141.437: <section prefix="1">"Active solar space-heating system" means a system that: <section prefix="a">Consists of solar energy collectors that collect and absorb solar radiation combined with electric fans or pumps to transfer and distribute that solar heat; </section><section prefix="b">May include an energy storage space-heating system to provide heat when the sun is not shining; and </section><section prefix="c">Is installed by a certified installer; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Certified installer" means an installer who has satisfied the professional certification standards established by the North American Board of Certified Energy Practitioners (NABCEP) and who has been certified as a NABCEP Certified Solar PV Installer or a NABCEP Certified Solar Thermal Installer; </section><section prefix="3">"Combined active solar space-heating and water-heating system" means a system that meets the requirements of both an active solar space-heating system and a solar water-heating system and is installed by a certified installer; </section><section prefix="4">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Dwelling unit" includes a manufactured home as defined in KRS 100.348; </section><section prefix="6">"Energy-efficient interior lighting system" means an interior lighting system that meets the maximum reduction in lighting power density requirements for the federal energy efficient commercial building deduction under 26 U.S.C. sec. 179D, as in effect December 31, 2007; </section><section prefix="7">"Energy-efficient heating, cooling, ventilation, or hot water system" means a heating, cooling, ventilation, or hot water system that meets the requirements for the federal energy-efficient commercial building deduction under 26 U.S.C. sec. 179D, as in effect December 31, 2007; </section><section prefix="8">"Energy-efficient windows and storm doors" means windows and storm doors that are: <section prefix="a">ENERGY STAR-labeled; and </section><section prefix="b">Certified by the National Fenestration Rating Council as meeting the North-Central U.S. climate zone performance standards for U-factor (nonsolar heat conductance), solar heat gain coefficient, air leakage, visible-light transmittance, and condensation resistance; </section></section><section prefix="9">"ENERGY STAR" shall have the same meaning as in KRS 56.770; </section><section prefix="10">"Installed cost" means the following, less any discounts, rebates, sales tax, installation-assistance credits, name-referral allowances, or other similar reductions: <section prefix="a">The purchase cost of equipment, components, and associated design; and </section><section prefix="b">Labor costs properly allocable to the on-site preparation, assembly, and original installation of the property, including piping or wiring to interconnect such property to the dwelling unit or commercial property; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Passive solar space-heating system" means a system that: <section prefix="a">Takes advantage of the warmth of the sun through the use of design features such as large south-facing windows and materials in the floors or walls that absorb warmth during the day and release that warmth at night; </section><section prefix="b">Includes one (1) or more of the following designs: <section prefix="1">Direct gain which stores and slowly releases heat energy collected from the sun shining directly into the building and warming materials such as tile or concrete; </section><section prefix="2">Indirect gain which uses materials that are located between the sun and the living space such as a wall to hold, store, and release heat; or </section><section prefix="3">Isolated gain which collects warmer air from an area that is remote from the living space, such as a sunroom attached to a house, and the warmer air flows naturally to the rest of the house; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Meets the guidelines and technical requirements for passive solar design established by administrative regulation pursuant to KRS 141.436(7); </section></section><section prefix="12">"Qualified energy property" means the following property that meets the performance, quality, and certification standards of and that would have been eligible for the federal tax credit for residential energy property expenditures under 26 U.S.C. sec. 25C, as it existed on December 31, 2007: <section prefix="a">An electric heat pump water heater; </section><section prefix="b">An electric heat pump; </section><section prefix="c">A closed loop geothermal heat pump; </section><section prefix="d">An open loop geothermal heat pump; </section><section prefix="e">A direct expansion (DX) geothermal heat pump; </section><section prefix="f">A central air conditioner; </section><section prefix="g">A natural gas, propane, or oil furnace or hot water heater; </section><section prefix="h">A hot water boiler including outdoor wood-fired boiler units; or </section><section prefix="i">An advanced main air circulating fan; </section></section><section prefix="13">"Solar photovoltaic system" means a system for electricity generation that: <section prefix="a">Includes solar photovoltaic panels, structural attachments, electrical wiring, inverters for converting direct current output to alternating current, and appropriate controls and safety measures for output monitoring; </section><section prefix="b">Meets the requirements of Article 690 of the National Electrical Code; </section><section prefix="c">Uses solar photovoltaic panels and inverters that are rated and listed by Underwriters Laboratories; and </section><section prefix="d">Is installed by a certified installer; </section></section><section prefix="14">"Solar water-heating system" means a system that: <section prefix="a">Uses solar-thermal energy to heat water; </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Is an indirect pressurized glycol system that uses propylene glycol; or </section><section prefix="2">Is an indirect drainback system that uses distilled water or propylene glycol; </section></section><section prefix="c">Uses OG-100 solar thermal collectors that are: <section prefix="1">Certified by the Solar Rating and Certification Corporation; and </section><section prefix="2">Covered by a manufacturer's warranty of not less than five (5) years; </section></section><section prefix="d">Is installed by a certified installer; and </section><section prefix="e">Is warranted by the certified installer for a period of not less than two (2) years; </section></section><section prefix="15">"Upgraded insulation" means insulation with the following R-value ratings: <section prefix="a">Attic insulation rated R-38 or higher; </section><section prefix="b">Exterior wall, crawl space, and basement exterior wall insulation rated R-13 or higher; and </section><section prefix="c">Floor insulation rated R-19 or higher; and </section></section><section prefix="16">"Wind turbine" or "wind machine" means a turbine or machine used for generating electricity that: <section prefix="a">Is certified as meeting the United States Wind Industry Consensus Standards developed by the American Wind Energy Association in partnership with the United States Department of Energy; </section><section prefix="b">Is covered by a manufacturer's warranty of not less than five (5) years; </section><section prefix="c">Is in compliance with all relevant building codes, height restriction variances, other special code requirements, and zoning ordinances; </section><section prefix="d">Has been installed in accordance with all building codes and all permits were received prior to the start of construction and installation; </section><section prefix="e">Is in compliance with all applicable Federal Aviation Administration regulations; </section><section prefix="f">Meets all requirements of Article 705 of the National Electrical Code for electrical components and installations; and </section><section prefix="g">Is rated and listed by Underwriters Laboratories. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 11, effective February 25, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> February 25, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008."  (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch.  139, sec. 26, provides that this section "shall apply to taxable periods beginning after December 31, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>