<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.80-100</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subchapter. </catch_line><order_by>80-100</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter: <section prefix="1">"Activity and use limitations" means restrictions or obligations created under KRS 224.80-100 to 224.80-210. </section><section prefix="2">"Applicant" means a person applying to the cabinet for approval of an environmental covenant. </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">"Common interest community" means a condominium, cooperative, or other real property owned by a person as part of a parcel of real property for which there is an obligation to pay property taxes, insurance premiums, or maintenance, or to make improvements to the real property as described and established in a recorded environmental covenant. </section><section prefix="5">"Environmental covenant" means a servitude arising under an environmental response project that imposes activity and use limitations. </section><section prefix="6">"Environmental response project" means a plan or work performed for the environmental remediation of real property conducted: <section prefix="a">Under a federal or state program governing environmental remediation of real property including programs established pursuant to KRS 224.1-400, 224.1-405, 224.46-530, and 224.1-450 to 224.1-465; </section><section prefix="b">Incident to closure of a solid or hazardous waste management unit, if the closure is conducted with approval of the cabinet; or </section><section prefix="c">Under a Commonwealth voluntary cleanup program authorized under KRS 224.1-510 to 224.1-532. </section></section><section prefix="7">"Holder" means the grantee of an environmental covenant. </section><section prefix="8">"Indexing" means the practice or method kept by a county clerk's office to record legal property transactions. </section><section prefix="9">"Interest" means all or part of a legal equitable claim to a right in real property which shall include both possessory and nonpossessory interests. </section><section prefix="10">"Owner" means a person that owns a fee simple interest or any other interest in real property that is subject to an environmental covenant. </section><section prefix="11">"Person" shall have the meaning specified in KRS 224.1-010(17). </section><section prefix="12">"Public notice" means the publication of required information in a daily or weekly newspaper of major circulation located in the county or counties where the property subject to the proposed environmental covenant is located. If there is no daily or weekly newspaper of major circulation in the county or counties where the property is located, public notice shall mean publication of required information in a daily or weekly newspaper of major circulation in a county adjacent to the county or counties where the property is located. </section><section prefix="13">"Subordination agreement" means an agreement affecting priority of interests in a real property that is subject to an environmental covenant. </section><section prefix="14">"Servitude" means a right, burden, or restriction on the use of real property that passes from the current owner or tenant to any owners or tenants in succession. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 383, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>