<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.600</section_number><catch_line>Certificate holder permitted to obtain only one contractor's license at a time. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text>In no case shall a certificate holder be allowed to obtain a fire protection sprinkler contractor's license for more than one (1) fire protection sprinkler contractor at a time. If the certificate holder should leave the employment of the fire protection sprinkler contractor, he or she must notify the commissioner within thirty (30) days. The certificate holder shall not be eligible to obtain a fire protection sprinkler contractor's license for more than one (1) other fire protection sprinkler contractor for a period of twelve (12) months thereafter. If the certificate holder should leave the employment of the fire protection sprinkler contractor, or die, the contractor shall have six (6) months or until the expiration of the current license, whichever shall last occur, to submit a new application on another certificate holder and be issued a new license. If such application is not received and a new license issued within the allotted time, the commissioner shall revoke the license of the fire protection sprinkler contractor. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 281, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7034</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>