<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.220</section_number><catch_line>Agency emergency operations procedures. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each agency, board, or commission of state government, unless the requirement is waived, in writing, by the director, shall develop agency emergency operations procedures which are consistent with and which meet the requirements of the Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan. The agency emergency operations procedures shall be updated not less than yearly. </section><section prefix="2">Each agency, board, or commission of state government shall take those measures necessary to ensure that it can continue to operate during times of disaster or emergency, that it can protect its vital records, and that it has designated at least four (4) persons, preferably by title, who may act for the agency, and for its major component operations, during an emergency or disaster if the primary person with the power to make necessary decisions is unavailable for any reason. </section><section prefix="3">In carrying out the provisions of subsections (1) and (2) of this section, each agency, board, or commission of state government shall follow the general planning guidance of the division and the requirements of administrative regulations promulgated by the division. </section><section prefix="4">Each agency, board, or commission of state government shall train its employees with regard to the contents of the agency emergency operations procedures, and shall give any additional training necessary to implement the procedures during times of emergency or disaster. </section><section prefix="5">Each agency, board, or commission of state government shall, upon request of the director, send an employee of the agency with full authority to take any action on behalf of the agency to the State Emergency Operations Center, area offices of the division, state command posts or other designated location during periods of emergency or disaster. </section><section prefix="6">As used in this section, agency, board, or commission means all agencies, unless the requirement is waived, in writing, by the director, listed in KRS 12.020, other state bodies created by executive order of the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Court of Justice and its agencies. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>