<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.808</section_number><catch_line>Energy technology career track program.   </catch_line><order_by>808</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the availability of funds, the Department of Education shall establish an energy technology career track program. The purpose of the program is to provide grants to school districts to develop and implement an energy technology engineering career track across middle and high schools within the district. Program components may include but not be limited to career exploration and counseling, strategies to increase the rigor of instruction in pertinent core content areas, strategies to link core content to an energy technology career focus, professional development for teachers, and cooperative learning opportunities with industry and postsecondary institutions. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations for the administration of the energy technology career track program. The Department of Education shall administer the program, approve grant recipients, and distribute the funds to local school districts. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 41, effective June 25, 2013. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 17, effective February 25, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 54, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>