<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.907</section_number><catch_line>Temporary licenses -- Cancellation of temporary licenses.   </catch_line><order_by>907</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the executive director of the board, based upon verified information contained in the application, determines that an applicant is eligible for licensure as an athletic trainer under this section, the executive director may issue to the applicant, on behalf of the board, a temporary license. The temporary license shall be nonrenewable and shall entitle the holder to practice as an athletic trainer for a maximum of six (6) months from the date of issuance, unless the temporary license is canceled by the executive director. The executive director may cancel the temporary license: <section prefix="a">At any time, without a hearing, for reasons deemed sufficient after appropriate consultation with the president of the board; </section><section prefix="b">Immediately, upon direction by the board; or </section><section prefix="c">Upon the board's denial of the holder's application for a regular license. </section></section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall present to the board the application for licensure made by the holder of the temporary license. If the board issues a regular license to the holder of a temporary license, the fee paid in connection with the temporary license shall be applied to the regular license fee. </section><section prefix="3">If the executive director cancels a temporary license, he or she shall promptly notify, by United States certified mail, the holder of the temporary license at the last known address on file with the board. The temporary license shall be terminated and of no further force or effect three (3) days after the date the notice was sent by certified mail. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41868</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>