<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.160</section_number><catch_line>Notification to school by parent or guardian of child's medical condition threatening school safety -- Exclusion of child with communicable disease from school -- Closing of school during epidemic. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A parent, legal guardian, or other person or agency responsible for a student shall notify the student's school if the student has any medical condition which is defined by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in administrative regulation as threatening the safety of the student or others in the school. The notification shall be given as soon as the medical condition becomes known and upon each subsequent enrollment by the student in a school. The principal, guidance counselor, or other school official who has knowledge of the medical condition shall notify the student's teachers in writing of the nature of the medical condition. </section><section prefix="2">If any student is known or suspected to have or be infected with a communicable disease or condition for which a reasonable probability for transmission exists in a school setting, the superintendent of the district may order the student excluded from school. The time period the student is excluded from school shall be in accordance with generally accepted medical standards which the superintendent shall obtain from consultation with the student's physician or the local health officer for the county in which the school district is located. During the presence in any district of dangerous epidemics, the board of education of the school district may order the school closed. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 134, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 116, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 402, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-59. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts Ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts Ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3456</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>