<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.9483</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction and powers of state fire marshal -- Duty of campus security authorities to report fire or threat of fire to fire marshal. </catch_line><order_by>9483</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Under the provisions of KRS Chapter 227, the state fire marshal shall have jurisdiction over all property in the state including property of public postsecondary education institutions and property of any private college or university that is licensed by the Council on Postsecondary Education as provided for by KRS 164.945 to 164.947, insofar as it is necessary for the administration and enforcement of any duty imposed on the office by law or administrative regulation and all laws, ordinances, regulations, and orders designed to protect the public from fire loss. </section><section prefix="2">The state fire marshal or the state fire marshal's employee or appointee may, without delay or advance notice and at all reasonable hours of the day or night, enter in or upon any property defined under KRS 227.200 located on the campus to make an inspection, investigation, or any other action necessary for the purpose of preventing fire loss or determining the origin of any fire. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall obstruct, hinder, or delay such an officer in the performance of his or her duty. </section><section prefix="4">Upon learning of a fire or threat of fire, a campus security authority designated by the college or university president to be responsible and liable for reporting shall immediately report each fire or threat of fire to the state fire marshal in Frankfort and the local deputies, assistants, and employees appointed under KRS 227.230. No fire scene located on a campus shall be cleared or cleaned without the express consent of the state fire marshal to do so after a representative of the state fire marshal has had an opportunity to investigate the scene. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 224, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4505</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>