<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="108" order_by="108">URBAN SERVICES DISTRICTS -- AMBULANCE SERVICE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>108.105</section_number><catch_line>Alternate method for creation of ambulance service district. </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of this section to create an alternative means of creating an ambulance service district in any city or county of the Commonwealth which has not heretofore created the same. </section><section prefix="2">In all counties where a county or city-county ambulance service has not been established pursuant to KRS 108.080 to 108.180, an ambulance service district may be created in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court or local legislative body may by ordinance create an ambulance service district and an ambulance service district tax in such amount as deemed sufficient, but not in excess of ten cents ($0.10) per one hundred dollars ($100) of full assessed valuation. </section><section prefix="4">The ambulance service district tax shall be collected in the same manner as provided in KRS 108.080 to 108.180 and shall be used solely for the maintenance and operation of the city, county, city-county, or district ambulance service. </section><section prefix="5">Other matters with regard to the operation and management of the ambulance service district shall be in accordance with the provisions of KRS 108.080 to 108.180 insofar as they do not conflict with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in this section shall be construed as to abridge the rights of two (2) or more cities, counties or cities in those counties from establishing a joint ambulance service district as provided in KRS 108.080 to 108.180. </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>