<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.252</section_number><catch_line>Public Protection Cabinet -- Organizational structure -- Appointment of cabinet secretary. </catch_line><order_by>252</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the Public Protection Cabinet a Department of Financial Institutions, a Department of Insurance, a Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, a Department of Charitable Gaming, and a Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control. Each department shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor as required by KRS 12.040 and, where appropriate, by KRS 238.510, 241.015, and 304.2-020. Commissioners shall be directly responsible to the secretary and shall perform the functions, powers, and duties provided by law and prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="2">There is established within the Public Protection Cabinet an Office of Occupations and Professions, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050. The executive director shall be directly responsible to the secretary and shall perform the functions, powers, and duties provided by law and prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet shall be appointed by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.255. The Office of the Secretary shall contain the following entities: <section prefix="a">The Office of Communications and Public Outreach, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; and </section><section prefix="b">The Office of Legal Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050 and 12.210. </section></section><section prefix="4">The following agencies are attached to the Public Protection Cabinet for administrative purposes only, except as provided in KRS 131.330: <section prefix="a">Crime Victims Compensation Board; </section><section prefix="b">Board of Claims; </section><section prefix="c">Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals; </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority; and </section><section prefix="e">Kentucky Horse Racing Commission. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>