<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Acquire" means to construct, purchase, obtain by lease, devise, gift, or by eminent domain, or to obtain by any other lawful means; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the board of directors of a corporation formed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="3">"Business entity" means a domestic and foreign limited liability company, corporation, general partnership, limited partnership, business or statutory trust, and not-for-profit unincorporated association; </section><section prefix="4">"Corporation" means a profit or nonprofit corporation formed under the laws of any state or a foreign country; </section><section prefix="5">"Farm Credit Act" means Section 12 of the Federal Farm Credit Act of 1935 and the amendments thereto; </section><section prefix="6">"Federal agency" means and includes the United States, the President of the United States, and all federal authorities, instrumentalities and agencies in the ordinary sense; </section><section prefix="7">"Improve" means to construct, reconstruct, extend, enlarge, alter, better, or repair; </section><section prefix="8">"Member" means and includes each person signing the articles of incorporation of a corporation formed under this chapter, each person later admitted to membership according to law or according to the articles of incorporation or bylaws of the corporation, and each common stockholder in a corporation organized under this chapter that has capital stock; </section><section prefix="9">"Name of record with the Secretary of State" means any real, fictitious, reserved, registered, or assumed name of a business entity; </section><section prefix="10">"Obligations" means and includes negotiable bonds, notes, debentures, interim certificates or receipts and all other evidences of indebtedness either issued or the payment thereof assumed by a corporation organized under this chapter; </section><section prefix="11">"Real name" shall have the meaning set forth in KRS 365.015; and </section><section prefix="12">"System" means and includes any plant, works, facilities, and properties, and all parts thereof and appurtenances thereto, used or useful in the generation, production, transmission, or distribution of electric energy. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 131, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 131, effective June 26, 2007. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 883j-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section."  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 131, subsection (11) cited "Section 164 of this Act." It is apparent from context that the section referred to should have been Section 163 of the Act, KRS 365.015. The Reviser of Statutes has made this change under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14183</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>