<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-254</section_number><catch_line>Duties of insurer offering health benefit plan. </catch_line><order_by>17A-254</order_by><text>An insurer that offers a health benefit plan that is not a managed care plan but provides financial incentives for a covered person to access a network of providers shall: <section prefix="1">Notify the covered person, in writing, of the availability of a printed document, in a manner consistent with KRS 304.14-420 to 304.14-450, containing the following information at the time of enrollment and upon request: <section prefix="a">A current directory of the in-network providers from which the covered person may access covered services at a financially beneficial rate. The directory shall, at a minimum, provide the name, type of provider, professional office address, telephone number, and specialty designations of the network provider, if any; and </section><section prefix="b">In addition to making the information available in a printed document, an insurer may also make the information available in an accessible electronic format; </section></section><section prefix="2">Assure that contracts with the providers in the network contain a hold harmless agreement under which the covered person will not be balanced billed by the in-network provider except for deductibles, co-pays, coinsurance amounts, and noncovered benefits; </section><section prefix="3">File with the department a copy of the directory required under subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="4">Have a process for the selection of health care providers who will be on the insurer's list of participating providers, with written policies and procedures for review and approval used by the insurer. The insurer shall establish minimum professional requirements for participating health care providers. An insurer may not discriminate against a provider solely on the basis of the provider's license by the state; </section><section prefix="5">Not contract with a health care provider to limit the provider's disclosure to a covered person, or to another person on behalf of a covered person, of any information relating to the covered person's medical condition or treatment options; </section><section prefix="6">Not penalize a health care provider, or terminate a health care provider's contract with the insurer, because the provider discusses medically necessary or appropriate care with a covered person or another person on behalf of a covered person. The health care provider may: <section prefix="a">Not be prohibited by the insurer from discussing all treatment options with the covered person; and </section><section prefix="b">Disclose to the covered person or to another person on behalf of a covered person other information determined by the health care provider to be in the best interests of the covered person; </section></section><section prefix="7">Include in any agreements it enters into with providers for the provision of health care services a clause stating that the insurer will, upon request of a health care provider, provide or make available to a health care provider, when contracting or renewing an existing contract with such provider, the payment or fee schedules or other information sufficient to enable the health care provider to determine the manner and amount of payments under the contract for the health care provider's services prior to the final execution or renewal of the contract and shall provide any change in such schedules at least ninety (90) days prior to the effective date of the amendment pursuant to KRS 304.17A-577; </section><section prefix="8">Establish a policy governing the removal of and withdrawal by health care providers from the provider network that includes the following: <section prefix="a">The insurer shall inform a participating health care provider of the insurer's removal and withdrawal policy at the time the insurer contracts with the health care provider to participate in the provider network, and when changed thereafter; </section><section prefix="b">If a participating health care provider's participation will be terminated or withdrawn prior to the date of the termination of the contract as a result of a professional review action, the insurer and participating health care provider shall comply with the standards in 42 U.S.C. sec. 11112; and </section><section prefix="c">If the insurer finds that a health care provider represents an imminent danger to an individual patient or to the public health, safety, or welfare, the medical director shall promptly notify the appropriate professional state licensing board; and </section></section><section prefix="9">Meet all requirements provided under KRS 304.17A-600 to 304.17A-633 and KRS 304.17A-700 to 304.17A-730. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17402</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>