<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.8-500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 271B.8-510 to 271B.8-580. </catch_line><order_by>8-500</order_by><text>As used in KRS 271B.8-510 to 271B.8-580: <section prefix="1">"Corporation" includes any domestic or foreign predecessor entity of a corporation in a merger or other transaction in which the predecessor's existence ceased upon consummation of the transaction. </section><section prefix="2">"Director" means an individual who is or was a director of a corporation or an individual, while a director of a corporation, is or was serving at the corporation's request as a director, officer, partner, trustee, employee, or agent of another foreign or domestic corporation, partnership, joint venture, trust, employee benefit plan, or other enterprise. A director shall be considered to be serving an employee benefit plan at the corporation's request if his duties to the corporation also impose duties on, or otherwise involve services by, him to the plan or to participants in or beneficiaries of the plan. "Director" includes, unless the context requires otherwise, the estate or personal representative of a director. </section><section prefix="3">"Expenses" include counsel fees. </section><section prefix="4">"Liability" means the obligation to pay a judgment, settlement, penalty, fine (including an excise tax assessed with respect to an employee benefit plan), or reasonable expenses incurred with respect to a proceeding. </section><section prefix="5">"Official capacity" means: <section prefix="a">When used with respect to a director, the office of director in a corporation; and </section><section prefix="b">When used with respect to an individual other than a director, as contemplated in KRS 271B.8-560, the office in a corporation held by the officer or the employment or agency relationship undertaken by the employee or agent on behalf of the corporation. "Official capacity" shall not include service for any other foreign or domestic corporation or any partnership, joint venture, trust, employee benefit plan, or other enterprise. </section></section><section prefix="6">"Party" includes an individual who was, is, or is threatened to be made a named defendant or respondent in a proceeding. </section><section prefix="7">"Proceeding" means any threatened, pending, or completed action, suit, or proceeding, whether civil, criminal, administrative, or investigative and whether formal or informal. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 94, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13398</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>