<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0211</section_number><catch_line>Board of Student Body Presidents.   </catch_line><order_by>0211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The student body president of each four (4) year public university, the two (2) student regents to be designated by the board of regents of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, and one (1) student body president representing the members of the Association of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities shall serve on an advisory board to be known as the Board of Student Body Presidents. The student body president representing the independent colleges and universities shall be selected under a process established by the Association of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities. </section><section prefix="2">The Board of Student Body Presidents shall advise the legislative and executive branches regarding postsecondary education issues and concerns of students. </section><section prefix="3">At least once each year, the Board of Student Body Presidents shall meet with the Council on Postsecondary Education and the Advisory Conference of Presidents. </section><section prefix="4">The Board of Student Body Presidents shall submit the names of three (3) nominees to the Governor for consideration in the appointment of a student member to the Council on Postsecondary Education pursuant to KRS 164.011. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>