<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.554</section_number><catch_line>Breast Cancer Screening Program -- Breast Cancer Advisory Committee -- Annual report.   </catch_line><order_by>554</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the department a Breast Cancer Screening Program for the purposes of: <section prefix="a">Reducing morbidity and mortality from breast cancer in women through early detection and treatment; and </section><section prefix="b">Making breast cancer screening services of high quality and reasonable cost available to women of all income levels throughout the Commonwealth and to women whose economic circumstances or geographic location limits access to breast cancer screening facilities. </section></section><section prefix="2">Services provided under the Breast Cancer Screening Program may be undertaken by private contract for services or operated by the department and may include the purchase, maintenance, and staffing of a truck, a van, or any other vehicle suitably equipped to perform breast cancer screening. The program may also provide referral services for the benefit of women for whom further examination or treatment is indicated by the breast cancer screening. </section><section prefix="3">The department may adopt a schedule of income-based fees to be charged for the breast cancer screening. The schedule shall be determined to make screening available to the largest possible number of women throughout the Commonwealth. The department shall, where practical, collect any available insurance proceeds or other reimbursement payable on behalf of any recipient of a breast cancer screening under KRS 214.552 to 214.556 and may adjust the schedule of fees to reflect insurance contributions. All fees collected shall be credited to the fund. </section><section prefix="4">The department may accept any grant or award of funds from the federal government or private sources for carrying out the provisions of KRS 214.552 to 214.556. </section><section prefix="5">For the purpose of developing and monitoring the implementation of guidelines for access to and the quality of the services of the Breast Cancer Screening Program, there is hereby created a Breast Cancer Advisory Committee to the commissioner of the Department for Public Health which shall include the directors of the James Graham Brown Cancer Center and the Lucille Parker Markey Cancer Center, the director of the Kentucky Cancer Registry, the director of the Division of Women's Health, one (1) radiologist with preference given to one who has been fellowship-trained in breast diagnostics and who shall be appointed by the Governor, one (1) representative of the Kentucky Office of Rural Health appointed by the Governor, one (1) representative of the Kentucky Commission on Women appointed by the Governor, and at least three (3) women who have had breast cancer and who shall be appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the Department for Public Health, in consultation with the Breast Cancer Advisory Committee, shall annually, but no later than November 1 of each year, make a report to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Interim Joint Committees on Appropriations and Revenue and on Health and Welfare on the: <section prefix="a">Implementation and outcome from the Breast Cancer Screening Program including, by geographic region, numbers of persons screened, numbers of cancers detected, referrals for treatment, and reductions in breast cancer morbidity and mortality; </section><section prefix="b">Development of quality assurance guidelines, including timetables, for breast cancer screening under this section, and monitoring of the manner and effect of implementation of those guidelines; and </section><section prefix="c">Funds appropriated, received, and spent for breast cancer control by fiscal year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 48, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 462, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 409, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40957</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>