<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.050</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of applicant for licensure -- Examination -- Standards for internship -- Certificate of internship.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every applicant for licensure as a pharmacist shall be not less than eighteen (18) years of age, of good mental health and moral character, a graduate of a school or college of pharmacy program approved by the board, and shall file proof satisfactory to the board, substantiated by proper affidavits, of completion of an approved internship. </section><section prefix="2">After the applicant has passed a satisfactory examination conducted before the board under regulations prescribed by the board, he shall be entitled to a license as a pharmacist. </section><section prefix="3">The examination for licensure shall be given by the board at least two (2) times during each year. The examination shall be prepared to measure the competency of the applicant to engage in the practice of pharmacy. The board may employ and cooperate with any organization or consultant in the preparation and grading of an appropriate examination, but shall retain the sole discretion and responsibility of determining which applicants have successfully passed such an examination. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall by regulation establish standards for pharmacist intern certification and an approved internship program and shall determine appropriate qualifications for pharmacists supervising approved internship programs. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall issue certificates of internship which shall be valid for six (6) years from date of issuance. The fee for a certificate shall be set by administrative regulation of the board, not to exceed fifty dollars ($50). </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 23, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 8; and ch. 221, sec. 4. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2625. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44620</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>