<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.085</section_number><catch_line>Application to practice chiropractic -- Course of study -- Qualifications.   </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any persons desiring to practice chiropractic in this state shall make application to the board, in the form and manner established by the board by the promulgation of administrative regulations. Each applicant shall have satisfactorily completed not less than sixty (60) semester credit hours of study from a college or university accredited by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools or other regional accrediting agencies as recognized by the United States Department of Education and the Council on Higher Education Accreditation, be a graduate of a college or university accredited by the Council on Chiropractic Education or their successors, and which maintains a standard and reputability approved by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board may by administrative regulation require a two-year pre-chiropractic course of instruction to be completed prior to entry into chiropractic college. The board may by administrative regulation establish a preceptorship program where students or graduates of accredited chiropractic colleges as stated in this section may work with and under the direction and supervision of a licensed doctor of chiropractic prior to the taking of the appropriate licensing examination. </section><section prefix="3">Applications shall be signed in applicant's own handwriting, and shall be sworn to and before an officer authorized to administer oaths, and shall recite the history of the applicant as to his educational experience, his length of study of chiropractic, what collateral branches he has studied, the length of time he has been engaged in clinical practice, accompanying same with a diploma, or diplomas awarded to applicant by a college or colleges in which such studies were pursued. Certificates of attendance from the college or colleges from which he is a graduate, stating dates of matriculation, graduation, and number of months and hours in attendance shall accompany the application, with satisfactory evidence of good character and reputation. No license shall be issued to any person convicted of a felony unless he has been pardoned and approved by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 252, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1990. --Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 9, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 8, effective June 14, 1962. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44616</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>