<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.048</section_number><catch_line>Voter registration agencies. </catch_line><order_by>048</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following agencies are designated as voter registration agencies in accordance with the National Voter Registration Act of 1993: <section prefix="a">Agencies that provide benefits under public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act, the Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children, the Kentucky Medical Assistance Program, or the Food Stamps Program; </section><section prefix="b">Armed Forces recruitment offices; </section><section prefix="c">Other agencies as the Secretary of State shall determine to be providing public assistance; and </section><section prefix="d">Other agencies as the Secretary of State shall determine to be state-funded programs primarily engaged in providing services to persons with disabilities. </section></section><section prefix="2">A voter registration agency that provides service or assistance in conducting voter registration shall: <section prefix="a">Distribute with each application for its service or assistance, and with each recertification, renewal, or change of address form, the office's own voter registration application form that complies with the requirements of Section 7 of Public Law 103-31, the National Voter Registration Act of 1993; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a form that includes: <section prefix="1">The question, "If you are not registered to vote where you live now, would you like to apply to register to vote here today?"; </section><section prefix="2">If the agency provides public assistance, the statement, "Applying to register or declining to register to vote will not affect the amount of assistance that you will be provided by this agency."; </section><section prefix="3">Boxes for the applicant to check to indicate whether the applicant would like to register or declines to register to vote (failure to check either box being deemed to constitute a declination to register for purposes of paragraph (c) of this subsection), together with the statement in close proximity to the boxes and in prominent type, "IF YOU DO NOT CHECK EITHER BOX, YOU WILL BE CONSIDERED TO HAVE DECIDED NOT TO REGISTER TO VOTE AT THIS TIME."; </section><section prefix="4">The statement, "If you would like help in filling out the voter registration application form, we will help you. The decision whether to seek or accept help is yours. You may fill out the application form in private."; and </section><section prefix="5">The statement, "If you believe that someone has interfered with your right to register or to decline to register to vote, your right to privacy in deciding whether to register or in applying to register to vote, or your right to choose your own political party or other political preference, you may file a complaint with __________________.", the blank being filled by the name, address, and telephone number of the appropriate official to whom a complaint should be addressed; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Provide to each applicant who does not decline to register to vote the same degree of assistance with regard to the completion of the registration application form as is provided by the office with regard to the completion of its own forms, unless the applicant refuses assistance. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">At each voter registration agency, the following services shall be made available: <section prefix="1">Distribution of mail voter registration forms; </section><section prefix="2">Assistance to applicants in completing voter registration application forms, unless the applicant refuses assistance; and </section><section prefix="3">Acceptance of completed voter registration application forms for transmittal to the county clerk of the county of the applicant's voting residence. </section></section><section prefix="b">If a voter registration agency designated under subsection (1)(d) of this section provides services to a person with a disability at the person's home, the agency shall provide the services described in paragraph (a) of this subsection at the person's home. </section></section><section prefix="4">A person who provides services described in subsection (3) of this section shall not: <section prefix="a">Seek to influence an applicant's political preference or party registration; </section><section prefix="b">Display any material indicating the person's political preference or party allegiance; </section><section prefix="c">Make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to discourage the applicant from registering to vote; or </section><section prefix="d">Make any statement to an applicant or take any action the purpose or effect of which is to lead the applicant to believe that a decision to register or not to register to vote has any bearing on the availability of services or benefits. </section></section><section prefix="5">The State Board of Elections may designate requirements for record keeping and document retention it deems necessary to comply with the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 and the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A completed registration application accepted at a voter registration agency shall be transmitted to the county clerk of the county of the applicant's voting residence or the State Board of Elections not later than ten (10) days after the date of acceptance. </section><section prefix="b">If a registration application is accepted within five (5) days before the last day for registration to vote in an election, the application shall be transmitted to the county clerk of the county of the applicant's voting residence or the State Board of Elections not later than five (5) days after the date of acceptance. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  In Attorney General Opinion 94-42, it was concluded that 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, which enacted this statute "will take effect on January 1, 1995, the date the National Voter Registration Act will take effect with respect to Kentucky." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27303</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>