<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.125</section_number><catch_line>Military judge of a general or special court-martial.   </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A military judge shall be detailed to each general and special court-martial. The military judge shall preside over each open session of the court-martial to which the military judge has been detailed. </section><section prefix="2">A military judge shall be: <section prefix="a">An active or retired commissioned officer of an organized state military force; </section><section prefix="b">A member in good standing of the bar of the highest court of a state or a member of the bar of a federal court for at least five (5) years; and </section><section prefix="c">Either: <section prefix="1">A certified military judge; or </section><section prefix="2">Certified as qualified for duty as a military judge by the senior force judge advocate which is the same force as the accused. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">In the instance when a military judge is not a member of the bar of the highest court of the state, the military judge shall be deemed admitted pro hac vice, subject to filing a certificate with the senior force judge advocate which is the same force as the accused setting forth the qualifications provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The military judge of a general or special court-martial shall be designated by the senior force judge advocate which is the same force as the accused, or a designee, for detail by the convening authority. Neither the convening authority nor any staff member of the convening authority shall prepare or review any report concerning the effectiveness, fitness, or efficiency of the military judge so detailed, which relates to performance as a military judge. </section><section prefix="5">No person is eligible to act as military judge in a case if that person is the accuser, a </section>witness, or has acted as investigating officer or a counsel in the same case. <section prefix="6">The military judge of a court-martial may not consult with the members of the court except in the presence of the accused, trial counsel, and defense counsel, nor vote with the members of the court. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 27, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 16. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41901</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>