<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.505</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited activities -- Commencement of proceedings for enforcement. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall, with intent to defraud, knowingly make a false statement or misrepresentation or by other means fail to disclose a material fact used in determining the person's qualification to receive benefits under any assistance program. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall, with intent to defraud, fail to report a change in the factors affecting the person's eligibility for benefits. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall, with intent to defraud, knowingly use, attempt to use, acquire, transfer, forge, alter, traffic, counterfeit, or possess a medical identification card, food stamp or food stamp identification card, or unique electronic authorization codes or numbers or electronic personal identification numbers in any manner not authorized by law. </section><section prefix="4">No person having responsibility for the administration of an assistance program shall, having knowledge that it is in violation of the law, knowingly aid or abet any person in obtaining benefits to which the person is not legally entitled, or in obtaining a benefit amount greater than that to which the person is fully entitled. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall misappropriate or attempt to misappropriate a food stamp authorization-to-purchase card, food stamp identification card, or Medicaid identification card or misappropriate other benefits from any program with which the person has been assigned responsibility, nor shall the person knowingly fail to report any of these activities when it is clearly in violation of the law. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall, with intent to defraud or deceive, devise a scheme or plan a scheme or artifice to obtain benefits from any assistance program by means of false or fraudulent representations or intentionally engage in conduct that advances the scheme or artifice. </section><section prefix="7">No person shall aid and abet another individual in acts prohibited in subsections (1) to (6) of this section knowing it to be in violation of the law. </section><section prefix="8">The Attorney General on behalf of the Commonwealth of Kentucky may commence proceedings to enforce this section, and the Attorney General shall in undertaking these proceedings exercise all powers and perform all duties that a prosecuting attorney would otherwise perform or exercise. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 30, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6676</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>