<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="424" order_by="424">LEGAL NOTICES </unit></structure><section_number>424.195</section_number><catch_line>Supplementation of printed notice by broadcast in certain cases. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any official of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any of its political subdivisions who is required by law to publish any legal notice or notice of event may supplement, not to exceed twelve (12) publications unless otherwise ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction thereof by use of radio or television spot announcements, or both, when, in his judgment, the public interest will be served thereby; except, that notices by political subdivisions may be made only by stations having a broadcast studio within the county of origin of the legal notice, and that broadcast notices shall call attention solely to published or posted notices required by statute. </section><section prefix="2">Each radio or television station broadcasting a legal notice or notice of event shall for a period of three (3) months subsequent to such broadcast retain at its office a copy of the transcript of the text of the notices actually broadcast and such shall be available for public inspection. </section><section prefix="3">The radio or television station which broadcasts the legal notice authorized by this section shall be entitled to receive payment of an amount equal to the customary charges of such station for such service. </section><section prefix="4">The publication of legal notices under this section shall be restricted to legal notices relating to those official acts of public officers requiring a final determination by order of any court of competent jurisdiction in the Commonwealth. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18256</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>