<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.50-110</section_number><catch_line>Statement of financial condition -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>50-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to reports required under KRS 304.50-060, each workers’ compensation self-insured group shall file with the commissioner an annual statement of financial condition audited by an independent certified public accountant on or before one hundred and twenty (120) days from the end of the group's fiscal year for the immediately preceding fiscal year. The annual financial statement shall be on a form approved by the commissioner and in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles. </section><section prefix="2">The annual financial statement shall include actuarially appropriate reserves for: <section prefix="a">Known claims and expenses related to such claims; </section><section prefix="b">Claims incurred but not reported and any expenses associated such claims; and </section><section prefix="c">Unearned premiums, contributions, and assessments. </section></section><section prefix="3">The annual financial statement shall also include an actuarial opinion by a qualified actuary and a supporting reserve study regarding reserves for known claims and expenses associated with such claims. The reserve study shall include documentation sufficient for another actuary practicing in the same field to evaluate the work. The documentation shall describe clearly the sources of data, material assumptions, and methods. </section><section prefix="4">The following statements shall be included with the annual financial statement: <section prefix="a">Balance sheet; </section><section prefix="b">Statement of gain or loss from operations; </section><section prefix="c">Statement of changes in financial position; and </section><section prefix="d">Notes to financial statements required by generally accepted accounting principles, which shall include a narrative explanation of all material transactions and balances of the self-insured group. </section></section><section prefix="5">No person shall make a deceptive statement or fail to correct a misstatement in connection with the solicitation of membership of a self-insured group. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1640, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 22, effective March 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30266</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>