<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.195</section_number><catch_line>Delivery of machines to precincts -- Arrangement in voting place -- Delivery of supplemental paper ballots, voting booths, supplies, and ballot box to each precinct -- County clerk to take receipt and retain keys to ballot box. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At least one (1) hour prior to the opening of the polls, the county clerk shall deliver each machine, with the operating device and mechanism and the device covering the registering counters securely locked, to the clerk of the precinct in which it is to be used, and shall take a receipt indicating the distinguishing number of the machine. The clerk of the precinct shall cause the machine to be arranged in the voting place so that the front of the machine, on which appear the ballot labels and the operating devices, will not be visible, when being operated, to any person other than the voter. </section><section prefix="2">In polling places in which machines for multiple precincts are located, the county clerk shall post a sign near each machine identifying the precinct for which the machine has been designated. </section><section prefix="3">If supplemental paper ballots have been approved as provided in KRS 118.215, the county clerk shall, at least one hour prior to the opening of the polls, deliver a sufficient number of ballots for the registered voters of each precinct, a sufficient number of voting booths for voting paper ballots, string, rubber stamps for marking "Spoiled" and "Unused" ballots and a locked ballot box for each precinct. The county clerk shall take a receipt for the number of ballots issued and the ballot box for each precinct. The county clerk shall retain the keys to all ballot boxes. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 24, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 5, effective March 19, 1977. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 33, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>