<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.2921</section_number><catch_line>Duties of cabinet -- Chief administrative officer -- Secretary or employee not subject to personal liability. </catch_line><order_by>2921</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall collect, pursuant to KRS 216.2925, analyze, and disseminate information in a timely manner on the cost, quality, and outcomes of health services provided by health facilities and health-care providers in the Commonwealth. The cabinet shall make every effort to make health data findings that can serve as a basis to educate consumers and providers for the purpose of improving patient morbidity and mortality outcomes available to the public, and state and local leaders in health policy, through the cost-effective and timely use of the media and the Internet and through distribution of the findings to health facilities and health-care providers for further dissemination to their patients. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall serve as chief administrative officer for the health data collection functions of KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929. </section><section prefix="3">Neither the secretary nor any employee of the cabinet shall be subject to any personal liability for any loss sustained or damage suffered on account of any action or inaction of under KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 474, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 419, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 427, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, Pt. 2, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8989</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>