<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-850</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of plan for industrial park component of site. </catch_line><order_by>46-850</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly that a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility contain an industrial park component. The approved site for a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility shall be of sufficient size to accommodate new industrial and commercial concerns that can utilize the energy by-products of the treatment technologies. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the responsibility of the Department for Energy Development and Independence to establish a plan for and develop the industrial park component of a regional integrated waste treatment and disposal demonstration facility. The industrial park component, located on property contiguous with the treatment and disposal technologies, shall be designed so as to utilize energy generated from the waste treatment technologies. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 374, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 30, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.2211. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10461</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>