<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.020</section_number><catch_line>Purpose -- Construction. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the purpose of this chapter to implement the Federal Commercial Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1986 (Title XII of Public Law 99-570) and reduce or prevent commercial vehicle accidents, fatalities and injuries by: <section prefix="a">Permitting commercial drivers to hold only one (1) license; </section><section prefix="b">Disqualifying commercial drivers who have committed certain serious traffic violations, or other specified offenses as herein defined; and </section><section prefix="c">Strengthening commercial driver licensing and testing standards. </section></section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall be liberally construed to promote the public health, safety and welfare. As applied to commercial drivers, to the extent this chapter conflicts with general driver licensing provisions this chapter prevails. If this chapter is silent, general driver licensing provisions shall apply. </section><section prefix="3">The issuance of a Class D, E, or M license as set forth in KRS 281A.170 shall be in accordance with the general driver licensing statutes in KRS Chapter 186 and shall be subject to the fees as set forth in KRS 186.531 in addition to any other fee required by statute. </section><section prefix="4">Any administrative action taken pursuant to this chapter against a Class A, B, or C license shall be in addition to any administrative action taken against a Class D, E, or M license imposed under any other applicable statute. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>