<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.200</section_number><catch_line>Distilled spirits and wine transporter's license -- Privileges, duties, and restrictions for eligible entities -- Reports to be filed with Department of Revenue -- Malt beverages transporter's license -- Privileges, duties, and restrictions for eligible persons and entities. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary license to a person engaged in business as a common carrier. A transporter's licensee may transport alcoholic beverages to or from the licensed premises of any licensee under this chapter if both the consignor and consignee in each case are authorized by the law of the states of their residence to sell, purchase, ship, or receive the alcoholic beverages. </section><section prefix="b">A transporter's license shall be issued only to persons authorized by proper certificate from the Department of Vehicle Regulation to engage in the business of a common carrier. Holders of a transporter's license issued under this section may transport alcoholic beverages in Kentucky only in conformity with the provisions of their common carrier certificate issued by the Transportation Cabinet. Such licensees are specifically prohibited from transporting alcoholic beverages anywhere within the state, except upon the route authorized by their respective common carrier certificates. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No person, firm, or corporation operating motor vehicles for hire over the highways of this state, under authority of a Certificate of Convenience and Necessity issued by the Transportation Cabinet, covering the same territory or highways designated in the certificate as irregular common carrier issued by the Interstate Commerce Commission shall be authorized or permitted to transport any alcoholic beverages in this state until the carrier has procured an appropriate transporter's license from the department, and filed with the department a statement of the proposed route of the territory over which the carrier proposes to transport alcoholic beverages. </section><section prefix="b">The statement of route shall be accompanied by an exhibit consisting of a Kentucky road map with the proposed route clearly indicated by suitable marking. </section><section prefix="c">The proposed route shall be restricted to designated federal highways, except as to access side roads to distilleries and terminals. The side roads shall be the nearest and most traveled route from the distillery to the designated federal highway, and shall be no more than seven (7) miles from the federal highway. </section><section prefix="d">When the carrier has obtained a transporter's license for distilled spirits and wine from the department for transportation over designated routes, pursuant to a regular common carrier certificate, no additional license shall be required upon filing of the designated routes and exhibit required under this section. </section><section prefix="e">The license shall be issued to a person legally transporting alcoholic beverages to allow transportation of the beverages over numbered Kentucky state highways, or officially prescribed detours from those highways. </section></section><section prefix="3">A transporter's license may be issued to a steam, diesel, or gasoline boatline, desiring to haul alcoholic beverages in barrels or in unbroken case lots, if it maintains published river-rail rates, but licensees shall not be restricted to routes covered by such river-rail rates. </section><section prefix="4">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary or supplementary license to any nonresident distiller, winery, or wholesaler who is authorized by the state of his or her residence and the federal government to receive and transport distilled spirits and wine. The nonresident licensee may transport for himself or herself only, distilled spirits and wine from the licensed premises of a Kentucky manufacturer, distiller, winery, or rectifier to the transporter's licensed premises only, and beverages on which the Kentucky tax has been paid may be transported from the licensed premises of a nonresident distiller, winery, or rectifier to wholesaler licensees within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, if he or she transports the alcoholic beverages in a truck or other vehicle owned and operated by a nonresident licensee. Each truck or vehicle shall have affixed to its side a sign in uniform letters of at least three (3) inches high containing the name of the company and the state and federal permit numbers for the vehicles. </section><section prefix="5">An application for a transporter's license shall include a statement that the applicant, if granted a license, will allow any authorized field representative of the department to stop and examine the cargo of any truck or vehicle in which alcoholic beverages are being transported within the boundaries of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="6">All persons or entities holding a transporter's license shall be required to file reports with the Department of Revenue on or before the fifteenth of each month, covering the preceding month's transactions. Only one (1) report may be submitted to cover each unit shipment of alcoholic beverages transported into and from the state. Each Department of Revenue report shall show the state license number, the name and address of consignor and consignee, shipping date, delivery date, and number of cases according to size contained in each shipment, and shall be signed by an official of the company handling the shipment. </section><section prefix="7">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary license to a person or entity wishing to transport distilled spirits and wine through this state over the public highways. A transporter's license authorizes the holder to transport distilled spirits and wine during the period of the license. The driver of a vehicle so transporting shall be in the possession of a copy of the license and bills of lading, consignment, or other evidence of ownership of the cargo which tally with the cargo. Failure of the driver to be in possession of these documents shall be prima facie evidence of illegal trafficking. The transporting of distilled spirits and wine without a transporter's license shall subject the offending party to the penalties established in KRS 243.990. </section><section prefix="8">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary license to a person wishing to transfer distilled spirits or wine from a licensed transporter to one (1) truck from another. The licensee may receive from and tender to transporters duly licensed under this section those distilled spirits and wine consigned to licensees under KRS 243.020, in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary license to a person or entity wishing to export malt beverages from the licensed premises of a Kentucky brewer or from the warehouse of a licensed Kentucky distributor, or from another state, through Kentucky. A transporter's license may be issued to an applicant who holds a beer wholesaler or distributor's license issued by the state into which malt beverages are to be transported, or who is licensed by the state to transport those malt beverages. </section><section prefix="b">Applicants for the transporter's license under this subsection, and their employees, may be exempt from the residence requirements of KRS 243.100 and 244.090. </section><section prefix="c">A transporter's license shall authorize the holder to transport malt beverages from the licensed premises of a Kentucky brewer or from the warehouse of the licensed Kentucky distributor, or from another state, through Kentucky, if the licensee transports the malt beverages in a truck or other vehicle carrying a transporter's license and owned and operated by its employees. </section></section><section prefix="10">A transporter's license may be issued as a primary or supplemental license to a person, except a retailer, wishing to transport malt beverages for hire. A transporter's license shall authorize the licensee to transport malt beverages for hire to or from the licensed premises of any licensee, except retailers, if both the consignor and consignee in each case are authorized by the law of the states of their residence to sell, purchase, ship, or receive the malt beverages. A transporter licensee may transport malt beverages for hire to or from the licensed premises of any licensee under KRS 243.040 in counties containing a population of less than forty thousand (40,000) if both the consignor and consignee in each case are authorized by the laws of the states of their residence to sell, purchase, ship, or receive the malt beverages. </section><section prefix="11">No person except a railroad company or railway express company shall transport or cause to be transported any distilled spirits or wine, unless expressly authorized to do so by law. </section><section prefix="12">Distilled spirits and wine may be transported by the holder of any license authorized to transport distilled spirits and wine to and from express or freight depots and the licensee's premises. </section><section prefix="13">A licensed alcoholic beverage store operator may move, within the same county, alcoholic beverages from one of the operator's licensed stores to another without a transporter's license. However, the licensed store operator shall keep and maintain, in one (1) of his or her stores in that county, adequate books and records of the transactions involved in transporting alcoholic beverages from one (1) licensed store to another in accordance with standards established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. The records shall be available to the department and the Department of Revenue upon request. </section><section prefix="14">Distilled spirits and wine may be transported by any licensed retailer selling distilled spirits or wine, by the package or by the drink, from the premises of a licensed wholesaler to the licensed premises of the retail licensee. Any retailer transporting alcoholic beverages under this subsection shall do so in a vehicle marked in conformity with administrative regulations of the department. Both the wholesaler and the retailer engaging in activity under this subsection shall be responsible for maintaining records documenting the transactions. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 66, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 570, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 648, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 214. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-124, 2554b-154, 2554b-190. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014). As amended by 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 14, subsection (9)(b) of this statute contains an erroneous reference to "residence requirements" of KRS 244.090. Although certain licensees were previously prohibited from employing any person who "has not had an actual bona fide residence in this Commonwealth for at least one (1) year" or "is not a citizen of the United States," the General Assembly removed the state residency requirement from that statute in 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 19, and the national citizenship requirement in 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 20. The reference to KRS 243.100 is correct. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43036</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>