<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.181</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>181</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Veterinary Examiners; </section><section prefix="2">"Animal" means any animal, except human beings; </section><section prefix="3">"Compensation" includes any gift, bonus, fee, money, credit, or other thing of value; </section><section prefix="4">"Veterinarian" means a practitioner of veterinary medicine who is duly licensed in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Practice of veterinary medicine" means: <section prefix="a">To diagnose, treat, correct, change, relieve, or prevent: animal disease, deformity, defect, injury, or other physical or mental conditions, including the prescription or administration of any drug, medicine, biologic, apparatus, application, anesthetic, or other therapeutic or diagnostic substance or technique, and the use of any manual or mechanical procedure for testing for pregnancy, or for correcting sterility or infertility, or to render advice or recommendation with regard to any of the above; </section><section prefix="b">To engage in veterinary surgery, obstetrics, embryo transfer, dentistry, acupuncture, manipulation, and all other branches or specialties of veterinary medicine and the prescribing, administering, or dispensing of drugs and medications for veterinary purposes, in accordance with the applicable federal statutes and regulations governing controlled prescription and legend drugs; and </section><section prefix="c">To use any title, words, abbreviation, or letters in a manner or under circumstances which induce the belief that the person using them is qualified to do any act described in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Embryo transfer" means to remove any embryo from any animal for the purpose of transplanting the embryo into another female animal or for the purpose of cryopreserving the embryo, or to implant the embryo into any animal, including food and companion animals; </section><section prefix="7">"Chemical restraint" means the use of any prescription or legend drug that restrains or tranquilizes the animal; </section><section prefix="8">"Direct supervision" means the veterinarian is on the premises, and is quickly and easily available, and the animal has been examined by a veterinarian at the times acceptable veterinary medical practice requires, consistent with the particular delegated animal health care tasks; </section><section prefix="9">"Indirect supervision" means the veterinarian does not have to be on the premises as long as a valid veterinary/client/patient relationship has been established and the veterinary technologist, veterinary technician, or veterinary assistant has been instructed on the applicable animal health care tasks in accordance with KRS 321.441 and 321.443; </section><section prefix="10">"Emergency" means the animal has been placed in a life threatening condition and immediate treatment is necessary to sustain life; </section><section prefix="11">"Impaired veterinarian program" means the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association sponsored program for the identification, intervention, and monitoring of veterinarians impaired as a result of alcoholism, chemical dependence, or drug abuse; </section><section prefix="12">"Veterinary medical impairment committee" means a committee of the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association, comprised of individuals who have expertise in the areas of alcoholism, chemical dependence, drug abuse, or physical or mental illness, that has been designated by the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association to perform activities related to the impaired veterinarian program; </section><section prefix="13">"Veterinary technologist" means a person who has successfully completed an accredited program of veterinary technology approved by the board and who is registered in accordance with KRS 321.441; </section><section prefix="14">"Veterinary technician" means a person who has an associate degree related to veterinary sciences, or its equivalent as approved by the board, and who is registered in accordance with KRS 321.441; </section><section prefix="15">"Veterinary assistant" means a lay person employed by a licensed veterinarian in accordance with KRS 321.443; </section><section prefix="16">"Certified animal control agency" means a county or municipal animal shelter or animal control agency; private humane society; state, county, or municipal law enforcement agency; or any combination of those entities that temporarily houses stray, unwanted, or injured animals and that is certified under the provisions of KRS 321.207; and </section><section prefix="17">"Certified animal euthanasia specialist" means a person employed by a certified animal control agency who is authorized by the board, under KRS 321.207, to humanely euthanize animals by administering drugs designated by the board for euthanasia. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 28, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>