<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.260</section_number><catch_line>Election to choose name and county seat of new county -- Period between elections on consolidation. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At the general election for the election of new officers for the new county, the voters of the combined area to be embraced within the new county shall select a name for the new county and a site for the county seat from among the names and sites recommended by the commissions as provided in KRS 67.240. The question of the selection of a name and county seat for the new county shall be filed with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day of the general election and shall be submitted to the voters at the election in the following form: </section>  "I am in favor of   .........    .........    .........   (These spaces shall be filled in with the names for the new county recommended by the commissions) as the name for the new county to be formed by the consolidation of ........ and ........ counties. (Fill in these spaces with the names of the two (2) counties to be consolidated.)  The voter shall be instructed to indicate his choice of one (1) of the names presented.   "I am in favor of   .........    .........    ........    (These spaces shall be filled in with the names of the sites for the county seat of the new county recommended by the commissions) as the site for the county seat of the new county formed by the consolidation of ........ and ........ counties. (Fill in these spaces with the names of the two (2) counties to be consolidated.)  The voter shall be instructed to indicate his choice of one (1) of the names presented. <section prefix="2">The new county shall bear the name approved by the majority of the voters of the combined area of the new county, voting on the proposition, and the county seat of the new county shall be located at the site approved by the majority of the voters of the combined area of the new county voting on the proposition. The name of the county shall not be changed thereafter, and the county seat shall not be changed thereafter, except as authorized by KRS 67.020. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever an election is held in any county on the question of consolidation of such county with any other county, no election affecting the consolidation of said county shall be held within four (4) years thereafter, except the election as provided for in KRS 67.250 and this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 35, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23717</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>