<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.030</section_number><catch_line>Limitations on applicability of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall not apply to installations under the exclusive control of electric utilities for the purpose of communication, metering, or for the generation, control, transformation, transmission, and distribution of electric energy located in buildings used exclusively by utilities for those purposes or located outdoors on property owned or leased by the utility or on public highways, streets, or roads, or outdoors by established rights on private property. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall require that a maintenance worker or maintenance engineer performing routine maintenance of electrical systems be licensed. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall prohibit or interfere with the ability of a homeowner or farmer to install or repair electrical wiring on his or her real property. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall require that a retailer or its agent engaged in making installations of an appliance purchased at a retail establishment be licensed. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall be construed to require persons making installations exempt by KRS 227.460 to be licensed or to work for a licensed person. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall preclude the use of unlicensed, nonresident electricians in temporary, emergency, or industrial shutdown situations. Those unlicensed, nonresident electricians shall apply for an electrician's license or a master electrician's license after they are employed and engaged in electrical work in the Commonwealth of Kentucky for a period of ten (10) days. No unlicensed, nonresident electrician shall be employed or engaged in electrical work in the Commonwealth of Kentucky for a total of more than thirty (30) days in any calendar year without applying for an electrician's license or a master electrician's license. The license shall be obtained by the temporary, unlicensed, nonresident electricians within sixty (60) days of securing employment. </section><section prefix="7">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall apply to a person performing work at a surface or underground coal mine or at a coal preparation plant. </section><section prefix="8">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall apply to a person performing work for a telecommunications company for which the voltage is fifty (50) volts or less. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall prohibit a factory-authorized representative from the installation, maintenance, or service of a medical equipment device. This exemption does not include work providing electrical feeds into the power distribution unit or installation of conduits and raceways. This exemption covers only those factory engineers or third-party service companies with equivalent training who are qualified to perform such service. </section><section prefix="10">Nothing in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall apply to low-voltage, power-limited installations for control or coordination of interconnected devices separated from a power source by a Class 2 or Class 3 transformer installed by a person licensed as: <section prefix="a">A master or journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning technician employed by a licensed HVAC contractor pursuant to KRS 198B.658; </section><section prefix="b">A fire protection sprinkler contractor pursuant to KRS 198B.560; </section><section prefix="c">A manufactured housing dealer or certified installer pursuant to KRS 227.610; </section><section prefix="d">A boiler mechanic pursuant to KRS 236.210; </section><section prefix="e">A master or journeyman plumber pursuant to KRS 318.030; </section><section prefix="f">An onsite sewage disposal system installer pursuant to KRS 211.357; or </section><section prefix="g">An electrician or master electrician employed by an electrical contractor pursuant to KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140. </section></section><section prefix="11">The provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall not apply to work performed at industrial manufacturing facilities or natural gas pipeline facilities by employees of those facilities. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 83, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 5, effective April 6, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 83, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/12/2006). 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 6, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known and may be cited as "Isaac's Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>