<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.513</section_number><catch_line>Interim financing -- Revenue bond anticipation notes -- Loan agreements -- Tax status. </catch_line><order_by>513</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the State Property and Buildings Commission makes a determination, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, that one (1) or more building projects or industrial development projects will be financed by the issuance of revenue bonds, then in anticipation of such financing the commission may borrow money to provide interim financing therefor and issue in evidence thereof its revenue bond anticipation notes, bearing interest at a rate or rates not exceeding the maximum rate permitted for the issuance of such bonds. Such interim financing may be entered into for the commission's own projects, for those of the University of Kentucky and the state colleges or universities or for any other agency of the Commonwealth where approval by the commission is required regarding the issuance of revenue bonds of such an agency. In instances where the revenue bonds involved are to be issued by other agencies, such agencies, with the prior approval of the commission, may borrow money in the same manner and for the same purpose and issue in evidence thereof their own revenue bond anticipation notes, according to rules and regulations promulgated by the commission. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall solicit proposals for such interim financing from at least three </section><section prefix="3">responsible lenders, and shall select in its discretion the best of such proposals </section>consistent with sound financial practices. A selection may be made even though less than three (3) proposals are received. The term of any such revenue bond anticipation note shall not exceed five (5) years; and the same may be renewed, if necessary. (3) Each revenue bond anticipation note may include prepayment provisions which will allow the commission or other borrowing agency to prepay the loan after giving reasonable notice to the lender; shall identify the revenue bond issue from the proceeds of which the note or notes and any interest thereon are to be paid; and shall include a statement that the note is being issued in anticipation of the identified revenue bond issue, and that neither the note, nor the interest thereon, shall constitute or evidence an indebtedness of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Each such note and the interest thereon (to any extent not previously paid from other sources) shall be paid from the proceeds of the identified revenue bond issue, when such proceeds have been received and are available. <section prefix="4">Instead of borrowing money and issuing revenue bond anticipation notes in the full amount necessary for construction contract purposes, the commission (or such agencies with the prior approval of the commission and according to its rules and regulations), may enter into loan agreements with one (1) or more lenders (determined by the commission to be responsible) according to the terms of which it may be agreed: <section prefix="a">That the lender will continuously make available to the borrowing agency a stated maximum amount of money for a stated period of time; </section><section prefix="b">That the borrowing agency may demand and obtain cash advances against such commitment from time to time upon reasonable and agreed notice, and upon issuing in evidence of each advance a bond anticipation note which will bear an agreed rate of interest, not exceeding the maximum rate permitted for the issuance of the proposed bonds; and </section><section prefix="c">That in consideration of the making of such loan agreement the borrowing agency will pay to the lender or lenders a commitment fee determined by the commission to be reasonable according to financial conditions existing at the time the loan agreement is made. </section></section> Such loan agreements may be recorded as receivables upon the books of account of the commission, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or other borrowing agency, and construction contracts may be awarded against the same to the amount of money which the lender contractually agrees to make available to the borrowing agency, the same as in the case of loan agreements made with departments or agencies of the United States government. <section prefix="5">Each revenue bond anticipation note issued according to this section, and the receipt of interest thereon, shall be exempt from all taxation by the Commonwealth and all of its subdivisions, municipalities, and taxing authorities; and this may be stated as a representation in the text of each such revenue bond anticipation note. </section><section prefix="6">The State Property and Building Commission and other state agencies authorized to issue revenue bond anticipation notes under the terms of this section may, as an alternative and if authorized to do so by the governing body of such commission or agency, adopt the procedures for interim financing established for counties, cities, and other municipal corporations, or their agencies, by KRS 58.150. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 287, effective July 13, 1990  -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 4, effective April 8, 1986. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>