<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.565</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of completion of telecommunications academy required for appointment as CJIS telecommunicator -- Completion of CJIS-full access course required for non-CJIS telecommunicator employed as CJIS telecommunicator -- Grandfather clause -- In-service training courses. </catch_line><order_by>565</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall receive an official appointment on a permanent basis as a CJIS telecommunicator unless that person has previously been awarded a certificate by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council attesting to that person's satisfactory completion of the CJIS telecommunications academy. Every person who is employed after July 15, 2006, as a CJIS telecommunicator shall forfeit his or her position as such unless, within six (6) months from the date of employment, that person satisfactorily completes the CJIS telecommunications academy and is awarded a certificate attesting thereto. The council shall waive the training requirements listed in this section and award a CJIS telecommunicator certificate for all CJIS telecommunicators who are serving on July 15, 2006, and have successfully completed the CJIS-full access course. </section><section prefix="2">A non-CJIS telecommunicator who gains employment as a CJIS telecommunicator shall successfully complete the CJIS-full access course within six (6) months from the date of his or her employment. A non-CJIS telecommunicator whose employing agency initiates the use of CJIS shall successfully complete the CJIS-full access course within six (6) months from the date that the agency initiates the use of CJIS. </section><section prefix="3">All CJIS telecommunicators, whether originally employed before or after July 15, 2006, shall successfully complete each calendar year an in-service training course, appropriate to their job assignment and responsibility, of at least eight (8) hours' duration at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="4">All CJIS telecommunicators, whether originally employed before or after July 15, 2006, shall successfully complete eight (8) hours of CJIS in-service training every two (2) years at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="5">Extensions of time in which to complete the training specified in this section may be granted by the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police or the commissioner's designee. </section><section prefix="6">A CJIS telecommunicator who fails to complete the training within a period of six (6) months and any extension of time granted under this section shall be terminated by the employing agency and shall not be permitted to serve as a telecommunicator with any governmental agency in the Commonwealth for a period of one (1) year. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 31, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=972</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>