<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.710</section_number><catch_line>Ordinance adopting provisions of state statutes on blighted or deteriorated areas -- Vacant property review commission. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the legislative body of a consolidated local government, a city of any class, or a county containing a city of the first class finds and declares that there exists in the consolidated local government, city of any class, or county containing a city of the first class blighted or deteriorated properties and that there is need in the city or county for the exercise of powers, functions, and duties conferred by KRS 99.705 to 99.730, the legislative body may adopt the provisions of KRS 99.705 to 99.730 by ordinance. </section><section prefix="2">The ordinance adopting the provisions of KRS 99.705 to 99.730 shall also establish a vacant property review commission which shall certify properties as blighted or deteriorated to the legislative body. The ordinance shall specify the duties of, the number of members that will serve on, the requirements of membership, and the makeup of the commission. Members shall be appointed by the mayor and approved by the legislative body. No officer or employee of the consolidated local government, city of any class, or county containing a city of the first class whose duties include enforcement of housing, building, plumbing, fire, or related codes shall be appointed to the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 129, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26582</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>