<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 174.500 to 174.510. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>As used in KRS 174.500 to 174.510, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Aviation; </section><section prefix="2">"State aircraft" means aircraft owned by the Commonwealth, leased by the Commonwealth, or otherwise under the control of the Commonwealth and administratively assigned to the department. It shall also include air charters by the department. However, this shall not include or apply to any and all aircraft assigned to, owned, leased, operated, or controlled by the Department of Kentucky State Police, or otherwise under the control or direction of the Department of Kentucky State Police. The operation, maintenance, scheduling, and care of Department of Kentucky State Police aircraft shall not be included under or affected by KRS 174.500 to 174.510; and </section><section prefix="3">"Official business" means any activity involving travel in a state aircraft if the activity is reasonably required, expected, or appropriate, considering the nature of the using public official's job responsibilities. The activities shall include but not be limited to attendance by officials at nonpartisan ceremonial functions and events where their appearance is normally expected by virtue of their office or where official representation of the Commonwealth is otherwise appropriate, and to nonpolitical flights by the Governor and members of his immediate family when accompanying or representing him. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 120, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 605, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification>KRS 36.400. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5030</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>