<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.405</section_number><catch_line>Registration with United States Selective Service System -- Duties of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any United States male citizen or immigrant who is at least eighteen (18) years of age but less than twenty-six (26) years of age shall be registered for the United States Selective Service System when applying to the Transportation Cabinet for the issuance, renewal, or duplicate copy of: <section prefix="a">An operator's license; </section><section prefix="b">A commercial driver's license; or </section><section prefix="c">A personal identification card. </section></section><section prefix="2">This registration is in compliance with federal Selective Service System requirements. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall forward, in an electronic format, the necessary personal information required for registration of the applicants identified in this section to the Selective Service System via the American Association of Motor Vehicles Administrators Network. If an applicant declines registration, the Transportation Cabinet shall forward the necessary personal information to the Selective Service System with the notation that automatic registration was declined. </section><section prefix="4">The applicant's submission of the application shall serve as an indication that the applicant has already registered with the Selective Service System, or that he is authorizing the Transportation Cabinet to forward the necessary information for registration to the Selective Service System. </section><section prefix="5">The Transportation Cabinet shall include the following statement on applications for licenses or identification cards described in this section: "By submitting this application, I am consenting to registration with the federal Selective Service System, if so required. If under eighteen (18) years of age, I understand that I will be registered as required by federal law when I attain eighteen (18) years of age." In the event the applicant declines Selective Service registration, the cabinet may issue an operator's license or personal identification card, but shall forward the necessary personal information to the Selective Service System. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 28, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>