<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.040</section_number><catch_line>Review of petition for interpersonal protective order -- Temporaryinterpersonal protective order.  </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>(1)(a)The court shall review a petition for an interpersonal protective orderimmediately upon its filing. If the review indicates that dating violence andabuse, stalking, or sexual assault exists, the court shall summons theparties to an evidentiary hearing not more than fourteen (14) days in thefuture. If the review indicates that such a basis does not exist, the courtmay consider an amended petition or dismiss the petition withoutprejudice.(b)Service of the summons and hearing order under this subsection shall bemade upon the adverse party personally and may be made in the mannerand by the persons authorized to serve subpoenas under Rule 45.03 ofthe Rules of Civil Procedure. A summons may be reissued if service hasnot been made on the adverse party by the fixed court date and time.(2)(a)If the review under this section also indicates the presence of animmediate and present danger of dating violence and abuse, sexualassault, or stalking, the court shall, upon proper motion, issue ex parte atemporary interpersonal protective order that:1.Authorizes relief appropriate to the situation utilizing the alternativesset out in KRS 456.060;2.Expires upon the conclusion of the evidentiary hearing required bythis section unless extended or withdrawn by subsequent order ofthe court; and3.Does not order or refer the parties to mediation unless requested bythe petitioner, and the court finds that:a.The petitioner's request is voluntary and not the result ofcoercion; andb.Mediation is a realistic and viable alternative to or adjunct tothe issuance of an order sought by the petitioner.(b)If an order is not issued under this subsection, the court shall note on thepetition, for the record, any action taken or denied and the reason for it.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 22, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44770</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>