<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.421</section_number><catch_line>Execution of certificates. </catch_line><order_by>421</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each certificate required by KRS 362.403 to 362.525 to be filed with the Secretary of State shall be executed in the following manner: <section prefix="a">An original certificate of limited partnership signed by all general partners; </section><section prefix="b">A certificate of amendment, signed by at least one (1) general partner and by each other general partner designated in the certificate as a new general partner; and </section><section prefix="c">A certificate of cancellation, signed by all general partners. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person may sign a certificate of limited partnership, certificate of amendment or certificate of cancellation by an attorney-in-fact, but a power of attorney to sign a certificate of amendment relating to the admission of a general partner shall specifically describe the admission. </section><section prefix="3">The execution of a certificate of limited partnership, certificate of amendment or certificate of cancellation by a general partner shall constitute an affirmation under the penalties of perjury that the facts stated therein are true. </section></text><history>Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>