<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="347" order_by="347">PERSONS WITH DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES </unit></structure><section_number>347.050</section_number><catch_line>Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Department of Education shall promulgate and implement rules and regulations for the: <section prefix="1">Enhancement and protection of the rights of persons receiving services and active treatment in both the public and private sectors under this chapter, including but not limited to the right to: <section prefix="a">Provision of services in the least restrictive, individually appropriate environment; </section><section prefix="b">An individualized service plan; </section><section prefix="c">Privacy and humane service; </section><section prefix="d">Confidentiality, access, referral, and transfer of records; </section><section prefix="e">Monitored active treatment in the least restrictive, individually appropriate environment; </section><section prefix="f">Notice of rights under this chapter; and </section><section prefix="g">A fair, timely, and impartial grievance procedure to resolve grievances concerning identification and evaluation, services and active treatment, residential alternatives, and the protection of the rights of persons with developmental disabilities under this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">Implementation of this chapter providing for the orderly development of services and coordination among organizational units, administrative bodies, and service providers to assure effective provision of services in both the public and private sectors to persons with developmental disabilities. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 163, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 614, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 569, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32722</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>