<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.125</section_number><catch_line>Application for title or registration -- Department to provide forms -- County clerk to process documents. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Application for a first certificate of registration, or title, in the name of an owner shall be made on forms prescribed by the Department of Vehicle Regulation consistent with this chapter, which shall be available from any county clerk. </section><section prefix="2">Application forms shall be completed, except as to required signatures, by legibly printing in ink, or typing all required information. </section><section prefix="3">The application, when presented to the county clerk, shall contain all required information and be fully executed with all required supporting documentation and fees. </section><section prefix="4">The county clerk shall reject any application upon which the information provided is not legibly printed or typed, the required information is not supplied, not accompanied by required supporting documents, not properly executed with signatures when required, or when the clerk determines that the application is improper or that the applicant is not entitled to registration or title of the vehicle for which registration or title is sought, or in the absence of the required fees. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>