<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 17.320 to 17.340 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="2">Any public official or employee who knowingly or intentionally makes, or causes to be made, a false return of information to the department shall be punished by confinement in jail for not more than ninety (90) days, by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500), or both. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Any child-care center which violates KRS 17.165(4) or child-care provider that violates KRS 17.165(5) may be liable for license or certification revocation and the imposition of a civil penalty of not less than five hundred dollars ($500) and not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) to be imposed and collected by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; and </section><section prefix="b">In addition to penalties listed in this subsection, any child-care center which violates KRS 17.165(4) or child-care provider that violates KRS 17.165(5) shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) or more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates KRS 17.545(2) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 94, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 26, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 76, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 475, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 5. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 6, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1276</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>