<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.220</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for motor vehicle dealer upon receipt of vehicle. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, when any motor vehicle dealer licensed in this state buys or accepts such a vehicle in trade, which has been previously registered or titled for use in this or another state, and which he holds for resale, he shall not be required to obtain a certificate of title for it, but shall, within fifteen (15) days after acquiring such vehicle, notify the county clerk of the assignment of the motor vehicle to his dealership and pay the required transferor fee. </section><section prefix="2">Upon purchasing such a vehicle or accepting it in trade, the dealer shall obtain from his transferor, properly executed, all documents required by KRS 186A.215, to include the odometer disclosure statement thereon, together with a properly assigned certificate of title. </section><section prefix="3">The dealer shall execute his application for assignment upon documents designated by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, to the county clerk of the county in which he maintains his principal place of business. Such clerk shall enter the assignment upon the automated system. </section><section prefix="4">The dealer shall retain the properly assigned certificate of title received from his transferor, and may make any reassignments thereon until the forms for dealer assignment on the certificate of title are exhausted. The Department of Vehicle Regulation may, if it deems it warranted, provide a special document to allow for additional dealer assignments without requiring system generated documents. </section><section prefix="5">When he assigns the vehicle to a purchaser for use, he shall deliver the properly assigned certificate of title, and other documents if appropriate, to such purchaser, who shall make application for registration and a certificate of title thereon. The dealer may, with the consent of the purchaser, deliver the assigned certificate of title, and other appropriate documents of a new or used vehicle, directly to the county clerk, and on behalf of the purchaser, make application for registration and a certificate of title. In so doing, the dealer shall require from the purchaser proof of insurance as mandated by KRS 304.39-080 before delivering possession of the vehicle. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 186.020, 186A.065, 186A.095, 186A.215, and 186A.300, if a dealer elects to deliver the title documents to the county clerk and has not received a clear certificate of title from a prior owner, the dealer shall retain the documents in his possession until the certificate of title is obtained. </section><section prefix="6">The department may make available, upon proper application from a licensed motor vehicle dealer, electronic means by which the dealer can interface directly with AVIS and the department. If the department grants this access, all fees currently required for the issuance of a certificate of title shall continue to be charged and remitted to the appropriate parties as provided by statute. </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall assure that the automated system is capable of accepting instructions from the county clerk that a certificate of title shall not be produced under a dealer registration situation. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 41, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6180</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>