<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-134</section_number><catch_line>Exemption of specific product forms or product lines -- Conditions.   </catch_line><order_by>6-134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may exempt specific product forms or product lines of a domestic company, that is licensed and doing business only in Kentucky, from the requirements of KRS 304.6-143 if: <section prefix="a">The commissioner has issued an exemption in writing to the company and has not subsequently revoked the exemption in writing; and </section><section prefix="b">The company computes reserves using assumptions and methods used prior to the operative date of the valuation manual and any requirements established by the commissioner and promulgated by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">A domestic company that has less than three hundred million dollars ($300,000,000) of ordinary life premiums or a company that is a member of a group of life insurers that has combined ordinary life premiums of less than six hundred million dollars ($600,000,000) and that is licensed and doing business in Kentucky is exempt from the requirements of KRS 304.6-143 and 304.6-151 if: <section prefix="a">The company reported total adjusted capital of at least four hundred fifty percent (450%) of authorized control level risk-based capital in the risk-based capital report for the prior calendar year; </section><section prefix="b">The appointed actuary has provided an unqualified opinion on the reserves in accordance with KRS 304.6-171 for the prior calendar year; and </section><section prefix="c">The company has provided a certification by a qualified actuary that any universal life policy with a secondary guarantee, issued or assumed by the company after the operative date of the valuation manual, meets the definition of a nonmaterial secondary guarantee universal life product as defined in the valuation manual. </section></section><section prefix="3">For purposes of subsection (2) of this section, ordinary life premiums are measured as direct, plus reinsurance assumed from an unaffiliated company, from the prior calendar year annual statement. </section><section prefix="4">A domestic company that meets the requirements of subsection (2) of this section shall file a statement with the commissioner certifying that these requirements have been met for the current calendar year based on premiums and other values from the prior calendar year's financial statements prior to July 1 of the current calendar year. </section><section prefix="5">For a domestic company that files a statement under subsection (4) of this section, KRS 304.6-130, 304.6-132, 304.6-133, 304.6-140, 304.6-141, 304.6-145, 304.6-150, 304.6-155, 304.6-160, 304.6-170, 304.6-171, 304.6-180, and 304.15-410 shall be applicable; however any references to KRS 304.6-143 and 304.6-151 shall not apply. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44433</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>