<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.120</section_number><catch_line>Clerk, deputy clerk, and stenographer of fiscal court and of the legislative council of a consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in counties containing a city of the first class or a consolidated local government, the county clerk, at his option, shall be clerk of the fiscal court. He shall attend its sessions and keep a full and complete record of all its proceedings, with a proper index. For his services as clerk of the fiscal court, he shall receive an annual salary fixed at a reasonable amount by the fiscal court and paid in monthly installments out of the county treasury. The salary must be fixed not later than the first Monday in May in the year in which county clerks are elected. If the county clerk chooses not to be the clerk of the fiscal court, the fiscal court may select a clerk according to the provisions of subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Except in a consolidated local government, the fiscal court of each county in this Commonwealth in which there is located a city of the first class shall have a clerk, and may have a deputy clerk and may employ a stenographer, all of whom shall attend its sessions and keep a full and correct record of all the proceedings of the court, together with a complete index, and who in addition shall perform such duties as may be required of them by the court. The fiscal court shall appoint a clerk who shall serve at the pleasure of the fiscal court. The clerk shall execute bond to be approved by the fiscal court. He shall receive an annual salary which shall be fixed by the court and paid in monthly installments out of the county levy. The court may appoint a deputy clerk and a stenographer who shall qualify by taking the constitutional oath and who shall serve at the will of the court. The salary of the deputy clerk and the stenographer shall be fixed by the court and paid in monthly installments out of the county levy. </section><section prefix="3">The legislative council of a consolidated local government shall have a clerk, and may have a deputy clerk and may employ a stenographer, all of whom shall attend its sessions and keep a full and correct record of all the proceedings of the council, together with a complete index, and who in addition shall perform such duties as may be required of them by the council. The legislative council shall appoint a clerk who shall serve at the pleasure of the council. The clerk shall execute bond to be approved by the council. He or she shall receive an annual salary which shall be fixed by the council. The council may appoint a deputy clerk and a stenographer, to assist in the official duties of the clerk, who shall qualify by taking the constitutional oath and who shall serve at the will of the council. The salaries of the deputy clerk and the stenographer shall be fixed by the council. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 40, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 9, effective January 1, 1979; and ch. 384, sec. 144, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 180, secs. 4 and 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1072, 1835, 1851b-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23699</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>