<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.201</section_number><catch_line>Duties of cabinet as to the aging and the minority elderly. </catch_line><order_by>201</order_by><text>The duties of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall be to: <section prefix="1">Promote and aid in the establishment of local programs and services for the aging; </section><section prefix="2">Conduct programs to educate the public as to problems of the aging; </section><section prefix="3">Review existing state programs and services for the aging and to make recommendations to the Governor, to the appropriate department and agencies of the state, and to the legislature for improvements in and additions to such programs and services; </section><section prefix="4">Assist and encourage governmental and private agencies to coordinate their efforts on behalf of the aging; </section><section prefix="5">Conduct and encourage other organizations to conduct studies concerning the aging; </section><section prefix="6">Establish, in selected areas and communities of the state, programs of services for the aging to demonstrate the value of such programs, and to encourage local agencies to continue the programs and to create new services where needed. Emphasis shall be given to services designed to foster continued participation of older people in family and community life and to lessen the need for institutional care; </section><section prefix="7">Provide services designed to meet the needs of the minority elderly in programs administered by the cabinet. The cabinet shall annually prepare a report identifying the special needs of the minority elderly population in the Commonwealth as compared to the elderly population at large. The report shall be completed no later than October 1 of each year and transmitted to the Legislative Research Commission. The report shall, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">Contain an overview of the health status of minority elderly Kentuckians; </section><section prefix="b">Identify specific diseases and health conditions for which the minority elderly are at greater risk than the general population; </section><section prefix="c">Identify problems experienced by the minority elderly in obtaining services from governmental agencies; and </section><section prefix="d">Identify programs at the state and local level designed to specifically meet the needs of the minority elderly; </section></section><section prefix="8">In preparing the report required by subsection (7) of this section, the cabinet shall solicit and consider the input of individuals and organizations representing the concerns of the minority elderly population as relates to: <section prefix="a">Programs and services needed by the minority elderly; </section><section prefix="b">The extent to which existing programs do not meet the needs of the minority elderly; </section><section prefix="c">The accessibility of existing programs to the minority elderly; </section><section prefix="d">The availability and adequacy of information regarding existing services; </section><section prefix="e">Health problems the minority elderly experience at a higher rate than the nonminority elderly population; and </section><section prefix="f">Financial, social, and other barriers experienced by the minority elderly in obtaining services; </section></section><section prefix="9">Conduct an outreach program that provides information to minority elderly Kentuckians about health and social problems experienced by minority elderly persons and available programs to address those problems, as identified in the report prepared pursuant to subsection (7) of this section; and </section><section prefix="10">Cooperate with the federal government and with the governments of other states in programs relating to the aging. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 219, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 19, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 186, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>