<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.095</section_number><catch_line>Persons barred by federal law from purchase of firearms -- Duty to notify courts and law enforcement agencies of purchase or attempt to purchase -- Protocol for providing notice -- Duty to notify petitioner -- Immunity from liability. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon receiving notice that a person barred from purchasing a firearm under 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(g)(8) has purchased or attempted to purchase a firearm, any agency with the responsibility of entering domestic violence records into the Law Information Network of Kentucky shall notify: <section prefix="a">The court in the jurisdiction where the domestic violence order was issued under KRS 403.750; and </section><section prefix="b">The law enforcement agencies, as designated by the Department of Kentucky State Police, that have jurisdiction in the county where the domestic violence order was issued and in the county of the victim's residence if different from the county where the domestic violence order was issued. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall develop a protocol for providing notice to the required court and law enforcement agencies under subsection (1) of this section. Within the protocol, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall designate which local law enforcement agencies are to receive notice in each county. A minimum of one (1) law enforcement agency shall be designated in each county. </section><section prefix="3">When a designated law enforcement agency for the county where the domestic violence order was issued or where the victim resides receives notice under subsection (1)(b) of this section, that agency shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that the petitioner who obtained the domestic violence order is notified that the respondent has purchased or attempted to purchase a firearm. </section><section prefix="4">Any person carrying out responsibilities under this section shall be immune from civil liability for good faith conduct in carrying out those responsibilities. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall apply only to domestic violence orders issued, or reissued, on or after July 14, 2000, through July 15, 2002. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 264, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11127</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>