<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.450</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 151B.450 to 151B.475. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>As used in KRS 151B.450 to 151B.475, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Assistive technology" means any item, piece of equipment, or device that enables an individual with a disability to improve his or her independence and quality of life; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the board of directors of the Kentucky Assistive Technology Loan Corporation; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">"Corporation" means the Kentucky Assistive Technology Loan Corporation created under KRS 151B.455; </section><section prefix="5">"Fund" means the Kentucky assistive technology loan fund created under KRS 151B.470; </section><section prefix="6">"Qualified borrower" means an individual with a disability that affects a major life activity such as mobility, sensory and cognitive communications, or self-care, a parent or legal guardian of an individual with a disability, or a nonprofit organization that provides assistive technology to individuals with disabilities who meet the criteria for participating in the Kentucky assistive technology loan fund; and </section><section prefix="7">"Qualified lender" means a financial lending institution or other qualified organization contracted with by the corporation to provide loans for the purchase of assistive technology. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 27, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 56, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2245</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>