<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.403</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 100.401 to 100.419.   </catch_line><order_by>403</order_by><text>As used in KRS 100.401 to 100.419, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Land use enforcement officer" in a county containing a consolidated local government means an officer authorized by a planning commission to enforce binding elements. </section><section prefix="2">"Land use ordinance" in a county containing a consolidated local government means an official action of a local government body which is a regulation of a general and permanent nature relating to the use and development of land within the jurisdictional boundary of the planning commission. It is enforceable as a local law and shall include any provision of a code of ordinances adopted by a local government which embodies all or part of an ordinance. </section><section prefix="3">"Local government" means a county containing a consolidated local government and all cities with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) or any city with a population of less than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census that regulated land use under the provisions of this chapter prior to January 1, 2014, within the county. </section><section prefix="4">"Binding element" in a county containing a consolidated local government means a binding requirement, provision, restriction, or condition imposed by a planning commission or its designee, or a promise or agreement made by an applicant in writing in connection with the approval of a land use development plan or subdivision plan. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 198, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 155, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43783</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>