<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.420</section_number><catch_line>Examinations -- Qualifications -- National board examinations -- Fees -- Issuance of licenses -- Expenses of board members -- Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall conduct examinations at least twice a year at such times and places as the board deems convenient for applicants for licenses to practice podiatry in this state, and shall admit to examination any applicant who: <section prefix="a">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Is a citizen of the United States and a resident of the State of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Is of good moral character and temperate habits; and </section><section prefix="d">Has completed a course in and graduated from a school or college of podiatry approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall prescribe the time, place, method, manner, scope and content of examinations as relates to KRS 311.380(2); and the board may accept certified, successful National Board of Podiatry examinations in lieu of its written examination. </section><section prefix="3">Applicants for examination shall present their credentials to the board by mail upon forms furnished by the board, and shall receive due notice of the place and date of the examination. Each application shall contain proof of the qualifications required of the applicant, shall be verified by the applicant under oath, and shall be accompanied by an examination fee set by the board. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall issue a license to any person who complies with the provisions of KRS 311.380 to 311.510 and who satisfactorily passes the examination. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the board shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be paid their traveling and other necessary expenses while employed upon the business of the board. </section><section prefix="6">The board may, in good faith, adopt rules and regulations to license and control those persons who may become formally educated, or by years of employment by a licensed podiatrist, as a podiatric assistant. </section><section prefix="7">The board may utilize such materials, services or facilities as may be made available to it by other state agencies or may contract therefor, to such extent as the board in its discretion, may determine. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 250, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 11. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 3. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 3. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30501</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>