<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.351</section_number><catch_line>Applications by state agencies -- Requirements. </catch_line><order_by>351</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every state administering agency shall submit any block grant application for the following fiscal year to the Legislative Research Commission no less than ninety (90) days prior to the date of submission, as required by federal law, of the block grant application to the federal administering agency or no less than ninety (90) days before the state administering agency elects to submit the block grant application to the federal administering agency. </section><section prefix="2">Each state administering agency shall, upon request of the Commission, make available to the Commission all background data and supporting information related to each block grant application under review by the Commission as will enable the Commission to perform its functions in an informed and efficient manner. </section><section prefix="3">Each block grant application submitted by the state administering agency to the Legislative Research Commission shall specify the proposed use and distribution of the block grant and other funds to be allocated by the state administering agency to programs and services; and in addition, each application shall specify: <section prefix="a">Programmatic and other requirements applicable to the receipt and expenditures of block grant and other funds, including state matching funds, specified in the application, and the restrictions imposed on the use of these funds; </section><section prefix="b">Whether the block grant and other funds included in the application have been included specifically in an appropriation provision or any branch budget bill enacted by the General Assembly in anticipation of such application; </section><section prefix="c">Whether the funding is one-time, recurring or continuing; </section><section prefix="d">What costs will accrue to the state if federal funds diminish or are cut, and whether a budget reduction plan has been prepared for such contingency; </section><section prefix="e">Whether the programs and services to be provided under the block grant are mandated by the laws of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="f">Whether the programs and services to be provided under the block grant are those which the Commonwealth currently administers and funds; </section><section prefix="g">The agencies expected to provide the services including whether such agencies are public or private or state or local; </section><section prefix="h">The manner in which the allocation of funds will be targeted to need; </section><section prefix="i">Geographic areas to be served by the programs and services; </section><section prefix="j">Standards of eligibility for services; </section><section prefix="k">The criteria and method that will be used by the state administering agency to distribute the block grant funds; </section><section prefix="l">Whether and how block grant funds would be transferred from one (1) block grant to another and the amount of the transfer; </section><section prefix="m">The proportion of the block grant funds to be used for administrative costs; and </section><section prefix="n">Estimated receipt of federal funds applied for by block grant. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22241</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>