<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.560</section_number><catch_line>Member account.   </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The member account shall be the account to which: <section prefix="a">All members' contributions, or contributions picked up by the employer after August 1, 1982, and interest allowances as provided in KRS 16.505 to 16.652 shall be credited, except as provided by KRS 61.702(2)(b); and </section><section prefix="b">For members who begin participating in the system on or after January 1, 2014, the employer pay credit and interest credited on such amounts as provided by KRS 16.583 shall be credited. </section></section> Only funds from this account shall be used to return accumulated contributions or accumulated account balances of a member when required by reason of any provision of KRS 16.505 to 16.652. Prior to the member's retirement, death, or refund in accordance with KRS 61.625, no funds shall be made available from the member's account. <section prefix="2">Each member's contribution or contribution picked up by the employer shall be credited to the individual account of the contributing member, except as provided by KRS 61.702(2)(b). </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Each member shall have his individual account credited with interest on June 30 of each fiscal year. </section><section prefix="b">For members who begin participating before September 1, 2008, interest shall be credited to their individual account at a rate determined by the board but not less than two and one-half percent (2.5%) per annum on the accumulated account balance of the member on June 30 of the preceding fiscal year. </section><section prefix="c">For members who begin participating on or after September 1, 2008, but prior to January 1, 2014, interest shall be credited to their individual account at a rate of two and one-half percent (2.5%) per annum on the accumulated account balance of the member on June 30 of the preceding fiscal year. </section><section prefix="d">For members who begin participating on or after January 1, 2014, in the hybrid cash balance plan, interest shall be credited to their individual account in accordance with KRS 16.583. </section><section prefix="e">The amounts of interest credited to a member's account under this subsection and KRS 16.583 and the employer pay credit as provided by KRS 16.583 shall be transferred from the retirement allowance account. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Upon the retirement of a member who began participating in the system prior to January 1, 2014, his or her accumulated account balance shall be transferred from the member's account to the retirement allowance account. </section><section prefix="b">Upon the retirement of a member who began participating in the system on or after January 1, 2014, who elects to annuitize his or her accumulated account balance as prescribed by KRS 16.583(7)(a) or (b), the member's accumulated account balance shall be transferred to the retirement allowance account. </section></section><section prefix="5">Included as a part of such member's account shall be his accumulated account balance in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System, if any, transferred to this system. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 36, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, effective June 27, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 40. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 8. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/27/2008). The Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering of subsection (3) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42664</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>