<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.221</section_number><catch_line>Basic height, width, length, and weight limits for trucks, trailers, manufactured homes, or vehicles -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>221</order_by><text>A person shall not operate on any highway, except those highways designated by the secretary of transportation under the provisions of KRS 189.222, or those locally maintained highways under the provisions of KRS 189.222(11) or KRS 189.230(4), any of the following trucks, trailers, manufactured homes, or vehicles: <section prefix="1">Any motor truck, semitrailer, trailer, manufactured home, or vehicle which exceeds eleven and one-half (11-1/2) feet in height or ninety-six (96) inches in width, including any part of the body or load; </section><section prefix="2">Any motor truck, except a semitrailer truck, which exceeds twenty-six and one half (26-1/2) feet in length, including any part of the body or load; </section><section prefix="3">Any semitrailer truck which exceeds thirty (30) feet in length, including any part of the body or load; </section><section prefix="4">Any truck, semitrailer truck, or truck and trailer unit which exceeds 36,000 pounds gross weight, including the load; </section><section prefix="5">Any truck, semitrailer truck, or tractor-trailer unit which exceeds a gross weight equal to the sum of six hundred (600) pounds per inch of the combined width of the tires upon which the vehicle may be propelled, but no more than thirty-six thousand (36,000) pounds. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, any truck hauling building materials under KRS 189.2226, or to a road construction project on a highway rated less than the maximum weight provided above, may haul up to eighty thousand (80,000) pounds gross weight, including the load, without a permit. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, secs. 35 and 38, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 484, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6326</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>