<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.092</section_number><catch_line>Consent requirement for entry upon lands of another person -- Private lands incentive programs -- Arrest and citation authority. </catch_line><order_by>092</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Persons shall not enter upon the lands of another to shoot, hunt, trap, or fish, or for other wildlife-related recreational purposes, without the oral or written permission of the landowner, tenant, or person who has authority to grant permission. </section><section prefix="2">The department may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to establish private lands incentive programs encouraging voluntary access to private lands for hunting, fishing, or other wildlife-related recreation, while at the same time protecting the rights of private property owners. Participation in these programs shall not waive any protection granted to the landowner by KRS 150.645 or 411.190. </section><section prefix="3">A fish and wildlife law enforcement officer may arrest or issue a citation to any person who is in violation of this section or the administrative regulations adopted thereunder. </section><section prefix="4">Persons who enter upon the lands of another to shoot, hunt, trap, or fish, or for other wildlife-related recreational purposes, shall not, through their actions, cause damage to any buildings, fences, crops, livestock or domestic animals, machinery, or other property while upon these lands. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the existing powers of peace officers. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 474, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 3. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1953</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>