<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.10-040</section_number><catch_line>Allocation of profits and losses.   </catch_line><order_by>10-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The organic rules may provide for allocating profits of a limited cooperative association among members, among persons that are not members but conduct business with the association, to an unallocated account, or to any combination thereof. Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, losses of the association shall be allocated in the same proportion as profits. </section><section prefix="2">Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, all profits and losses of a limited cooperative association shall be allocated to patron members. </section><section prefix="3">If a limited cooperative association has investor members, the organic rules may not allocate to patron members less than fifty percent (50%) of profits. For purposes of this subsection, the following rules apply: <section prefix="a">Amounts paid or due on contracts for the delivery to the association by patron members of products, goods, or services are not considered amounts allocated to patron members; and </section><section prefix="b">Amounts paid, due, or allocated to investor members as a stated fixed return on equity are not considered amounts allocated to investor members. </section></section><section prefix="4">Unless prohibited by the organic rules, in determining the profits for allocation under subsections (1), (2), and (3) of this section, the board of directors may first deduct and set aside a part of the profits to create or accumulate: <section prefix="a">An unallocated capital reserve; and </section><section prefix="b">Reasonable unallocated reserves for specific purposes, including: <section prefix="1">Expansion and replacement of capital assets; </section><section prefix="2">Education, training, and cooperative development; </section><section prefix="3">Creation and distribution of information concerning principles of cooperation; and </section><section prefix="4">Community responsibility. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">Subject to subsections (2) and (6) of this section and the organic rules, the board of directors shall allocate the amount remaining after any deduction or setting aside of profits for unallocated reserves under subsection (4) of this section: <section prefix="a">To patron members in the ratio of each member’s patronage to the total patronage of all patron members during the period for which allocations are to be made; and </section><section prefix="b">To investor members, if any, in the ratio of each investor member’s contributions to the total contributions of all investor members. </section></section><section prefix="6">For purposes of allocation of profits and losses or specific items of profits or losses of a limited cooperative association to members, the organic rules may establish allocation units or methods based on separate classes of members or, for patron members, on class, function, division, district, department, allocation units, pooling arrangements, members’ contributions, or other equitable methods. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 80, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41056</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>