<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.365</section_number><catch_line>Named federal employees deemed peace officers in Kentucky. </catch_line><order_by>365</order_by><text>The following persons who are employed by the federal government as law enforcement or investigative officers who have the power of arrest and who are residents of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall be deemed peace officers and shall have the same powers and duties of any other peace officer in the Commonwealth, except that they shall not be required to serve process unless permitted to do so by their respective agencies: <section prefix="1">Federal Bureau of Investigation special agents; </section><section prefix="2">United States Secret Service special agents; </section><section prefix="3">United States Marshal's service deputies; </section><section prefix="4">Drug Enforcement Administration special agents; </section><section prefix="5">Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, and Firearms special agents; </section><section prefix="6">United States Forest Service special agents and law enforcement officers; </section><section prefix="7">Special agents and law enforcement officers of the Office of the Inspector General of the United States Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="8">United States Customs Service special agents; and </section><section prefix="9">United States National Park Service law enforcement rangers. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 137, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22925</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>