<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.250</section_number><catch_line>Duties of operator or owner in case of accident. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the operator of a vessel involved in a collision, accident, or other casualty, so far as he can do so without serious danger to his own vessel, crew, and passengers (if any), to render to other persons affected by the collision, accident, or other casualty such assistance as may be practicable and as may be necessary in order to save them from or minimize any danger caused by the collision, accident, or other casualty, and also to give his name, address, and identification of his vessel in writing to any person injured and to the owner of any property damaged in the collision, accident, or other casualty. </section><section prefix="2">In the case of collision, accident, or other casualty involving a vessel, the operator thereof, if the collision, accident, or other casualty results in death or injury to a person or damage to property in excess of five hundred dollars ($500), shall file with the department a full description of the collision, accident, or other casualty, including such information as said agency may by regulation require. When the operator of a vessel, who is not the owner of it, cannot submit the casualty or accident report required by subsection (1) of this section, the owner shall submit the casualty or accident report. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 446, sec. 4, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 17, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 18. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 27, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>