<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.270</section_number><catch_line>Use of existing facilities -- Grade crossing elimination -- Public way connections. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text>The highway authority of the state, county, city, town, or village may designate and establish limited access highways as new and additional facilities or may designate and establish an existing street or highway as included within a limited access facility. The state or any of its subdivisions shall have authority to provide for the elimination of intersections at grade of limited access facilities with existing state and county roads, and city and town or village streets, by grade separation or service road, or by closing off such roads and streets at the right-of-way boundary line of such limited access facility; and after the establishment of any limited access facility, no highway or street which is not part of said facility shall intersect the same at grade. No city, town, or village street, county or state highway or other public way shall be opened into or connected with any such limited access facility without the consent and previous approval of the highway authority in the state, county, city, town, or village having jurisdiction over such limited access facility. Such consent and approval shall be given only if the public interest shall be served thereby. </text><history>Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5300</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>