<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.525</section_number><catch_line>Center for Mathematics -- Creation, duties, and location. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Center for Mathematics is hereby created to make available professional development for teachers in reliable, research-based diagnostic assessment and intervention strategies, coaching and mentoring models, and other programs in mathematics. The center shall be headed by an executive director and administered by a public postsecondary education institution. The center shall: <section prefix="a">Act as a clearinghouse for information about professional development programs for teachers that address mathematics diagnostic assessment, intervention programs, coaching and mentoring programs, and other instructional strategies to address students' needs; </section><section prefix="b">Collaborate with Kentucky's other public and private postsecondary institutions to develop teachers' mathematical knowledge needed for teaching and help teachers improve students' mathematical concepts, thinking, problem-solving, and skills, with an emphasis on diagnostic assessment and intervention programs for students in the primary program; </section><section prefix="c">Provide teacher training to develop teacher leaders and teaching specialists in primary programs who have skills in diagnostic assessment and intervention services to assist struggling students or those who are at risk of failure in mathematics. The center may contract for services in order to carry out this responsibility; </section><section prefix="d">Maintain a demonstration and training site for mathematics located at each of the public universities; </section><section prefix="e">Advise the Kentucky Department of Education and Kentucky Board of Education regarding: <section prefix="1">Early mathematics content, diagnostic assessment practices, and intervention programs; </section><section prefix="2">Costs and effectiveness of various mathematics intervention programs; </section><section prefix="3">Coaching and mentoring models that help improve student achievements; </section><section prefix="4">Trends and issues relating to mathematics programs in schools throughout the state; and </section><section prefix="5">The establishment and implementation of the Middle School Mathematics and Science Scholars Program established under KRS 158.848; and </section></section><section prefix="f">Disseminate information to teachers, administrators, and policymakers on an ongoing basis. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall select a location for the center no later than January 1, 2006. The council shall use a request for proposal process. In developing the request for proposal, the council shall seek advice from the Committee for Mathematics Achievement created in KRS 158.842 and the commissioner of education. The center shall be located at the selected university through July 1, 2011, unless funding is not available, the council deems the performance of the institute to be inadequate, or the university requests to discontinue its relationship to the institute. Contingent upon available funding at the end of the initial cycle, and each five (5) year period thereafter, the council shall issue a request for proposal to all public postsecondary education institutions to administer the center. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 4, effective March 18, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note>(3/18/2005). 2005  Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 4, contained one reference to the Mathematics Achievement Committee. The correct name for this entity is the Committee for Mathematics Achievement. The Statute Reviser, under the authority of KRS 7.136, has changed this reference to be consistent with sec.2 of this Act, which created the Committee for Mathematics Achievement and was codified as KRS 158.842. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>