<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-135</section_number><catch_line>Banker's bank authorized -- Limitations on holdings -- Issuance of charter. </catch_line><order_by>3-135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, any bank doing business in the Commonwealth, whether state or nationally chartered, may purchase for its own account shares of a bank or bank holding company which owns or controls such a bank provided: <section prefix="a">The stock of such bank or bank holding company is owned exclusively (except to the extent director's qualifying shares are required by law) by depository institutions; and </section><section prefix="b">Such bank or bank holding company and all subsidiaries thereof are engaged exclusively in providing services for depository institutions, their parent companies, their subsidiaries, the officers, directors, and employees of each. </section></section><section prefix="2">In no event shall the total amount of stock held by a bank in any bank or bank holding company described in subsection (1) above exceed at any time ten percent (10%) of a bank's capital stock and paid in and unimpaired surplus and in no event shall the purchase of such stock result in a bank acquiring more than five percent (5%) of any class of voting securities of such bank or bank holding company. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner is authorized to receive applications, hold hearings on such applications, and issue charters for a banker's bank. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 625, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 309, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.135.</former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14539</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>