<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.448</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of state administering agency. </catch_line><order_by>448</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The responsibilities and powers of the state administering agency shall be: <section prefix="a">To establish standards in accordance with applicable state and federal laws and regulations by which administrative, fiscal and programmatic effectiveness of the federal act in the Commonwealth shall be measured. </section><section prefix="b">To monitor and evaluate community action agencies' compliance with: <section prefix="1">The standards provided under subsection (1)(a) of this section and as set forth in administrative regulations by the state administering agency; </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 273.405 to 273.451; and </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of the federal act. </section></section><section prefix="c">To receive and review annual independent audits of all funds received by community action agencies. </section><section prefix="d">To direct community action agencies to submit such reports, records or other information necessary to determine community action agencies' administrative, fiscal, and programmatic effectiveness in their use of funds made available under the federal act. </section><section prefix="e">To provide for training and technical assistance to the community action agencies. </section><section prefix="f">To serve as liaison between community action agencies and other state and federal agencies for the purposes of: <section prefix="1">Increasing the awareness of state and federal agencies toward the needs of low-income persons; </section><section prefix="2">Providing information regarding capabilities of community action agencies; </section><section prefix="3">Mobilizing resources for utilization by community action agencies; </section><section prefix="4">Promoting the services and activities of community action agencies; and </section><section prefix="5">Developing, promoting, or otherwise encouraging means for private sector involvement in the services and activities of community action agencies. </section></section><section prefix="g">To develop annually a plan describing the intended use and distribution of the community services block grant under the federal act based on the provisions of KRS 273.446(1), (2), (3) and (4).  The plan shall include a provision for the administrative costs of the community action agencies. </section><section prefix="h">To provide the Commission and the designated review body all materials, information, reports and documents as provided by KRS 45.351 and 45.357. </section></section><section prefix="2">The state administering agency's administrative costs for administering the federal act shall not exceed the limit contained in the federal act and except as otherwise provided under KRS 45.353. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>