<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.705</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications -- Vacancy -- Salary -- Minimum annual compensation -- Exception -- Duties and salaries of judge/executive and magistrates or commissioners in county containing a consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>705</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county shall have a chief executive officer known as the county judge/executive. Only a resident of the county shall be eligible for election as county judge/executive. He shall be nominated and elected by the qualified voters of the county in the manner provided by law for the election of county officers. In case the office of county judge/executive becomes vacant by reason of death, resignation, or removal, it shall be filled with a person appointed by the Governor, in accordance with Section 152 of the Constitution, for the unexpired term. The Governor shall appoint a person to fill a vacancy in the office of county judge/executive not later than thirty (30) days after the date on which the vacancy occurs. If a vacancy occurs in the office of county judge/executive, the remaining members of fiscal court shall elect one (1) of their members to serve as temporary county judge/executive until the Governor fills the vacancy in the office, notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 61.080(2) to the contrary. </section><section prefix="2">The county judge/executive shall receive an annual salary pursuant to the salary schedule in KRS 64.5275, except in counties that contain an urban-county form of government or a consolidated local government, where the county judge/executive shall receive the salary set by the legislative body. </section><section prefix="3">Except in counties containing a consolidated local government, in no event shall the county judge/executive, justice of the peace, magistrate, or commissioners who serve on the fiscal court holding office on January 2, 1978, receive less than the total annual compensation received by that official during calendar year 1976. </section><section prefix="4">In a county containing a consolidated local government, the county judge/executive and magistrates or commissioners may have those duties as determined by ordinance of the consolidated local government and shall receive a salary as set by the legislative council of the consolidated local government for those duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 41, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 592, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 610, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective January 2. 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>.  Section 10 of Acts 1976 (Ex. Sess.), ch. 20, as amended by รยง 4 of Acts 1982, ch. 384 provided that: "This section and KRS 67.710 to 67.720 shall not apply in counties having an urban county form of government. In such counties, the duties of the county judge/executive shall be as prescribed by the comprehensive plan of such government and his salary shall be fixed by the legislative body of such government." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>