<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.670</section_number><catch_line>Civil action by commission on behalf of aggrieved person electing judicial proceeding. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an election is made under KRS 344.635 for a judicial rather than an administrative proceeding, the commission shall not later than thirty (30) days after the election is made, commence and maintain a civil action on behalf of the aggrieved person in the appropriate Circuit Court seeking relief under this section. </section><section prefix="2">Any aggrieved person with respect to the issues to be determined in a civil action under this section may intervene as of right in that civil action. </section><section prefix="3">If the court finds that a discriminatory housing practice has occurred or is about to occur, the court may grant as relief any relief under KRS 344.660 which a court could grant with respect to a discriminatory housing practice in a civil action under KRS 344.650. Any relief granted under KRS 344.660 that would accrue to an aggrieved person in a civil action commenced by that aggrieved person under KRS 344.650 shall also accrue to that aggrieved person in a civil action under this section. If monetary relief is sought for the benefit of an aggrieved person who does not intervene in the civil action, the court shall not award relief if that aggrieved person has not complied with discovery orders entered by the court. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 32, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32674</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>