<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.280</section_number><catch_line>Requirement of license for race meeting -- Qualifications of applicants. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall hold or conduct any horse race meeting for any stake, purse, or reward within the Commonwealth of Kentucky without securing the required license from the racing commission. </section><section prefix="2">The racing commission shall investigate the qualifications of each applicant for a license to conduct a horse race meeting or the renewal of a license to conduct a horse race meeting. The racing commission may issue or renew a license unless the racing commission determines that: <section prefix="a">The track location, traffic flow, facilities for the public, and facilities for racing participants and horses do not meet state code or are otherwise inadequate to protect the public health and safety; </section><section prefix="b">The racing dates and times requested conflict with another race meeting of the same breed of horse; </section><section prefix="c">The financing or proposed financing of the entire operation is not adequate for the operation or is from an unsuitable source; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant or licensee has failed to disclose or has misstated information or otherwise attempted to mislead the racing commission with respect to any material fact contained in the application for the issuance or renewal of the license; </section><section prefix="e">The applicant has knowingly failed to comply with the provision of this chapter or any administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="f">Any of the principals of the applicant or licensee is determined to be unsuitable because he or she has: <section prefix="1">Been convicted of any crime of moral turpitude, embezzlement, or larceny, or any violation of any law pertaining to illegal gaming or gambling, or any crime that is inimical to the declared policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky with regard to horse racing and pari-mutuel wagering thereon; </section><section prefix="2">Been convicted in any jurisdiction within ten (10) years preceding initial licensing or license renewal of any crime that is or would be a felony or class A misdemeanor in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">Been identified in the published reports of any federal or state legislative or executive body as being a member or associate of organized crime, or of being of notorious or unsavory reputation; </section><section prefix="4">Been placed and remains in the custody of any federal, state, or local law enforcement authority; </section><section prefix="5">Had a racing or gaming license revoked in another jurisdiction on grounds that would have been grounds for revoking the license in Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="6">Engaged in any other activities that would pose a threat to the public interest or to the effective regulation of horse racing and wagering in Kentucky, or enhance the dangers of unsuitable, unfair, or illegal practices, methods, and activities in the conduct of racing and wagering or in the operation of the business and financial arrangements incidental thereto; or </section></section><section prefix="g">The applicant or licensee has had a racing or gaming license denied or revoked in another jurisdiction on grounds that would be grounds for license denial or revocation in Kentucky. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 453, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 18, effective March 30, 1992. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 8, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10840</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>