<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="172" order_by="172">COUNTY LAW LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>172.170</section_number><catch_line>County law library.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 172.100 to 172.160 shall not apply to any county that has a law library acquired under the provisions of Chapter 2 of the Acts of 1916. The fiscal court of such county may make such rules and regulations regarding the maintenance and operation of the library as the court deems proper and as are approved by the judge or judges of the Circuit Court of the county, and may employ a librarian at a salary not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) per month, and pay said salary out of the general funds of the county. The library shall be for the use of the court officers and county officers of the county, and the fiscal court may provide for the use of the library by others than the court and county officers, on such terms as the fiscal court deems advisable and proper. </section><section prefix="2">All books belonging to the state heretofore or hereafter sent to the county officials directed by law to receive such books, all books sent to the library by the state, and all books now owned or hereafter acquired by the county for the library, shall constitute part of the library. The county may acquire books, maps or other articles for the library by purchase, gift or devise. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 242, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43827</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>