<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.040</section_number><catch_line>Front lights -- Flashing lights. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every motor vehicle, other than a motorcycle or motor-driven cycle, shall be equipped with at least two (2) head lamps with at least one (1) on each side of the front of the motor vehicle, which head lamps shall comply with the requirements and limitations set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="2">Every motorcycle, moped, and every motor-driven cycle shall be equipped with at least one (1) and not more than two (2) head lamps which shall comply with the requirements and limitations of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Except as hereinafter provided, the head lamps or the auxiliary driving lamps or the auxiliary passing lamp or combinations thereof on motor vehicles, other than a motorcycle or motor-driven cycle, shall be so arranged that the driver may control the selection between distribution of light projected to different elevations, subject to the following requirements and limitations: <section prefix="a">There shall be an uppermost distribution of light, or composite beam, so aimed and of such intensity as to reveal persons and vehicles at a distance of at least three hundred fifty (350) feet ahead for all conditions of loading; </section><section prefix="b">There shall be a lowermost distribution of light, or composite beam, so aimed and of sufficient intensity to reveal persons and vehicles at a distance of at least one hundred (100) feet ahead; and on a straight level road under any condition of loading none of the high-intensity portion of the beam shall be directed to strike the eyes of an approaching driver; and </section><section prefix="c">Every new motor vehicle, other than a motorcycle or motor-driven cycle, registered in this state after January 1, 1956, which has multiple-beam road-lighting equipment shall be equipped with a beam indicator, which shall be lighted whenever the uppermost distribution of light from the head lamps is in use, and shall not otherwise be lighted. Said indicator shall be so designed and located that when lighted it will be readily visible without glare to the driver of the vehicle so equipped. </section></section><section prefix="4">Whenever a motor vehicle is being operated on a roadway or shoulder adjacent thereto during the times specified in KRS 189.030, the driver shall use a distribution of light or composite beam directed high enough and of sufficient intensity to reveal persons and vehicles at a safe distance in advance of the vehicle, subject to the requirements and limitations hereinafter set forth. </section><section prefix="5">Whenever a driver of a vehicle approaches an oncoming vehicle within five hundred (500) feet, such driver shall use a distribution of light or composite beam, so aimed that the glaring rays are not projected into the eyes of the oncoming driver. The lowermost distribution of light or composite beam specified in paragraph (b) of subsection (3) of this section shall be deemed to avoid glare at all times, regardless of road contour and loading. </section><section prefix="6">Whenever the driver of a vehicle follows another vehicle within three hundred (300) feet to the rear, except when engaged in the act of overtaking and passing, such driver shall use a distribution of light other than the uppermost distribution of light specified in paragraph (a) of subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">Headlamps arranged to provide a single distribution of light not supplemented by auxiliary driving lights shall be permitted on motor vehicles manufactured and sold prior to May 30, 1939, in lieu of multiple-beam road-lighting equipment, if the single distribution of light complies with the following requirements and limitations: <section prefix="a">The headlamps shall be so aimed that when the vehicle is not loaded none of the high intensity portion of the light shall, at a distance of twenty-five (25) feet ahead, project higher than a level of five (5) inches below the level of the center of the light from which it comes, and in no case higher than forty-two (42) inches above the level on which the vehicle stands, at a distance of seventy-five (75) feet ahead; </section><section prefix="b">The intensity shall be sufficient to reveal persons and vehicles at a distance of at least two hundred (200) feet; </section><section prefix="c">Whenever the operator of a motor vehicle approaches an oncoming vehicle within five hundred (500) feet, he shall use a distribution of light or composite beam so aimed that the glaring rays are not projected into the eyes of the oncoming driver. In no case shall the high intensity portion which is projected to the left of the prolongation of the extreme left side of the vehicle be aimed higher than the center of the lamp from which it comes at a distance of twenty-five (25) feet ahead, and in no case higher than a level of forty-two (42) inches above the level upon which the vehicle stands at a distance of seventy-five (75) feet ahead. </section></section><section prefix="8">Flashing lights are prohibited on all motor vehicles except as a means for indicating a right or left turn or for the purpose of warning the operators of other vehicles of the presence of a vehicular traffic hazard requiring the exercise of unusual care in approaching, overtaking or passing. </section><section prefix="9">The height of the headlamps, from the center of the lamp to level ground when the vehicle is unloaded, shall be between twenty-four (24) and fifty-four (54) inches. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 8. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 3; ch. 50, sec. 2; ch. 73, sec. 1; and ch. 227, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-24. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6297</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>