<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.5-271</section_number><catch_line>Inspection of books -- Records confidential -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>5-271</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every member shall have the right to inspect such books and records of an association as pertain to his loan or savings account. Otherwise, the right of inspection and examination of the books and records shall be limited: <section prefix="a">To the commissioner or the commissioner's duly authorized representatives as provided in this subtitle; </section><section prefix="b">To persons duly authorized to act for the association; and </section><section prefix="c">To any federal instrumentality or agency authorized to inspect or examine the books and records of an insured association. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise authorized by KRS 205.835, the books and records pertaining to the accounts and loans of members shall be kept confidential by the association, its directors, officers and employees, and by the commissioner and the commissioner's examiners and representatives, except where the disclosure thereof shall be compelled by a court of competent jurisdiction, and no member or any other person shall have access to the books and records or shall be furnished or shall possess a partial or complete list of the members except upon express action and authority of the board of directors. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 691, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1964. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification>KRS 289.271. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14689</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>