<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="26" order_by="26">A COURT OF JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>26A.164</section_number><catch_line>Court facility use allowance contingency fund -- Purpose -- Conditional use -- Legislative oversight. </catch_line><order_by>164</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a court facility use allowance contingency fund. The fund shall consist of money appropriated to it in the judicial branch budget by the General Assembly. Money in the fund shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year or biennium. </section><section prefix="2">The Court of Justice may agree to increase the budgeted scope of a court project or project pool authorized in a judicial branch budget bill enacted by the General Assembly, and may use the use allowance contingency fund to cover any resulting increase in the budgeted annual use allowance, if and only if: <section prefix="a">The appropriate unit of government first submits a proposal for the increase to the Court Facilities Standards Committee, and the Court Facilities Standards Committee approves the increase; </section><section prefix="b">The annual use allowance for the project or project pool, adjusted for the proposed increase in scope, would not exceed the annual use allowance specified for that project or project pool in the multiyear use allowance schedule set out in the judicial branch budget bill by more than fifteen percent (15%); and </section><section prefix="c">The requirements of KRS 26A.166 have been met. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>