<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.120</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition of facilities by cabinet -- Aid to other agencies. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may acquire or dispose by contract, purchase, lease, donation, condemnation or otherwise, airports, buildings, runways, grounds and other facilities suitable for airport purposes and the proper safeguards to flying where such acquisition or disposal shall be in the public interest. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet may make additions and improvements to such airports, or facilities and either alone or with the cooperation of others provide personnel, heat, light, water, fuel, telephone service, drainage, runways, fueling facilities, radio and navigation facilities, and other costs of operation and maintenance, including insurance, and may bear the expense of removal or change of obstructions that menace air travel. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may enter into contracts of lease for land or facilities to which title is vested in the Commonwealth with any city, or cities, county, or counties, governmental unit, political subdivision, airboard or person for the furtherance of the purposes of this chapter. All rents or revenues derived from such contracts of lease shall become the property of the cabinet to be expended by it in carrying out the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may give such advice and assistance, including financial aid, engineering and technical assistance within the limits of its resources as it deems advisable, to enable any governmental unit or board to acquire, construct, expand, maintain and operate airports or otherwise assist in the development of aeronautics within their limits. Such aid may include the exercise of the cabinet's power of eminent domain, if such usage is requested by the governmental unit or board. Where such eminent domain powers are utilized, title to acquire property may vest in the governmental unit. </section></text><history>Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 15, effective March 25, 1960. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 165-57. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1960 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>