<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="26" order_by="26">A COURT OF JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>26A.100</section_number><catch_line>Places of holding court -- Facilities to be furnished by local governmental units -- Procedure when local public facilities not available. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Circuit and the District Court shall be held in the county courthouse of each county unless otherwise ordered by the Supreme Court in which case it may be held at any other location made available by the county and owned, leased, or controlled by the county. Circuit or District Court may also be held in such other locations in the county as may be convenient and approved by the Supreme Court. </section><section prefix="2">Every county or urban-county government shall provide such reasonably available space which would not disrupt the operation of county government as necessary in the county courthouse, or in other county facilities as permitted in subsection (1) of this section, for: <section prefix="a">A courtroom or courtrooms for the Circuit and the District Court; </section><section prefix="b">Chambers for the Circuit Judge and District Judge or Judges; </section><section prefix="c">Office space for the Circuit and District Court staffs; </section><section prefix="d">Office and storage space for the circuit clerk's operations; </section><section prefix="e">Jury facilities for the Circuit and the District Court; </section><section prefix="f">Office space for other officers of the Court of Justice including pretrial release officers, court reporters, court administrators, judges' secretaries, friends of the court and commissioners; and </section><section prefix="g">Such other facilities necessary for the operation of the Circuit and the District Court as may be agreed upon by the county or urban-county government and the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section></section><section prefix="3">If all necessary facilities for the holding of Circuit or District Court, for the clerk's operations, or for the operation of the court or its ancillary functions, are not available in county facilities, every city shall, upon request of the Administrative Office of the Courts, provide such reasonably available space which would not disrupt the operation of city government as necessary in the city's facilities for the operations of Circuit or District Court, or both. The city shall be responsible for providing space for the operations listed in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">If all necessary facilities for the holding of Circuit or District Court, for the clerk's operations, or for the operation of the court or its ancillary functions, are not available in county or city facilities, every agency of state government, special district, and independent agency of local government, other than a city, may, upon the request of the Administrative Office of the Courts, provide such space as necessary in facilities owned, leased, or controlled by such organization for the operations of Circuit or District Court, or both. The agency may provide space for the operations listed in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">If all necessary facilities for the holding of Circuit or District Court, for the clerk's operations, or for the operation of the court or its ancillary functions, are not available in public facilities, private facilities may be rented, leased, purchased, or otherwise acquired, by the Administrative Office of the Courts pursuant to permission granted by the Chief Justice for such acquisition and in compliance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 45 and 56. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 7, effective November 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20889</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>