<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-100</section_number><catch_line>Investment of bank funds -- Property that may be held. </catch_line><order_by>3-100</order_by><text>A bank may: <section prefix="1">Hold personal property that has been transferred to it as collateral for the payment of any debt; </section><section prefix="2">Acquire and hold title to real estate, provided: <section prefix="a">The real estate is necessary or appropriate for the transaction of legitimate business; and </section><section prefix="b">The cost of the real estate, including furniture and fixtures, shall not exceed forty percent (40%) of the total paid-in capital, unimpaired surplus and undivided profits (determined on accrual basis). The investment may exceed the bank's forty percent (40%) limit with prior written approval of the commissioner; </section></section><section prefix="3">Acquire and hold for not longer than ten (10) years, any real estate conveyed to it in satisfaction of debts previously contracted in the course of its business, or that it may purchase under a judgment in its favor. A bank acquiring real estate in satisfaction of debts previously contracted in the course of business shall write down the acquisition at ten percent (10%) per year; </section><section prefix="4">Invest in the bonds of any federal home loan bank; </section><section prefix="5">Invest in obligations issued separately or collectively by or for federal land banks, federal intermediate credit banks and banks for cooperatives under the Act of Congress known as the Farm Credit Act of 1971, 85 Stat. 583, 12 U.S.C. sec. 2001 and amendments thereto; </section><section prefix="6">Invest, subject to the approval of the commissioner, in the capital stock or bonds or both of any domestic realty corporation organized or existing for the sole purpose of acquiring and holding title to real property used by the bank, through lease or otherwise, for the transaction of the bank's legitimate business; </section><section prefix="7">Purchase, hold, and convey the shares of any open end registered investment company registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940, or a series of the company, whose shares are registered under the Securities Act of 1933 and whose investments are limited to: <section prefix="a">Bonds or other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or those for the payment of the principal and interest on which the faith and credit of the United States is pledged; </section><section prefix="b">Stocks, bonds, or other interest-bearing or dividend-yielding obligations issued or guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest or dividend by any instrumentality presently or hereafter incorporated by authority of an Act of Congress; </section><section prefix="c">General obligation bonds or revenue bonds issued and guaranteed as to payment of principal and interest by any state, county, or municipal governments legally authorized to issue these instruments of indebtedness; </section><section prefix="d">Any other obligations in which national banking associations organized under the laws of the United States are permitted to invest in directly; </section></section><section prefix="8">Purchase and hold shares of a bank service corporation as that term is used in the Bank Service Corporation Act (12 U.S.C. sec. 1861) and any amendments thereto; </section><section prefix="9">Invest in: <section prefix="a">Bonds or other interest-bearing obligations of the United States, or those for the payment of the principal and interest on which the faith and credit of the United States is pledged; </section><section prefix="b">Stocks, bonds, or other interest-bearing or dividend-yielding obligations issued or guaranteed as to the payment of principal and interest or dividend by any instrumentality presently or hereafter incorporated by authority of an Act of Congress; </section><section prefix="c">General obligation bonds or revenue bonds issued and guaranteed as to payment of principal and interest by any state, county, or municipal governments legally authorized to issue such instruments of indebtedness; </section></section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">Invest in other real estate in the bank's generally accepted banking market. For purposes of this section, "the bank's generally accepted banking market" means the geographic banking market at the time the investment is made as defined by the Federal Reserve Bank in the Federal Reserve District in which the bank is located. The investment shall not exceed ten percent (10%) of the bank's actual paid-in capital and surplus, calculated at the time the investment is made, for each real estate investment; and </section><section prefix="b">Investment in other real estate not to exceed ten percent (10%) of the bank's actual paid-in capital and surplus, calculated at the time the investment is made, for each real estate investment, if the bank has acquired the real estate in satisfaction of a debt previously contracted and the investment is for the purpose of improving the real estate for sale. Any real estate acquired in satisfaction of a debt previously contracted and improved by the bank shall be disposed of within five (5) years of the date of acquisition, with the commissioner authorized to extend the disposition upon written request of the bank for good cause shown on a year-to-year basis not exceeding an additional five (5) years; </section></section><section prefix="11">Own or operate a discount brokerage service either through the bank or a bona fide subsidiary of the bank; </section><section prefix="12">Own or operate a travel agency either through the bank or a bona fide subsidiary of the bank; </section><section prefix="13">Invest, with the prior approval of the commissioner, in the capital stock or bonds of a trust company; and </section><section prefix="14">Own or operate a courier service, either through the bank or a bona fide subsidiary of the bank, in any county where the bank has its principal office or a branch. </section><section prefix="15">Except for real estate provided in subsection (3) of this section, acquire and hold for not more than one (1) year, or for an additional period allowed in writing by the commissioner, any assets taken as security for debts previously contracted in the ordinary course of business. </section>Investments in accordance with subsections (7) and (9) of this section are subject to KRS 286.3-280 and 286.3-290. For purposes of computing the maximum investment of a bank in bonds, notes, and other investments, book value shall be used. For deep discount bonds or zero coupon bonds, accreted book value shall be used. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 622, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 28, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 444, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 472, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 7, effective April 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 5, effective June 18, 1970. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 582. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.100. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 28, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "executive director" of financial institutions in subsection (15) of this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 10, has been changed in codification to the "commissioner" of financial institutions to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Orders 2009-535 and 2009-1086 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. (7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>