<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.090</section_number><catch_line>Place of holding fiscal court -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of each county shall hold its sessions at the county seat or at other county government centers within the county as authorized by the fiscal court. On the seventh day prior to any meeting of the fiscal court at a site other than the county seat, the clerk of the fiscal court shall, for one (1) day, publish notice of the meeting in a newspaper as provided by KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall hold a regular term each month, which shall continue until the business of the court is completed. The county judge/executive may, by an order of record, fix the dates for the commencement of the regular terms. </section><section prefix="3">The county judge/executive may call a special term of the fiscal court for the transaction of any business of which that court has jurisdiction. If a special term is necessary and the county judge/executive is unable, or refuses to act, a majority of the members of the fiscal court may call the special term. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1838, 1839. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>