<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.363</section_number><catch_line>Computer-assisted remote hunting unlawful -- Citizens with disabilities. </catch_line><order_by>363</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, "computer-assisted remote hunting" means the use of a computer or any other device, equipment, or software to remotely control the aiming and discharge of a rifle, shotgun, handgun, bow and arrow, crossbow, or any other implement to hunt or harvest wildlife in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be unlawful for any person to hunt or harvest wildlife in the Commonwealth by means of computer-assisted remote hunting. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be unlawful for any person to provide or operate a facility that allows others to engage in computer-assisted remote hunting of wildlife in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of this section shall not be construed to limit or prohibit the hunting rights or privileges provided to citizens with disabilities pursuant to KRS 150.025, the Americans with Disabilities Act, and Kentucky administrative regulations. Additionally, this section shall not be construed to prohibit a person who is physically impaired, to the degree that he or she cannot operate a device allowed for taking of game under Kentucky law, from taking game, subject to administrative regulations, with a device which is in the immediate vicinity of the permittee and which the permittee operates using remote-control technology other than the Internet. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2007</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>