<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.120</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Agriculture. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall consist of fourteen (14) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The commissioner who shall be a voting member and serve as chairman; </section><section prefix="b">The director of the agricultural experiment station who shall be a voting member and serve as vice chairman; </section><section prefix="c">Nine (9) citizens of the Commonwealth appointed by the Governor who shall serve as voting members; </section><section prefix="d">The state president of the Future Farmers of America who shall serve as a nonvoting member; </section><section prefix="e">The state president of the Young Farmers of America who shall serve as a nonvoting member; and </section><section prefix="f">The state president of the 4-H Club who shall serve as a nonvoting member. </section></section><section prefix="2">The nine (9) voting members from the state at large shall be experienced and practical farmers or agriculturalists. No more than five (5) of the nine (9) shall belong to the same political party. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the expiration of the term of each member of the board, and every four (4) years thereafter, the Governor shall appoint a successor. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall be a body corporate under the corporate name "State Board of Agriculture" and shall have the usual corporate powers. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1, effective March 25, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 37-2, 37-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11524</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>