<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.750</section_number><catch_line>Budget -- Payment of office expenses -- Purchase of liability insurance. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each Commonwealth's attorney and each county attorney shall submit a proposed budget for his office to the Prosecutors Advisory Council to be included in the total budget of the unified prosecutorial system and submitted as part of the budget of the Office of the Attorney General in accordance with KRS Chapter 48. Nothing contained herein shall be construed as limiting, restricting, or terminating the authority of local governmental units, including cities, counties, and urban counties, to provide financial support for the office of any prosecutor. </section><section prefix="2">Office expenses incurred by the Commonwealth's attorney in the performance of his duties, as required by the Kentucky Revised Statutes, shall be paid by the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Office expenses incurred by the county attorney in the performance of his duties as criminal prosecutor shall be paid by the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">Office expenses incurred by the county attorney in the performance of his duties as legal adviser to the county shall be paid by the fiscal court or by the urban-county council as required by the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="5">The Prosecutors Advisory Council, under such terms and conditions as it deems appropriate, may purchase or authorize the purchase of liability insurance on behalf of county attorneys, Commonwealth's attorneys, and their employees to protect them from malpractice or otherwise, arising in the course or scope of their official duties. The purchase of liability insurance for or by county attorneys, Commonwealth's attorneys, and their employees shall not constitute a waiver of any immunity or defense the insured may now or in the future assert under state or federal law, regulation, or rule. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. - Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 52, effective July 1, 1983. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1002</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>