<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.230</section_number><catch_line>Duties of boat marina owner. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owner of a boat marina shall cause to be kept a record of the name and address of the person or persons hiring any vessel which is designed or permitted by him to be operated as a motorboat; the identification number thereof; and the departure time and date, and the expected time of return. The record shall be preserved for at least six (6) months. </section><section prefix="2">Neither the owner of a boat marina, nor his agent or employee shall permit any motorboat or any vessel owned or leased by him to be operated as a motorboat to depart from his premises unless it shall have been provided, either by the owner or the renter, with the equipment required pursuant to KRS 235.200 and any rules and regulations made pursuant thereto, except that the operator need not have the certificate of registration in his possession. </section><section prefix="3">The certificate of registration and number for vessels leased or rented by a marina may be retained on shore by the owner of the marina or his representative at the place from which the vessel departs or returns to the possession of the livery or his representative; provided, however, the operator shall have with him a copy of the lease or rental agreement signed by the marina owner or an authorized representative of the marina and by the person leasing or renting the vessel that contains the vessel's number which appears on the certificate of number and the period of time for which the vessel is leased or rented. </section><section prefix="4">By July 15, 2000, the owner of a marina shall provide access to sewage pumpout facilities for the owners of motorboats with marine toilet facilities. For the purpose of this subsection a sewage pumpout facility means equipment designed to receive the discharge of sewage from a marine sanitation device and allow the disposal of the sewage in a manner that prevents the sewage from entering the waters of the state. To provide access to sewage pumpout facilities a marina owner may, by way of illustration and not to limit the options available to a marina owner: <section prefix="a">Build and operate pumpout facilities; </section><section prefix="b">Contract with another marina owner with pumpout facilities, if the contracting marinas are not more than eight (8) water miles apart and accessible in a way that does not require motorboats to be trailered; and </section><section prefix="c">Contract with a person licensed under KRS 211.972 to provide pumpout facility service, if the service is available during normal business hours including holidays and if the service can be provided within a reasonable time upon request by a motorboat owner. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 16, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 25, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11070</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>