<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.795</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Recreational Trails Authority -- Purpose -- Membership -- Meetings -- Land use agreements for recreational purposes -- General use permits -- Authority may hold property for public use -- Proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>795</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Agreement" means a recreational land use agreement where at least one (1) party is a governmental entity as defined in this section; </section><section prefix="b">"Government" or "governmental entities" means any government entity of the Commonwealth, including state government agency, city, county, urban-county government, consolidated local government, unified local government, or charter county; </section><section prefix="c">"Land" means land, roads, water, watercourses, private ways and buildings, structures, and machinery when attached to the realty; </section><section prefix="d">"Owner" means a private individual, corporation, or government who possesses a fee interest in the land; and </section><section prefix="e">"Recreational purpose" includes but is not limited to any of the following, or any combination thereof: hunting, fishing, rock climbing, swimming, boating, camping, picnicking, hiking, bicycling, horseback riding, pleasure driving, nature study, waterskiing, winter sports, all-terrain vehicle riding, and viewing or enjoying historical, archaeological, scenic, or scientific sites. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Recreational Trails Authority is hereby established and attached to the Office of the Secretary, Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, for the purpose of planning and implementing programs to expand tourism opportunities for off-road activities that are pertinent to nonmotorized and motorized vehicle use, including but not limited to pedestrians, bicycles, mountain bicycles, horses, all-terrain vehicles (ATVs), and off-highway vehicles (OHVs), on designated lands in Kentucky. Membership of the authority shall consist of the following: <section prefix="a">A chairman, selected from its members, to be designated by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">Membership shall include the following members: <section prefix="1">Two (2) representatives of the Kentucky Motorcycle Association, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of five (5) nominees selected by the association. The initial term of one (1) member shall expire one (1) year after the date of appointment. The initial term of the other member shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member of the League of Kentucky Sportsmen, appointed by the Governor. The initial term of this member shall expire one (1) year after the date of appointment; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member of the Kentucky Council of Area Development Districts, appointed by the Governor. The initial term of this member shall expire four (4) years after the date of appointment; </section><section prefix="4">Two (2) members selected from ATV associations, with consideration given to geographic diversity. The initial term of one (1) of these members shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment, and the initial term of the other member shall expire three (3) years after the date of appointment; </section><section prefix="5">Two (2) members representing Kentucky Farm Bureau, with consideration to the eastern and western parts of the state. The initial term of one (1) member shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment, and the initial term of the other member shall expire four (4) years after the date of appointment; and </section><section prefix="6">Two (2) members representing the coal industry, with consideration to the eastern and western parts of the state. The initial term of one (1) member shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment, and the initial term of the other member shall expire four (4) years after the date of appointment; </section></section><section prefix="c">Seven (7) additional members who shall be appointed by the Governor from the following groups: <section prefix="1">One (1) member shall be chosen from a Kentucky bicycling organization that is affiliated with either the League of American Bicyclists, the United States Cycling Federation, or the International Mountain Bicycling Association. The initial term of this member shall expire three </section></section></section><section prefix="3">years after the date of appointment; </section>2. One (1) member shall be from a Kentucky equine organization that has trail riding as its primary focus. The initial term of this member shall expire one (1) year after the date of appointment; 3. One (1) member shall be chosen from a state or national hiking or backpacking organization. The initial term of this member shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment; 4. Two (2) members shall be chosen from five (5) persons nominated in writing by the Kentucky Horse Council. The initial term of one (1) of these members shall expire four (4) years after the date of appointment, and the initial term of the other member shall expire two (2) years after the date of the appointment; 5. One (1) member shall be chosen by the Governor from the public at large. The initial term of this member shall expire three (3) years after the date of appointment; and 6. One (1) member shall be selected from among the county judges/executive of the Commonwealth. The initial term of this member shall expire two (2) years after the date of appointment; (d) Additionally, the following shall serve as members by virtue of their official positions: 1. The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; 2. The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; 3. The commissioner of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, or the commissioner's designee; 4. The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; 5. The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; and 6. The Commissioner of the Department of Agriculture, or the Commissioner's designee; and (e) Upon the expiration of the terms of the initial members described in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this subsection, the Governor shall appoint thirteen (13) members of the public in such a manner as to ensure equal representation of motorized and nonmotorized use of trails and in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (b) and (c) of this subsection. Any vacancy on the authority shall be filled by the Governor for the unexpired term. (3) (a) Each appointed member shall serve for a term of four (4) years. Sitting members shall be eligible to succeed themselves. (b) Any member may be removed from his or her appointment by the Governor for cause. (c) Appointed members shall be reimbursed for travel costs incurred in attending meetings, which shall be paid from the funds of the Kentucky Department of Travel and Tourism and in compliance with the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet's procedures for travel and reimbursement. <section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The chairman shall set the agenda, place, and time of meetings, which shall be held a minimum of two (2) times per year and conducted in accordance with the Open Meetings Act, KRS 61.805 to 61.850. </section><section prefix="b">A quorum for all meetings shall consist of seven (7) of the members. </section><section prefix="c">The chairman shall be a nonvoting member, except in cases of a tie vote, in which case, the chairman may cast the deciding vote. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">An agreement as defined in subsection (1) of this section may be entered into by any owner or owners and any governmental entities as defined in subsection (1)(b) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The agreement shall be a contractual arrangement that authorizes the public to utilize the owner's land for a recreational purpose. The allowable recreational purpose or purposes may include but are not limited to all-terrain vehicle riding, public hunting, nature conservation, biking, rock climbing, hiking, and horseback trail riding and may be limited in scope by the terms of the agreement. </section><section prefix="c">The agreement may specify that the governmental entity or entities may be responsible for the maintenance and upkeep of the land. </section><section prefix="d">The provisions of KRS 411.190 shall apply to public use of lands for recreational purposes authorized under an agreement entered into pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="e">Unless otherwise agreed by the parties, the agreement may be terminated by either party at any time for any reason if thirty (30) days' notice is given. </section></section><section prefix="6">An agreement executed pursuant to this section, or the use of land under an agreement created pursuant to this section, shall not: <section prefix="a">Create in any user any interest in the property; </section><section prefix="b">Ripen into a claim of adverse possession; </section><section prefix="c">Alter the land or status of the land to make it unsuitable for mining pursuant to KRS 350.610; or </section><section prefix="d">Cause a denial of a mining permit pursuant to KRS 350.085 or other statutes or regulations of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any political subdivision thereof. </section></section><section prefix="7">In accordance with the purpose and limitations specified in this section, the governmental entities may: <section prefix="a">Construct, develop, manage, maintain, operate, improve, renovate, finance, or otherwise provide for recreational activities and facilities on designated public lands and private lands where owners have voluntarily entered into use agreements with the authority or government; and </section><section prefix="b">Charge for a general use permit to access the lands for off-road activities as described in subsection (5) of this section that shall be valid for not less than thirty (30) days. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Kentucky Recreational Trails Authority may accept, acquire, dispose of, or hold real or personal property, and any interest therein, by deed, grant, loan, gift, devise, bequest, lease, license, easement, or transfer from any state or federal government agency, or from any person, corporation, or other entity, for the purpose of public use. </section><section prefix="9">All proceeds derived from the sale of a general use permit pursuant to subsection (7)(b) of this section, or any proceeds derived from property identified in subsection (8) of this section, shall be paid to the State Treasurer, who shall deposit the proceeds in a revolving fund to carry out the purposes of this chapter. The fund shall be administered by the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="10">The Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A in order to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. sec. 139, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 65, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 25, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 65, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1795</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>