<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.950</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>950</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No motor vehicle, except those designated under KRS 189.910 to 189.950 as emergency vehicles, shall be equipped with, nor shall any person use upon a vehicle, any siren, whistle, or bell. Any vehicle may be equipped with a theft alarm signal device which shall be so arranged that it cannot be used as an ordinary warning signal. </section><section prefix="2">No motor vehicle, except those designated under KRS 189.910 to 189.950 as emergency vehicles, shall be equipped with, nor shall any person use upon a vehicle any red or blue flashing, revolving, or oscillating light or place a red light on the front thereof. This subsection shall not apply to the use of red flashing lights on school buses or to stop lights or turn signals at the rear of any motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="3">No motor vehicle, except those designated under KRS 189.910 to 189.950 as public safety vehicles, shall be equipped with, nor shall any person use upon any vehicle any yellow flashing, revolving, or oscillating light. This subsection shall not apply to the use of yellow lights for turn signals; or to emergency flasher lights for use when warning the operators of other vehicles of the presence of a vehicular traffic requiring the exercise of unusual care in approaching, overtaking, or passing; or to vehicles operated by mail carriers while on duty; funeral escort vehicles and church buses. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who is a regular or voluntary member of any fire department furnishing fire protection for a political subdivision of the state or any person who is a regular or voluntary member of a rescue squad may equip his vehicle with red flashing, rotating, or oscillating lights and a siren, bell, or exhaust whistle if he has first been given permission, in writing, to do so by the chief of the fire department or rescue squad. He may use such lights and equipment only while proceeding to the scene of a fire or other emergency or to a location where another emergency vehicle is on emergency call in the performance of his official duties as a member of a fire department or rescue squad. </section><section prefix="5">Any constable may, upon approval of the fiscal court in the county of jurisdiction, equip vehicles used by said officer as emergency vehicles with one (1) or more flashing, rotating or oscillating blue lights, visible under normal atmospheric condition from a distance of five hundred (500) feet to the front of such vehicle, and a siren, whistle or bell, capable of emitting a sound audible under normal conditions from a distance of not less than five hundred (500) feet. This equipment shall be in addition to any other equipment required by the motor vehicle laws. Any constable authorized by the fiscal court to utilize blue lights and a siren pursuant to this section shall maintain at least the insurance described by KRS 304.39-110. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who is a paid or voluntary member of any ambulance service furnishing emergency medical services for a political subdivision of the state may equip his vehicle with red flashing, rotating, or oscillating lights and a siren, bell, or exhaust whistle if he has first been given permission, in writing, to do so by the chief or director of the ambulance service. He may use such lights and equipment only while proceeding to the scene of an emergency, a medical facility, or to a location where another emergency vehicle is on emergency call in the performance of his official duties as a member of the ambulance service. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 437, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by two 1986 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6473</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>