<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.090</section_number><catch_line>Legislative Research Commission -- Membership -- Vacancies -- Meetings -- Vote required to act -- Compensation -- Director -- Qualifications -- Personnel -- Work-related incentive program -- Notice of issue involving General Assembly member that may result in litigation against General Assembly or LRC -- Contracts -- Display of In God We Trust. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Legislative Research Commission as an independent agency in the legislative branch of state government, which is exempt from control by the executive branch and from reorganization by the Governor. The Commission shall have the duties, responsibilities, and powers assigned to it or authorized it by the General Assembly, by statute or otherwise. </section><section prefix="2">The Legislative Research Commission shall be composed of the President of the Senate, the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Speaker Pro Tempore of the House of Representatives, the majority and minority floor leaders of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the majority and minority whips of the Senate, the majority and minority whips of the House, and the majority and minority caucus chairs of the Senate and House of Representatives. Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled by the remaining members who are of the same chamber membership and political party affiliation as the person having vacated Commission membership. If the vacancy is in the membership of the House of Representatives, the successor shall be from the House, and if the vacancy is from the Senate membership of the Commission, the successor shall be from the Senate. A member elected to fill any vacancy shall hold office for the unexpired term of his or her predecessor. The President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall serve as co-chairs of the Commission. </section><section prefix="3">The Legislative Research Commission shall meet during regular and special sessions of the General Assembly, and during the intervals between sessions at such times and places as the co-chairs may determine. Meetings of the Commission shall be called by the co-chairs on their own initiative, or at the written request of any three (3) members of the Commission. Any action of the Commission shall require an affirmative roll call vote of a majority of the Commission's entire membership. For attending meetings of the Commission or any of its subcommittees whose membership consists only of members of the Commission between sessions of the General Assembly, the members of the Commission shall be paid their necessary traveling expenses and in addition thereto an amount per day equal to the per diem compensation they receive during any session. For attending meetings of interim joint committees or other Commission subcommittees, members of the Commission shall be paid an amount per day equal to that received by all other members of the committees or subcommittees who are not designated as chairs or co-chairs. </section><section prefix="4">The Commission shall appoint a director, who shall be a person who has demonstrated exemplary moral and ethical leadership while holding a significant leadership position in business, government, military service, or a nonprofit organization or charity, and who shall hold office at the pleasure of the Commission. The salary of the director shall be determined by the Commission. The Commission shall have exclusive jurisdiction over the employment of personnel necessary to effectuate the provisions of KRS 7.090 to 7.110. </section><section prefix="5">Any professional, clerical, or other employees required by any committee appointed by the General Assembly shall be provided to the committee by the Legislative Research Commission. The chair of the committee shall advise the director of the Legislative Research Commission of his or her need for personnel. In the event that the personnel required by any committee cannot be met by the staff of the Legislative Research Commission, the director shall employ personnel as necessary to meet the needs of the committee, and shall fix the rate of compensation of the employees. </section><section prefix="6">The director shall, at the discretion of the Commission and under its supervision and control, provide for the: <section prefix="a">Allocation of the work and activities of all employees of the Commission; and </section><section prefix="b">Implementation of a work-related incentive program for employees of the Commission using an employee suggestion system. Employees may be recognized and rewarded for submitting suggestions that result in the improvement of services or in the realization of financial savings by the legislative branch. When an employee suggestion has been adopted and resulted in financial savings to the legislative branch of government, the employee who submitted the suggestion may be compensated through a cash bonus in an amount that is the lesser of ten percent (10%) of the amount saved or two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500). </section></section><section prefix="7">The director shall inform the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House, and the Minority Floor Leaders of each chamber of any personnel matter or allegation of wrongdoing involving a member of the General Assembly that has the potential of leading to litigation in which the General Assembly or Legislative Research Commission may be a party. The members so informed shall keep the matter confidential. The director shall inform the members within forty-eight (48) hours of becoming aware of the allegation or situation. </section><section prefix="8">The Commission may, in effectuating the provisions of KRS 7.090 to 7.110, contract with any public or private agency or educational institution or any individual for research studies, the gathering of information, or the printing and publication of its reports. </section><section prefix="9">The Legislative Research Commission shall constitute administrative offices for the General Assembly and the director shall serve as administrative officer for the assembly when it is not otherwise in session. </section><section prefix="10">A Senate bill may be pre-filed or approved as pre-filed by an interim joint committee if it receives the affirmative votes of a majority of the Senate members of that interim joint committee. A House of Representatives bill may be pre-filed or approved as pre-filed by an interim joint committee if it receives the affirmative votes of a majority of the House members of that interim joint committee. An interim joint committee shall not pre-file a bill or approve a bill as pre-filed in any other manner. </section><section prefix="11">The President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall have the authority to approve the in-state and out-of-state per diem and expenses for members of their respective chambers. </section><section prefix="12">The Legislative Research Commission shall display the national motto "In God We Trust" directly above and behind the chairman or chairwoman in each committee room used by members of the General Assembly in the Capitol and Capitol Annex and behind the dais of the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate. The display shall be consistent with the historic and patriotic display of the national motto located directly above and behind the dais of the Speaker of the United States House of Representatives. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 6, effective March 24, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 11, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 443, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 11, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 1; and ch. 370, sec. 1, effective June 21, 1974. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1972. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1966. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective March 26, 1960. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. XII, sec. 1, effective March 29, 1956. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 9. sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1948. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 75 and 79, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>