<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="363" order_by="363">WEIGHTS, MEASURES, AND MILLERS' TOLLS </unit></structure><section_number>363.710</section_number><catch_line>Provisions for weights and measures for liquid, solid form. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Commodities in liquid form shall be sold only by liquid measure or by weight, and, except as otherwise provided in KRS 363.510 to 363.850, commodities not in liquid form shall be sold only by weight, by measure of length or area, or by count: provided, that liquid commodities may be sold by weight, and commodities not in liquid form may be sold by count only if such methods give accurate information as to the quantity of commodity sold; and provided further, that the provisions of this section shall not apply:  <section prefix="a">To commodities when sold for immediate consumption on the premises where sold,  </section><section prefix="b">To vegetables when sold by head or bunch,  </section><section prefix="c">To commodities in containers standardized by a law of this state or by federal law,  </section><section prefix="d">To commodities in package form when there exists a general consumer usage to express the quantity in some other manner,  </section><section prefix="e">To concrete aggregates, concrete mixtures, and loose solid materials such as earth, soil, gravel, crushed stone, and the like, when sold by cubic measure, or  </section><section prefix="f">To unprocessed vegetable and animal fertilizer when sold by cubic measure.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The director may issue such reasonable regulations as are necessary to assure that amounts of commodity sold are determined in accordance with good commercial practice and are so determined and represented as to be accurate and informative to all parties at interest.  </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 22. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34693</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>