<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.525</section_number><catch_line>Functions of divisions. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Tourism Services shall operate the highway welcome centers, conduct a hospitality education program for the tourism industry, coordinate the provision of mail and telephone information services to visitors, and generate sales revenue to the tourism industry of the Commonwealth through participation in trade shows and markets. </section><section prefix="2">The Division of Marketing and Advertising shall be responsible for state tourism advertising, the state matching fund tourism advertising program, the development and maintenance of a marketing and research database on tourism, market survey programs, and special studies related to the tourism industry. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner of tourism may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with provisions of KRS Chapter 13A in order to carry out the provisions of KRS 148.522 and this section. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 424, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992.  </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>