<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7049</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of development area for investment, reinvestment, development, use, and reuse pursuant to this section and KRS 65.7051 and 65.7053 -- Conditions for establishment -- Findings required.   </catch_line><order_by>7049</order_by><text>Any city or county may establish a development area pursuant to this section, KRS 65.7051, and 65.7053 to encourage investment and reinvestment in and development, use, and reuse of areas of the city or county under the following conditions: <section prefix="1">The area shall be contiguous and shall be no more than three (3) square miles; </section><section prefix="2">The establishment or expansion of the development area shall not cause the assessed value of taxable real property within all development areas and local development areas of the city or county establishing the development area to exceed twenty percent (20%) of the assessed value of all taxable real property within its jurisdiction. For the purpose of determining whether the twenty percent (20%) threshold has been met, the assessed value of taxable real property within all of the development areas and local development areas shall be valued as of the establishment date; </section><section prefix="3">The governing body of the city or county shall determine that the development area either: <section prefix="a">Has two (2) or more of the following conditions: <section prefix="1">Substantial loss of residential, commercial, or industrial activity or use; </section><section prefix="2">Forty percent (40%) or more of the households are low-income households; </section><section prefix="3">More than fifty percent (50%) of residential, commercial, or industrial structures are deteriorating or deteriorated; </section><section prefix="4">Substantial abandonment of residential, commercial, or industrial structures; </section><section prefix="5">Substantial presence of environmentally contaminated land; </section><section prefix="6">Inadequate public improvements or substantial deterioration in public infrastructure; or </section><section prefix="7">Any combination of factors that substantially impairs or arrests the growth and economic development of the city or county; impedes the provision of adequate housing; impedes the development of commercial or industrial property; or adversely affects public health, safety, or general welfare due to the development area's present condition and use; or </section></section><section prefix="b">The project is a mixed-use development: <section prefix="1">Located in a university research park; </section><section prefix="2">Located within three (3) miles of a military base that houses, deploys, or employs any combination of at least twenty-five thousand (25,000) military personnel, their families, military retirees, or civilian employees; or </section><section prefix="3">The project is a mixed-use development which includes either or both significant public storm water and sanitary sewer facilities designed to comply with a community-wide court decree mandating corrective action by the local government or an agency thereof; and </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The governing body of the city or county shall find that all of the following are true for projects meeting the requirements of paragraph (a) of subsection (3) of this section: <section prefix="a">That the development area is not reasonably expected to be developed without public assistance. This finding shall be supported by specific reasons and supporting facts, including a clear demonstration of the financial need for public assistance; and </section><section prefix="b">That the public benefits of the development area justify the public costs proposed. This finding shall be supported by specific data and figures demonstrating that the projected benefits outweigh the anticipated costs and shall take into account the positive and negative effects of investment in the development on existing businesses and residents within the community as a whole; and </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">That the area immediately surrounding the development area has not been subject to growth and development through investment by private enterprise; or </section><section prefix="2">If the area immediately surrounding the development area has been subject to growth and development through investment by private enterprise, the identification of special circumstances within the development area that would prevent its development without public assistance. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 58, effective June 26, 2009. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 5, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42364</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>