<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.130</section_number><catch_line>Federal forest reserve appropriations for county roads and schools. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All moneys paid to the state under an Act of Congress of May 23, 1908 (35 Stat. 260) as amended, and arising from any national forest reserve created in the state by the federal government, shall be paid over to the Finance and Administration Cabinet and be turned into the State Treasury. The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall keep a separate account of all funds so received. </section><section prefix="2">The treasurer of each county in which there is situated any part of a forest reserve owned by the United States shall ascertain and report to the Finance and Administration Cabinet the name and area of that part of each reserve located in his county. The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall apportion the amount received by reason of each reserve among the counties in which the reserve is located, according to the area of the reserve in each county. If a fund is received from a reserve which lies in only one (1) county, it shall all be apportioned to that county. The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall draw a warrant on the State Treasury in favor of the treasurer of each county for the amount apportioned to that county. </section><section prefix="3">The county treasurer shall place one-half (1/2) of the funds to the credit of the public roads of his county and the other half (1/2) shall be distributed among the school districts in the county according to the area of the reserve in each school district. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 362, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2007L-1 to 2007L-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1847</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>