<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-070</section_number><catch_line>"Secured person" -- Obligor's rights to recovery. </catch_line><order_by>39-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Secured person" means the owner, operator or occupant of a secured motor vehicle, and any other person or organization legally responsible for the acts or omissions of such owner, operator or occupant.  </section><section prefix="2">A reparation obligor which has paid or may become obligated to pay basic reparation benefits shall be subrogated to the extent of its obligations to all of the rights of the person suffering the injury against any person or organization other than a secured person.  </section><section prefix="3">A reparation obligor shall have the right to recover basic reparation benefits paid to or for the benefit of a person suffering the injury from the reparation obligor of a secured person as provided in this subsection, except as provided in KRS 304.39-140(3). The reparation obligor shall elect to assert its claim (i) by joining as a party in an action that may be commenced by the person suffering the injury, or (ii) to reimbursement, pursuant to KRS 304.39-030, sixty (60) days after said claim has been presented to the reparation obligor of secured persons. The right to recover basic reparation benefits paid under (ii) shall be limited to those instances established as applicable by the Kentucky Insurance Arbitration Association as provided in KRS 304.39-290.  </section><section prefix="4">Any entitlement to recovery for basic or added reparation benefits paid or to be paid by the subrogee shall in no event exceed the limits of automobile bodily injury liability coverage available to the secured party after priority of entitlement as provided in this section and KRS 304.39-140(3) has been satisfied.  </section><section prefix="5">An attorney representing a secured person in any action filed under KRS 304.39-060 shall be entitled to a reasonable attorneys' fee in the event that reparation benefits paid to said secured person by that secured person's reparation's obligor are reimbursed by any insurance carrier on behalf of a tortfeasor who is the defendant in any such action filed by the said secured person or in the event such potential "action" is settled by said potential tortfeasor's insurance carrier on his behalf prior to the filing of any such suit. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 384, sec. 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1975.</history><metadata><effective> June 17, 1978</effective><lrc-note>.This section was amended by two 1978 acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30031</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>