<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.021</section_number><catch_line>Voluntary admission to an ICF/ID -- Discharge of voluntarily admitted resident -- Release of voluntarily admitted resident upon written request.   </catch_line><order_by>021</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Minors and adult persons with an intellectual disability may be voluntarily admitted for care and treatment in an ICF/ID under the applicable provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the recommendation or approval of the interdisciplinary team of an ICF/ID, a physician may admit for care and treatment a minor with an intellectual disability upon application of a parent or guardian. Upon recommendation or approval of the interdisciplinary team of an ICF/ID, the physician may also admit an individual with an intellectual disability who applies voluntarily therefor and who, in the opinion of the physician, possesses the mental capacity to give informed consent for admission. </section><section prefix="3">Upon recommendation or approval of the interdisciplinary team of an ICF/ID, the physician shall discharge any voluntarily admitted resident whose care and treatment in the ICF/ID is determined to be no longer necessary or advisable. </section><section prefix="4">If an adult resident who has been admitted voluntarily requests his or her release in writing, or if the release of a minor resident is requested in writing by the minor's parent or guardian, the resident shall be released unless further detained under the applicable provisions of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 38, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>