<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-510</section_number><catch_line>Small Business Stationary Source Advisory Panel -- Membership -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>20-510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Small Business Stationary Source Compliance Advisory Panel, referred to hereafter as "the panel," to determine the overall effectiveness of Kentucky's Small Business Stationary Source Technical and Environmental Compliance Assistance Program. The panel shall be attached to the Energy and Environment Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The eleven (11) member panel shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members, who are not owners, or representatives of owners, of small business stationary sources, shall be selected by the Governor to represent the general public; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members, who are owners, or representatives of owners, of small business stationary sources, shall be selected by the Governor to represent small business stationary sources; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members shall be selected by the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet to represent that agency; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be selected by the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development; and </section><section prefix="e">Four (4) members who are owners, or representatives of owners of small business stationary sources, shall be selected by the Kentucky General Assembly as follows: <section prefix="1">One (1) member selected by the minority leadership and one (1) member selected by the majority leadership of the Senate, and </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member selected by the minority leadership and one (1) member selected by the majority leadership of the House of Representatives. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Members who were appointed before July 15, 1998, shall continue in office until October 30, 1998. The Governor shall then designate the members who have been appointed in accordance with subsection (2) of this section to serve initial terms as follows: <section prefix="a">Three (3) members shall serve in office for four (4) years; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members shall serve in office for three (3) years; </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall serve in office for two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) members shall serve in office for one (1) year. </section></section> When those initial terms expire, members shall serve in office for four (4) year terms. <section prefix="4">Any vacancy in an unexpired term shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment to that term. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the panel shall receive no compensation, but shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in accordance with Kentucky statutes and administrative regulations while performing official duties. </section><section prefix="6">The panel shall select one (1) of its members as chair and another as vice chair. </section><section prefix="7">Staff services for the panel shall be performed, insofar as practicable, by personnel of the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 363, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>