<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="133" order_by="133">SUPERVISION, EQUALIZATION, AND REVIEW OF ASSESSMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>133.120Appeal</section_number><catch_line>procedure.   </catch_line><order_by>120Appeal</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any taxpayer desiring to appeal an assessment on real property made by the property valuation administrator shall first request a conference with the property valuation administrator or his or her designated deputy. The conference shall be held prior to or during the inspection period provided for in KRS 133.045. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Any person receiving compensation to represent a property owner at a conference with the property valuation administrator for a real property assessment shall be: <section prefix="a">An attorney; </section><section prefix="b">A certified public accountant; </section><section prefix="c">A certified real estate broker; </section><section prefix="d">A Kentucky licensed real estate broker; </section><section prefix="e">An employee of the property owner; </section><section prefix="f">A licensed or certified Kentucky real estate appraiser; </section><section prefix="g">An appraiser who possesses a temporary practice permit or reciprocal license or certification in Kentucky to perform appraisals and whose license or certification requires him or her to conform to the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; or </section><section prefix="h">Any other individual possessing a professional appraisal designation recognized by the department. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person representing a property owner before the property valuation administrator shall present written authorization from the property owner which sets forth his or her professional capacity and shall disclose to the property valuation administrator any personal or private interests he or she may have in the matter, including any contingency fee arrangements, except that attorneys shall not be required to disclose the terms and conditions of any contingency fee arrangement. </section></section><section prefix="c">During this conference, the property valuation administrator or his or her deputy shall provide an explanation to the taxpayer of the constitutional and statutory provisions governing property tax administration, including the appeal process, as well as an explanation of the procedures followed in deriving the assessed value for the taxpayer's property. </section><section prefix="d">The property valuation administrator or his or her deputy shall keep a record of each conference which shall include but not be limited to the initial assessed value, the value claimed by the taxpayer, an explanation of any changes offered or agreed to by each party, and a brief account of the outcome of the conference. </section><section prefix="e">At the request of the taxpayer, the conference may be held by telephone. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any taxpayer still aggrieved by an assessment on real property made by the property valuation administrator after complying with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section may appeal to the board of assessment appeals. </section><section prefix="b">The taxpayer shall appeal his or her assessment by filing in person or sending a letter or other written petition to the county clerk stating the reasons for appeal, identifying the property for which the appeal is filed, and stating the taxpayer's opinion of the fair cash value of the property. </section><section prefix="c">The appeal shall be filed no later than one (1) workday following the conclusion of the inspection period provided for in KRS 133.045. </section><section prefix="d">The county clerk shall notify the department of all assessment appeals and of the date and times of the hearings. </section><section prefix="e">The board of assessment appeals may review and change any assessment made by the property valuation administrator upon recommendation of the county judge/executive, mayor of any city using the county assessment, or the superintendent of any school district in which the property is located, if the recommendation is made to the board in writing specifying the individual properties recommended for review and is made no later than one (1) work day following the conclusion of the inspection period provided for in KRS 133.045, or upon the written recommendation of the department. If the board of assessment appeals determines that the assessment should be increased, it shall give the taxpayer notice in the manner required by subsection (4) of KRS 132.450, specifying a date when the board will hear the taxpayer, if he or she so desires, in protest of an increase. </section><section prefix="f">Any real property owner who has listed his or her property with the property valuation administrator at its fair cash value may ask the county board of assessment appeals to review the assessments of real properties he or she believes to be assessed at less than fair cash value, if he or she specifies in writing the individual properties for which the review is sought and factual information upon which his or her request is based, such as comparable sales or cost data and if the request is made no later than one (1) work day following the conclusion of the inspection period provided for in KRS 133.045. </section><section prefix="g">Nothing in this section shall be construed as granting any property owner the right to request a blanket review of properties or the board the power to conduct such a review. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The board of assessment appeals shall hold a public hearing for each individual taxpayer appeal in protest of the assessment by the property valuation administrator filed in accordance with the provisions of subsection (2) of this section, and after hearing all the evidence, shall fix the assessment of the property at its fair cash value. </section><section prefix="b">The department may be present at the hearing and present any pertinent evidence as it pertains to the appeal. </section><section prefix="c">The taxpayer shall provide factual evidence to support his or her appeal. If the taxpayer fails to provide reasonable information pertaining to the value of the property requested by the property valuation administrator, the department, or any member of the board, his or her appeal shall be denied. </section><section prefix="d">This information shall include but not be limited to the physical characteristics of land and improvements, insurance policies, cost of construction, real estate sales listings and contracts, income and expense statements for commercial property, and loans or mortgages. </section><section prefix="e">The board of assessment appeals shall only hear and consider evidence which has been submitted to it in the presence of both the property valuation administrator or his or her designated deputy and the taxpayer or his or her authorized representative. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Any person receiving compensation to represent a property owner in an appeal before the board shall be: <section prefix="1">An attorney; </section><section prefix="2">A certified public accountant; </section><section prefix="3">A certified real estate broker; </section><section prefix="4">A Kentucky licensed real estate broker; </section><section prefix="5">An employee of the taxpayer; </section>6 A licensed or certified Kentucky real estate appraiser; 7. An appraiser who possesses a temporary practice permit or reciprocal license or certification in Kentucky to perform appraisals and whose license or certification requires him or her to conform to the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; or 8. Any other individual possessing a professional appraisal designation recognized by the department. </section><section prefix="b">A person representing a property owner before the county board of assessment appeals shall present a written authorization from the property owner which sets forth his or her professional capacity and shall disclose to the county board of assessment appeals any personal or private interests he or she may have in the matter, including any contingency fee arrangements, except that attorneys shall not be required to disclose the terms and conditions of any contingency fee arrangement. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall provide a written opinion justifying its action for each assessment either decreased or increased in the record of its proceedings and orders required in KRS 133.125 on forms or in a format provided or approved by the department. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall report to the property valuation administrator any real property omitted from the tax roll. The property valuation administrator shall assess the property and immediately give notice to the taxpayer in the manner required by KRS 132.450(4), specifying a date when the board of assessment appeals will hear the taxpayer, if he or she so desires, in protest of the action of the property valuation administrator. </section><section prefix="7">The board of assessment appeals shall have power to issue subpoenas, compel the attendance of witnesses, and adopt rules and regulations concerning the conduct of its business. Any member of the board shall have power to administer oaths to any witness in proceedings before the board. </section><section prefix="8">The powers of the board of assessment appeals shall be limited to those specifically granted by this section. </section><section prefix="9">No appeal shall delay the collection or payment of any taxes based upon the assessment in controversy. The taxpayer shall pay all state, county, and district taxes due on the valuation which he or she claims as true value and stated in the petition of appeal filed in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. When the valuation is finally determined upon appeal, the taxpayer shall be billed for any additional tax and interest at the tax interest rate as defined in KRS 131.010(6) from the date when the tax would have become due if no appeal had been taken. The provisions of KRS 134.015(6) shall apply to the tax bill. </section><section prefix="10">Any member of the county board of assessment appeals may be required to give evidence in support of the board's findings in any appeal from its actions to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals. Any persons aggrieved by a decision of the board, including the property valuation administrator, taxpayer, and department, may appeal the decision to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals. Any taxpayer failing to appeal to the county board of assessment appeals, or failing to appear before the board, either in person or by designated representative, shall not be eligible to appeal directly to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals. </section><section prefix="11">The county attorney shall represent the interest of the state and county in all hearings before the board of assessment appeals and on all appeals prosecuted from its decision. If the county attorney is unable to represent the state and county, he or she the fiscal court shall arrange for substitute representation. </section><section prefix="12">Taxpayers shall have the right to make audio recordings of the hearing before the county board of assessment appeals. The property valuation administrator may make similar audio recordings only if prior written notice is given to the taxpayer. The taxpayer shall be entitled to a copy of the department's recording as provided in KRS 61.874. </section><section prefix="13">The county board of assessment appeals shall physically inspect a property upon the request of the property owner or property valuation administrator. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 42, effective January 1, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 231, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 449, sec. 6, effective April 13, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 339, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 264, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 6. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 34. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1. -- Amended 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 7. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 131, secs. 16 and 32. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/14/92).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), in codifying this section the Reviser of Statutes has corrected an erroneous cross-reference that resulted from the amendment process in the enactment of 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 3. That Act and Acts ch. 449 both amend this statute and not otherwise being in conflict have been compiled together. (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44476</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>