<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">MOTOR VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190.270</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful acts -- Suspension and revocation schedule for violations.   </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is unlawful for any person to advertise for sale, to sell, to use, or to install or to have installed, any device which causes an odometer to register any mileage other than the true mileage driven. For purposes of this section, the true mileage driven is that mileage the vehicle has been driven as registered by the odometer within the manufacturer's designed tolerance.  </section><section prefix="2">It is unlawful for any person or his agent to disconnect, reset, or alter the odometer of any motor vehicle or motor home with the intent to change the number of miles indicated thereon.  </section><section prefix="3">It is unlawful for any person with the intent to defraud to operate a motor vehicle or motor home on any street or highway knowing that the odometer of such vehicle is disconnected or nonfunctional.  </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall deny, suspend or revoke the license of any person who violates or causes, aids or abets any violation of this section which denial, suspension or revocation may be in addition to, and not exclusive of, any other penalties provided for elsewhere in this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 23, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 246, secs. 2, 3, 4, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>