<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.394</section_number><catch_line>State employees' leave of absence -- Pay -- Unused military leave. </catch_line><order_by>394</order_by><text>All officers and employees of this state, or of any department or agency thereof who are members of the National Guard or of any reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States, or of the reserve corps of the United States Public Health Service, shall be entitled to leave of absence from their respective duties, without loss of time, pay, regular leave, impairment of efficiency rating, or of any other rights or benefits to which they are entitled, while in the performance of duty or training in the service of this state or of the United States under competent orders as specified in this section. In any one (1) federal fiscal year, officers or employees, while on military leave, shall be paid their salaries or compensations for a period or periods not exceeding twenty-one (21) calendar days. Any unused military leave in a federal fiscal year shall be carried over to the next year. Any unused military leave shall expire two (2) years after it has accrued. </text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22937</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>