<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14">DEPARTMENT OF STATE </unit></structure><section_number>14.105</section_number><catch_line>Acceptance of electronic signatures.   </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State may accept electronic signatures to meet the filing requirements for a: <section prefix="a">Corporation as required in KRS Chapter 271B; </section><section prefix="b">Nonprofit corporation as required in KRS Chapter 273; </section><section prefix="c">Professional service corporation as required in KRS Chapter 274; </section><section prefix="d">Limited liability company as required in KRS Chapter 275; </section><section prefix="e">Partnership as required in KRS Chapter 362; </section><section prefix="f">Partnership as required in Subchapter 1 of KRS Chapter 362; </section><section prefix="g">Limited partnership as required in Subchapter 2 of KRS Chapter 362; </section><section prefix="h">Cooperative corporations and associations as required in KRS Chapter 272 or 272A; </section><section prefix="i">Business trust as required in KRS Chapter 386 or a statutory trust under KRS Chapter 386A; </section><section prefix="j">Rural electric and rural telephone cooperative corporation as required in KRS Chapter 279; </section><section prefix="k">Unincorporated nonprofit association as required in KRS Chapter 273A; </section><section prefix="l">Assumed name filing under KRS Chapter 365; and </section><section prefix="m">Filings under KRS Chapter 14A. </section></section><section prefix="2">The electronic signature shall satisfy the requirements set forth in KRS 369.101 to 369.120. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 133, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 41, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 41, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>