<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="393" order_by="393">ESCHEATS </unit></structure><section_number>393.140</section_number><catch_line>Claim of interest in property surrendered to state. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person claiming an interest in any property paid or surrendered to the state in accordance with KRS 393.020 to 393.050 who was not actually served with notice, and who did not appear, and whose claim was not considered during the action or at the proceedings that resulted in its payment to the state, may, within five (5) years after the judgment, file his claim to the property with the department. </section><section prefix="2">Any person claiming an interest in any estate or property paid or surrendered to the state in accordance with KRS 393.060 to 393.120, that was not subsequently adjudged under the procedure set out in KRS 393.230 to have been actually abandoned, or owned by a decedent who had no heir, distributee, devisee, or other person entitled under the laws of this state relating to wills, descent, and distribution to take the legal or equitable title, may file his claim to it at any time after it was paid to this state. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 560, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 11, effective March 10, 1994; and ch. 83, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch.  239, sec. 223, effective June 16, 1966. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1614. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>