<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.076</section_number><catch_line>Probation and parole officer salary improvement program. </catch_line><order_by>076</order_by><text>The department shall establish a probation and parole officer salary improvement program consisting of the following elements: <section prefix="1">Probation and parole officer I with less than five (5) years of service shall receive no salary improvement. </section><section prefix="2">Probation and parole officer II with five (5) but less than ten (10) years of service shall receive a salary improvement of five percent (5%). </section><section prefix="3">Probation and parole officer III with ten (10) but less than fifteen (15) years of service shall receive a salary improvement of ten percent (10%). </section><section prefix="4">Probation and parole officer IV with fifteen (15) or more years of service shall receive a salary improvement of ten percent (10%) or two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500), whichever is less. </section><section prefix="5">Salary improvements under this section shall be in addition to all other increments or other salary increases authorized by law but shall only be paid if the probation and parole officer has attained a favorable work-performance rating for four (4) of the previous five (5) years. </section><section prefix="6">The service requirement shall be satisfied only by service as a Kentucky probation and parole officer. </section><section prefix="7">At the time of implementation, officers who already meet the performance rating and service time requirements shall be awarded the respective position title and salary improvement. Officers who have not yet met those requirements shall be awarded the position title and salary improvements only upon meeting the requirements. </section><section prefix="8">Probation and parole seniors, coordinators, and supervisors shall be included in the appropriate progression series level for salary improvement based upon the work performance rating and respective service time requirement attained. However, the progression series titles shall not apply to probation and parole seniors, coordinators and supervisors. </section><section prefix="9">The department shall make the administrative regulations necessary for the administration of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 23, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6791</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>