<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-505</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure of terms and conditions of health benefit plan -- Filing with department. </catch_line><order_by>17A-505</order_by><text>An insurer shall disclose in writing to a covered person and an insured or enrollee, in a manner consistent with the provisions of KRS 304.14-420 to 304.14-450, the terms and conditions of its health benefit plan and shall promptly provide the covered person and enrollee with written notification of any change in the terms and conditions prior to the effective date of the change. The insurer shall provide the required information at the time of enrollment and upon request thereafter. <section prefix="1">The information required to be disclosed under this section shall include a description of: <section prefix="a">Covered services and benefits to which the enrollee or other covered person is entitled; </section><section prefix="b">Restrictions or limitations on covered services and benefits; </section><section prefix="c">Financial responsibility of the covered person, including copayments and deductibles; </section><section prefix="d">Prior authorization and any other review requirements with respect to accessing covered services; </section><section prefix="e">Where and in what manner covered services may be obtained; </section><section prefix="f">Changes in covered services or benefits, including any addition, reduction, or elimination of specific services or benefits; </section><section prefix="g">The covered person's right to the following: <section prefix="1">A utilization review and the procedure for initiating a utilization review, if an insurer elects to provide utilization review; </section><section prefix="2">An internal appeal of a utilization review made by or on behalf of the insurer with respect to the denial, reduction, or termination of a health care benefit or the denial of payment for a health care service, and the procedure to initiate an internal appeal; and </section><section prefix="3">An external review and the procedure to initiate the external review process; </section></section><section prefix="h">Measures in place to ensure the confidentiality of the relationship between an enrollee and a health care provider; </section><section prefix="i">Other information as the commissioner shall require by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="j">A summary of the drug formulary, including, but not limited to, a listing of the most commonly used drugs, drugs requiring prior authorization, any restrictions, limitations, and procedures for authorization to obtain drugs not on the formulary and, upon request of an insured or enrollee, a complete drug formulary; and </section><section prefix="k">A statement informing the insured or enrollee that if the provider meets the insurer's enrollment criteria and is willing to meet the terms and conditions for participation, the provider has the right to become a provider for the insurer. </section></section><section prefix="2">The insurer shall file the information required under this section with the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1229, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 500, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 26, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>