<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.730</section_number><catch_line>Executive director of Commonwealth Office of Technology -- Roles and duties. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology shall be the principal adviser to the Governor and the executive cabinet on information technology policy, including policy on the acquisition and management of information technology and resources. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall carry out functions necessary for the efficient, effective, and economical administration of information technology and resources within the executive branch. Roles and duties of the executive director shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Assessing, recommending, and implementing information technology governance and organization design to include effective information technology personnel management practices; </section><section prefix="b">Integrating information technology and resources plans with agency business plans; </section><section prefix="c">Overseeing shared Commonwealth information technology resources and services; </section><section prefix="d">Performing as the focal point and representative for the Commonwealth in information technology and related areas with both the public and private sector; </section><section prefix="e">Establishing appropriate partnerships and alliances to support the effective implementation of information technology projects in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="f">Identifying information technology applications that should be statewide in scope, and assisting agencies in avoiding duplicate services; </section><section prefix="g">Establishing performance measurement and benchmarking policies and procedures; </section><section prefix="h">Preparing annual reports and plans concerning the status and result of the state's specific information technology plans and submitting these annual reports and plans to the Governor and the General Assembly; and </section><section prefix="i">Managing the Commonwealth Office of Technology and its budget. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 3, effective March 16, 2011. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 23, effective June 20, 2005. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2011 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.511 and 61.936. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39513</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>