<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.6471</section_number><catch_line>Meetings -- Required attendance for department representative -- Report -- Assignment of regulation to committee - Consideration. </catch_line><order_by>6471</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within forty-five (45) days after publication of an administrative regulation in "The Administrative Register" or within sixty (60) days of the receipt of a statement of consideration, the Education Assessment and Accountability Review Subcommittee shall meet to review the administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">The meetings shall be open to the public. </section><section prefix="3">Public notice of the time, date, and place of the subcommittee meeting shall be given in The Administrative Register. </section><section prefix="4">A representative of the Department of Education shall be present to explain the administrative regulation and to answer questions thereon. If a representative of the Department of Education is not present at the subcommittee meeting, the administrative regulation shall be deferred to the next regularly scheduled meeting of the subcommittee. </section><section prefix="5">Following the meeting and before the next regularly scheduled meeting of the Legislative Research Commission, the subcommittee shall forward to the Commission its findings, recommendations, or other comments it deems appropriate in writing. The subcommittee shall also forward to the Commission its findings, recommendations, or other comments it deems appropriate on an existing administrative regulation it has reviewed. One (1) copy shall be sent to the Department of Education. The subcommittee's findings shall be published in The Administrative Register. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">After review by the subcommittee, the Commission shall at its next regularly scheduled meeting assign the matter as appropriate to the Interim Joint Committee on Education, the Senate standing Education Committee, the House standing Education Committee, or the Senate and the House standing committees meeting jointly. </section><section prefix="b">Upon notification of the assignment by the Commission, the Education Committee shall notify the regulations compiler: <section prefix="1">Of the date, time, and place of the meeting at which it will consider the matter; or </section><section prefix="2">That it will not meet to consider the matter. </section></section></section><section prefix="7">Within thirty (30) days of the assignment, the Education Committee, when it plans to consider an administrative regulation, shall hold a public meeting during which the regulation shall be reviewed. If the thirtieth day of the assignment falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or holiday, the deadline for review shall be the workday following the Saturday, Sunday, or holiday. The committee may also review an existing administrative regulation and make a determination as provided by KRS 13A.030(2) and (3). Notice of the time, date, and place of the meeting shall be placed in the legislative calendar. </section><section prefix="8">The Department of Education shall comply with subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="9">The Education Committee shall be empowered to make the same nonbinding determinations and to exercise the same authority as the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee. </section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">Upon adjournment of the meeting at which the Education Committee has considered an administrative regulation pursuant to subsection (7) of this section, the committee shall inform the regulations compiler of its findings, recommendations, or other action taken on the administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="b">Following the meeting and before the next regularly scheduled meeting of the Commission, the committee shall forward to the Commission its findings, recommendations, or other comments it deems appropriate in writing. One (1) copy shall be sent to the Department of Education. The committee's findings shall be published in The Administrative Register. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 18, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 4, effective April 14, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3562</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>