<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.032</section_number><catch_line>Industrial revenue bond information clearinghouse. </catch_line><order_by>032</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "department" means the Department for Local Government. </section><section prefix="2">The department may, to the extent resources are available, establish an industrial revenue bond information clearinghouse to serve as a central statewide point of contact for the dissemination of information and guidance relating to the issuance and use of industrial revenue bonds by units of local government. </section><section prefix="3">The clearinghouse shall collect and disseminate information and guidance that may be adopted by units of local government seeking to issue industrial revenue bonds, including: <section prefix="a">Identification of best practices; </section><section prefix="b">Model ordinances and resolutions; </section><section prefix="c">Proper issuance procedures; </section><section prefix="d">Examples of possible uses of industrial revenue bond proceeds; and </section><section prefix="e">Other model guidelines. </section></section><section prefix="4">Information provided through the clearinghouse shall be published on a Web site that is accessible to the general public to assist private sector businesses, nonprofit organizations, and others that may benefit from the issuance of industrial revenue bonds. </section><section prefix="5">The Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Cabinet for Economic Development, and the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall assist the department, as needed, in the development of the clearinghouse, to ensure the most complete, accurate, and current information relating to the issuance and possible uses of industrial revenue bonds is available on the Web site. </section><section prefix="6">After the initial development of the clearinghouse is complete, and for as long as it is available, a link to the Web site shall be made available on the one-stop business portal established in KRS 14.250. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>