<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.560</section_number><catch_line>Appeal to Circuit Court from order of board -- How taken -- Costs. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any final order of the board refusing, revoking or suspending a license may be appealed from by the applicant or licensee, and any final order of the board granting or refusing to revoke or suspend a license may be appealed from by any citizen feeling himself aggrieved. </section><section prefix="2">The person aggrieved by a final order may file a petition in the office of the clerk of the Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">The board and the licensee or applicant shall be necessary parties to any appeals. If the appeal is from a final order refusing, revoking, or suspending a license, the board, when served with the summons, or a person as the board may designate, shall appear and defend the action of the board in refusing, revoking, or suspending the license in question. If the appeal is from a final order granting or refusing to revoke or suspend a license the burden of appearing and defending the action of the board shall be upon the licensee. </section><section prefix="4">If the appeal is from a final order of the board refusing, revoking, or suspending a license, the costs of the appeal shall be taxed against the applicant or licensee in any case. If the appeal is from a final order issuing or refusing to revoke or suspend a license, the costs shall be taxed against the citizen who, feeling himself aggrieved, has contested the final order, if the final order of the board issuing or refusing to revoke the license is sustained. If the final order is set aside with direction to the board to refuse, revoke, or suspend the license, the costs shall be taxed against the licensee. </section><section prefix="5">No final order of the board issuing a license shall become effective, and no license under that final order shall be issued, until the expiration of the appeal period contained in KRS Chapter 13B. If an appeal from a final order has been filed as provided under KRS 13B.140, the final order shall not become effective until the appeal has been finally determined by the courts. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 163, effective July 15, 1996. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-147. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11380</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>