<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any provisions of KRS 161.164 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. Any school board candidate or school board member who willfully violates any provision of KRS 161.164 shall also be disqualified from holding the office of school board member. </section><section prefix="2">Any teacher or employee of a district who willfully violates any provision of KRS 161.164 shall be ineligible for employment in the common schools for a period of five (5) years. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 161.190 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Any teacher who violates any of the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 161.210 shall be subject to a fine of fifty dollars ($50) and upon conviction his certificate shall be revoked. </section><section prefix="5">A violation of any of the provisions of KRS 161.661 or 161.690 is a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be punished by a fine of not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000). </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 87, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 1, effective June 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 24. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. IV, sec. 3. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4503-6, 4503-8, 4506b-50. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4022</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>