<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6674</section_number><catch_line>Trust and agency account to be used for enforcement of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. </catch_line><order_by>6674</order_by><text>All fees and fines collected and paid into the State Treasury shall be credited to a revolving trust and agency account and shall be used only for the administration and enforcement of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689 and the repayment of moneys borrowed from surplus trust and agency accounts of the department. The moneys in the account are hereby appropriated by the General Assembly for the purposes set forth in KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689, and shall not lapse at the close of the fiscal year. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 291, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 8, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 4, to be effective July 1, 2008, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be July 1, 2010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7062</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>