<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.052</section_number><catch_line>Powers, qualifications, and training of special investigations officers. </catch_line><order_by>052</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any officer appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 350.035(2) shall be empowered to arrest, without a warrant, any person detected by him or her to be violating the provisions of this chapter which constitute criminal offenses. </section><section prefix="2">Any officer appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 350.035(2) shall have the authority to use physical force, which he or she believes necessary, in accomplishing any lawful arrest for a criminal offense; however, deadly physical force may be used only when the officer is authorized to make an arrest, the arrest is for a felony involving the threatened use of physical force likely to cause death or serious physical injury, and the officer believes that the person to be arrested is likely to endanger human life unless arrested without delay. </section><section prefix="3">Any officer appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 350.035(2) shall meet the qualifications set forth in KRS 61.300(1), (4), and (5) and shall prior to appointment: <section prefix="a">Successfully complete not fewer than eighty (80) hours of training in a program provided by the Department of Criminal Justice Training, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and dealing comprehensively with the subjects of criminal law and the law of arrest, search, and seizure; and </section><section prefix="b">Demonstrate in written and practical examinations approved by the Department of Criminal Justice Training, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, knowledge of and proficiency in firearms safety, range firing, the moral and legal aspects of firearms use, and first aid. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 303, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32774</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>