<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-150</section_number><catch_line>Records -- Inspection -- Destruction -- Subject to Open Records Act. </catch_line><order_by>2-150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall carefully preserve in the department and in permanent form, a correct account of all his or her transactions and of all fees and moneys received by him or her by virtue of his or her office, together with all financial statements, examination reports, correspondence, filings, and documents duly received by the department. The commissioner shall hand the same over to his or her successor in office. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall keep a suitable record of all insurer certificates of authority and of all licenses issued under this code, together with all applicable suspensions and revocations and of the causes thereof. </section><section prefix="3">Unless otherwise provided by law, records of the department shall be open to the extent provided by the Kentucky Open Records Act, KRS 61.872 to 61.884: <section prefix="a">The following records shall be open: <section prefix="1">Rate and form filings and information filed in support thereof; </section><section prefix="2">Other records as provided by law; and </section><section prefix="3">All information filed by the department with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, which that association makes available; </section></section><section prefix="b">The following records shall be closed: <section prefix="1">All information received in confidence from insurance supervisory officials of other states or countries, or the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, including, but not limited to, information from the insurance regulatory information system. However, records described in this paragraph may be used by the commissioner in enforcement prosecutions and proceedings for disciplinary action, and may be disclosed to other law enforcement authorities; and </section><section prefix="2">Other records as provided by law; and </section></section><section prefix="c">When inspection of department records is denied, any person challenging the denial shall follow the procedures set forth in the Kentucky Open Records Act, KRS 61.872 to 61.884. </section></section><section prefix="4">After five (5) years, the commissioner may destroy unneeded or obsolete records and filings in the department. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall not charge a fee inconsistent with fees charged by other state agencies for copies of records requested by the public pursuant to this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 930, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 29, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 496, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 15, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16662</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>