<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.138</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of registration as pharmacy technician -- Display of registration certificate. </catch_line><order_by>138</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every pharmacy technician who wishes to renew his or her registration shall pay to the executive director of the board an annual renewal fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) and shall file with the board an application in such form and containing such information that the board reasonably determines necessary to renew the registration. Each pharmacy technician's registration shall expire on March 31 of each year. A delinquent renewal penalty fee not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) may be assessed for each renewal period the registrant fails to remove his or her registration after the expiration of the registration. </section><section prefix="2">Every pharmacy technician shall keep his or her current certificate of registration conspicuously displayed in the technician's primary place of employment. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to a current certificate of registration, each pharmacy technician shall be issued, upon renewal, a pocket registration card which shall be in the registrant's possession when the registrant is assisting in the practice of pharmacy. The pocket registration card shall be exhibited upon the request of any member, inspector, or agent of the board. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31017</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>