<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9131</section_number><catch_line>Duty to report noncompliance with KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135 -- Location and retention of required records. </catch_line><order_by>9131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any certified person shall report to the cabinet the discovery of any apparent noncompliance with any provision of KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135 or any administrative regulation promulgated thereunder by the cabinet pertaining to radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis. </section><section prefix="2">Records required by this chapter or administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135, including but not limited to records of radon measurement, mitigation, quality control program plans, calibration certifications, laboratory analysis activities, worker health and safety plans, and equipment repairs shall be retained by certificate holders, as applicable, for a minimum period of five (5) years or the length of time of any warranty or guarantee, whichever is greater. </section><section prefix="3">Any measurement or mitigation contractor applying for certification or renewal of certification shall specify, for approval by the cabinet, the location where records required under this section shall be maintained for inspection by the cabinet. This location shall be within the Commonwealth of Kentucky or within fifty (50) miles of the border of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and at the location where the certificate holder who supervises the quality control program plan is located. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 16, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>