<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-507</section_number><catch_line>Conditions under which license authorizes employee or representative to transact business -- Licensee may not hold self out as insurance agent without applicable license. </catch_line><order_by>9-507</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A license issued to a business entity under KRS 304.9-505 shall authorize an employee or representative of the business entity licensee to sell, solicit, or negotiate rental vehicle insurance without being licensed, registered, or otherwise individually identified, if all of the following are true: <section prefix="a">The employee, representative, or managing employee operates with permission from the business entity licensee; </section><section prefix="b">The business entity licensee assumes responsibility for the insurance activities of its unlicensed employees, representatives, or managing employees; </section><section prefix="c">The employee or representative operates under the supervision of a managing employee who is licensed as a rental vehicle agent and who shall be available at all times for consultation for and adequate supervision of the business locations registered with the commissioner during the sale, solicitation, or negotiation of rental vehicle insurance. However, a managing employee need not be present at each business location registered with the commissioner; </section><section prefix="d">The business entity maintains an adequate number of managing employees available for consultation and supervision for the employees or representatives offering insurance products; </section><section prefix="e">The employee, representative, or managing employee has been instructed by the rental vehicle agent with respect to the consumer disclosures that are required under KRS 304.9-509 prior to the sale of the rental vehicle insurance; </section><section prefix="f">The employee or representative is not primarily compensated based on the amount of insurance sold by the employee or representative; and </section><section prefix="g">The business location is registered with the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">A licensee shall not advertise, represent, or otherwise hold out the licensee or any employee or representative of the licensee as a licensed insurance agent under another section of this subtitle, unless the entity or individual actually holds the applicable license. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch 24, sec. 1082, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 83, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 83, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16965</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>