<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.460</section_number><catch_line>Procedure when no map filed or map incorrect. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the operator, superintendent, or mine manager of any mine fails to furnish to the commissioner any map required by KRS 352.450 and 352.480, the commissioner may cause a correct survey and map of the mine or extensions thereof to be made at the expense of the owner, lessee, or operator of the mine, and the cost of the map shall be recoverable from the owner, lessee, or operator in the same manner as debts are recoverable by law. </section><section prefix="2">If at any time the commissioner has reason to believe that any map furnished under KRS 352.450 and 352.480 is materially incorrect, so that it will not serve the purpose for which it was intended, he may have a survey and map made or corrected, and the expense of making the survey, map, or correction shall be paid by the owner, lessee, or operator of the mine, or recovered in the same manner as debts are recoverable by law; but if the map furnished by the operator or superintendent is found to be correct, the expense of the survey and drafting of the map shall be paid by the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 28, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 29, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 41. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-43. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33027</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>