<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1440</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful possession of ephedrine-based products -- AOC to provide Office of Drug Control Policy with updated information on certain drug offenders -- Convicting court to inform defendant of restrictions.   </catch_line><order_by>1440</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding KRS 218A.1446, it shall be unlawful for a person convicted after July 12, 2013, of any offense in this chapter relating to methamphetamine or any offense in KRS Chapter 250 or 514 relating to anhydrous ammonia to possess or attempt to possess any compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, phenylpropanolamine, their salts or optical isomers, or salts of optical isomers until ten (10) years have elapsed from the date the person was convicted, unless the offense was a violation of KRS 218A.1432, in which case the prohibition shall be permanent. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding KRS 218A.1446, it shall be unlawful for a person convicted prior to July 12, 2013, of any offense in this chapter relating to methamphetamine or any offense in KRS Chapter 250 or 514 relating to anhydrous ammonia to possess or attempt to possess any compound, mixture, or preparation containing ephedrine, pseudoephedrine, phenylpropanolamine, their salts or optical isomers, or salts of optical isomers without a prescription until ten (10) years have elapsed from the date the person was convicted, unless the offense was a violation of KRS 218A.1432, in which case the prohibition shall be permanent. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall report monthly to the Office of Drug Control Policy for utilization in the electronic logging or recordkeeping mechanism required under KRS 218A.1446 the conviction of any person for any offense in this chapter relating to methamphetamine or any offense in KRS Chapter 250 or 514 relating to anyhydrous ammonia, as well as the vacating, reversing, or overruling of any previously reported conviction. The information reported shall include: <section prefix="a">The defendant's name; </section><section prefix="b">The defendant's date of birth; </section><section prefix="c">The defendant's address; </section><section prefix="d">The defendant's identification number on a government-issued photographic identification document if available in the defendant's records readily available to the circuit clerk; </section><section prefix="e">Any offense or offenses specified in subsection (1) of this section for which the defendant was convicted; </section><section prefix="f">The defendant's date of conviction; and </section><section prefix="g">The defendant's sentence or, if applicable, that the conviction was reversed, overruled, or vacated. </section></section><section prefix="3">A court convicting a defendant of an offense triggering the prohibition established in subsection (1) of this section shall inform the defendant of the restrictions contained in this section. Failure of a court to provide the information in accordance with this subsection shall not affect the validity of the prohibition. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 4, effective March 19, 2013. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> March 19, 2013</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41676</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>