<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.335</section_number><catch_line>Diabetes educator license -- Requirements -- Renewal -- Issuance of license before July 1, 2014 -- Application for licensure before May 1, 2014.   </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure as a diabetes educator shall: <section prefix="a">File a written application on forms provided by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Provide evidence to the board showing successful completion of one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">A board-approved course in diabetes education with demonstrable experience in the care of people with diabetes under supervision that meets requirements specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="2">The credentialing program of the American Association of Diabetes Educators or the National Certification Board for Diabetes Educators; or </section><section prefix="3">An equivalent credentialing program as determined by the board; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Pay licensing amounts as promulgated by the board through administrative regulation, with the following restrictions: <section prefix="1">Initial licensing shall not exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section><section prefix="2">Annual renewal shall not exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section><section prefix="3">Biennial renewal shall not exceed two hundred dollars ($200); </section><section prefix="4">Late renewal shall not exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150); and </section><section prefix="5">The reinstatement fee shall not exceed two hundred twenty-five dollars ($225). </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Licenses or permits shall be renewed annually or biennially if the board requires biennial license renewal by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="b">Licenses or permits not renewed within thirty (30) days after the renewal date shall pay a late penalty as promulgated by the board in administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="c">Licenses or permits not renewed within ninety (90) days of the renewal date shall lapse and may only be reinstated with payment of a reinstatement fee and initial licensing amount as promulgated by the board in administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="d">An apprentice diabetes educator shall not carry a permit for more than five (5) years without becoming licensed. </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2) of this section, prior to July 1, 2014, a person who the board finds to have successfully achieved a core body of knowledge and skills in the biological and social sciences, communication, counseling, and education, by training or instruction, as well as experience in the care of people with diabetes under supervision that meets the requirements specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, may be issued an initial license by the board upon payment of an initial licensing fee, completion of a written application on forms provided by the board, and submission of any other information requested by the board. </section><section prefix="4">Until May 1, 2014, notwithstanding subsection (1) of this section, individuals who have practiced diabetes education for a minimum of one thousand (1,000) hours per year for the past three (3) years, but are not currently credentialed by the American Association of Diabetes Educators as a board-certified advanced diabetes manager or by the National Certification Board for Diabetes Educators as a certified diabetes educator, may apply to the board for licensure as a diabetes educator by submitting the initial licensure fee and proof of employment, in order to continue to practice diabetes education, as defined by KRS 309.325(2). </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>. (6/8/2011).   Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal numbering of this statute from the way it appeared in 2011 Ky. Acts ch.  87, sec.  6, in order to correct a manifest clerical or typographical error. An internal reference was also changed to correspond to the new numbering system, but the words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42416</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>