<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.090</section_number><catch_line>Licensed health care practitioners and other professions not to be limited or restricted by KRS Chapter 319B.   </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text>Nothing in this chapter or in the administrative regulations promulgated by the board pursuant to this chapter shall be interpreted to limit or restrict: <section prefix="1">A licensed health care practitioner or provider from engaging in the full scope of practice authorized by the license for that person's profession, training, or services; </section><section prefix="2">A person licensed as a physical therapist under KRS Chapter 327 or as an occupational therapist under KRS Chapter 319A from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training; </section><section prefix="3">A person licensed as an athletic trainer under KRS Chapter 311 from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training; </section><section prefix="4">A person licensed as a physician under KRS Chapter 311 from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training; </section><section prefix="5">A person licensed as a chiropractor under KRS Chapter 312 from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training; </section><section prefix="6">A person licensed as a pharmacist under KRS Chapter 315 from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training; </section><section prefix="7">A person certified as a therapeutic shoe fitter by a nationally recognized board from engaging in that person's profession pursuant to his or her education and training and within that person's scope of practice as defined by the certifying board; </section><section prefix="8">Individuals acting under the supervision and control of a licensed pharmacist or pharmacy from measuring, fitting, or adjusting any noncustom fabricated and fitted device including but not limited to over-the-counter devices, so long as such individual does not create a cast, mold, or scan of a part of the human body for the purpose of constructing a medical device to treat a patient's medical condition, and so long as such individual meets one (1) of the following criteria for the device: <section prefix="a">Documented training from a manufacturer or training from a licensed or certified orthotist, prosthetist, or pedorthist; </section><section prefix="b">Certification or registration as a fitter of orthotic, prosthetic, or pedorthic devices from a nationally recognized board or association such as the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), the National Community Pharmacists Association (NCPA), or the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC); or </section><section prefix="c">Direct supervision by a trained and experienced, or certified, or registered, fitter of orthotic, prosthetic, or pedorthic devices; or </section></section><section prefix="9">Individuals acting under the supervision and control of a licensed pharmacist or pharmacy from measuring, fitting, or adjusting any noncustom fabricated and fitted pedorthic devices including but not limited to diabetic shoes, so long as the individual meets the criteria of either subsection (8)(a) or (8)(b) of this section, and so long as the individual does not create a cast, mold, or scan of a part of the human body for the purpose of constructing a medical device to treat a patient's medical problem. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41872</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>