<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.445</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for terms used in KRS 45A.445 to 45A.460. </catch_line><order_by>445</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45A.445 to 45A.460, unless the context indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Conspicuously" shall mean written in such special or distinctive format, print, or manner that a reasonable person against whom it is to operate ought to have noticed it. </section><section prefix="2">"Confidential information" shall mean any information which is available to an employee only because of his status as an employee of the local public agency and is not a matter of public knowledge or available to the public on request. </section><section prefix="3">"Debarment" shall mean the disqualification of a person to receive invitations for bids or requests for proposals, or the award of a contract by the local public agency for a specified period of time. </section><section prefix="4">"Financial interest" shall mean: <section prefix="a">Ownership of any interest or involvement in any relationship from which, or as a result of which, a person has, within the past three (3) years, received or is presently or in the future entitled to receive more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) per year, or its equivalent; or </section><section prefix="b">Ownership of more than a ten percent (10%) interest in any business; or </section><section prefix="c">Holding a position in a business such as an officer, director, trustee, partner, employee, or the like, or holding any position of management. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Gratuity" shall mean a payment, loan, subscription, advance, deposit of money, services, or anything of more than fifty dollars ($50) value, present or promised, unless consideration of substantially equal or greater value is received. </section><section prefix="6">"Immediate family" shall mean a spouse, children, grandchildren, parents, grandparents, brothers and sisters, and such other relatives as designated by the local public agency. </section><section prefix="7">"Official responsibility" shall mean direct administrative or operating authority, whether intermediate or final, either exercisable alone or with others, either personally or through subordinates, to approve, disapprove, or otherwise direct local public agency actions. </section><section prefix="8">"Suspension" shall mean the disqualification of any person to receive invitations for bids or requests for proposals, or to be awarded a contract by a local public agency for a temporary period, pending the completion of an investigation and any legal proceedings that may ensue. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 15, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 90, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>