<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.46994</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of numbers on zero call list to national Do Not Call Registry -- Consumer education materials -- Publication of materials by telephone companies. </catch_line><order_by>46994</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of the Attorney General immediately shall request that the Federal Trade Commission include on the national Do Not Call Registry the residential numbers that were placed on the zero call list on or before June 26, 2007. If the Federal Trade Commission denies the request, then those households whose residential numbers will be purged from the zero call list shall be informed by the Office of the Attorney General on how to place their telephone number on the national Do Not Call Registry. </section><section prefix="2">Persons whose telephone numbers appear on the zero call list shall not receive telephone solicitations except in accordance with the provisions of KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999. </section><section prefix="3">Information contained in a database established for the purpose of administering the zero call list shall be used only for the purpose of implementing the zero call program in conformance with KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Public Service Commission shall produce consumer education materials that: <section prefix="a">Describe Kentucky's telemarketing laws; </section><section prefix="b">Describe the consumer's rights and responsibilities regarding the receipt of telephone solicitation; </section><section prefix="c">Explain how consumers can apply to be placed on any federal Do Not Call Registry established by the Federal Communications Commission and the Federal Trade Commission; </section><section prefix="d">Explain how to apply to be placed on company-specific and industrywide no solicitation calls list, including those lists provided by the Direct Marketing Association (DMA) and the Telephone Preference Service (TPS); and </section><section prefix="e">Describe how a consumer can file a complaint if the consumer receives calls after being placed on the Do Not Call Registry established by the Federal Communications Commission and the Federal Trade Commission. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Public Service Commission shall require that, once a year, telephone companies under the jurisdiction of the Public Service Commission shall include the customer education material or portions thereof, at the discretion of the companies, in either the billing inserts, billing messages, or in the Customer Guide pages of their telephone directories. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34984</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>