<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.605</section_number><catch_line>Annual renewal of certificates and licenses. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">All certificates issued under KRS 198B.570 shall expire on the last day of the certificate holder's birth month in the following year. The department may reduce the license fee on a pro rata basis for initial certificates issued for less than twelve (12) months. Renewed certificates shall expire on the last day of the certificate holder's birth month of each year after the date of issuance of the renewed certificate. Application for a renewal shall be upon such form as is prescribed by the commissioner, and the certificate holder shall furnish the information required by such form. </section><section prefix="b">Failure of any certificate holder to secure his or her renewal certificate within sixty (60) days after the last day of the certificate holder's birth month shall constitute sufficient cause for the commissioner to revoke his or her license. </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner may restore a certificate that has been revoked for failure to pay the renewal fee, upon the receipt of payment of all delinquent fees. </section></section><section prefix="2">A certificate holder may voluntarily surrender his or her certificate to the commissioner and thereby be relieved of the annual renewal fee. After surrendering of certificate, he or she shall not be known as a certificate holder and shall desist from the practice thereof. Within five (5) years from the time of surrender of the certificate, he or she may again qualify for a certificate without examination by the payment of the required fee. If five (5) years thereafter have lapsed, he or she shall return to the status of a new applicant. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The initial license for a fire protection sprinkler contractor shall expire on the last day of the licensee's birth month in the following year. The department may reduce the license fee on a pro rata basis for initial licenses issued for less than twelve (12) months. Renewed licenses shall expire on the last day of the licensee's birth month of each year after the date of issuance of the renewed license. Application for a renewal shall be upon such form as is prescribed by the commissioner and license holder shall furnish the information required by such form. </section><section prefix="b">Failure of any certificate holder to secure his renewal certificate within sixty (60) days after the last day of the certificate holder's birth month shall constitute sufficient cause for the commissioner to revoke his or her license. </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner may restore a license that has been revoked for failure to pay the renewal fee, upon the receipt of payment of all delinquent fees. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 282, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7035</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>