<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.150</section_number><catch_line>Extending water supply or sanitary sewer system outside city limits -- Limitation -- Consideration of installation of fire hydrants on extended lines. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city that owns or operates a water supply or sanitary sewer system may extend the system into, and furnish and sell water and provide sanitary sewers to any person within, any territory contiguous to the city, and may install within that territory necessary apparatus; provided, however, that the extension of a water supply or sanitary sewer system shall not enter into any territory served by an existing water supply or sanitary sewer district unless such district requests the extension of water or sewer services from a city. For these purposes the city or sanitation authority established by an interlocal agreement may condemn or otherwise acquire franchises, rights, and rights-of-way, as private corporations may do. </section><section prefix="2">When extending the system to any person, water district, or water association, the city may consider the installation of fire hydrants on the extended lines. The city may extend water lines which are incapable of servicing fire hydrants only if the city determines that servicing hydrants is not feasible. The determination shall include consideration of the incremental costs of adequately sized pipe and associated pumps and towers, and the benefits of real estate development, water sales, the availability of fire protection insurance, and the reduction in fire insurance premiums which may result from the installation of hydrants at specified intervals. When extending lines to a water district or water association, the determination may be made in consultation with the district or association, taking into consideration their fiscal capacity. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2741a-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26180</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>