<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.535</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of credentials -- Fees -- Reinstatement. </catch_line><order_by>535</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each credential holder shall pay to the board an annual renewal fee on or before the renewal date established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. All credentials not renewed by the renewal date each year shall expire because they were not timely renewed. </section><section prefix="2">A person who fails to renew his or her credential on or before the renewal date shall be given a sixty (60) day grace period. During the grace period, the credential holder may continue to practice and may renew the credential upon payment of the renewal fee and a late fee. </section><section prefix="3">All credentials not renewed within sixty (60) days after the renewal date shall terminate. Upon termination, the credential holder shall not be eligible to use the credential in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">After the sixty (60) day grace period, individuals with terminated credentials may reinstate their credential upon payment of the renewal fee and a reinstatement fee. </section><section prefix="5">A suspended credential shall be renewed as provided in this section; however, the credential holder shall not use the credential until the suspension has ended or has been removed by the board. </section><section prefix="6">A revoked credential may not be renewed. However, the credential holder shall pay the reinstatement and renewal fees as set forth in this section before the credential is reinstated. </section><section prefix="7">A person who fails to reinstate his or her credential within three (3) years after its termination may not have it renewed, restored, reissued, or reinstated. This person may apply for and obtain a new credential by meeting the current requirements of KRS 335.525. </section><section prefix="8">The board may require that a person applying for renewal or reinstatement of his or her credential show proof of having completed continuing education requirements. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31964</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>