<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.1947</section_number><catch_line>Statewide electronic registry for organ and tissue donations -- Collaboration among agencies -- Strategies for operation. </catch_line><order_by>1947</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Contingent upon the availability of funding, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall facilitate the establishment of a statewide electronic registry for organ and tissue donation for transplantation purposes. The cabinet may contract with a public or private nonprofit entity to perform gatekeeper functions of the registry that include but are not limited to the operation, maintenance, privacy, and security of the registry. </section><section prefix="2">An ongoing collaboration shall be established among the Transportation Cabinet, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Kentucky Circuit Court Clerks Trust for Life, the Kentucky Hospital Association, the Kentucky Medical Association, and the federally certified organ and tissue procurement organizations that operate in Kentucky to develop strategies for the operation of the registry. Strategies shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Donor designation at the time of application or renewal of a driver's license; </section><section prefix="b">Online registration as a donor; </section><section prefix="c">Removal or exit from the registry; </section><section prefix="d">Timely access to the registry by relevant parties in accordance with federal laws and regulations relating to organ and tissue donation and procurement for transplantation purposes; and </section><section prefix="e">Evaluation of the effectiveness of the registry. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 194A.750 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30445</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>