<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.320</section_number><catch_line>Regulations as to use and construction of works and improvements -- Enforcement -- Penalties and damages. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text>Where necessary in order to secure the best results from the construction, operation, and maintenance of the works and improvements of the district or construction subdistricts and to prevent their damage from misuse, the board of directors may make and enforce regulations pertaining to the use by persons and public corporations of the works and improvements of the district or construction subdistricts. Such regulations may prescribe the design, construction and use of sewers within the district or construction subdistricts and the manner in which connections to laterals, trunk sewers, intercepting sewers and to other works of the district or construction subdistricts shall be made, may prevent the unnecessary pollution of any watercourse or supply within the district or construction subdistricts and may prohibit the discharge into such sewers of any wastes deemed detrimental to the works and improvements of the district or construction subdistricts. Such regulations shall have no effect until approved by the Energy and Environment Cabinet. The board may recover by civil action from any person or public corporation violating such regulations, a sum not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each offense, together with costs. The directors may enforce by mandamus or otherwise all necessary and authorized regulations made by them, and may remove any improper construction or close any connections made improperly or in violation of the regulations. Any person or public corporation willfully failing to comply with the regulations shall be liable for damages caused by such failure and for the cost of renewing any construction damaged or destroyed. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 333, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(2). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 35. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 29. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-33. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9803</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>