<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.065</section_number><catch_line>Establishing voting places for precincts -- Change -- Expense -- Authority to designate as voting places buildings constructed with tax revenues -- Voter accessibility -- Immediate telephone accessibility. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county board of elections shall, not later than September 20 of each year, establish the voting place for each precinct. If a change becomes necessary after that date, notice of change shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. If a change becomes necessary on election day, notice shall be posted at the former voting place. The expense of renting voting places, for which rent of not less than twenty dollars ($20) shall be paid, shall be paid in the same manner as other election expenses. </section><section prefix="2">The county board of elections shall have the authority to designate as voting places, without cost to the board, buildings constructed in whole or in part with tax revenues. </section><section prefix="3">The county board of elections shall designate as voting places only those places which are accessible to all eligible voters, including those with physical limitations and the elderly. </section><section prefix="4">The county board of elections shall ensure that each precinct polling place in the county has immediate access to a telephone within the polling place on the day of any election. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 2, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 23, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 394 and 416 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27364</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>