<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.313</section_number><catch_line>Articles of dissolution.   </catch_line><order_by>313</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At any time after dissolution is authorized and proceedings have not been revoked, articles of dissolution shall be delivered to the Secretary of State for filing and shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation; </section><section prefix="b">The date dissolution was authorized; </section><section prefix="c">If there are members entitled to vote thereon: <section prefix="1">The number of votes entitled to be cast on the proposal to dissolve; </section><section prefix="2">Either the total number of votes cast for and against dissolution or the total number of undisputed votes cast for dissolution and a statement that the number cast for dissolution was sufficient for approval; and </section><section prefix="3">If voting by voting groups was required, the information required by this paragraph shall be separately provided for each voting group entitled to vote separately on the plan to dissolve; </section></section><section prefix="d">If there are no members, or no members entitled to vote thereon, a statement of such fact, the date of the meeting of the board of directors at which the resolution to dissolve was adopted and a statement of the fact that such resolution received the vote of a majority of the directors in office; and </section><section prefix="e">A copy of the plan of distribution as adopted by the corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State shall immediately forward one (1) of the exact or conformed copies of the articles of dissolution to the secretary of revenue. </section><section prefix="3">A corporation shall be dissolved upon the effective date of its articles of dissolution. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 72, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 207, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 48. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44385</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>