<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.750</section_number><catch_line>Nonrenewal of limited contracts. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any teacher employed under a limited contract may be reemployed under the provisions of KRS 161.720 to 161.810 for the succeeding school year at the same salary, plus any increment or decrease as provided by the salary schedule, upon notification of the board by the superintendent of schools that the contract of the teacher is renewed. </section><section prefix="2">If the superintendent does not renew the contract he shall present written notice to the teacher that the contract will not be renewed no later than May 15 of the school year during which the contract is in effect. Upon receipt of a request by the teacher, the superintendent shall provide a written statement containing the specific, detailed, and complete statement of grounds upon which the nonrenewal of contract is based. </section><section prefix="3">The teacher shall be presumed to have accepted employment, unless he notifies the superintendent of schools in writing to the contrary on or before the fifteenth day of June, and a written contract for the succeeding year shall be executed accordingly. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 4, effective April 14, 2008. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 83, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 4. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> April 14, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3995</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>