<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.506</section_number><catch_line>Membership of commission -- Officers -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Motorcycle Advisory Commission for Highway Safety shall be composed of seven (7) members, appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) representative of the Office of Project Delivery and Preservation within the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet's Department of Highways, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) representative of the Office of Project Development within the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet's Department of Highways, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative of the Department of Kentucky State Police, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) representatives of the Kentucky Motorcycle Association, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of five (5) nominees selected by the association; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member of the Kentucky Motorcycle Safety Education Advisory Commission, appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) representative of the Kentucky Association of Highway Contractors, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of five (5) nominees selected by the association. </section></section><section prefix="2">Members of the Motorcycle Advisory Commission for Highway Safety shall serve a term of four (4) years. Sitting members shall be eligible to succeed themselves. </section><section prefix="3">Commission members shall receive no compensation for their services and shall not be compensated for expenses incurred from travel or in connection with the performance of their duties as commission members. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall elect its chair and vice chair from its membership. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall meet quarterly or upon the call of the chair or the request of the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="6">A majority of the members of the commission constitutes a quorum and the commission may make recommendations only at meetings where a quorum is present. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall keep a record of its meetings and recommendations. </section><section prefix="8">For administrative purposes, the commission shall be attached to the Office of Highway Safety within the Department of Highways. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 184, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5223</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>