<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.736</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 42.734, 42.736, and 42.738. </catch_line><order_by>736</order_by><text>As used in this section and KRS 42.734 and 42.738, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Architecture" means the design principles, physical structure, and functional organization of a land mobile radio system; </section><section prefix="2">"Frequency" means for a periodic function, the number of cycles or events per unit time that comprises the frequency spectrum used by or assigned to a wireless public safety voice or data communications system; </section><section prefix="3">"Interoperability" means: <section prefix="a">The ability of public safety agencies to be able to communicate with one another; to exchange voice or data with one another in real time; </section><section prefix="b">The ability of systems, units, or forces to provide services to and accept services from other systems, units, or forces and to use the services so exchanged to enable them to operate effectively together; and </section><section prefix="c">The condition achieved among communications-electronics systems or items of communications-electronic equipment when information or services can be exchanged directly and satisfactorily between them and their users; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Primary wireless public safety voice or data communications systems" means a regular interacting group of base, mobile, and associated control and fixed relay stations intended to provide land mobile radio voice or data communications service over a single area of operation for public safety agencies. This definition shall not include "911" telephone systems; </section><section prefix="5">"Public safety shared infrastructure" means any component that by the nature of its function or physical characteristics can be used by multiple agencies to implement or support primary wireless public safety voice or data communications systems. This shall include but not be limited to towers, equipment shelters, radios, and other electronic equipment, backbone communications networks, and communications-related software; </section><section prefix="6">"Public safety working group" means a working group whose mission is to design and develop a seamless coordinated plan for the use of the public safety frequency spectrum as regulated by the Federal Communications Commission; </section><section prefix="7">"Spectrum" means a usable radio frequency in the electromagnetic distribution; and </section><section prefix="8">"Standards" means: <section prefix="a">Engineering and technical requirements that are necessary to be employed in the design of systems, units, or forces and to use the services so exchanged to enable them to operate effectively together, including but not limited to operating frequencies, over-the-air protocols, and bandwidth; and </section><section prefix="b">Established protocol that provides a common interface. </section></section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.5162. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22097</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>