<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.450</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Missing Child Information Center. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall establish within the cabinet a "Kentucky Missing Child Information Center," which shall serve as a central repository of and clearinghouse for information about Kentucky children believed to be missing and children from other states believed to be missing in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall provide the Missing Child Information Center with computer equipment and a computer program which shall list and be capable of immediately retrieving the name and complete description of any missing Kentucky child referred to in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall design the computer program so as to accept and generate complete information on a missing child, which information shall be retrievable by the child's name and date of birth, Social Security number, fingerprint classification, any number of physical descriptions, including hair and eye color and body marks, and known associates and locations. </section><section prefix="4">Only law enforcement agencies shall be authorized to order missing child information entered into or retrieved from the missing child information center computer, except that a parent or guardian may order from the Department of Kentucky State Police information on his or her child to be entered or retrieved when another law enforcement agency has refused to enter or retrieve such missing child information. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet, through the Kentucky Missing Child Information Center, shall regularly issue flyers containing physical and situational descriptions of missing children when requested by a law enforcement agency or when determined by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="6">For purposes of this section, child shall mean any person under eighteen (18) years of age or any person certified or known to be mentally incompetent or disabled. </section><section prefix="7">A complete written report shall be issued annually by the cabinet, which report shall include statistical information on the numbers of missing children entered on the computer and located and recommendations for more accurate and timely reports and better usage of the computer. </section><section prefix="8">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations in conformance with this section which provide for the orderly receipt of missing child information and requests for retrieval of missing child information. </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Kentucky State Police and each city, county, and urban-county police department and each sheriff's office shall fingerprint children without charge on forms provided by the cabinet. The completed fingerprint forms shall be delivered to the child's parent or guardian and no copy of the fingerprint form shall be retained by the police department or sheriff's office. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 96, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1246</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>