<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.110</section_number><catch_line>Application for licensure -- Display of license -- Continuing education -- Renewal -- Inactive status -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure as an advanced imaging professional, medical imaging technologist, radiographer, radiation therapist, nuclear medicine technologist, or limited X-ray machine operator shall file an application in a format prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Licensees shall display or have available an original current license at any place of employment. It shall be unlawful for any person to display a license in an effort to misrepresent his or her qualifications. An individual who no longer meets the licensure requirements shall not display a license nor purport to have the qualifications. </section><section prefix="3">Licensees shall meet continuing education requirements. </section><section prefix="4">Licenses shall be renewed or reinstated in accordance with the requirements set out by the board. </section><section prefix="5">Licenses may be placed on inactive status for those who are not actively employed, as defined by this chapter. To reactivate an inactive license, the applicant shall submit a new application and required fee and meet all requirements for reactivation. </section><section prefix="6">The requirements of this section shall be established by the board through the promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40205</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>