<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Except as provided by paragraph (b) of this subsection, any person who violates any administrative regulation promulgated by the board under the provisions of this chapter, for the violation of which no other penalty is provided in this section, shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for the first offense; for each subsequent offense he shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or be imprisoned not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section><section prefix="b">This subsection shall not apply to administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 257.196. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 257.040 shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates KRS 257.050 shall be fined not less than two hundred dollars ($200) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for the first offense; for each subsequent offense he shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), and shall be imprisoned for not less than sixty (60) days nor more than one hundred and twenty (120) days. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates subsection (1) of KRS 257.060 shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) for the first offense; for each subsequent offense he shall be fined not less than one thousand dollars ($1,000) nor more than two thousand dollars ($2,000), and shall be imprisoned for not less than sixty (60) days nor more than one hundred and twenty (120) days. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates subsection (2) of KRS 257.060 shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 257.080 or 257.180 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 257.160 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for the first offense. For each subsequent offense, he shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or be imprisoned not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section><section prefix="8">Any person who violates any ruling of the board or who hinders any agent of the board in carrying out the duties assigned to him, or any officer who refuses to enforce the provisions of this chapter when called upon by the board to do so, or any other person who in any way attempts to hinder or obstruct the board in carrying out the provisions of this chapter shall be fined not less than two hundred dollars ($200) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 257.330 to 257.350 or the regulations made thereunder for carrying out their provisions, or who fails or refuses to comply with or intends to deceive, or who answers or represents falsely in response to any requirement of KRS 257.330 to 257.350, or who willfully interferes with the Office of State Veterinarian or their employees or agents, in the carrying out of their duties provided in KRS 257.330 to 257.350, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor. Any person who shall violate any of the provisions of KRS 257.330 to 257.350 shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in any sum not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="10">Any person, firm, or corporation who shall violate any provision of KRS 257.370 to 257.460 or any rule or regulation made under authority thereof shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and, upon conviction thereof, shall be fined in any sum not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense. </section><section prefix="11">Any person who resists, obstructs, interferes with, threatens, attempts to intimidate, or in any other manner interferes with an officer under KRS 257.490 or who willfully refuses to obey his lawful orders shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or imprisoned in the county jail not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 234, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 3; and ch. 277, sec. 4. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 79. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 2 and ch. 165, sec. 7. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2; and ch. 103, secs. 7 and 8. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 47, 47a, 63a-11(5), 63c-2, 63c-3, 63c-4, 63c-5, 63c-6, 63c-8, 63c-11, 63c-14, 1332. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12408</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>