<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.136</section_number><catch_line>Suspension or revocation of certification or denial of recertification of firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor. </catch_line><order_by>136</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Criminal Justice Training may suspend or revoke the certification of a firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor who is found, after a hearing held in conformity with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B, to have violated a statute or administrative regulation relating to the concealed deadly weapon training program. The suspension of a certification may be for a period not to exceed five (5) years, and the department may require the person whose certification is suspended to successfully complete the level of course instruction for the certification which was suspended prior to reinstating the certification. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall deny recertification to a person whose certification has been revoked pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall deny recertification to a person whose certification has been suspended for the remaining period of suspension. </section><section prefix="4">The department may temporarily suspend the certification of a firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor prior to holding a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B if the department believes that the safety of the public requires such an action. In the event that a certification is temporarily suspended prior to holding a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, the department shall hold a Chapter 13B hearing not later than thirty (30) days from the date of the temporary suspension unless the defendant requests an extension for a time certain. If the defendant requests an extension for a time certain, then the certification shall remain suspended until the conclusion of the hearing. </section><section prefix="5">A firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor who is the subject of an investigation shall be notified as required by KRS Chapter 13B and shall have, at all stages in the proceeding, the right to be represented by counsel. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11142</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>