<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="510" order_by="510">SEXUAL OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>510.155</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful use of electronic means originating or received within the Commonwealth to induce a minor to engage in sexual or other prohibited activities -- Prohibition of multiple convictions arising from single course of conduct -- Solicitation as evidence of intent.   </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly use a communications system, including computers, computer networks, computer bulletin boards, cellular telephones, or any other electronic means, for the purpose of procuring or promoting the use of a minor, or a peace officer posing as a minor if the person believes that the peace officer is a minor or is wanton or reckless in that belief, for any activity in violation of KRS 510.040, 510.050, 510.060, 510.070, 510.080, 510.090, 510.110, 529.100 where that offense involves commercial sexual activity, or 530.064(1)(a), or KRS Chapter 531. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be convicted of this offense and an offense specified in KRS 506.010, 506.030, 506.040, or 506.080 for a single course of conduct intended to consummate in the commission of the same offense with the same minor or peace officer. </section><section prefix="3">The solicitation of a minor through electronic communication under subsection (1) of this section shall be prima facie evidence of the person's intent to commit the offense, and the offense is complete at that point without regard to whether the person met or attempted to meet the minor. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall apply to electronic communications originating within or received within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="5">A violation of this section is punishable as a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 12, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 35, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42076</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>