<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.382</section_number><catch_line>Proposed nomination to National Register of Historic Places -- Notice -- Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>382</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Prior to deciding whether to nominate a district, site, building, or object to the National Register of Historic Places created by the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966, the Kentucky Historic Preservation Review Board and the Kentucky Heritage Commission shall afford persons desiring to comment on the proposed nomination the opportunity to be heard by the board, in accordance with subsection </section><section prefix="2">of this section. </section>(2) The Kentucky Heritage Commission shall give public notice of the proposed nomination of any district, site, building, or object to the National Register of Historic Places before such nomination is presented to the Kentucky Historic Preservation Review Board. The notice shall be published in the county in which the district, site, building, or object is located in accordance with KRS Chapter 424, except that the notice shall be published only one (1) time, at least thirty (30) days prior to the review board's consideration of the nomination. The notice shall state the time and place of the meeting at which the nomination is to be considered and shall indicate that any person desiring to be heard by the historic preservation review board shall be afforded the opportunity to comment on the proposed nomination. </text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>