<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.27-100</section_number><catch_line>Bond of attorney. </catch_line><order_by>27-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Concurrently with the filing of the declaration provided for in KRS 304.27-060, the attorney of a domestic reciprocal insurer shall file with the commissioner a bond in favor of this state for the benefit of all persons damaged as a result of breach by the attorney of the conditions of his or her bond as set forth in subsection (2) of this section. The bond shall be executed by the attorney and by an authorized corporate surety, and shall be subject to the commissioner's approval. </section><section prefix="2">The bond shall be in the penal sum of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), aggregate in form, conditioned that the attorney will faithfully account for all moneys and other property of the insurer coming into his or her hands, and that he or she will not withdraw or appropriate to his or her own use from the funds of the insurer, any moneys or property to which he or she is not entitled under the power of attorney. </section><section prefix="3">The bond shall provide that it is not subject to cancellation unless thirty (30) days' advance notice in writing of cancellation is given both the attorney and the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1377, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 27, sec. 10, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29618</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>