<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.080</section_number><catch_line>Personnel program for employees -- Conflict of interest provisions -- Background investigations -- Employment of specified persons by corporation prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The corporation shall establish and maintain a personnel program for its employees. The corporation may procure benefit programs or group insurance plans and shall provide a retirement plan. Employees of the corporation shall serve at the pleasure of the president who shall determine their compensation and benefits. The employees shall be subject to suspension, dismissal, reduction in pay, demotion, transfer, or other personnel action at the discretion of the president. Such personnel actions shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS Chapter 18A. The compensation of officers at the division head level and above shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 64.640. </section><section prefix="2">No officer or employee of the corporation shall have a financial interest in any vendor doing business or proposing to do business with the corporation. </section><section prefix="3">No officer or employee of the corporation with decision-making authority shall participate in any decision involving a retailer with whom the officer or employee has a financial interest of five percent (5%) or more of the total value thereof. </section><section prefix="4">No officer or employee of the corporation who leaves the employ of the corporation may represent any vendor, lottery retailer, or related entity before the corporation for a period of two (2) years following termination of employment with the corporation. </section><section prefix="5">A background investigation shall be conducted by the chief security officer of the corporation on every applicant who has reached the final selection process prior to employment by the corporation. Applicants may be fingerprinted as a condition of employment. In addition, all division directors of the corporation and employees of the corporation performing duties primarily related to security matters, prior to employment, shall be subject to a background investigation report conducted by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall be reimbursed by the corporation for the cost of investigations conducted pursuant to this section. No person who has been convicted of a felony, bookmaking or other forms of illegal gambling, or of a crime involving moral turpitude shall be employed by the corporation. Any employee of the corporation who is or has been convicted of a felony, bookmaking, or any other form of illegal gambling or of a crime involving moral turpitude shall be terminated from employment by the corporation, except that this requirement shall not be interpreted to limit the right of the corporation to terminate the employment of any employee, at will, prior to any conviction. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 162, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 8, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>