<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.152</section_number><catch_line>Emergency leave for school employees. </catch_line><order_by>152</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of this section, "school personnel" shall mean any person employed as a full-time employee in the public schools. </section><section prefix="2">Each district board of education may allow each person employed as a full-time employee in the public schools not to exceed three (3) emergency days per school year for reasons designated by the district board of education, without loss of salary to the employee and without affecting his sick leave. </section><section prefix="3">Personal leave granted under this section shall not be treated as having effect on the provisions of KRS 161.155, except that school personnel, after using the maximum days allowed in subsection (2) of this section, may, upon the recommendation of the school district superintendent and approval of the district board of education, use up to three (3) sick-leave days per school year for emergency leave according to the district board policy as established pursuant to subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Payments made by a district board of education under the provisions of this section are presumed to be for services rendered and for the benefit of the common schools and the payments do not affect the eligibility of any school district to participate in the public school funding program as established in KRS Chapter 157. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 238, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3871</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>