<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.650</section_number><catch_line>Construction of certain sections relating to educational technology -- Power of School Facilities Construction Commission. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By establishing the education technology funding program in the School Facilities Construction Commission, the General Assembly expresses its commitment to promote a partnership with the state and the local public school districts to meet the educational technology needs of Kentucky's students in a manner which will insure an equitable distribution of funds. Nothing in KRS 157.611, 157.615, 157.650 to 157.665, or 160.160 shall be construed as limiting a local school district's legal options to acquire education technology equipment and related software with state dollars if the equipment and software is approved under the master technology plan. </section><section prefix="2">The School Facilities Construction Commission is empowered to assist requesting local boards of education to issue bonds or to enter into lease agreements, or both, to finance the purchase or lease of technological equipment and related software or major renovation of existing school facilities to allow the use of educational technology. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1, effective April 3, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>April 3, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 28, (3) at 623.   See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (16) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>