<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">SPECIALISTS IN HEARING INSTRUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>334.080</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of license -- Reciprocity -- Qualifications of applicant holding master's degree in audiology. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon payment of a fee, established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation, the board shall register each applicant who satisfactorily passes the examination. Thereupon the board shall issue to the applicant a license. The license shall be effective for one (1) year. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever the board determines that another state or jurisdiction has requirements equivalent to or higher than those in effect pursuant to this chapter for practice of selling or fitting of hearing instruments, and that such state or jurisdiction has a program equivalent to or stricter than the program for determining whether applicants pursuant to this chapter are qualified to sell or fit hearing instruments, the board may issue a license to those applicants who hold current, unsuspended, and unrevoked licenses to sell or fit hearing instruments in such other state or jurisdiction upon application and successful completion of examination. No applicant for a license pursuant to this subsection shall be required to submit to or undergo any training or other procedure, other than the payment of fees and examination pursuant to KRS 334.050 to 334.070. The holder of a license issued under this subsection shall be registered in the same manner as holders of initial licenses. The fee for licenses issued under this subsection shall be the same as the fee for an initial license. Fees, grounds, and procedures for renewal, suspension, and revocation of licenses issued under this subsection shall be the same as for renewal, suspension, and revocation of initial licenses. </section><section prefix="3">Any applicant holding a master's degree in audiology licensed under KRS Chapter 334A or holding at least a master's degree from a recognized college or university and having the certification of clinical competence in audiology from the American Speech-Language-Hearing Association shall not be required to submit to or undergo any training or other procedures other than the payment of fees and successful completion of examination pursuant to KRS 334.050 to 334.070. Fees, grounds, and procedures for renewal, suspension, and revocation of license issued under this subsection shall be the same as for renewal, suspension, and revocation of initial licenses. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31874</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>