<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.856</section_number><catch_line>Annual assessment and evaluation of school  nutrition in district -- Special board meeting and public forum to discuss nutrition and physical activity in the schools -- School district to prepare and submit findings and recommendations to Board of Education. </catch_line><order_by>856</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each school food service director shall annually assess school nutrition in the district and issue a written report to parents, the local school board, and school-based decision making councils. The report shall include: <section prefix="a">An evaluation of compliance with the National School Breakfast and National School Lunch programs; </section><section prefix="b">An evaluation of the availability of contracted fast foods or foods sold through commercial vendors; </section><section prefix="c">A review of access to foods and beverages sold outside the National School Breakfast and National School Lunch programs, including vending machines, school stores, canteens, and a la carte cafeteria sales; </section><section prefix="d">A list of foods and beverages that are available to students, including the nutritional value of those foods and beverages; and </section><section prefix="e">Recommendations for improving the school nutrition environment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall develop an assessment tool that each school district may use to evaluate its physical activity environment. </section><section prefix="3">The evaluation shall be completed annually and released to the public at the time of the release of the nutrition report under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Each school board shall discuss the findings of the nutrition report and physical activity report and seek public comments during a publicly advertised special board meeting or at the next regularly scheduled board meeting following the release of the nutrition and physical activity reports. </section><section prefix="5">By January 31 of each year, the local board of education shall hold an advertised public forum to present a plan to improve school nutrition and physical activities in the school district. </section><section prefix="6">Each school district shall compile a summary of findings and recommendations and submit the summary to the Kentucky Board of Education. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3624</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>