<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">A RESPIRATORY CARE PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>314A.100</section_number><catch_line>Scope of practice. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A respiratory care practitioner may perform respiratory care procedures under medical direction with documented competency, in accordance with agency or facility guidelines and only in accordance with the prescription of a physician. The procedures shall include, but not be limited to, the assessment and therapeutic use of the following: medical gases, exclusive of general anesthesia; aerosols, humidification, environmental control systems; pharmacologic agents related to cardiopulmonary procedures, unless prohibited by the medical staff of the licensed health-care facility; mechanical or physiological ventilatory support; bronchopulmonary hygiene, maintenance of the natural airways; insertion without cutting tissues and maintenance of artificial airways; specific assessment and testing procedures such as drawing and analyzing of arterial blood gases employed in the medical measurement and monitoring of cardiac function as it relates to pulmonary pathophysiology. </section><section prefix="2">The practice of respiratory care may be performed in hospitals or in other settings where respiratory care is to be provided in accordance with a prescription of a physician. In addition, respiratory care may be provided during the transportation of a patient, or under any circumstances where an emergency necessitates respiratory care. </section><section prefix="3">The respiratory care practitioner may transcribe and implement a physician's written or verbal orders pertaining to the practice of respiratory care procedures as defined in this section. </section><section prefix="4">The respiratory care practitioner's scope of practice shall include practice standards and guidelines as developed by the American Association for Respiratory Care, or its equivalent, and as incorporated by the board through promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30974</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>