<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.554</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations -- Educational literature -- Negotiation for price of vaccines -- Report.</catch_line><order_by>554</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of the department shall implement the provisions of KRS 209.550 to 209.554 through the promulgation of administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall make educational literature that describes the risks of influenza and pneumococcal disease; the efficacy, side effects, and contraindications of these immunizations; and the recommendations from the Centers for Disease Control available to every long-term care facility. </section><section prefix="3">The department, on behalf of long-term care facilities, shall negotiate with any appropriate manufacturer of the vaccines for adult pneumococcal disease and influenza for a purchase price of the vaccines. Long-term care facilities shall be entitled to purchase the vaccines at the negotiated price for the purposes specified under KRS 209.552. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner of the department shall report by September 1, 2005, to the Governor, the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare, and the Legislative Research Commission on the number of outbreaks in long-term care facilities for each year due to influenza virus and pneumococcal disease and the number of hospitalizations of long-term care facility residents each year due to influenza virus, pneumococcal disease, and associated complications. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8208</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>