<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLI" order_by="41">LAWS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="446" order_by="446">CONSTRUCTION OF STATUTES </unit></structure><section_number>446.145</section_number><catch_line>Manner of indicating amended, created, repealed, and repealed and reenacted sections and sections not intended to be codified. </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Bills amending an existing section of the statutes shall indicate the material proposed to be deleted by brackets and by striking through the material. </section><section prefix="2">Bills amending an existing section of the statutes shall indicate new material by underlining. </section><section prefix="3">Bills creating a new section of the statutes shall begin with the phrase "A NEW SECTION OF KRS CHAPTER --- IS CREATED TO READ AS FOLLOWS:" and shall contain underlining of all material in the section. </section><section prefix="4">Bills repealing a section of the statutes shall list the statute number and headnote. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Bills repealing and reenacting a section of the statutes without change from the text of that statute as it read at the time of its repeal shall begin with the phrase "KRS --- is repealed and reenacted (or "reenacted as a new section of KRS Chapter ---", if appropriate) to read as follows:" and shall not contain underlining of the reenacted text. </section><section prefix="b">Bills repealing and reenacting a section of the statutes with changes from the text of that statute as it read at the time of its repeal shall begin with the phrase "KRS --- is repealed, reenacted (or "reenacted as a new section of KRS Chapter ---", if appropriate), and amended to read as follows:", shall indicate the material proposed to be deleted by brackets and by striking through the material, and shall indicate new material by underlining. </section><section prefix="c">Bills repealing and reenacting a section of the statutes with text totally different from the text of that statute as it read at the time of its repeal or so substantially different that using the procedure set out in paragraph (b) of this subsection is impracticable shall begin with the phrase "KRS --- IS REPEALED AND REENACTED (or "REENACTED AS A NEW SECTION OF KRS CHAPTER ---", if appropriate) TO READ AS FOLLOWS:" and shall indicate the reenacted text of the statute by underlining. </section></section><section prefix="6">Sections of a bill not intended to be codified shall begin simply with the section number within the bill without any further introductory phrase, and the text of those sections shall be in normal type and not in all capitals or with underlining.  These not-to-be-codified sections shall ordinarily be placed at the end of the bill or, in a bill having multiple parts, at the end of a particular part of that bill. Unless expressly drafted in a manner indicating codification is intended or unless determined by the reviser of statutes that codification is appropriate and necessary, the following material shall not be codified, in conformity with KRS 7.131(3): <section prefix="a">Repealers and repeals of repealers; </section><section prefix="b">Appropriation provisions; </section><section prefix="c">Temporary provisions; </section><section prefix="d">Construction clauses, including severability clauses; </section><section prefix="e">A short title, if necessary, for an act that is not a distinct codifiable unit; and </section><section prefix="f">Effective date provisions. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 10, effective July 1, 1997. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19404</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>