<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.840</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Milk Handlers Advisory Board. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Milk Handlers Advisory Board shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The coordinator of the dairy section of the Animal Science Department at the University of Kentucky, College of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="b">The chair of the dairy committee of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation; </section><section prefix="c">The branch manager of the Milk Safety Branch of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) permitted producers or permitted producer representatives; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) processors or processor representatives; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) sampler-weigher or sampler-weigher representative; and </section><section prefix="g">One (1) tester or tester representative. </section></section> The coordinator of the dairy section of the Animal Science Department at the University of Kentucky, College of Agriculture shall act as chair of the board. <section prefix="2">The director, or his designated representative, shall be an ex officio member and secretary to the board. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Each permitted producer shall be appointed by the director from a list of two (2) persons nominated by the dairy committee of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation. If a permitted producer becomes chair of the dairy committee of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation during his or her term, the dairy committee shall appoint an alternate to serve the remainder of the term of the permitted producer. </section><section prefix="b">Each processor shall be appointed by the director from a list of two (2) persons nominated by the executive committee of the Dairy Products Association of Kentucky. If a processor becomes president of the Dairy Products Association of Kentucky during his or her term, the executive committee shall appoint an alternate to serve the remainder of the term of the processor. </section><section prefix="c">The sampler-weigher and tester shall be at-large appointees and shall be appointed by the director. </section></section><section prefix="4">Appointments to the board shall be for a term of three (3) years, or until their successors are appointed, except that the terms of office of the members first appointed shall be as follows: two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) members shall be appointed for two (2) years, and three (3) members shall be appointed for three (3) years. The respective terms of the first members shall be designated by the director at the time of their appointment. No appointed board member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="5">Board members not already employed by the state shall be compensated at the rate of one hundred dollars ($100) per day for board service and be reimbursed for any actual expense incurred while performing board duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 576, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 20, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 14, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>