<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="396" order_by="396">CLAIMS AGAINST DECEDENTS' ESTATES </unit></structure><section_number>396.185</section_number><catch_line>Liability of personal representative. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless otherwise provided in the contract, a personal representative is not individually liable on a contract properly entered into in his fiduciary capacity in the course of administration of the estate unless he fails to reveal his representative capacity and identify the estate in the contract. </section><section prefix="2">A personal representative is individually liable for obligations arising from ownership or control of the estate or for torts committed in the course of administration of the estate only if he is personally at fault. </section><section prefix="3">Claims based on contracts entered into by a personal representative in his fiduciary capacity, on obligations arising from ownership or control of the estate or on torts committed in the course of estate administration may be asserted against the estate by proceeding against the personal representative in his fiduciary capacity, whether or not the personal representative is individually liable therefor. </section><section prefix="4">Issues of liability as between the estate and the personal representative individually may be determined in a proceeding for accounting, surcharge or indemnification or other appropriate proceeding. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36440</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>