<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.072</section_number><catch_line>Motorcycle awareness signs. </catch_line><order_by>072</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Local government" means: <section prefix="1">Any city organized and governed under KRS Chapter 83 or 83A; </section><section prefix="2">Any urban-county government organized and governed under KRS Chapter 67A; </section><section prefix="3">Any consolidated local government organized and governed under KRS Chapter 67C; and </section><section prefix="4">All of Kentucky's one hundred twenty (120) counties; and </section></section><section prefix="b">"Motorcycle awareness signs" means signs that increase the awareness of the traveling public to the possible presence of motorcycles and which are erected in the highway right-of-way of any highway that is part of the state primary road system established under KRS 177.020. </section></section><section prefix="2">All statutes to the contrary notwithstanding, the cabinet shall permit any local government, subject to the provisions of subsection (4) of this section, to erect motorcycle awareness signs. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may, in addition to authorizing a local government to erect motorcycle awareness signs, also erect motorcycle awareness signs. </section><section prefix="4">Any local government wanting to erect motorcycle awareness signs shall submit a written request to the cabinet. The request shall identify the routes and the specific location on the routes where motorcycle awareness signs will be erected. If the cabinet determines that any location identified in the request would pose a traffic safety hazard, the cabinet shall identify an alternative location for the placement of the motorcycle awareness signs. </section><section prefix="5">The signs authorized to be erected under this section shall consist of two (2) signs. The upper sign shall be diamond shaped with a motorcyclist pictured on the sign. A second rectangular sign shall be placed directly below the diamond shaped sign and contain the words "Share the Road." The signs shall conform with the standards established in the "Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices" published by the United States Department of Transportation, Federal Highway Administration. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5254</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>