<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.560</section_number><catch_line>Mandatory revocation or denial of license -- Causes -- Period of revocation or denial -- Prohibition against reductions of certain revocations or denials -- Limited exception relating to enrollment in alcohol or substance abuse education or treatment programs.   </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall forthwith revoke the license of any operator of a motor vehicle upon receiving record of his or her: <section prefix="a">Conviction of any of the following offenses: <section prefix="1">Murder or manslaughter resulting from the operation of a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">Driving a vehicle which is not a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or any other substance which may impair one's driving ability; </section><section prefix="3">Perjury or the making of a false affidavit under KRS 186.400 to 186.640 or any law requiring the registration of motor vehicles or regulating their operation on highways; </section><section prefix="4">Any felony in the commission of which a motor vehicle is used; </section><section prefix="5">Conviction or forfeiture of bail upon three (3) charges of reckless driving within the preceding twelve (12) months; </section><section prefix="6">Conviction of driving a motor vehicle involved in an accident and failing to stop and disclose his identity at the scene of the accident; </section><section prefix="7">Conviction of theft of a motor vehicle or any of its parts, including the conviction of any person under the age of eighteen (18) years; </section><section prefix="8">Failure to have in full force and effect the security required by Subtitle 39 of KRS Chapter 304 upon conviction of a second and each subsequent offense within any five (5) year period; </section><section prefix="9">Conviction for fraudulent use of a driver's license or use of a fraudulent driver's license to purchase or attempt to purchase alcoholic beverages, as defined in KRS 241.010, in violation of KRS 244.085(5); and </section><section prefix="10">Conviction of operating a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped without an operator's license as required by KRS 186.410; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Being found incompetent to stand trial under KRS Chapter 504. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the person convicted of any offense named in subsection (1) of this section or who is found incompetent to stand trial is not the holder of a license, the cabinet shall deny the person so convicted a license for the same period of time as though he had possessed a license which had been revoked. If through an inadvertence the defendant should be issued a license, the cabinet shall forthwith cancel it. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet, upon receiving a record of the conviction of any person upon a charge of operating a motor vehicle while the license of that person is denied, or suspended, or revoked, or while his privilege to operate a motor vehicle is withdrawn, shall immediately extend the period of the first denial, suspension, revocation, or withdrawal for an additional like period. </section><section prefix="4">The revocation or denial of a license or the withdrawal of the privilege of operating a motor vehicle for a violation of subsection (1)(a)1. of this section shall be for a period of not less than five (5) years. Revocations or denials under this section shall not be subject to any lessening of penalties authorized under any other provision of this section or any other statute. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in subsections (3), (4), (8), and (9) of this section, in all other cases, the revocation or denial of a license or the withdrawal of the privilege of operating a motor vehicle under this section shall be for a period of six (6) months, except that if the same person has had one (1) previous conviction of any offense enumerated in subsection (1) of this section, regardless of whether the person's license was revoked because of the previous conviction, the period of the revocation, denial, or withdrawal shall be one (1) year. If the person has had more than one (1) previous conviction of the offenses considered collectively as enumerated in subsection (1) of this section, regardless of whether the person's license was revoked for any previous conviction, the period of revocation, denial, or withdrawal shall be for not less than two (2) years. If the cabinet, upon receipt of the written recommendation of the court in which any person has been convicted of violating KRS 189.520(1) or 244.085(5) as relates to instances in which a driver's license or fraudulent driver's license was the identification used or attempted to be used in the commission of the offense, who has had no previous conviction of said offense, the person's operator's license shall not be revoked, but the person's operator's license shall be restricted to any terms and conditions the secretary in his discretion may require, provided the person has enrolled in an alcohol or substance abuse education or treatment program as the cabinet shall require. If the person fails to satisfactorily complete the education or treatment program or violates the restrictions on his operator's license, the cabinet shall immediately revoke his operator's license for a period of six (6) months. </section><section prefix="6">In order to secure the reinstatement of a license to operate a motor vehicle or motorcycle restored following a period of suspension or revocation pursuant to KRS 189A.070, 189A.080, and 189A.090, the person whose license is suspended or revoked shall comply with the fees and other procedures of the Transportation Cabinet with regard to the reinstatement of suspended or revoked licenses. </section><section prefix="7">The cabinet shall revoke the license of any operator of a motor vehicle upon receiving notification that the person is under age eighteen (18) and has dropped out of school or is academically deficient, as defined in KRS 159.051(1). </section><section prefix="8">A person under the age of eighteen (18) who is convicted of the offenses of subsections (1) or (3) of this section, except for subsection (1)(a)8. or 9. of this section, shall have his license revoked until he reaches the age of eighteen (18) or shall have his license revoked as provided in this section, whichever penalty will result in the longer period of revocation. </section><section prefix="9">A revocation or denial of a license or the withdrawal of the privilege of operating a motor vehicle under this section due to a person being found incompetent to stand trial shall extend until the person is found competent to stand trial or the criminal case is dismissed. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, secs. 26 and 29, effective October 1, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 8, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Acts Ch. 15, Sec. 20, effective July 1, 1991. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 434, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 443, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1985; and ch. 165, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1985. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-49. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). In codifying 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, (this statute), a reference in subsection (8) to "subsection (1)(a)8. or 8. of this section" has been changed to "subsection (1)(a)8. or 9. of this section." The internal numbering of subsection (1) of this statute was modified by that Act, but the reference in subsection (8) of this statute was incorrectly modified to conform with that renumbering. The Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h).</lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41813</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>