<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.600</section_number><catch_line>Court, upon petition, may extend district -- Amend plan for reclamation -- Appoint appraisers -- Notice. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board, or the owners of property adjacent to the district who desire to have their property made a part of the district, may file a petition with the clerk of the fiscal court organizing the district praying the court to amend its former order organizing the district, by correcting the plan, striking out or adding the names of owners or property, or by any other means. If the petition asks permission to change the plan for reclamation or that the boundary lines be changed, it shall also ask for three (3) appraisers to be appointed as provided in KRS 268.260 for the original proceedings.  </section><section prefix="2">As soon as the petition is filed, the clerk of the fiscal court shall give notice as other notice is given, and substantially in the following form:   ".........................................................................Court. </section>Commonwealth of Kentucky. To ....................................., Greeting:   "(Name of owner of land)   "To the owners and all persons interested in the property in and adjacent to (drainage), (levee), (reclamation) district No. ................. of .................. County (Counties), Kentucky.   "(Here insert the names of all persons who are shown in the petition to own land sought to be annexed to the district).   "You are hereby notified that (here state by whom petition was filed) has filed in the office of the clerk of the ............................. court a petition praying the court for permission to (here insert the prayer of the said petition) (and if it contains a prayer to annex land, describe the land), and unless you show cause to the contrary on or before the ........ day of .................., 19......, the prayer of this petition may be granted.  "This............ day of..............., 19........        .........................................................Clerk." </text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 254, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380b-46. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12984</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>