<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.050</section_number><catch_line>Notice of administrative hearing. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any administrative hearing, the agency shall conduct the hearing as soon as practicable and shall give notice of the hearing to the parties not less than twenty (20) days in advance of the date set for the hearing, unless otherwise required by federal law. An agency shall make reasonable effort to schedule a hearing on a date that is convenient to the parties involved. </section><section prefix="2">The notice required by subsection (1) of this section shall be served on the parties by certified mail, return receipt requested, sent to the last known address of the parties, or by personal service, with the exception of notices of Personnel Board hearings and all board orders which may be served by first-class mail. Service by certified mail shall be complete upon the date on which the agency receives the return receipt or the returned notice. </section><section prefix="3">The notice required by this section shall be in plain language and shall include: <section prefix="a">A statement of the date, time, place, and nature of the hearing; </section><section prefix="b">The name, official title, and mailing address of the hearing officer; </section><section prefix="c">The names, official titles, mailing addresses, and, if available, telephone numbers of all parties to the hearing, including the counsel or representative of the agency; </section><section prefix="d">A statement of the factual basis for the agency action along with a statement of issues involved, in sufficient detail to give the parties reasonable opportunity to prepare evidence and argument; </section><section prefix="e">A reference to the specific statutes and administrative regulations which relate to the issues involved and the procedure to be followed in the hearing; </section><section prefix="f">A statement advising the person of his right to legal counsel; </section><section prefix="g">A statement of the parties' right to examine, at least five (5) days prior to the hearing, a list of witnesses the parties expect to call at the hearing, any evidence to be used at the hearing and any exculpatory information in the agency's possession; and </section><section prefix="h">A statement advising that any party who fails to attend or participate as required at any stage of the administrative hearing process may be held in default under this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="4">If an agency decides not to conduct an administrative hearing in response to a petition, the agency shall notify the petitioner of its decision in writing, with a brief statement of the agency's reasons and any administrative review available to the petitioner. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 425, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>