<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.542</section_number><catch_line>Auxiliary county police force. </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in counties containing a consolidated local government or city of the first class, or counties containing an urban-county government, the fiscal court of any county in which there is an established county police force pursuant to KRS 70.540, may provide for the establishment or abolishment of an auxiliary county police force to perform duties within the county upon such terms and conditions as the fiscal court deems necessary and proper. The fiscal court shall prescribe the number of members comprising such auxiliary county police force, and prescribe rules and regulations that shall govern the powers and duties of the members of such auxiliary county police force, unless otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A member of an auxiliary county police force shall: <section prefix="a">Be appointed by the county judge/executive and serve at his or her pleasure; </section><section prefix="b">Be answerable and under the direction of the county judge/executive, except when the county judge/executive delegates such authority to the chief officer of the county police force; </section><section prefix="c">Not receive any compensation or benefits for his or her time or service, except that the fiscal court may provide for the payment of any reasonable and necessary expenses incurred by a member of the auxiliary county police force in the conduct of his or her official duties; and </section><section prefix="d">Be appointed regardless of race, color, creed, or position. </section></section><section prefix="3">Before any person is appointed as a member of an auxiliary county police force, he or she shall give bond to the county judge/executive in an amount as prescribed by the fiscal court. The fiscal court may authorize the premium therefor to be paid out of the general funds of the county. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 71, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24246</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>