<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.060</section_number><catch_line>Applications. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>All applications for the veterans' bonus shall be submitted to the administrator, in writing, upon forms prepared and made available by the administrator; and shall be accompanied by such documentary evidence as the administrator may by regulation prescribe. Every application shall be verified under oath, and shall contain representations of the claimant (or, if he shall have been adjudged mentally disabled, or be an infant, his guardian or conservator), that:  <section prefix="1">The facts therein stated are true to the best of his or her knowledge and belief;  </section><section prefix="2">All documents submitted in support of the application are believed by the claimant to be genuine originals, or copies, as the case may be; and the claimant has no knowledge that any fact appearing therein is false, or no longer true, or that the document has been superseded or canceled;  </section><section prefix="3">The claimant has not received a veterans' bonus or like compensation from any other state;  </section><section prefix="4">That the claimant has neither paid nor agreed to pay, directly or indirectly, any compensation for assistance received in preparing or tendering the application; and has not solicited, received, or agreed to receive, directly or indirectly, any compensation for rendering assistance to any other claimant; and  </section><section prefix="5">The claimant has knowledge of the penal and forfeiture provisions of this chapter.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 43, effective July 1, 1982. --- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 6, effective February 20, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>: July 1, 1982</effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 46 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21826</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>