<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.2-010</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of trust.   </catch_line><order_by>2-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A statutory trust is formed when a certificate of trust that complies with subsection </section><section prefix="2">of this section and filed by the Secretary of State is effective as determined <section prefix="a">The name of the statutory trust, which must comply with KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The name and business address of each person who, upon formation of the </section><section prefix="c">The mailing address of the principal office of the trust; </section><section prefix="d">The name and street address of the trust’s initial registered office and </section><section prefix="e">The name and business address of the person executing the certificate of trust </section></section>under KRS 14A.2-070. (2) A certificate of trust must state: trust, will be a trustee; registered agent that comply with KRS 14A.4-010; and as the organizer thereof. <section prefix="3">If the trust may have one (1) or more series, the certificate of trust must contain a statement to that effect as provided in KRS 386A.4-020(2)(c). </section><section prefix="4">A certificate of trust may contain any term required or permitted to be set forth in the trust instrument. </section><section prefix="5">A filed certificate of trust, statement of cancellation, statement of change or articles of conversion or merger prevail over inconsistent terms of a trust instrument.  </section><section prefix="6">That the certificate of trust is on file with the Secretary of State is notice: <section prefix="a">That the statutory trust formed by the certificate of trust is a statutory trust formed under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Of all other facts set forth in the certificate which are required to be set forth by subsection (2) of this section; and </section><section prefix="c">Of any statement made pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40349</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>