<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6037</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Commercialization Fund Program -- Purposes. </catch_line><order_by>6037</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established in the Council on Postsecondary Education a Kentucky Commercialization Fund Program to provide seed funding as defined in KRS 164.6011, for the development and commercialization of promising technologies at and emerging from Kentucky's colleges and universities. </section><section prefix="2">The purposes of the Kentucky Commercialization Fund Program are to: <section prefix="a">Accelerate knowledge transfer and technological innovation, improve economic competitiveness, and spur economic growth in Kentucky-based companies; </section><section prefix="b">Provide seed funding for promising technologies developed in Kentucky's colleges and universities; </section><section prefix="c">Support promising technologies with commercial potential that are in their early stages of development; </section><section prefix="d">Promote technologies and resources offered by Kentucky's postsecondary institutions to private enterprises; and </section><section prefix="e">Support the formation and organization of private enterprise that advances commercial applications based on a university's research and development work. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4359</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>