<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.6604Confidentiality</section_number><catch_line>of trade secrets -- When disclosure is required.   </catch_line><order_by>6604Confidentiality</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the vendor, service provider, or operator of a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment claims that the volume of a chemical or relative concentration of chemical is a trade secret, the operator of the horizontal well shall indicate that claim on the chemical disclosure registry form and, as applicable, the vendor, service provider, or operator shall submit a request to the director to designate the information as a trade secret. </section><section prefix="2">At the time of claiming entitlement to trade secret protection, the vendor, service provider, or operator shall file with the director the following information on a form prescribed by the division. The form shall include: <section prefix="a">The claimant's name, authorized representative, mailing address, and phone number; </section><section prefix="b">The specific information claimed to be entitled to trade secret protection; </section><section prefix="c">Whether there has been a previous determination by a court or by a governmental agency that the information is or is not entitled to confidential treatment; and </section><section prefix="d">The measures taken by the vendor, service provider, or operator to protect the confidentiality of the information. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any information claimed to be a trade secret shall be disclosed by the director only: <section prefix="a">In accordance with this section and KRS 353.6605 and 353.6606; or </section><section prefix="b">If ordered by a court to do so. </section></section><section prefix="4">Vendors, service providers, and operators shall identify the volume and relative concentration of any chemicals used in the high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment that are claimed to be a trade secret to the cabinet. The cabinet shall release that information to any health professional who request the information if: <section prefix="a">The request is in writing; </section><section prefix="b">The health professional provides a written statement of the need for the </section>information; and <section prefix="c">The health professional executes a confidentiality agreement. </section></section><section prefix="5">The health professional's written statement of need under subsection (4)(b) of this section shall be a statement that the health professional has a reasonable basis to believe that: <section prefix="a">The information is needed for purposes of diagnosis or treatment of an individual; and </section><section prefix="b">The individual being diagnosed or treated may have been exposed to the chemical concerned. </section></section><section prefix="6">The confidentiality agreement shall state: <section prefix="a">The health professional shall not use the information for purposes other than the health needs asserted in the written statement of need; and </section><section prefix="b">The health professional shall otherwise maintain the information as confidential. </section></section><section prefix="7">Where a health professional determines that a medical emergency exists, and the amount or mixture of any chemicals claimed to be a trade secret are necessary for emergency treatment, the director shall: <section prefix="a">Immediately direct the vendor, service provider, or operator, as applicable, to disclose the information to the health professional upon verbal acknowledgement by the health professional that: <section prefix="1">The information shall not be used for purposes other than the health needs asserted; and </section><section prefix="2">The health professional shall otherwise maintain the information as confidential; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Request a written statement of need and a confidentially agreement from all health professionals to whom the information regarding the concentration or mixture of any chemicals claimed to be a trade secret was disclosed, as soon as circumstances permit. </section></section><section prefix="8">Information disclosed to a health professional under this section shall not be construed as publicly available by virtue of the disclosure of the information to a health care professional. Release of the information under this section shall not be construed as a waiver of a trade secret claim by the party who has asserted that claim. </section><section prefix="9">The division shall develop a form for the vendor, service provider, or operator to claim trade secret status under subsections (1) and (2) of this section and a standard confidentiality agreement for medical professionals under subsections (5), (6), and (7) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44247</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>