<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Highways. </section><section prefix="2">"Crosswalk" means: <section prefix="a">That part of a roadway at an intersection within the connections of the lateral lines of the sidewalks on opposite sides of the highway measured from the curbs or in the absence of curbs, from the edges of the traversable roadway; or </section><section prefix="b">Any portion of a roadway at an intersection or elsewhere distinctly indicated for pedestrian crossing by lines or other markings on the surface. </section></section><section prefix="3">"Highway" means any public road, street, avenue, alley or boulevard, bridge, viaduct, or trestle and the approaches to them and includes private residential roads and parking lots covered by an agreement under KRS 61.362, off-street parking facilities offered for public use, whether publicly or privately owned, except for-hire parking facilities listed in KRS 189.700. </section><section prefix="4">"Intersection" means: <section prefix="a">The area embraced within the prolongation or connection of the lateral curb lines, or, if none, then the lateral boundary lines of the roadways of two (2) highways which join one another, but do not necessarily continue, at approximately right angles, or the area within which vehicles traveling upon different highways joining at any other angle may come into conflict; or </section><section prefix="b">Where a highway includes two (2) roadways thirty (30) feet or more apart, then every crossing of each roadway of such divided highway by an intersecting highway shall be regarded as a separate intersection. If the intersecting highway also includes two (2) roadways thirty (30) feet or more apart, every crossing of two (2) roadways of the highways shall be regarded as a separate intersection. The junction of a private alley with a public street or highway shall not constitute an intersection. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Manufactured home" has the same meaning as defined in KRS 186.650. </section><section prefix="6">"Motor truck" means any motor-propelled vehicle designed for carrying freight or merchandise. It shall not include self-propelled vehicles designed primarily for passenger transportation but equipped with frames, racks, or bodies having a load capacity of not exceeding one thousand (1,000) pounds. </section><section prefix="7">"Operator" means the person in actual physical control of a vehicle. </section><section prefix="8">"Pedestrian" means any person afoot or in a wheelchair. </section><section prefix="9">"Right-of-way" means the right of one (1) vehicle or pedestrian to proceed in a lawful manner in preference to another vehicle or pedestrian approaching under such circumstances of direction, speed, and proximity as to give rise to danger of collision unless one grants precedence to the other. </section><section prefix="10">"Roadway" means that portion of a highway improved, designed, or ordinarily used for vehicular travel, exclusive of the berm or shoulder. If a highway includes two (2) or more separate roadways, the term "roadway" as used herein shall refer to any roadway separately but not to all such roadways collectively. </section><section prefix="11">"Safety zone" means the area or space officially set apart within a roadway for the exclusive use of pedestrians and which is protected or is so marked or indicated by adequate signs as to be plainly visible at all times while set apart as a safety zone. </section><section prefix="12">"Semitrailer" means a vehicle designed to be attached to, and having its front end supported by, a motor truck or truck tractor, intended for the carrying of freight or merchandise and having a load capacity of over one thousand (1,000) pounds. </section><section prefix="13">"Truck tractor" means any motor-propelled vehicle designed to draw and to support the front end of a semitrailer. The semitrailer and the truck tractor shall be considered to be one (1) unit. </section><section prefix="14">"Sharp curve" means a curve of not less than thirty (30) degrees. </section><section prefix="15">"State Police" includes any agency for the enforcement of the highway laws established pursuant to law. </section><section prefix="16">"Steep grade" means a grade exceeding seven percent (7%). </section><section prefix="17">"Trailer" means any vehicle designed to be drawn by a motor truck or truck-tractor, but supported wholly upon its own wheels, intended for the carriage of freight or merchandise and having a load capacity of over one thousand (1,000) pounds. </section><section prefix="18">"Unobstructed highway" means a straight, level, first-class road upon which no other vehicle is passing or attempting to pass and upon which no other vehicle or pedestrian is approaching in the opposite direction, closer than three hundred (300) yards. </section><section prefix="19"><section prefix="a">"Vehicle" includes: <section prefix="1">All agencies for the transportation of persons or property over or upon the public highways of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="2">All vehicles passing over or upon the highways. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Motor vehicle" includes all vehicles, as defined in paragraph (a) of this subsection except: <section prefix="1">Road rollers; </section><section prefix="2">Road graders; </section><section prefix="3">Farm tractors; </section><section prefix="4">Vehicles on which power shovels are mounted; </section><section prefix="5">Construction equipment customarily used only on the site of construction and which is not practical for the transportation of persons or property upon the highways; </section><section prefix="6">Vehicles that travel exclusively upon rails; </section><section prefix="7">Vehicles propelled by electric power obtained from overhead wires while being operated within any municipality or where the vehicles do not travel more than five (5) miles beyond the city limits of any municipality; and </section><section prefix="8">Vehicles propelled by muscular power. </section></section></section><section prefix="20">"Reflectance" means the ratio of the amount of total light, expressed in a percentage, which is reflected outward by the product or material to the amount of total light falling on the product or material. </section><section prefix="21">"Sunscreening material" means a product or material, including film, glazing, and perforated sunscreening, which, when applied to the windshield or windows of a motor vehicle, reduces the effects of the sun with respect to light reflectance or transmittance. </section><section prefix="22">"Transmittance" means the ratio of the amount of total light, expressed in a percentage, which is allowed to pass through the product or material, including glazing, to the amount of total light falling on the product or material and the glazing. </section><section prefix="23">"Window" means any device designed for exterior viewing from a motor vehicle, except the windshield, any roof-mounted viewing device, and any viewing device having less than one hundred fifty (150) square inches in area. </section><section prefix="24">"All-terrain vehicle" means any motor vehicle used for recreational off-road use. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 270, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 587, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 400, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 22. -- Amended 1956 (2nd Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 78, secs. 1 and 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-1, 2739g-69gg, 2739g-80. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 47, 270, and 587 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>