<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="406" order_by="406">UNIFORM ACT ON PATERNITY </unit></structure><section_number>406.035</section_number><catch_line>Written order of paternity -- Limit on public inspection -- Persons who may inspect. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If paternity has been determined under the provisions of subsection (1) or (2) of KRS 406.021, the court shall make a written order of paternity. </section><section prefix="2">Information concerning this action received or transmitted shall not be published or be open for public inspection, including where the cabinet determines reasonable evidence of domestic violence or child abuse, if the disclosure of the information could be harmful to the custodial parent or the child of the parent. </section><section prefix="3">Such orders are to be kept separately and shall not be open for public inspection except that they may be inspected by employees of governmental agencies in the performance of their duties, all law enforcement agencies including county attorneys, Commonwealth's attorneys, District and Circuit Judges, and anyone else under order of the court expressly permitting inspection. Either party to an action under this chapter or attorneys of a party to an action under this chapter shall be permitted to inspect the order entered in the action to which he is a party. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 162, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 411, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17616</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>