<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.815</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for conducting closed sessions. </catch_line><order_by>815</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the following requirements shall be met as a condition for conducting closed sessions authorized by KRS 61.810: <section prefix="a">Notice shall be given in regular open meeting of the general nature of the business to be discussed in closed session, the reason for the closed session, and the specific provision of KRS 61.810 authorizing the closed session; </section><section prefix="b">Closed sessions may be held only after a motion is made and carried by a majority vote in open, public session; </section><section prefix="c">No final action may be taken at a closed session; and </section><section prefix="d">No matters may be discussed at a closed session other than those publicly announced prior to convening the closed session. </section></section><section prefix="2">Public agencies and activities of public agencies identified in paragraphs (a), (c), (d), (e), (f), but only so far as (f) relates to students, (g), (h), (i), (j), (k), (l), and (m) of subsection (1) of KRS 61.810 shall be excluded from the requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 2, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23045</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>