<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.13-220</section_number><catch_line>Dissenters' notice. </catch_line><order_by>13-220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If proposed corporate action creating dissenters' rights under KRS 271B.13-020 is authorized at a shareholders' meeting, the corporation shall deliver a written dissenters' notice to all shareholders who satisfied the requirements of KRS 271B.13-210. </section><section prefix="2">The dissenters' notice shall be sent no later than ten (10) days after the date the proposed corporate action was authorized by the shareholders, or, if no shareholder authorization was obtained, by the board of directors, and shall: <section prefix="a">State where the payment demand must be sent and where and when certificates for certificated shares must be deposited; </section><section prefix="b">Inform holders of uncertificated shares to what extent transfer of the shares will be restricted after the payment demand is received; </section><section prefix="c">Supply a form for demanding payment that includes the date of the first announcement to news media or to shareholders of the terms of the proposed corporate action and requires that the person asserting dissenters' rights certify whether or not he acquired beneficial ownership of the shares before that date; </section><section prefix="d">Set a date by which the corporation must receive the payment demand, which date may not be fewer than thirty (30), nor more than sixty (60) days after the date the notice provided in subsection (1) of this section is delivered; and </section><section prefix="e">Be accompanied by a copy of this subtitle. </section></section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 128, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>