<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.38-030</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>38-030</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Insurance; </section><section prefix="2">"Enrollee" means a person who has been enrolled in a health maintenance organization; </section><section prefix="3">"Evidence of coverage" means any certificate, agreement, contract, or other document issued to an enrollee stating the health care services to which the enrollee is entitled. All coverages described in an evidence of coverage issued by a health maintenance organization are deemed to be "health benefit plans" to the extent defined in KRS 304.17A-005 unless exempted by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="4">"Health care services" means any services included in the furnishing to any individual of medical, optometric, or dental care, or hospitalization or incident to the furnishing of such care or hospitalization, as well as the furnishing to any person of any and all other services and goods for the purpose of preventing, alleviating, curing, or healing human illness, physical disability, or injury; </section><section prefix="5">"Health maintenance organization" means any person who undertakes to provide, directly or through arrangements with others, health care services to individuals enrolled with such an organization on a per capita or a predetermined, fixed prepayment basis. A health maintenance organization is authorized to provide all health care services; </section><section prefix="6">"Person" includes but is not limited to any individual, partnership, association, trust, or corporation; and </section><section prefix="7">"Provider" means a person or group of persons licensed to practice medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, podiatry, optometry, or another health profession in a state or licensed to act as a hospital or another health care facility. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1498, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 427, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 357, subtit. 38, sec. 3, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29964</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>