<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.525</section_number><catch_line>Duties of CASA volunteers. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">CASA volunteers who have a conflict of interest in a case shall not be appointed to the case. </section><section prefix="2">The CASA volunteer shall: <section prefix="a">Attend all court hearings except that the CASA volunteer may be excused by the court or the program director if emergency circumstances arise; </section><section prefix="b">Submit a written report and recommendation to the judge for consideration in determining the best interest of the child at the dispositional hearing, dispositional review hearings, other hearings as requested by the court, and at least one (1) report every six (6) months for as long as the case is assigned to a CASA volunteer; </section><section prefix="c">Monitor the case by visiting the child as often as necessary to observe whether the child's essential needs are being met and whether court orders are actually being carried out; </section><section prefix="d">Participate in any treatment planning conferences and reviews involving the child to assess whether reasonable efforts are being made to provide services to the child and family and determine the appropriateness and progress of the child's permanent plan; </section><section prefix="e">Advocate a prompt, thorough review of the case if the child's circumstances warrant the attention of the court; </section><section prefix="f">Interview parties involved in the case, including interviewing and observing the child; </section><section prefix="g">Maintain complete written records about the case; </section><section prefix="h">Report any incidents of child or adult abuse or neglect to the appropriate authorities and to the program director; </section><section prefix="i">Remain actively involved in the case until dismissed from the case by the program director or judge with competent jurisdiction, or when an adoption proceeding is finalized; </section><section prefix="j">Return all case-related materials including, but not limited to, written notes, court reports, and agency documents, to the program director upon the request of the program director; and </section><section prefix="k">Work with the cabinet representatives to advocate the best interest of the child. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20232</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>