<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.828</section_number><catch_line>Temporary emergency jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>828</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A court of this state has temporary emergency jurisdiction if the child is present in this state and the child has been abandoned or it is necessary in an emergency to protect the child because the child, or a sibling or parent of the child, is subjected to or threatened with mistreatment or abuse. </section><section prefix="2">If there is no previous child custody determination that is entitled to be enforced under KRS 403.800 to 403.880 and a child custody proceeding has not been commenced in a court of a state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826, a child custody determination made under this section remains in effect until an order is obtained from a court of a state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826. If a child custody proceeding has not been or is not commenced in a court of a state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826, a child custody determination made under this section becomes a final determination, if it so provides and this state becomes the home state of the child. </section><section prefix="3">If there is a previous child custody determination that is entitled to be enforced under KRS 403.800 to 403.880, or a child custody proceeding has been commenced in a court of a state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826, any order issued by a court of this state under this section shall specify in the order a period that the court considers adequate to allow the person seeking an order to obtain an order from the state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826. The order issued in this state remains in effect until an order is obtained from the other state within the period specified or the period expires. </section><section prefix="4">A court of this state which has been asked to make a child custody determination under this section, upon being informed that a child custody proceeding has been commenced in, or a child custody determination has been made by, a court of a state having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826, shall immediately communicate with the other court. A court of this state which is exercising jurisdiction pursuant to KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826, upon being informed that a child custody proceeding has been commenced in, or a child custody determination had been made by, a court of another state under a statute similar to this section shall immediately communicate with the court of that state to resolve the emergency, protect the safety of the parties and the child, and determine a period for the duration of the temporary order. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 15, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>