<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="133" order_by="133">SUPERVISION, EQUALIZATION, AND REVIEW OF ASSESSMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>133.160</section_number><catch_line>Notice of assessment raised by Department of Revenue -- To whom given -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text>When it is contemplated by the Department of Revenue that it will be necessary to raise the assessed valuation of property in any county, it shall give notice of the contemplated action to the county judge/executive, the superintendent of any school district affected by such action, the mayor of any city which is affected and which has adopted the assessment, and to the taxpayers of that county through the county judge/executive, who shall post the notice sent him on the courthouse door and certify to the Department of Revenue that this has been done, and it shall fix a time and place for a hearing which may be in Frankfort or any convenient place in or nearer the county seat. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 236, effective June 20, 2005. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 340, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 267, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 3. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 17. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 3. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 131, secs. 24 and  32. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4114i-16, 4114i-17. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28349</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>