<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.575</section_number><catch_line>Statewide system for stroke response and treatment.   </catch_line><order_by>575</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "department" means the Department for Public Health. </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Public Health shall establish and implement a plan for achieving continuous quality improvement in the quality of care provided under a statewide system for stroke response and treatment. In implementing the plan, the department shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain a statewide stroke database to compile information and statistics on stroke care as follows: <section prefix="1">The database shall align with the stroke consensus metrics developed and approved by the American Heart Association, the American Stroke Association, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Joint Commission; </section><section prefix="2">The department shall utilize the "Get With The Guidelines-Stroke" quality improvement program maintained by the American Heart Association and the American Stroke Association or another nationally recognized program that utilizes a data set platform with patient confidentiality standards no less secure than the statewide stroke database established in this paragraph; and </section><section prefix="3">Require primary stroke centers as established in KRS 216B.0425 to report to the database each case of stroke seen at the facility. The data shall be reported in a format consistent with nationally recognized guidelines on the treatment of individuals within the state with confirmed cases of stroke; </section></section><section prefix="b">To the extent possible, coordinate with national voluntary health organizations involved in stroke quality improvement to avoid duplication and redundancy; </section><section prefix="c">Encourage the sharing of information and data among health care providers on methods to improve the quality of care of stroke patients in the state; </section><section prefix="d">Facilitate communication about data trends and treatment developments among health care professionals involved in the care of individuals with stroke; </section><section prefix="e">Require the application of evidence-based treatment guidelines for the transition of stroke patients upon discharge from a hospital following acute treatment to community-based care provided in a hospital outpatient, physician office, or ambulatory clinic setting; and </section><section prefix="f">Establish a data oversight process and a plan for achieving continuous quality improvement in the quality of care provided under the statewide system for stroke response and treatment, which shall include: <section prefix="1">Analysis of the data included in the stroke database; </section><section prefix="2">Identification of potential interventions to improve stroke care in specific geographic regions of the state; and </section><section prefix="3">Recommendations to the department and the Kentucky General Assembly for improvement in the delivery of stroke care in the state. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">All data reported under subsection (2)(a) of this section shall be made available to the department and all government agencies or contractors of government agencies which are responsible for the management and administration of emergency medical services throughout the state. </section><section prefix="4">On June 1, 2013, and annually on June 1 thereafter, the department shall provide a report of its data and any related findings and recommendations to the Governor and to the Legislative Research Commission. The report also shall be made available on the department's Web site. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require the disclosure of confidential information or data in violation of the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>