<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.154</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by small farm winery wholesaler's license -- Licensed premises on small farm winery.   </catch_line><order_by>154</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A small farm winery wholesaler's license shall authorize the licensee: <section prefix="a">To purchase, receive, store, or possess wine produced by small farm winery licensees; </section><section prefix="b">To sell the wine at wholesale from the licensed premises only; and </section><section prefix="c">To transport from the licensed premises for himself or herself only any wine produced by small farm winery licensees that the small farm winery wholesaler's license authorizes him or her to sell. </section></section><section prefix="2">A small farm winery wholesaler licensed under this section shall: <section prefix="a">Transport the wine in the manner provided for manufacturers in KRS 243.120; and </section><section prefix="b">Transport the wine from a small farm winery's licensed premises or another wholesaler's premises to the small farm winery wholesaler's premises. </section></section><section prefix="3">A small farm winery wholesaler licensed under this section shall not purchase, receive, store, possess, sell, or transport wine or distilled spirits, except as provided in this section, and shall comply with all provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes applicable to wholesalers licensed under KRS 243.030, to the extent the provisions are not inconsistent with this section. </section><section prefix="4">A small farm winery wholesaler licensed under this section shall be allowed to have its licensed premises on or in the licensed premises of a small farm winery. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 61, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 15, effective January 1, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42496</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>