<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.502</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with Mental Illness, Alcohol and Other Drug Abuse Disorders, and Dual Diagnoses.   </catch_line><order_by>502</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with Mental Illness, Alcohol and Other Drug Abuse Disorders, and Dual Diagnoses. The commission shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of the Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="e">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="f">The commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice; </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="h">The executive director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="i">The director of the Protection and Advocacy Division of the Department for Public Advocacy; </section><section prefix="j">The director of the Division of Family Resource and Youth Services Centers; </section><section prefix="k">The commissioner of the Department for Aging and Independent Living of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="l">The executive director of the Office of Drug Control Policy; </section><section prefix="m">The director of the Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="n">The chief executive officer of the Kentucky Housing Corporation; </section><section prefix="o">The executive director of the Office of Transportation Delivery of the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="p">The commissioner of the Department of Public Health; </section><section prefix="q">Three (3) members of the House of Representatives who are members of the Health and Welfare Committee or the Appropriations and Revenue Committee, appointed by the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="r">Three (3) members of the Senate who are members of the Health and Welfare Committee or the Appropriations and Revenue Committee, appointed by the Senate President; </section><section prefix="s">A chairperson and one (1) alternate who is a chairperson of a regional planning council appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services from a list of five (5) chairpersons submitted by the Kentucky Association of Regional Programs; </section><section prefix="t">A consumer and one (1) alternate who is a consumer of mental health or substance abuse services, who is over age eighteen (18), appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services from a list of up to three (3) consumers submitted by any consumer advocacy organization operating within Kentucky or submitted by any regional planning council established under KRS 210.506; and </section><section prefix="u">An adult family member and one (1) alternate who is an adult family member of a consumer of mental health or substance abuse services appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services from a list of up to three (3) persons submitted by any family advocacy organization operating within Kentucky or submitted by any regional planning council established under KRS 210.506. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and one (1) member of the General Assembly appointed to the commission shall serve as co-chairs of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Members designated in subsection (1)(a) to (r) of this section shall serve during their terms of office. </section><section prefix="4">Members and alternates designated in subsection (1)(s) to (u) of this section shall serve a term of two (2) years and may be reappointed for one (1) additional term. These members may be reimbursed for travel expenses in accordance with administrative regulations governing reimbursement for travel for state employees. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 89, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 38, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 19, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 244, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 124, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 54, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 2, effective April 21, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>