<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.991</section_number><catch_line>Revocation or denial of operator's license. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever a person who is seventeen (17) years of age or younger but not less than fourteen (14) years of age is convicted of a violation of any offense in this chapter or is adjudicated delinquent as a result of any act which would be an offense under this chapter, the court may, in addition to any other penalty: <section prefix="a">If the person has a motor vehicle or motorcycle operator's license, recommend the revocation of the license for a period not to exceed one (1) year, if it is the person's first offense; </section><section prefix="b">If the person has a motor vehicle or motorcycle operator's license, recommend the revocation of the license for two (2) years, if it is a second or subsequent offense so long as the suggested period of revocation does not extend beyond the person's eighteenth birthday; and </section><section prefix="c">If the person has no motor vehicle or motorcycle operator's license, in the event of a first offense, recommend that no such license shall be issued to such person for the period described in paragraph (a) of this subsection and in the event of a second or subsequent offense, recommend that no license shall be issued to such person for the period described in  paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each court recommending the revocation of a motor vehicle operator's license or motorcycle operator's license or recommending the denial of such license pursuant to this section shall notify the Transportation Cabinet of the violation and the terms of the suggested revocation or denial. </section><section prefix="3">Upon notice of such recommendation, the Transportation Cabinet shall forthwith revoke the license of that person, or deny to that person a license for the period recommended by the court.  If through inadvertence the defendant should be issued a license, the cabinet shall forthwith cancel it. </section><section prefix="4">Licenses revoked pursuant to this section shall be retained by the Transportation Cabinet for the period of revocation and shall be returned to the person after the expiration of the revocation period upon payment of the reinstatement fees and satisfaction of other requirements for the reinstatement of revoked licenses as may be required by the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="5">Revocations of operator's licenses and denials of licenses pursuant to this section shall be in addition to any other suspension, revocation, or denial of motor vehicle or motorcycle operator's licenses authorized by law. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>