<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.397</section_number><catch_line>Salary supplement for speech-language pathologists or audiologists -- Supplement to be considered in calculation for retirement. </catch_line><order_by>397</order_by><text>Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If funds are appropriated by the General Assembly for this purpose, a local board of education shall provide an annual salary supplement to all speech-language pathologists or audiologists: <section prefix="1">Who are employed by the local board of education to provide or coordinate speech-language pathology or audiology services for students; and </section><section prefix="2">Who hold: <section prefix="a">i. A certificate of clinical competence issued by the American  Speech-Language Hearing Association; or </section> ii. Board certification from the American Board of  Audiology; and <section prefix="b">i. A valid Kentucky credential approved and issued by the  Education  Professional Standards Board under KRS  Chapter 161; or </section> ii. A license approved and issued by the Kentucky Board of  Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology under KRS  Chapter 334A. </section></section><section prefix="b">The salary supplement shall be in the same amount as the salary supplement provided to a public school teacher who has attained certification from the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards as provided in KRS 157.395. If the amount appropriated by the General Assembly is less than the amount necessary to meet the requirements of this paragraph, the salary supplement received by each qualified speech-language pathologist or audiologist shall be reduced proportionately by the Department of Education so that all eligible individuals receive the same amount as a supplement. </section><section prefix="c">The supplement shall remain available to a speech-language pathologist or audiologist so long as funds are appropriated for this purpose by the General Assembly, and the speech-language pathologist or audiologist continues to meet the requirements established by this subsection. The supplement shall cease if the speech-language pathologist or audiologist is employed in another capacity by the local board where the provision of speech-language pathology or audiology services is incidental to his or her other duties. </section><section prefix="d">The Department of Education shall: <section prefix="1">Determine how many speech-language pathologists and audiologists qualify for the supplement each year; </section><section prefix="2">Determine the amount of the supplement available each year for each qualified speech-language pathologist and audiologist based on appropriated funds available; </section><section prefix="3">Notify each local board of education of the supplement amount available to each qualifying speech-language pathologist and audiologist employed by the local board of education; and </section><section prefix="4">Develop a process for payment to local boards of education of supplement amounts due; </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If funds are not appropriated by the General Assembly to support the salary supplement established by subsection (1) of this section, a local board of education may provide an annual salary supplement under the conditions established by subsection (1) of this section using the resources available to the local board of education; and </section><section prefix="3">The supplement authorized by this section shall be considered in the calculation for contribution to the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3324</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>