<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.3-040</section_number><catch_line>Name of foreign entity.   </catch_line><order_by>3-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the real name of a foreign entity does not satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010 as would apply were the foreign entity organized in this Commonwealth, the foreign entity seeking to obtain or maintain a certificate of authority to transact business in this Commonwealth: <section prefix="a">May use a fictitious name to transact business in this Commonwealth if its real name is not distinguishable from any name of record with the Secretary of State; or </section><section prefix="b">May supplement its name with such identifier as would be appropriate under KRS 14A.3-010 were the foreign entity organized in this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">The real or fictitious name of a foreign entity shall be distinguishable upon the records of the Secretary of State from any name of record with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="3">If a foreign entity authorized to transact business in this Commonwealth changes its real name to one that does not satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010, it shall not transact business in this Commonwealth under the changed name until it adopts a fictitious name satisfying the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010 and obtains an amended certificate of authority in accordance with KRS 14A.9-040. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 132, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 26, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41106</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>