<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">A OCCUPATIONAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319A.160</section_number><catch_line>License renewal, reinstatement, restoration, and reissuance -- Inactive license status -- Change of licensee's name, address, or employment. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Licenses issued under this chapter shall be subject to annual renewal and shall expire unless renewed upon the payment of a renewal fee in the manner prescribed by the rules of the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board may set a required number of continuing education units for license renewal. </section><section prefix="3">At least thirty (30) days before the renewal date, the board shall mail an application for renewal to every person to whom a license was issued during the current licensure period. </section><section prefix="4">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed during which time licenses may be renewed on payment of a late renewal fee as set forth in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="5">The board may provide for the late renewal of a license upon the payment of a late fee in accordance with its rules, but no such renewal of a license may be granted more than five (5) years after its expiration. </section><section prefix="6">Licenses not renewed in a timely manner or by the end of the grace period shall be considered expired. Expired licenses may be restored in accordance with the requirements set forth by the board in administrative regulation. A person who fails to restore his license within five (5) years after its expiration may not restore it, and it shall not be restored, reissued, or reinstated thereafter. The person may apply for and obtain a new license if current requirements of this chapter are met. </section><section prefix="7">Any person practicing occupational therapy after the license has expired shall be considered an illegal practitioner and shall be subject to the penalties provided for violations of the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="8">A suspended license is subject to expiration and may be restored as provided in this section, but restoration shall not entitle the licensee, while the license remains suspended and until it is reinstated, to engage in the licensed activity, or in any other conduct or activity in violation of the order or judgment by which the license was suspended. </section><section prefix="9">A license revoked on disciplinary grounds is subject to expiration and may not be renewed. If the license is subsequently reinstated, the licensee, as a condition of reinstatement shall pay a reinstatement fee, the renewal fee, and any late fee that may be applicable. </section><section prefix="10">Upon petition to the board, licensees may be granted inactive license status for a period of time not to exceed three (3) years. Licensees shall not practice occupational therapy or assist in the practice of occupational therapy while under inactive status. Inactive licensees may apply for an active license after paying a fee provided for by administrative regulation of the board. </section><section prefix="11">Each occupational therapist and occupational therapy assistant licensed under this chapter shall notify the board in writing of any change in the person's name, home or office address, or employment within thirty (30) days after the change has taken place. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31269</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>