<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.227</section_number><catch_line>Officers.   </catch_line><order_by>227</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A corporation shall have the officers described in its bylaws or appointed by the board of directors in accordance with the bylaws. </section><section prefix="2">A duly appointed officer may appoint one (1) or more officers or assistant officers if authorized by the bylaws or the board of directors. </section><section prefix="3">The bylaws or the board of directors shall delegate to one (1) of the officers responsibility for preparing minutes of the directors' and members' meetings and for authenticating records of the corporation. </section><section prefix="4">The same individual may simultaneously hold more than one (1) office in a corporation. </section><section prefix="5">Each officer shall be elected or appointed at such time and in such manner and for such terms not exceeding three (3) years as may be prescribed in the articles of incorporation or the bylaws. In the absence of any such provision, all officers shall be elected or appointed annually by the board of directors. </section><section prefix="6">The articles of incorporation or the bylaws may provide that any one (1) or more officers of the corporation shall be ex officio members of the board of directors. </section><section prefix="7">Every officer of a corporation, by acceptance of election or appointment as an officer, including by service, shall be deemed to have consented to the jurisdiction of the courts of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for any action by, in the name of, or on behalf of the corporation. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 51, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 101, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 197, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 22. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44364</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>