<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.530</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance of turnpike -- Restoration of private property -- Donation of property by county or city -- Annual report of turnpike activities -- Audits -- Personnel of Department of Highways not to have interest in project -- Penalty for failure to pay toll -- Lien on vehicle. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each turnpike project when constructed and opened to traffic shall be maintained and kept in good condition and repair by the department and shall be operated and maintained by such force of toll-takers and other operating and maintenance employees and, unless policed by the Department of Kentucky State Police as an ordinary incident to the performance of statutory functions, shall be policed by the department by such force of police, as the department may in its discretion employ, and the department may be reimbursed for the cost thereof unless it has previously assumed such cost as provided in KRS 177.480. </section><section prefix="2">All private property damaged or destroyed in carrying out the powers granted by KRS 177.390 to 177.570 shall be restored or repaired and placed in its original condition as nearly as practicable or adequate compensation made therefor out of funds provided under the authority of KRS 177.390 to 177.570. </section><section prefix="3">All counties, cities, towns, and other political subdivisions and all public agencies and commissions of the Commonwealth, notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, are hereby authorized and empowered to lease, lend, grant, or convey to the department at its request upon such terms and conditions as the proper authorities of such counties, cities, towns, political subdivisions, agencies, or commissions of the Commonwealth may deem reasonable and fair and without the necessity for any advertisement, order of court, or other action or formality, other than the regular and formal action of the authorities concerned, any real property which may be necessary or convenient to the effectuation of the authorized purposes of the department, including public roads and other real property already devoted to public use. </section><section prefix="4">On or before January 30 in each year the department shall make an annual report of its activities for the preceding calendar year to the Governor and to the General Assembly. Each such report shall set forth a complete operating and financial statement covering its operations during the year. The department shall cause an audit of its books and accounts to be made at least once in each year by certified public accountants, and the cost thereof may be treated as a part of the cost of construction or operation of the project. Such audits shall be deemed to be public records within the meaning of KRS 61.870(2). </section><section prefix="5">No officer or employee of the department shall have any interest, direct or indirect, in the sale or purchase of any bonds authorized by KRS 177.390 to 177.570. Violation of this provision is punishable by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or by imprisonment for not more than one (1) year, or both. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who uses any turnpike project and fails or refuses to pay the toll provided therefor shall be punished by a fine of not more than one hundred dollars ($100) or by imprisonment for not more than thirty (30) days, or both, and in addition thereto the department shall have a lien upon the vehicle driven by such person for the amount of such toll and may take and retain possession thereof until the amount of such toll and all charges and penalties in connection therewith shall have been paid. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 186, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 133, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 164. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 9. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 15. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5339</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>