<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Ambulance" means a vehicle which has been inspected and approved by the board, including a helicopter or fixed-wing aircraft, except vehicles or aircraft operated by the United States government, that are specially designed, constructed, or have been modified or equipped with the intent of using the same, for the purpose of transporting any individual who is sick, injured, or otherwise incapacitated who may require immediate stabilization or continued medical response and intervention during transit or upon arrival at the patient's destination to safeguard the patient's life or physical well-being; </section><section prefix="2">"Ambulance provider" means any individual or private or public organization, except the United States government, who is licensed by the board to provide medical transportation services at either basic life support level or advanced life support level and who may have a vehicle or vehicles, including ground vehicles, helicopters, or fixed-wing aircraft to provide such transportation. An ambulance provider may be licensed as an air ambulance provider, as a Class I ground ambulance provider, as a Class II ground ambulance provider, or as a Class III ground ambulance provider; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services; </section><section prefix="4">"Emergency medical facility" means a hospital or any other institution licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services that furnishes emergency medical services; </section><section prefix="5">"Emergency medical services" means the services utilized in providing care for the perceived individual need for immediate medical care to protect against loss of life, or aggravation of physiological or psychological illness or injury; </section><section prefix="6">"Emergency Medical Services for Children Program" or "EMSC Program" means the program established under this chapter; </section><section prefix="7">"Emergency medical services personnel" means persons, certified or licensed, and trained to provide emergency medical services, and an authorized emergency medical services medical director, whether on a paid or volunteer basis; </section><section prefix="8">"Emergency medical services system" means a coordinated system of health-care delivery that responds to the needs of acutely sick and injured adults and children, and includes community education and prevention programs, centralized access and emergency medical dispatch, communications networks, trained emergency medical services personnel, medical first response, ground and air ambulance services, trauma care systems, mass casualty management, medical direction, and quality control and system evaluation procedures; </section><section prefix="9">"Emergency medical services training or educational institution" means any person or organization which provides emergency medical services training or education or in-service training, other than a licensed ambulance service which provides training, or in-service training in-house for its own employees or volunteers; </section><section prefix="10">"Emergency medical technician" or "EMT" means a person certified under this chapter as an EMT-basic, EMT-basic instructor, or EMT-instructor trainer; </section><section prefix="11">"First responder" means a person certified under this chapter as a first responder or first responder instructor; </section><section prefix="12">"Emergency medical services medical director" means a physician licensed in Kentucky who is employed by, under contract to, or has volunteered to provide supervision for a paramedic or an ambulance service, or both; </section><section prefix="13">"Paramedic" means a person who is involved in the delivery of medical services and is licensed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="14">"Paramedic course coordinator" means a person certified under this chapter to coordinate a paramedic course. A paramedic course coordinator shall not practice as a paramedic unless they are also licensed as a paramedic; </section><section prefix="15">"Paramedic preceptor" means a licensed paramedic who supervises a paramedic student during the field portion of the student's training; </section><section prefix="16">"Prehospital care" means the provision of emergency medical services or transportation by trained and certified or licensed emergency medical services personnel at the scene or while transporting sick or injured persons to a hospital or other emergency medical facility; and </section><section prefix="17">"Trauma" means a single or multisystem life-threatening or limb-threatening injury requiring immediate medical or surgical intervention or treatment to prevent death or permanent disability. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 592, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30717</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>