<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.1-070</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>1-070</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Business" includes every trade, occupation, and profession; </section><section prefix="2">"Corporation" means a business corporation governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 271B, a cooperative or association governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 272, a nonprofit corporation governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 273, and a rural electric or rural telephone cooperative corporation governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 279; </section><section prefix="3">"Business trust" means a business trust governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 386 or a statutory trust governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 386A; </section><section prefix="4">"Debtor in bankruptcy" means a person who is the subject of: <section prefix="a">An order for relief under Title 11 of the United States Code or a comparable order under a successor statute of general application; or </section><section prefix="b">A comparable order under federal, state, or foreign law governing insolvency; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Deliver" or "delivery" means any method of delivery used in conventional commercial practice, including delivery by hand, mail, commercial delivery, and electronic transmission; </section><section prefix="6">"Electronic transmission" or "electronically transmitted" means any process of communication not directly involving the physical transfer of paper that is suitable for the retention, retrieval, and reproduction of information by the recipient; </section><section prefix="7">"Entity" means a corporation, business trust, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company, governed as to its internal affairs by the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="8">"Foreign business trust" means a business or statutory trust not governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 386 or 386A; </section><section prefix="9">"Foreign corporation" means a corporation as defined in subsection (2) of this section that is not: <section prefix="a">Organized pursuant to the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="b">As to its internal affairs, governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Foreign entity" means a corporation, not-for-profit corporation, cooperative, association, business or statutory trust, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company not: <section prefix="a">Organized pursuant to the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="b">As to its internal affairs, governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Foreign limited cooperative association" means a limited cooperative association that is not: <section prefix="a">Organized pursuant to the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="b">As to its internal affairs, governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Foreign limited liability partnership" means a partnership that: <section prefix="a">Is formed under laws other than the laws of this Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="b">Has the status of a limited liability partnership under those laws; </section></section><section prefix="13">"Foreign professional service corporation" has the same meaning as in KRS 274.005; </section><section prefix="14">"Foreign rural electric cooperative" means a rural electric cooperative organized otherwise than under KRS 279.010 to 279.210; </section><section prefix="15">"Foreign rural telephone cooperative" means a rural telephone cooperative organized otherwise than under KRS 279.310 to 279.990 excepting 279.570; </section><section prefix="16">"Good standing" means that all annual reports which are required to be received from an entity or foreign entity have been delivered to and filed by the Secretary of State, that all other lawfully required statutory documentation has been received and filed, and that all fees, costs, and expenses, including penalties incurred in connection therewith, have been paid; </section><section prefix="17">"Limited cooperative association" means a limited cooperative association governed as to its affairs by KRS Chapter 272A; </section><section prefix="18">"Limited liability company" has the same meaning as in KRS 275.015; </section><section prefix="19">"Limited liability partnership" means a partnership that has filed a statement of qualification under KRS 362.1-931 or a registration as a registered limited liability partnership under KRS 362.555 and does not have a similar statement of registration in effect in any other jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="20">"Name of record with the Secretary of State" means any real, fictitious, reserved, registered, or assumed name of an entity or foreign entity; </section><section prefix="21">"Nonprofit corporation," other than in the term "foreign nonprofit corporation," means a nonprofit corporation incorporated pursuant to and governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 273 or predecessor law; </section><section prefix="22">"Organic act" means the law of a state or other jurisdiction governing the organization and internal affairs of an entity or foreign entity; </section><section prefix="23">"Organized" means organized, incorporated, or formed; </section><section prefix="24">"Organizational filing" means a filing made with the Secretary of State as a precondition to the formation, organization, or incorporation of an entity, including articles of incorporation, articles of organization, articles of association, certificates of trust, and certificates of limited partnership. A statement of qualification filed pursuant to KRS 362.1-931 or a registration as a limited liability partnership filed pursuant to KRS 362.555 is not an organizational filing; </section><section prefix="25">"Partnership" means an association of two (2) or more persons to carry on as co-owners a business for profit formed under KRS 362.1-202, predecessor law, or comparable law of another jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="26">"Partnership agreement" means the agreement, whether written, oral, or implied, among the partners concerning the partnership, including amendments to the partnership agreement; </section><section prefix="27">"Person" means an individual, an entity, a foreign entity, or any other legal or commercial entity; </section><section prefix="28">"Principal office" means the address required by this chapter or the organic act to be of record with the Secretary of State as the principal office, the principal place of business address, the designated office of a limited partnership, or the chief executive office of a limited liability partnership; </section><section prefix="29">"Professional service corporation" has the same meaning as in KRS 274.005; </section><section prefix="30">"Professional services" means the personal services rendered by physicians, osteopaths, optometrists, podiatrists, chiropractors, dentists, nurses, pharmacists, psychologists, occupational therapists, veterinarians, engineers, architects, landscape architects, certified public accountants, public accountants, physical therapists, and attorneys; </section><section prefix="31">"Property" means all property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, or any interest therein; </section><section prefix="32">"Qualified person" has the same meaning as in KRS 274.005; </section><section prefix="33">"Registered agent" means a registered agent appointed in accordance with KRS 14A.4-010 or predecessor law, and is synonymous with agent for service of process; </section><section prefix="34">"Regulatory board" means the agency that is charged by law with the licensing and regulation of the practice of the profession which the professional partnership is organized to provide; </section><section prefix="35">"Rural electric cooperative" means a rural electric cooperative governed as to its internal affairs by KRS 279.010 to 279.210; </section><section prefix="36">"Rural telephone cooperative" means a rural telephone cooperative governed as to its internal affairs by KRS 279.310 to 279.990 excepting KRS 279.570; </section><section prefix="37">"Series entity" means an entity or a foreign entity authorized and enabled by its organic act and organizational filing to create series having separate rights, powers, or duties with respect to specific property or obligations of the series entity, or the profits and losses associated with specific property or obligations; </section><section prefix="38">"Sign" or "signature" includes any manual, facsimile, conformed, or electronic signature; </section><section prefix="39">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States; and </section><section prefix="40">"Statutory trust" means a trust governed as to its internal affairs by KRS Chapter 386A. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec, 78, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 160, sec. 125, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 81 and 160, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41101</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>