<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.656</section_number><catch_line>Practice as and assumption and use of title master contractor, journeyman, or apprentice without a license prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>656</order_by><text>Except as otherwise provided in KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689: <section prefix="1">No person shall hold himself out as a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor or assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression of this licensure, unless he is the holder of a valid master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor's license issued in accordance with the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. The holder of a valid master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor's license shall be entitled to practice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting, including the obtaining of any necessary permits in connection with the practice of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting, and shall be primarily responsible for the heating, ventilation, and air conditioning work performed; </section><section prefix="2">No person shall hold himself out as a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic or assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression of this licensure, unless he is the holder of a valid journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic's license issued in accordance with the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689; </section><section prefix="3">No person shall hold himself out as an apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic or assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression of certification, unless he is the holder of a valid apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic's certificate issued in accordance with the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689; and </section><section prefix="4">No person shall practice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting, unless he is otherwise qualified according to the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7053</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>