<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-730</section_number><catch_line>Vehicle emission control fund. </catch_line><order_by>20-730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created within the State Treasury a trust and agency fund which shall not lapse to be known as the "Vehicle Emission Control Fund," which shall consist of: <section prefix="a">Money appropriated by the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="b">All money remitted by county clerks which is collected for vehicle emissions inspections: </section><section prefix="c">All money remitted by county fiscal courts which have been delegated authority to implement a vehicle emission control program; </section><section prefix="d">Money received from private grants or donations; and </section><section prefix="e">Money received from the United States by grant or otherwise to assist the Commonwealth in any vehicle emission control program. </section><section prefix="f">Money received from independent contractors as required in subsection (3)(c) of KRS 224.20-740. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall administer the vehicle emission control fund to achieve the purposes of KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section><section prefix="3">Money in the vehicle emission control fund shall not revert to the general fund and shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 45.229 relating to lapsing of appropriations. </section><section prefix="4">All purchases, capital outlay, and operating costs relating to the vehicle emission control program conducted pursuant to KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765 shall be charged against the vehicle emission control fund. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.470. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10368</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>