<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.720</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations relating to cervids -- Costs resulting from importation of diseased animal. </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Agriculture in cooperation with the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources shall promulgate administrative regulations pertaining to health requirements, eradication of diseases, importation and unique individual identification, including visual identification tags, of privately owned and farm raised cervids maintained for the production of meat and other products. Nothing in this section shall limit the authority of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources to regulate the unique individual identification, including visual identification, of captive cervids that are not privately owned and farm-raised cervids maintained for the production of meat and other products. The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, in cooperation with the Department of Agriculture, shall promulgate administrative regulations pertaining to the holding of cervids. </section><section prefix="2">If any person imports a diseased animal into the Commonwealth in violation of the statutes and administrative regulations, then that person shall be responsible to the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources for all costs incurred in the investigation, response, and eradication of that disease. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective March 28, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>