<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-120</section_number><catch_line>Licensure of residents as agents. </catch_line><order_by>9-120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each applicant for license as a resident licensee shall be qualified to designate and shall designate Kentucky as the applicant's home state at the date of application for the license and shall maintain that eligibility throughout the duration of the license. </section><section prefix="2">In determining the good faith of an applicant's claim that Kentucky is the applicant's principal place of residence, the commissioner may give due consideration to the following: <section prefix="a">The amount of time actually spent by the applicant within this state during the claimed residence period; </section><section prefix="b">The circumstances of the applicant's residence, that is, whether in a single or multiple family-type dwelling, or leased apartment, or permanent residential type; or in hotel, resort, motel, mobile home, or other temporary or transient type of dwelling or accommodation; </section><section prefix="c">The circumstances of the applicant, his or her past history and activities, and the probability that he or she will continue as a resident of this state indefinitely into the future if the license were to be issued; and </section><section prefix="d">All other pertinent factors. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1049, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 12, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16901</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>