<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-516</section_number><catch_line>Action on application -- Reapplication. </catch_line><order_by>1-516</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall notify an applicant for the voluntary environmental remediation program within forty-five (45) working days of receipt of the application as to whether the application is accepted or denied. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall deny an application if: <section prefix="a">The cabinet determines the property is ineligible to participate in the program under KRS 224.1-510 to 224.1-532; </section><section prefix="b">The cabinet withdraws from agreed order negotiations pursuant to KRS 224.1-518; or </section><section prefix="c">The application is not complete. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the cabinet denies an application, the cabinet shall notify the applicant in writing, stating the reasons for the denial. If the reason for denial is incompleteness, the cabinet shall inform the applicant of the information needed to make the application complete. </section><section prefix="4">The applicant may submit, within ninety (90) working days of receipt of the initial denial notice, a completed or revised application without incurring an additional fee. </section><section prefix="5">Within forty-five (45) working days of resubmittal, the cabinet shall review any revised or completed application and notify the applicant in writing of its determination to accept or deny the application. If the cabinet denies the application again for incompleteness, the cabinet shall again inform the applicant of the information needed to make the application complete. The cabinet may assess a new application fee for the resubmittal. </section><section prefix="6">If the applicant's second revised application fails to provide the information necessary to address all the concerns of the cabinet, the applicant and the cabinet may meet to clarify the cabinet's expectations and concerns. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification>KRS 224.01-516. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>