<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.238</section_number><catch_line>Compliance with KRS 324.160(4) and 324.235 to 324.238 -- Sanctions and penalties. </catch_line><order_by>238</order_by><text>For purposes of KRS 324.235 to 324.238: <section prefix="1">A person licensed in a jurisdiction where there is not a legal distinction between a real estate principal broker and a real estate broker or salesperson shall satisfy the requirements of an out-of-state principal broker; </section><section prefix="2">Preliminary exchanges of information and materials, discussions, and investment or other advice pertaining to commercial real estate shall not constitute acts of real estate brokerage by out-of-state principal brokers or out-of-state licensees; </section><section prefix="3">If any change in circumstances prevents compliance by the out-of-state principal broker or out-of-state licensee, that person shall immediately cease and desist from performing acts of real estate brokerage with respect to commercial real estate; and </section><section prefix="4">The commission may impose one (1) or more of the following sanctions or penalties against an out-of-state principal broker or an out-of-state licensee for failure to substantially comply with KRS 324.235 to 324.238 or for engaging in improper conduct as set out in KRS 324.160(4): <section prefix="a">Levy fines not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000); </section><section prefix="b">Issue a formal or informal reprimand; </section><section prefix="c">Report misconduct to the licensing authority of any state; </section><section prefix="d">Revoke or suspend the authority of the out-of-state principal broker or out-of-state licensee to perform acts of real estate brokerage with respect to commercial real estate; </section><section prefix="e">Publish and maintain a public registry of any sanctions or penalties imposed pursuant to this subsection; and </section><section prefix="f">Report suspected violations of KRS Chapter 523 to the Commonwealth's attorney of the county in which the office of the commission is located. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>