<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.1801</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 136.1801 to 136.1806. </catch_line><order_by>1801</order_by><text>As used in KRS 136.1801 to 136.1806: <section prefix="1">"Corporation" means any corporation, company, association, partnership, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, other business association, or person operating any watercraft for commercial purposes in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">"Watercraft" means any boat, towboat, pushboat, barge, or similar vessel. Watercraft shall not include: <section prefix="a">Floating equipment used in construction, including but not limited to dredges, pile drivers, and flats; </section><section prefix="b">Houseboats; </section><section prefix="c">Fishing boats; </section><section prefix="d">Pleasure boats; or </section><section prefix="e">Commercial dining boats; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="4">"Operating" or "operated" means owned, leased, rented, or used; </section><section prefix="5">"Local taxing district" means a local taxing jurisdiction or district, including a county, city, charter county, school district, consolidated local government, urban-county government, and special taxing district, which has a navigable waterway within its borders; and </section><section prefix="6">"Navigable waterway" means and shall include the following: <section prefix="a">All of the Mississippi River within or bordering this state; </section><section prefix="b">All of the Ohio River within or bordering this state; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 545.8 and ending at Kentucky River mile marker 65; </section><section prefix="d">The Green River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 784.4 and ending at Green River mile marker 108.9; </section><section prefix="e">The Tennessee River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 934.5 and ending at Tennessee River mile marker 62.4; </section><section prefix="f">The Cumberland River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 922.5 and ending at Cumberland River mile marker 74.7; </section><section prefix="g">The Big Sandy River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 317.2 and ending at Big Sandy River mile marker 14.2; </section><section prefix="h">The Licking River beginning at Ohio River mile marker 470.2 and ending at Licking River mile marker 7; and </section><section prefix="i">Any other waterway in this state utilized by a corporation for the transportation of watercraft during the previous calendar year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28518</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>