<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="359" order_by="359">WAREHOUSES AND WAREHOUSEMEN </unit></structure><section_number>359.230</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of lien against occupant in default -- Requirements prior to conduct of sale -- Redemption by occupant -- Application of proceeds -- Rights of purchaser -- Limitation on liability of operator -- Stored personal property value limit -- Alternative to sale of motor vehicle subject of default of more than sixty days. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If the occupant is in default for a period of more than forty-five (45) days, the operator may enforce a lien by selling the property stored in the leased space at a public or private sale, for cash. </section><section prefix="b">Proceeds shall then be applied to satisfy the lien, with any surplus disbursed as provided in subsection (5) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">Before conducting a sale under subsection (1) of this section, the operator shall: <section prefix="a">Notify the occupant of the default by regular or verified electronic mail at the occupant's last known address; </section><section prefix="b">Send a second notice of default by verified mail or verified electronic mail to the occupant at the occupant's last known address which includes: <section prefix="1">A statement that the contents of the occupant's leased space are subject to the operator's lien; </section><section prefix="2">A statement of the operator's claim, indicating the charges due on the date of the notice, the amount of any additional charges which shall become due before the date of sale, and the date those additional charges shall become due; </section><section prefix="3">A demand for payment of the charges due within a specified time, not less than fourteen (14) days after the date of the notice; </section><section prefix="4">A statement that unless the claim is paid within the time stated, the contents of the occupant's leased space shall be sold at a specified time and place; and </section><section prefix="5">The name, street address, and telephone number of the operator, or his or her designated agent, whom the occupant may contact to respond to the notice; and </section></section><section prefix="c">At least three (3) days before the sale, advertise the time, place, and terms of the sale in a newspaper of general circulation in the jurisdiction where the sale is to be held. </section></section><section prefix="3">At any time before a sale under this section, the occupant may pay the amount necessary to satisfy the lien and redeem the occupant's personal property. </section><section prefix="4">The sale under this section shall be held at the self-service storage facility, the location of the self-contained storage unit where the personal property is stored, or a publicly accessible Web site. </section><section prefix="5">If a sale is held under this section, the operator shall: <section prefix="a">Satisfy the lien from the proceeds of the sale; </section><section prefix="b">Hold the balance, if any, for delivery to any other recorded lienholders who present claims within sixty (60) days. Notwithstanding Article 9 of KRS Chapter 355, claims shall be satisfied on a first come first served basis; and </section><section prefix="c">Deliver, upon expiration of sixty (60) days, the balance of any remaining proceeds to the occupant. </section></section><section prefix="6">A purchaser in good faith of any personal property sold under KRS 359.200 to 359.250 takes the property free and clear of any rights of: <section prefix="a">Persons against whom the lien was valid; and </section><section prefix="b">Other lienholders. </section></section><section prefix="7">If the operator complies with the provisions of KRS 359.200 to 359.250, the operator's liability: <section prefix="a">To the occupant shall be limited to the net proceeds received from the sale of the personal property; </section><section prefix="b">To other lienholders shall be limited to the net proceeds received from the sale of any personal property covered by that other lien; and </section><section prefix="c">To the occupant or valid lienholders shall be relieved upon full distribution of proceeds in accordance with the provisions of KRS 359.200 to 359.250. </section></section><section prefix="8">If an occupant is in default, the operator may deny the occupant access to the leased space. </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">Unless otherwise specifically provided, all notices required by KRS 359.200 to 359.250 shall be sent by verified mail or verified electronic mail. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Notices sent to the operator shall be sent to the operator's principal office, as listed on the rental agreement. </section><section prefix="2">Notices to the occupant shall be sent to the occupant at the occupant's last known address. </section></section><section prefix="c">Notices shall be deemed delivered when deposited with the United States Postal Service, properly addressed as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, with postage paid, or sent by verified electronic mail. </section></section><section prefix="10">Provided, however, unless the rental agreement specifically provides otherwise and until a lien sale under KRS 359.200 to 359.250, the exclusive care, custody, and control of all personal property stored in the leased space shall remain vested in the occupant. </section><section prefix="11">If the rental agreement specifies a limit on the value of the personal property that may be stored in the occupant's leased space, the limit shall be deemed to be the maximum value of the stored personal property. </section><section prefix="12">If the occupant is in default for more than sixty (60) days and the personal property stored in the leased space is a motor vehicle as defined in KRS 376.268, the operator may, in lieu of a sale authorized in this chapter, have the vehicle or watercraft towed or removed from the self-service storage facility, and the towing company shall execute the notice provisions as specified in KRS 376.275. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(9/20/96).  A reference to "this Act" in subsection (7) of this statute was overlooked in the initial codification of this statute and has been changed to the range of statutes created by 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 360 under KRS 7.136(1)(f). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43281</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>