<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.682</section_number><catch_line>Continuing education requirements. </catch_line><order_by>682</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall, by administrative regulation, prescribe continuing education requirements not to exceed thirty (30) hours biennially, as a condition for renewal of a license. All education programs that contribute to the advancement, extension, or enhancement of professional skills and knowledge related to the practice of acupuncture, whether conducted by a nonprofit or profit-making entity, are eligible for approval. The continuing professional education requirements must be in acupuncture or oriental medicine subjects, including but not limited to anatomy, biological sciences, adjunctive therapies, sanitation and sterilization, emergency protocols, and diseases. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall have the authority to set a fee for each continuing education provider. </section><section prefix="3">The licensed practitioner shall retain in his or her records the certificates of completion of continuing professional education requirements to prove compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="4">All national and state acupuncture and oriental medicine organizations and acupuncture and oriental medicine schools are approved to provide continuing professional education in accordance with this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). For the sake of clarity and under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c), the Reviser of Statutes has divided 2006 Ky. Acts. ch. 249, sec. 12, into subsections. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>