<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.170</section_number><catch_line>Transactions permitted to wholesalers.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A wholesaler may sell, deliver, and transport distilled spirits and wine at wholesale, and from the licensed premises only, to: <section prefix="a">Other wholesalers; </section><section prefix="b">Retailers; or </section><section prefix="c">A point out of the state to persons authorized by the law of the state of their residence, and by the United States government if located in the United States, to receive the distilled spirits and wine. </section></section><section prefix="2">A wholesaler may purchase distilled spirits and wine at wholesale from licensed distillers, rectifiers, wineries, or other wholesalers and from nonresidents authorized by the law of the states of their residence, and by the United States government if located in the United States, to make the sales. A wholesaler may not transport distilled spirits and wine from any point to his or her own licensed premises, except as provided in KRS 243.200(12). </section><section prefix="3">No wholesaler shall sell or contract to sell, give away, or deliver any distilled spirits or wine to any person in Kentucky who is not licensed to receive, possess, distribute, or sell distilled spirits and wine, and no wholesaler shall sell or contract to sell, give away, or deliver any distilled spirits or wine to any consumer. This section does not permit sales or deliveries of distilled spirits in Kentucky by licensed wholesalers to nonresidents who are not licensed by their own states. </section><section prefix="4">A wholesaler may extend credit on distilled spirits and wine sold to retail licensees for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days from the date of invoice, with the date of invoice included in the total number of days. When the thirty (30) day period has passed without payment in full, no wholesaler shall sell to the licensee except for cash on delivery. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 64, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-121. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43035</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>