<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.184</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of sections governing legend drugs. </catch_line><order_by>184</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All police officers and deputy sheriffs, directly employed full-time by state, county, city, or urban-county governments, the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the offices of all city, county, and Commonwealth's attorneys, the Office of the Attorney General, and any of their officers and agents, within their respective jurisdictions, shall enforce KRS 217.207, 217.208, 217.209, 217.181, and 217.182 relating to legend drugs and cooperate with all agencies charged with the enforcement of the laws of the United States, of this state, and of all other states relating to legend drugs. </section><section prefix="2">Designated agents of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy are empowered to remove from the files of any pharmacy or other custodian any prescription or other legend drug record upon tendering a receipt. The receipt shall be sufficiently detailed to accurately identify the record and a copy of the records seized shall be returned to the pharmacist within a reasonable amount of time. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 251, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 514, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>