<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.27-090</section_number><catch_line>Advance disbursement of incentives -- Computation of maximum disbursement amount -- Schedule for disbursement -- Repayment. </catch_line><order_by>27-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An approved company may be eligible for the advance disbursement of a portion of the post-construction period incentives for which it has been approved. The amount of the advance disbursement shall be based on the employment of Kentucky residents during the construction of the facility, shall be negotiated with the authority as part of the tax incentive agreement, and shall not exceed the limitations established by this section. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall compute the maximum amount of the advance disbursement employment incentive as follows: <section prefix="a">The base amount shall equal the total capital investment specified in the tax incentive agreement multiplied by the labor intensity factor as determined in paragraph (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="b">The base amount shall then be multiplied by the Kentucky resident factor as determined in paragraph (d) of this subsection. The resulting amount shall be the maximum advance disbursement employment incentive that the authority may approve; </section><section prefix="c">The labor intensity factor shall be: <section prefix="1">Twenty-five percent (25%), if the estimated labor component for the eligible project is greater than thirty percent (30%) of the total capital investment; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty percent (20%), if the estimated labor component for the eligible project is greater than twenty-five percent (25%) but less than or equal to thirty percent (30%) of the total capital investment; or </section><section prefix="3">Fifteen percent (15%), if the estimated labor component for the eligible project is equal to or less than twenty-five percent (25%) of the total capital investment; and </section></section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky resident factor shall be four percent (4%) multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be the estimated total gross wages that will be paid to Kentucky residents who are working on the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the eligible project, and the denominator of which shall be the estimated total gross wages that will be paid to all workers working on the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the eligible project. </section></section><section prefix="3">The tax incentive agreement shall include a schedule for the disbursement of the advance disbursement employment incentive during the construction period. In negotiating the disbursement schedule, the authority shall consider the possible increased risk to the Commonwealth associated with the disbursement of funds prior to construction completion. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The approved company shall repay the advance disbursement through a reduction in the post-construction period incentive amounts it would otherwise receive. The amount by which the post-construction period incentive amounts are reduced shall be applied as a credit against the amount owed by the approved company. </section><section prefix="b">The amount of the annual reduction, the incentives the reduction shall apply to, interest due, the time period over which the advance disbursement amount shall be recouped, and alternate payment methods if incentives are not sufficient to repay the advance disbursement shall be negotiated between the authority and the approved company as part of the tax incentive agreement. </section><section prefix="c">The repayment schedule included in the tax incentive agreement shall require uniform incremental payments, to the extent possible, and shall continue until the entire advance disbursement amount has been repaid by the approved company. </section><section prefix="d">The tax incentive agreement shall include a provision addressing an alternate method for payment if incentives are not sufficient to repay the advance disbursement. </section><section prefix="e">The total post-construction incentive payments for which an approved company is eligible shall be tracked by the department. That portion of the incentive amounts identified in the tax incentive agreement as being devoted to the repayment of the advance disbursement amount shall be credited against the balance due from the approved company and shall not be paid to or retained by the approved company. </section><section prefix="f">The department shall forward the amounts credited to the repayment of the advance disbursement amount to the Cabinet for Economic Development, Department of Financial Incentives for deposit in the Energy Projects Economic Development Bond Pool. </section><section prefix="g">During the period for which any portion of the post-construction incentive payments are being credited toward the advance disbursement amount, the approved company shall, at the direction of the authority or the department, file all required requests for incentives, submit all required remittances, make all required tax payments, and provide to the department and the authority any information that would normally be required for the approved company to receive the incentives. </section></section><section prefix="5">The authority may, for purposes of administering the provisions of this section, solicit information or consultation from one (1) or more of the following sources: <section prefix="a">The Department for Energy Development and Independence; </section><section prefix="b">The Center for Applied Energy Research; </section><section prefix="c">The Department for Workforce Investment; or </section><section prefix="d">Any public postsecondary education institution within the Commonwealth. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 203, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 9, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (8/30/2007).  A manifest clerical or typographical error in subsection (4)(b) of this section has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes during codification pursuant to the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>