<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.350</section_number><catch_line>Revocation or suspension of, or refusal to renew license of firm. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After notice and hearing as provided in KRS Chapter 13B, the board shall revoke the license to practice of a firm if at any time it does not have all the qualifications prescribed by this chapter under which it qualified for licensing. </section><section prefix="2">After notice and hearing as provided in KRS Chapter 13B, the board may revoke, suspend, or refuse to renew the license to practice of a firm or may censure the licensee for any of the causes enumerated in KRS 325.340, and for the following additional causes: <section prefix="a">The revocation, suspension, or refusal to renew the license to practice of any partner or shareholder, or any other person with an ownership interest; or </section><section prefix="b">The cancellation, revocation, suspension, or refusal to renew the authority of the firm or any partner or shareholder, or any other person with an ownership interest thereof to practice public accounting in any other state. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 295, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 107, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 11. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>