<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.219</section_number><catch_line>Conflict of interest transaction. </catch_line><order_by>219</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A conflict of interest transaction is a transaction with the nonprofit corporation in which a director of such corporation has a direct or indirect interest. A conflict of interest transaction shall not be voidable by the corporation solely because of the director's interest in the transaction if any one of the following is true: <section prefix="a">The material facts of the transaction and the director's interest were disclosed or known to the board of directors or a committee of the board of directors and the board of directors or committee authorized, approved, or ratified the transaction; or </section><section prefix="b">The transaction was fair to the corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section, a director of a nonprofit corporation shall be considered to have an indirect interest in a transaction if: <section prefix="a">Another entity in which he has a material  financial interest or in which he is a general partner is a party to the transaction; or </section><section prefix="b">Another entity of which he is a director, officer, or trustee is a party to the transaction and the transaction is or should be considered by the board of directors of the corporation. </section></section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>