<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.426</section_number><catch_line>Refusal to comply with advance directive or surrogate's decision -- Effect of refusal. </catch_line><order_by>426</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A health care provider or health care facility shall provide mental health treatment that complies with the instructions in an advance directive to the fullest extent possible when the instructions are within standards for mental and physical health care and permitted by state and federal law. </section><section prefix="2">A health care provider or health care facility may override expressed refusals of treatment only if: <section prefix="a">A court order contradicts the advance directive; or </section><section prefix="b">There is an emergency endangering a person's life or posing a serious risk to physical health. </section></section><section prefix="3">Deviations from expressed preferences in an advance directive shall be documented by the health care provider or health care facility in the grantor's medical record. </section><section prefix="4">A health care provider or health care facility that refuses to comply with an advance directive of a grantor or a decision made by a surrogate shall: <section prefix="a">Immediately inform the grantor or surrogate, if one is designated, of the refusal; and </section><section prefix="b">Not impede the transfer of the grantor to another health care provider or health care facility. </section></section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7504</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>