<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.221</section_number><catch_line>Statements of financial transactions. </catch_line><order_by>221</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any executive agency lobbyist who has had any financial transaction with, or for the benefit of, an elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or any member of the staff of any of those officials shall describe the details of the transaction, including the name of the official or employee, the purpose and nature of the transaction, and the date it was made or entered into, in a statement filed with the commission with the updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211(2). Each statement shall describe each financial transaction that occurred during the prior fiscal year. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (5) of this section, any employer who has had any financial transaction with or for the benefit of an elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or any member of the staff of any of those officials shall describe the details of the transaction, including the name of the official or employee, the purpose and nature of the transaction, and the date it was made or entered into, in a statement filed with the commission with the updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211(2). The statement shall be filed at the times specified in KRS 11A.211. Each statement shall describe each financial transaction that occurred during the prior fiscal year. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsection (6) of this section, any real party in interest who has had any financial transaction with or for the benefit of any elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or any member of the staff of any of those officials shall describe the details of the transaction, including the name of the official or employee, the purpose and nature of the transaction, and the date it was made or entered into, in a statement filed with the commission with the updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211(2). The statement shall be filed at the times specified in KRS 11A.211. Each statement shall describe each financial transaction that occurred during the prior fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4">At least ten (10) days before the date on which the statement is filed, each employer, executive agency lobbyist, or real party in interest who is required to file a statement describing a financial transaction under this section shall deliver a copy of the statement to the official or employee with whom or for whose benefit the transaction was made. </section><section prefix="5">An employer shall not be required to file any statement under this section or to deliver a copy of the statement to an official or employee with whom or for whose benefit the transaction was made if the financial transaction to which the statement pertains is reported by an executive agency lobbyist engaged by the employer. </section><section prefix="6">A real party in interest shall not be required to file any statement under this section or to deliver a copy of the statement to an official or employee with whom or for whose benefit the transaction was made if the financial transaction to which the statement pertains is reported by an executive agency lobbyist who is acting on behalf of the real party in interest. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 542, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 49, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>