<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.840</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares that it is a policy of the Commonwealth to retain agriculture and rural landscapes in urban counties. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly further finds and declares that the preservation of agriculture and rural landscapes contributes to the development of tourism and recreation. </section><section prefix="3">The General Assembly further finds and declares that the urban-county form of government promotes industrialization and commercialization, attended by rapid residential development, which threatens the preservation of agriculture and rural landscapes. </section><section prefix="4">The General Assembly further finds and declares that in urban counties a single government embraces the entire county and, by nature, has within its jurisdiction both substantial urban areas and substantial rural areas thereby creating the ability to distribute both the benefits and the financial obligations of a purchase of development rights program fairly among the constituents of a single government. </section><section prefix="5">The General Assembly further finds and declares that conferring responsibility upon the electorate in urban-county governments to make decisions regarding the establishment and funding of programs to retain and enhance agriculture and rural landscapes and to promote tourism and recreation is consistent with the broad home rule concepts embodied in this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 372, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23946</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>