<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.550</section_number><catch_line>Violations. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>The following acts are declared to be a violation of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585: <section prefix="1">Making any material representation for the purpose of defrauding the public, or using any method or material that is not reasonably suited for the purpose for which it was employed, by any licensed applicator, manager or his solicitor or agent. </section><section prefix="2">Failure of a licensed operator or manager to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter or any reasonable rule or regulation promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="3">Failure to pay any final judgment rendered against any licensed operator or manager, his employee, solicitor or representative by reason of liabilities resulting from activities under KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585. </section><section prefix="4">Failure to make the registration and pay the annual licensing fees as required by KRS 217B.535. </section><section prefix="5">Failure to attend training courses approved by the department on recommendation of the Pest Control Advisory Board as specified by the Kentucky state plan. </section><section prefix="6">The making of false or fraudulent claims through any media, misrepresenting the effect of materials or methods to be utilized. </section><section prefix="7">The making of a pesticide recommendation or application not in accordance with the label registered by the department under KRS 217.542 to 217.640. </section><section prefix="8">The application of known improper materials. </section><section prefix="9">Knowingly operating faulty or unsafe equipment. </section><section prefix="10">Knowingly operating in a faulty, careless or negligent manner. </section><section prefix="11">Failure to keep and maintain the records required by KRS 217B.510, or to make reports when and as required. </section><section prefix="12">The making of false or fraudulent records, invoices or reports. </section><section prefix="13">Engaging in the business of the application of a pesticide without having a licensed applicator or operator in direct supervision. </section><section prefix="14">Using fraud or misrepresentation in making an application for a license or renewal of a license. </section><section prefix="15">Failure to comply with any limitations or restrictions on or in a duly issued license, permit or certification. </section><section prefix="16">Aiding or abetting a licensed or an unlicensed person to evade the provisions of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585, combining or conspiring with such a licensed or an unlicensed person to evade the provisions of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585, or allowing one's license to be used by an unlicensed person. </section><section prefix="17">The making of false or misleading statements during or after an inspection concerning any infestation or infection of pests found on land. </section><section prefix="18">Impersonating any state, county or city inspector or official. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 219, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>