<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">A MASS TRANSIT AUTHORITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96A.095</section_number><catch_line>Authorization for the Transportation Cabinet to accept funds for promotion of, development of, and provision of capital for mass transit services and human service transportation delivery -- Authority to promulgate administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet may receive and accept from the Commonwealth or any of its agencies, including the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Department of Workforce Investment, and from federal agencies appropriations or grants to promote, develop, and provide capital and operating subsidies for mass transit services and human service transportation delivery in Kentucky, and to receive and accept aid or contributions from any source of either money, property, labor, or other things of value to promote mass transit services. Subject to the provisions of Section 230 of the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, any of these funds, property, or things of value received by the Transportation Cabinet may be given directly to any of the following entities in order to accomplish the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">A local transit authority as created under this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">A city; </section><section prefix="c">A county; </section><section prefix="d">Other public mass transit providers; </section><section prefix="e">A nonprofit or public mass transit provider operating under 49 U.S.C. sec. 5310 or 5311; or </section><section prefix="f">An entity providing human service transportation delivery. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet is authorized and directed to apply for any available federal funds for operating subsidies, either on a matching basis or otherwise and to make any of these funds received available to any of the following entities in order to accomplish the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">A local transit authority as created under this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">A city; </section><section prefix="c">A county; </section><section prefix="d">Other public mass transit providers; </section><section prefix="e">A nonprofit or public mass transit provider operating under 49 U.S.C. sec. 5310 or 5311; or </section><section prefix="f">An entity promoting or providing transit services such as safety, planning, research, coordination, or training activities. </section></section> In those cases where federal laws or regulations preclude the Transportation Cabinet from direct application for this type of federal funds, the cabinet is authorized and directed to provide assistance to any of the entities listed in this subsection as necessary to enable it to apply for and obtain this type of federal funds in order to accomplish the purposes of this section. <section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet is authorized to assist cities and counties in the formation of local transit authorities in conformance with this chapter, but nothing in this chapter shall be construed as preventing the Transportation Cabinet from providing assistance as authorized in this chapter to cities or counties where local transit authorities do not exist. </section><section prefix="4">The Transportation Cabinet is authorized to contract, in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 45A and 281, with a broker to provide human service transportation delivery within a specific delivery area. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 19, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 607, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26331</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>