<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.650</section_number><catch_line>Division of Geographic Information Systems -- Powers and duties -- Authority for administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Geographic Information Systems is hereby established in the Office of Application Development within the Commonwealth Office of Technology in the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Division of Geographic Information Systems shall be headed by a division director, whose appointment is subject to KRS 12.050. The division director may employ personnel, pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 18A, as required to perform the functions of the office. </section><section prefix="3">The division may solicit, receive, and consider proposals for funding from any state agency, federal agency, local government, university, nonprofit organization, or private person or corporation. The division may also solicit and accept money by grant, gift, donation, bequest, legislative appropriation, or other conveyance. </section><section prefix="4">The division shall: <section prefix="a">Establish a central statewide geographic information clearinghouse to maintain map inventories, information on current and planned geographic information systems applications, information on grants available for the acquisition or enhancement of geographic information resources, and a directory of geographic information resources available within the state or from the federal government; </section><section prefix="b">Coordinate multiagency geographic information system projects, including overseeing the development and maintenance of statewide base maps and geographic information systems; </section><section prefix="c">Provide access to both consulting and technical assistance, and education and training, on the application and use of geographic information technologies to state and local agencies; </section><section prefix="d">Maintain, update, and interpret geographic information and geographic information systems standards, under the direction of the council; </section><section prefix="e">Provide geographic information system services, as requested, to agencies wishing to augment their geographic information system capabilities; </section><section prefix="f">In cooperation with other agencies, evaluate, participate in pilot studies, and make recommendations on geographic information systems hardware and software; </section><section prefix="g">Assist the council with review of agency information resource plans and participate in special studies as requested by the council; </section><section prefix="h">Provide staff support and technical assistance to the Geographic Information Advisory Council; and </section><section prefix="i">Prepare proposed legislation and funding proposals for the General Assembly which will further solidify coordination and expedite implementation of geographic information systems. </section></section><section prefix="5">The division may promulgate necessary administrative regulations for the furtherance of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 57, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40262</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>