<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.200</section_number><catch_line>Nature of district -- Governing body -- Corporate powers -- Operating funds. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A district shall constitute a governmental subdivision of the state and public body corporate and politic, exercising public power. </section><section prefix="2">The governing body of the district shall consist of a board of seven (7) supervisors. On organization of a district, the first two (2) supervisors shall be appointed by the committee as provided in KRS 262.150, and five (5) shall be elected under KRS 262.210 and 262.220. The supervisors shall hold no other city, county, or state elective office. Where the need for urban representation on the board of supervisors exists, it shall be limited to three (3) members. </section><section prefix="3">The board may sue and be sued in the name of the district; have a seal, which shall be judicially noticed; have perpetual succession unless terminated as provided in KRS 262.530 to 262.560; make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to exercise its powers. </section><section prefix="4">The board may request annual operating funds from the fiscal court. To support the request, the board shall present to the fiscal court a report of the previous year's operation, a long range plan for natural resource development, and an annual plan of work. Should a fiscal court fail to approve a requested budget, it shall present a specific list of objections and suggested corrections to the board in writing and within a reasonable time.  If a budget request is not approved, the board may submit a revised budget request.  Funds for an approved budget shall be supplied either from general funds or from the levy of a millage tax on all real property within the boundaries of the county. The tax shall be collected in the same manner as other county taxes, and shall be credited to the board. The funds so collected shall be expended by the board for the employment of soil conservation aids and for other purposes directly associated with the program, including promotional activities, prize moneys, office equipment and supplies, and incidentals deemed necessary. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 272, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42i-5, 42i-7, 42i-8. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>