<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.655</section_number><catch_line>Education technology program. </catch_line><order_by>655</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To participate in the education technology funding program, a local public school district shall have an unmet technology need described in its local district technology plan and approved by the Kentucky Board of Education pursuant to its technology master plan, and shall match equally the amount of funds offered by the School Facilities Construction Commission for this purpose each biennium, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section. Technology approved for the Kentucky Education Technology System and included in the local district technology plan, which was acquired prior to April 3, 1992, and for which the district has an outstanding financial obligation, shall qualify for commission funding. This provision shall not apply to any purchases or contracts made between April 3, 1992, and the first offers of assistance recommended by the Council for Education Technology to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education. </section><section prefix="2">For fiscal year 1992-93, funding shall be allotted to districts without an approved plan upon the recommendation of the Council for Education Technology to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education. </section><section prefix="3">If a local board of education determines that for any reason the district's approved technology plan is grossly inconsistent with the administrative regulations governing the development of the plan, the local board may certify, by official action, the reason for the inconsistency and may request that the Department of Education reevaluate the technology plan of the district. After review of the data, the chief state school officer may require a reevaluation and the approval of a new technology plan certified prior to an official offer from the School Facilities Construction Commission. If the chief state school officer elects to recommend the new technology plan to the Kentucky Board of Education, the board shall notify the School Facilities Construction Commission of any change required in the offer of assistance for the district. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 2, effective April 3, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 28, (3) at 623.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (16) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note>(7/15/96).  Notwithstanding 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, references to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education in subsections (1) and (2) of this statute have been left unchanged because these references are historical in nature. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3362</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>