<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.500</section_number><catch_line>Annual review of program -- Referendum requirement -- Termination. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall review the assessment program annually. If, at the end of each year after the first year of the assessment program, the board determines that the producers in the referendum area representing fifty percent (50%) of the production of milk are not participating in the program, the commissioner shall then conduct a referendum among the producers in such area. If, upon such referendum, a majority of the producers in such area reject such program, it shall be terminated as at the end of the month in which such referendum for such area was conducted and held; otherwise such assessment program shall continue in force and effect.  </section><section prefix="2">If the certified commission, council, board, association, or other agency of producers expresses in writing its desire to the commissioner to discontinue the assessment program and terminate the same, the commissioner shall within fifteen (15) days following receipt of such request convene the board to review and act on such request. The board, after reviewing such request and conducting whatever proceedings are deemed appropriate and necessary in connection with such request, may terminate such program effective at the end of the month in which such board action is taken; and in this event the commissioner shall notify, by certified mail, the purchasers of such agricultural commodity of the termination of such program.  </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 46, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 77. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11686</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>