<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.605</section_number><catch_line>Sewage systems may become construction subdistricts, when -- Incorporated in district, when. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text>A sewage system owned by any municipality, political subdivision, or any other entity, public or private, may be made a construction subdistrict or incorporated into the district area by the board under the conditions of this section.  <section prefix="1">Any such system may be made a construction subdistrict only when:  <section prefix="a">Express, written consent of all bondholders and secured creditors has been obtained;  </section><section prefix="b">The governing body or owner of such district or system has consented in writing; and  </section><section prefix="c">The board has determined that the policy of KRS 220.010 to 220.540 will best be served by making such district or system a construction subdistrict.  </section></section><section prefix="2">When such district or system has been made a construction subdistrict under subsection (1), KRS 220.553 to 220.575 and KRS 220.583 to 220.587 shall not apply to it.  </section><section prefix="3">Any such system may be incorporated by the board into the district areas only when:  <section prefix="a">All debts of the system have been paid or an amount of either money or securities lawful as investments under KRS 386.020 has been laid aside to pay them by the governing body or owner of such district or system;  </section><section prefix="b">The governing body or owner of such system has consented in writing;  </section><section prefix="c">The board has determined that the policy of KRS 220.010 to 220.540 will best be served by incorporating such district or system into the district area.  </section></section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 85, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>