<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.375</section_number><catch_line>Termination of contract -- Civil action -- Liability of principal or sales representative. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a contract between a sales representative and a principal is terminated for any reason, the principal shall pay the sales representative all commissions accrued under the contract to the sales representative within thirty (30) days after the effective date of such termination. </section><section prefix="2">A principal who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be liable to the sales representative in a civil action for: <section prefix="a">All amounts due the sales representative, plus exemplary damages in an amount not to exceed two (2) times the amount of commissions due the sales representative; and </section><section prefix="b">Attorney's fees actually and reasonably incurred by the sales representative in the action and court costs. </section></section><section prefix="3">Where the court determines that an action brought by a sales representative against a principal under KRS 371.370 to 371.385 is frivolous, the sales representative shall be liable to the principal for attorney's fees actually and reasonably incurred by the principal in defending the action and court costs. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 371.370 to 371.385 shall invalidate or restrict any additional right or remedy available to a sales representative or preclude a sales representative from seeking to recover in an action on any other claim against a principal. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35254</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>