<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.760</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of 911 emergency telephone service by city, county, or urban-county government -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>760</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city, county, or urban-county government may establish 911 emergency telephone service upon approval of the governing body of the city, county, or urban-county government and may adopt regulations concerning the provision of this service by ordinance. </section><section prefix="2">Any city, county, or urban-county government, or any combination thereof, may with the approval of their governing bodies enter into an interlocal cooperation agreement creating a joint 911 emergency telephone service. </section><section prefix="3">The funds required by a city, county, or urban-county government to establish and operate 911 emergency telephone service, or to participate in joint service with other local governments, may be obtained through the levy of any special tax, license, or fee not in conflict with the Constitution and statutes of this state. The special tax, license, or fee may include a subscriber charge for 911 emergency telephone service that shall be levied on an individual exchange-line basis, limited to a maximum of twenty-five (25) exchange lines per account per government entity. Any private commercial telephone service or owner of a dispersed private telephone system (DPTS) that provides local and 911 emergency service to subscribers for compensation shall collect and remit the subscriber charge to the local government on the same basis as the primary local exchange carrier, except that this requirement shall not apply to a state agency that currently maintains an independent 911 system with its own public safety answering point. All revenues from a tax or fee expressly levied to fund 911 emergency services shall be expended solely for the establishment, operation, and maintenance of a 911 emergency communications system; this may include expenditures to train communications personnel and to inform the public of the availability and proper use of 911 service. </section><section prefix="4">The governing body may apply for and accept federal moneys and may accept contributions and donations from any source for the purpose of funding 911 emergency telephone service. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall preclude other means of establishing or funding a 911 emergency telephone service within any local area or exchange, nor require the operation of such service by any local government. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23499</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>