<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="433" order_by="433">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>433.873</section_number><catch_line>Wrongful disturbance or damage to cave surfaces or material found therein. </catch_line><order_by>873</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person, without the express, prior, written permission of the owner, to willfully and knowingly: <section prefix="a">Break, break off, crack, carve upon, write, burn, or otherwise mark upon, remove, or in any manner destroy, disturb, deface, mar or harm the surfaces of any cave or any material which may be found therein, notwithstanding whether such material is attached or broken, including speleothems, speleogens, and sedimentary deposits. The provisions of this section shall not prohibit minimal disturbance for scientific exploration. </section><section prefix="b">Break, force, tamper with or otherwise disturb a door, lock, gate, or other obstruction designed to control or prevent access to any cave, even though entrance thereto may not be gained. </section><section prefix="c">Place any gate or other obstruction which may restrict the movement of air or animals through such device. </section><section prefix="d">Deface, tamper with or remove a sign stating that a cave is posted or citing provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="e">Excavate, remove, destroy, injure, deface, or in any other manner disturb any burial grounds, historic or prehistoric resources, archaeological or paleontological site or any part thereof, including fossils, bones, relics, inscriptions, saltpeter workings, remains of historical human activity, or any other such features which may be found in any cave, except those caves owned by the Commonwealth or designated as Commonwealth archaeological sites or zones, and which are subject to the provisions of KRS 164.705 to 164.735. </section></section><section prefix="2">The entering or remaining in a cave which has not been posted by the owner shall not by itself constitute a violation of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>