<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44">CLAIMS UPON THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>44.045</section_number><catch_line>Motor vehicles, purchase for state use -- License plates -- Markings and administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A passenger motor vehicle or vehicles may be purchased by the Finance and Administration Cabinet for the use of the Governor and the Lieutenant Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Motor vehicles, including passenger motor vehicles, may be purchased by the Finance and Administration Cabinet as are deemed necessary by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet or by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet for the discharge of the authorized duties and functions of the various agencies of the state. The vehicles shall be used for official purposes only and for no other purposes. The assignment of passenger motor vehicles to specific individuals shall be discouraged but may be made upon approval by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet of a written request to make the assignment by the head of the agency involved. </section><section prefix="3">All motor vehicles purchased pursuant to this section shall be issued official license plates and shall bear on one (1) door on each side the great seal of the Commonwealth, and the words "For official use only." It shall not be necessary that the vehicles purchased pursuant to subsections (1), (4), and (5) of this section bear the seal and the words. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Revenue, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and the Department of Law may, upon approval by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet of a written request by the head of the agency involved, register a vehicle or vehicles under KRS 186.020 and be issued regular license plates. The vehicles shall be used for investigatory purposes only and for no other purposes. </section><section prefix="5">The Administrative Office of the Courts may register a vehicle or vehicles used by Justices and Judges of the Supreme Court and Court of Appeals under KRS 186.020 and be issued regular license plates. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet may adopt administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A necessary to govern the use of those state-owned vehicles acquired pursuant to the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="7">Any person violating subsections (2) and (4) of this section shall, on conviction thereof, be subject to the penalties prescribed in KRS 44.990. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 124, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(1). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section. (8/18/2011).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, relating to the reorganization of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in subsection (6) of this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22129</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>