<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="72" order_by="72">CORONERS, INQUESTS, AND MEDICAL EXAMINATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>72.450</section_number><catch_line>Disposal of body and valuables found thereon. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A coroner who has possession of a dead body or a part thereof shall make a bona fide attempt to notify the spouse, if any, or next of kin of the decedent's death. In the event the coroner is unable to locate the spouse, if any, or next of kin, he or she may cause the body to be buried at the expense of the fiscal court, consolidated local government, or urban-county government, whichever is appropriate. </section><section prefix="2">In the event the body is buried at public expense, the coroner shall take possession of all money or other property found on or belonging to the decedent and shall deliver same to the fiscal court, consolidated local government, or urban-county government, whichever is appropriate. Any money or other property found on the body of the decedent or belonging to him or her shall be delivered by the coroner to the fiscal court, consolidated local government, or urban-county government, whichever is appropriate, to help defray burial expenses. Any excess funds shall escheat to such governmental agency one (1) year thereafter. </section><section prefix="3">In lieu of having an unclaimed body buried at public expense, the coroner may deliver such body or part thereof to a state medical school in accordance with the provisions of KRS 311.300 to 311.350. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 74, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 14, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24323</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>