<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="518" order_by="518">MISCELLANEOUS CRIMES AFFECTING BUSINESSES, OCCUPATIONS, AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>518.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Benefit" means gain or advantage to the beneficiary or to a third person pursuant to the desire or consent of the beneficiary. </section><section prefix="2">"Event" means a sports contest or other public performance to which the general public is not admitted without consideration. </section><section prefix="3">"Public performance" means any form of entertainment other than a sports contest involving machines, persons, animals, or objects that is viewed by the public. </section><section prefix="4">"Sports contest" means any professional or amateur sport, athletic game or contest, or race or contest involving machines, persons, animals, or objects that is viewed by the public. </section><section prefix="5">"Sports official" means any person who acts or expects to act in a sports contest as an umpire, referee, or judge, or otherwise to officiate at a sports contest. </section><section prefix="6">"Sports participant" means any person who participates or expects to participate in a sports contest as a player, contestant, or member of a team, or as a coach, manager, trainer or other person directly associated with a player, contestant, or team. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 156, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19849</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>