<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.780</section_number><catch_line>Emergency repair, maintenance, and replacement account. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created within the capital construction fund the emergency repair, maintenance, and replacement account. The account shall consist of moneys appropriated to the fund by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="2">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may transfer money from the emergency repair, maintenance, and replacement account to the allotment account of an emergency repair, replacement, or maintenance project, for expenditure thereon, even though the specific project is not included in any branch budget bill enacted for that biennium. Moneys may be transferred from the emergency repair, maintenance, and replacement account to the allotment account of an emergency repair, replacement, or maintenance project only if no other funding source is available. </section><section prefix="3">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall report each transfer, including the necessity, purpose, and amount of the transfer, to the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee not later than thirty (30) days after the transfer. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 7, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 1, (5) at 655. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39787</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>