<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.450Fees</section_number><catch_line>and qualifications for licenses -- Annual renewal.   </catch_line><order_by>450Fees</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The board shall issue a probationary license to practice barbering to any person who: <section prefix="1">Is at least seventeen and one-half (17-1/2) years of age; </section><section prefix="2">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="3">Has graduated from high school or possesses a General Educational Development (GED) certificate or transcript from an issuing institution that is recognized by the educational authority in the state from which the diploma, certificate, or transcript is issued; </section><section prefix="4">Has graduated from a licensed school of barbering; </section><section prefix="5">Has satisfactorily passed the probationary examination prescribed by the barber board, which shall include a practical assessment of the applicant's skills, including but not limited to a haircut and a chemical application; and </section><section prefix="6">Has paid a fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50). </section></section><section prefix="b">A barber shall serve a probationary period of six (6) months of continuous service from the effective date of the license issued pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="c">In addition to the grounds for disciplinary action specified in KRS 317.590, the board may, during the probationary period, require a licensee to retake any part or all of the written or practical examination, or both. </section><section prefix="d">At the end of the probationary period, the board shall issue a license to practice barbering to a probationary licensee who has: <section prefix="1">Satisfactorily passed the barber examination prescribed by the board by administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A; and </section><section prefix="2">Complied with all other requirements of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="e">The board may issue a barber license by endorsement to a resident of another state, district, or territory within the United States of America upon payment of a fee not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250) and upon submission of satisfactory evidence that the requirements for licensure in the other state are substantially equivalent to the requirements of this state at the time of application. In the absence of the required equivalency, an applicant from another state, district, or territory within the United States of America, shall show proof of three (3) years or more experience immediately before making application and be currently licensed and in good standing with the state, district, or territory in which he or she is licensed. The board may also require an applicant under this section to pass a written and practical examination to establish equivalency. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Issue a license to operate a barber shop to any barber licensed under the provisions of this chapter upon application and payment of a fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50); </section><section prefix="b">Refuse to issue the license upon a failure of the licensed barber to comply with the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="c">Allow the licensed owner of a barber shop, which is licensed under this chapter, to rent or lease space in his or her barber shop to an independent contract owner; and </section><section prefix="d">Allow an unlicensed owner of a barber shop, which is licensed under this chapter and managed by a barber licensed under this chapter, to rent or lease space in his or her barber shop to an independent contract owner. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall issue a license to operate a school of barbering to any person, firm, or corporation who or which: <section prefix="a">Applies for a license upon forms furnished by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Has the equipment and facilities that may be required by administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="c">Has furnished adequate evidence to the board that: <section prefix="1">There is an intent to establish a bona fide school for the education and training of competent barbers; and </section><section prefix="2">A sufficient number of teachers licensed by the board will be employed to conduct the school, including at least one (1) teacher with a minimum of twelve (12) months' experience teaching in a barber school that includes administrative experience; and </section></section><section prefix="d">Pays a fee not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section></section><section prefix="4">The board shall issue a license to teach barbering to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Has graduated from high school, or possesses a General Educational Development (GED) certificate; </section><section prefix="c">Has been a licensed and practicing barber for at least eighteen (18) months; </section><section prefix="d">Has satisfactorily passed the examination prescribed by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations; and </section><section prefix="e">Has paid a fee not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100). </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall issue a license to any barber who holds an independent contract owner's license who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Has graduated from high school, or possesses a General Educational Development (GED) certificate; </section><section prefix="c">Is a licensed and practicing barber under this chapter; and </section><section prefix="d">Has paid a fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50). </section></section><section prefix="6">Applications for examination required in this section shall be accompanied by an examination fee as follows: <section prefix="a">Barber -- not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300); and </section><section prefix="b">Teaching barbering -- not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">On and after July 1, 2016, a license issued pursuant to this section shall expire on the first day of July next following the date of its issuance. A license shall be renewed on June 1 through July 1 of each year. </section><section prefix="b">Any license shall automatically be renewed by the board: <section prefix="1">Upon receipt of the application for renewal or duplicate renewal application form and the required annual renewal license fee submitted either in person or via written or electronic means; and </section><section prefix="2">If the applicant for renewal is otherwise in compliance with the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations of the board. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">The annual renewal license fee for each type of license renewal shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Barber -- not to exceed fifty dollars ($50); </section><section prefix="b">Teacher of barbering -- not to exceed fifty dollars ($50); </section><section prefix="c">Barber shop -- not to exceed fifty dollars ($50); </section><section prefix="d">Barber school -- not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150); and </section><section prefix="e">Independent contract owner -- not to exceed fifty dollars ($50). </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">The fee per year for the renewal of an expired license, if the period of expiration does not exceed five (5) years, shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Barber -- not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) plus lapse fees; </section><section prefix="2">Barber shop -- not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) plus lapse fees; </section><section prefix="3">Barber school -- not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) plus lapse fees; </section><section prefix="4">Teacher of barbering -- not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) plus lapse fees; and </section><section prefix="5">Independent contract owner - - not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25) plus lapse fees. </section></section><section prefix="b">An applicant who fails to renew a license within five (5) years of its expiration shall comply with the requirements for relicensure established by the board through promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 54. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 5, effective June 30, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006). A reference in subsection (10) of this statute to "subsection (7) of this section" has been changed by the Reviser of Statutes during codification to read "subsection (8) of this section." 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 5, added a new subsection (6) to this statute, resulting in the renumbering of subsequent subsections but did not make the necessary change to the internal reference in subsection (10). The Reviser of Statutes has made the conforming change under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>