<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.053</section_number><catch_line>Certification of teachers of exceptional children/communication disorders. </catch_line><order_by>053</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Education Professional Standards Board shall have the authority and responsibility to certify as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders, an individual who has: <section prefix="a">Completed an approved program of preparation that corresponds to the certificate; </section><section prefix="b">Achieved a passing score on an appropriate assessment as determined by the Education Professional Standards Board; </section><section prefix="c">Fulfilled other requirements for teacher certification as determined by the Education Professional Standards Board, in accordance with KRS Chapter 161 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; and </section><section prefix="d">Completed the requirements set forth in subsection (2) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Education Professional Standards Board shall issue two (2) levels of certification for teachers of exceptional children/communication disorders: <section prefix="a">Baccalaureate level certification shall be issued to a person who has: <section prefix="1">Completed an approved program of preparation leading to a bachelor's degree in speech-language pathology; </section><section prefix="2">Been granted licensure as a speech-language pathology assistant from the Kentucky Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology, under KRS Chapter 334A; and </section><section prefix="3">Completed the other requirements set forth in subsection (1) of this section; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Master's level certification shall be issued to a person who has: <section prefix="1">Completed an approved program of preparation leading to a master's degree in speech-language pathology; and </section><section prefix="2">Completed the other requirements specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">A person holding licensure through the Kentucky Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology as a speech-language pathology assistant, but not certified as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders, may: <section prefix="a">Continue to work in the public schools as a classified employee under the provisions of KRS Chapter 334A and administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology; or </section><section prefix="b">Pursue certification as a baccalaureate level teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders while working as a speech-language pathology assistant. </section></section><section prefix="4">Candidates for certification as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders shall participate in the teacher internship program under KRS 161.030. </section><section prefix="5">A bachelor's level teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders shall work under requirements for speech-language pathology assistants set forth in KRS Chapter 334A. </section><section prefix="6">The Education Professional Standards Board shall develop a policy through the promulgation of administrative regulations by June 30, 2001, to permit a speech-language pathology assistant with two (2) years or more of successful professional experience pursuing certification as a baccalaureate level teacher of exceptional children to: <section prefix="a">Substitute prior professional experience for student teaching requirements; and </section><section prefix="b">Substitute prior professional experience for beginning teacher internship requirements. </section></section><section prefix="7">A teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders shall receive salary and benefits, including membership in the Teachers' Retirement System, commensurate with his or her education, certification, and experience as prescribed by law. Years of experience as a speech-language pathology assistant shall be included in the calculation of all benefits, including membership in the Teachers' Retirement System, for individuals with baccalaureate level certification as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3842</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>