<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.502</section_number><catch_line>Health services in school setting -- Designated provider -- Liability protection. </catch_line><order_by>502</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Health services" means the provision of direct health care, including the administration of medication; the operation, maintenance, or health care through the use of medical equipment; or the administration of clinical procedures. "Health services" does not include first aid or emergency procedures; and </section><section prefix="b">"School employee" means an employee of the public schools of this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">Health services shall be provided, within the health care professional's current scope of practice, in a school setting by: <section prefix="a">A physician who is licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 311; </section><section prefix="b">An advanced practice registered nurse, registered nurse, or licensed practical nurse who is licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 314; </section><section prefix="c">A nonlicensed health technician that has the administration of health services in his or her contract or job description as a job responsibility and who is delegated responsibility to perform the health service by a physician, advanced practice registered nurse, or registered nurse and has been trained and approved in writing by the delegating physician or delegating nurse for delegable health services; or </section><section prefix="d">A school employee who is delegated responsibility to perform the health service by a physician, advanced practice registered nurse, or registered nurse; and <section prefix="1">Has been trained by the delegating physician or delegating nurse for the specific health service, if that health service is one that could be delegated by the physician or nurse within his or her scope of practice; and </section><section prefix="2">Has been approved in writing by the delegating physician or delegating nurse. The approval shall state that the school employee consents to perform the health service when the employee does not have the administration of health services in his or her contract or job description as a job responsibility, possesses sufficient training and skills, and has demonstrated competency to safely and effectively perform the health service. The school employee shall acknowledge receipt of training by signing the approval form. A copy of the approval form shall be maintained in the student's record and the personnel file of the school employee. A delegation to a school employee under this paragraph shall be valid only for the current school year. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">If no school employee has been trained and delegated responsibility to perform a health service, the school district shall make any necessary arrangement for the provision of the health service to the student in order to prevent a loss of a health service from affecting the student's attendance or program participation. The school district shall continue with this arrangement until appropriate school personnel are delegated the responsibility for health care in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">A school employee who has been properly delegated responsibility for performing a medical procedure under this section shall act as an agent of the school and be granted liability protection under the Federal Paul P. Coverdell Teacher Liability Protection Act of 2001, Pub. L. No. 107-110, unless the claimant establishes by clear and convincing evidence that harm was proximately caused by an act or omission of the school employee that constitutes negligence, willful or criminal misconduct, or a conscious, flagrant indifference to the rights and safety of the individual harmed. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to deny a student his or her right to attend public school and to receive public school services, or to deny, prohibit, or limit the administration of emergency first aid or emergency procedures. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective March 5, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 29, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> March 5, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42933</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>