<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.6-020</section_number><catch_line>Terms of class or series determined by board of directors -- Articles of amendment. </catch_line><order_by>6-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the articles of incorporation so provide, the board of directors may determine, in whole or in part, the preferences, limitations, and relative rights, within the limits set forth in KRS 271B.6-010, of: <section prefix="a">Any class of shares before the issuance of any shares of that class; or </section><section prefix="b">One (1) or more series within a class before the issuance of any shares of that series. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each series of a class shall be given a distinguishing designation. </section><section prefix="3">All shares of a series shall have preferences, limitations, and relative rights identical with those of other shares of the same series and, except to the extent otherwise provided in the description of the series, with those of other series of the same class. </section><section prefix="4">Before issuing any shares of a class or series created under this section, the corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of State for filing articles of amendment, which are effective without shareholder action, that set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation; </section><section prefix="b">The text of the amendment determining the terms of the class or series of shares; </section><section prefix="c">The date it was adopted; and </section><section prefix="d">A statement that the amendment was duly adopted by the board of directors. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board of directors may adopt articles of amendment without shareholder action to make any of the following changes to a class or series created under this section: <section prefix="a">Increase the number of shares of a series but not above the total number of authorized and unissued shares of the class; </section><section prefix="b">Decrease the number of shares of a series but not below the number of shares of the series then issued and outstanding; </section><section prefix="c">Amend the designation, preferences, limitations, or relative rights of the shares of a class or series if no shares of the class or series are then issued or outstanding; or </section><section prefix="d">Eliminate the designation of, and all references to, a series from the articles of incorporation if no shares of the series are then issued and outstanding. </section></section><section prefix="6">If an amendment reduces the number of shares of a series, or eliminates a series, the shares previously subject to issuance in the series shall return to the status they had before the creation of the series. </section><section prefix="7">Articles of amendment adopted pursuant to subsection (5) of this section shall be delivered to the Secretary of State for filing and shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation; </section><section prefix="b">The designation of the class or series subject to the amendment; </section><section prefix="c">The text of the amendment changing the class or series; </section><section prefix="d">The date the amendment was adopted; and </section><section prefix="e">A statement that the amendment was duly adopted by the board of directors. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 34, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13337</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>