<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.030</section_number><catch_line>Assumption or use of title, designation, or abbreviation to create impression of certification or licensure prohibited -- Powers of certified or licensed appraiser -- Appraiser for Transportation Cabinet – Prohibition against certain activities by unlicensed persons.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful, unless certified or licensed by the board, for any person to: <section prefix="a">Assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression that he or she holds a license or certificate issued by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Describe or refer to any appraisal or evaluation of real estate by the term, "state certified," "state licensed," or words of substantially similar meaning; or </section><section prefix="c">Assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression of certification or licensure by the state as a real estate appraiser firm, partnership, or corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">A certificate holder or licensee shall not assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression of certification or licensure by the board other than the correct type of certification or licensure. </section><section prefix="3">Each certificate holder or licensee who is a resident of Kentucky shall have and maintain a definite place of business in this state, a current e-mail address, and a current telephone number. A nonresident is not required to maintain an active place of business in this state if a definite place of business is maintained in the state where the nonresident resides. A nonresident shall maintain a current e-mail address and a current telephone number. </section><section prefix="4">Failure by a certificate holder or licensee to notify the board of any change of business address, change of company name, change of surname, change of phone number, or change of e-mail address within thirty (30) days of the change shall result in a penalty not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200). </section><section prefix="5">In the case of the death of a certificate holder or licensee, the board may, in its sound discretion, permit a suitable individual to complete the affairs and appraisal assignments of the deceased. </section><section prefix="6">For any employee of the Transportation Cabinet whose job description includes real estate appraisals which require certification, the Transportation Cabinet shall bear the costs of initial application, examination, continued education, and annual renewal. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Those Transportation Cabinet employees serving as right-of-way agents or supervisors, who actually perform on-site appraisals as part of their job descriptions and who have obtained an appraiser certification under the provisions of KRS 324A.010 to 324A.090, shall receive a five percent (5%) salary increase effective January 1 following certification. Those right-of-way agents or supervisors who received certification prior to January 1, 1991, shall receive the salary increase effective January 1, 1991. </section><section prefix="b">The salary increases provided for in subsection (a) of this section shall be made within existing Transportation Cabinet appropriations. </section></section><section prefix="8">A person shall not provide appraisal, appraisal review, or appraisal consulting assignments or perform any of the duties usually performed by a licensed or certified real property appraiser for a federally related transaction unless the person at the time holds a license or certification of real property appraiser issued and validly existing under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, as provided in this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 3, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42096</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>