<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.673</section_number><catch_line>Administration regulations -- Acupuncture Advisory Committee -- Membership -- Meetings -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>673</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to the licensure and regulation, including temporary licensure, of acupuncturists. Regulation of acupuncture includes continuing education requirements and fee schedules. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall establish an eight (8) member Acupuncture Advisory Committee that shall review and make recommendations to the board regarding matters relating to acupuncturists that come before the board, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Applications for acupuncturist licensure; </section><section prefix="b">Licensure renewal requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Fees; </section><section prefix="d">Applicable standards of practice for acupuncture practitioners; </section><section prefix="e">Continuing education requirements; </section><section prefix="f">Rotating appointment of committee members; </section><section prefix="g">Disciplinary actions, at the request of a panel of the board; and </section><section prefix="h">Promulgation and revision of administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the Acupuncturist Advisory Committee shall be appointed by the board for four (4) year terms, on a rotating basis to provide for continuity, and shall consist of: <section prefix="a">One (1) member of the board; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) physicians licensed by the board whose practices include the use of acupuncture; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member of the public who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice of acupuncture; and </section><section prefix="d">Four (4) acupuncture practitioners licensed by the board. </section></section><section prefix="4">The chairperson and secretary of the committee shall be elected by a majority vote of the committee members annually. The president shall be responsible for presiding over meetings that shall be held on a regular basis, but no less than two (2) times each calendar year. Additional meetings may be held each calendar year at the call of the chairperson or by the written request of at least three (3) committee members. The secretary shall keep a record of the minutes of the committee's meetings. Five (5) members of the committee shall constitute a quorum to conduct business. </section><section prefix="5">Members shall receive reimbursement for expenditures relating to attendance at committee meetings consistent with state policies for reimbursement of travel expenses for state employees. </section><section prefix="6">The board may remove any member on the member's request or for poor attendance at committee meetings, neglect of duties, or malfeasance in office. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43052</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>