<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="168" order_by="168">EDUCATIONAL TELEVISION </unit></structure><section_number>168.040</section_number><catch_line>Membership of authority. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall consist of nine (9) members, as follows: </section> The chief state school officer, ex officio, who shall initially serve as temporary chairman and shall call and preside over the organizational meeting or meetings until the members of the authority shall elect a chairman from among their number; a member of the staff or personnel of the department elected by the board upon recommendation of the chief state school officer as being qualified to serve as liaison and coordinator between the authority and the department on matters of curriculum, and his term shall be the same as that of the chief state school officer by whom he is recommended, but terminable by the board in the event he is transferred to other duties in the department, and automatically terminated in the event of his severance from the department for any reason; a representative of the University of Kentucky and a representative of the state universities to be elected by the Council on Postsecondary Education; and five (5) additional members appointed by the Governor who need possess no special or prescribed qualifications except that they shall be citizens of Kentucky. <section prefix="2">Effective at 11:59 p.m. on June 30, 1994, all terms of gubernatorial appointees to the authority shall expire. Effective July 1, 1994, five (5) appointees nominated pursuant to KRS 164.005 and appointed by the Governor shall become members of the authority. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 143, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2, effective March 22, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 279, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 4. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4 (first paragraph). </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>