<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 42.010. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in KRS 42.010, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means a basic unit of administrative organization of the Finance and Administration Cabinet designated by statute or by statutorily authorized executive action as a "department." A department may contain offices, divisions, or both, that report to it; </section><section prefix="2">"Office" means a basic unit of administrative organization of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. An office may or may not report directly to the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. An office may contain offices, divisions, or both, that report to it; </section><section prefix="3">"Division" means a major branch of a department or office established by statute or by statutorily authorized administrative action; </section><section prefix="4">"Administrative body" includes authority, board, bureau, interstate compact, commission, committee, conference, council, and any other form or organization in the executive branch of government, but does not include "office," "department," "program cabinet" or "division"; </section><section prefix="5">"Program cabinet" means a group of departments, or departments and commissions, or departments and offices, or other administrative bodies, designated by statute or statutorily authorized executive action as a "program cabinet." </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 48, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>