<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.240</section_number><catch_line>State Emergency Operations Center -- Agency representatives. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The division shall maintain the State Emergency Operations Center and those alternate locations deemed necessary, and shall activate the State Emergency Operations Center when deemed necessary by the director, the Adjutant General, or the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Each cabinet of state government, and each independent agency of state government, and other organizations provided for in the Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan shall immediately send a designated person to the State Emergency Operations Center upon request of the director, during a time of emergency or disaster or the threatened or impending happening of such an incident. They shall remain at the State Emergency Operations Center until relieved and replaced, unless released by the director. </section><section prefix="3">Persons representing agencies of state government or other organizations assigned to the State Emergency Operations Center during times of emergency or disaster or the threatened or impending happening thereof may obligate the funds, equipment, and personnel of the organization which they represent, and make decisions on behalf of the organization which they represent. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21718</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>