<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.040</section_number><catch_line>Filing and approval of articles -- When corporation may begin business.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The incorporators shall execute triplicate originals of the articles of incorporation that satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.2-010 to 14A.2-150, and each incorporator shall acknowledge each triplicate original before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments of deeds. They shall then file the triplicate originals, together with the certificate of acknowledgment, in the office of the Secretary of State. If the Secretary of State finds the articles to be legal and valid, he shall immediately indorse his approval on each of the triplicate originals, retain, record and file one (1) triplicate original in his office, and deliver the other two (2) triplicate originals, with his approval indorsed thereon, to the incorporators. The incorporators shall then file one (1) approved triplicate original in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the principal office of the corporation is to be located. </section><section prefix="2">As soon as the Secretary of State has filed the articles of incorporation, the proposed corporation shall be a body politic and corporate and may transact business in its corporate name. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 81, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 3, effective June 21, 1974. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 883j-5. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>