<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.328</section_number><catch_line>Appeal by the state.   </catch_line><order_by>328</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">In a trial by court-martial in which a punitive discharge may be adjudged, the state may appeal the following, other than a finding of not guilty with respect to the charge or specification by the members of the court-martial, or by a judge in a bench trial so long as it is not made in reconsideration: <section prefix="1">An order or ruling of the military judge which terminates the proceedings with respect to the charge or specification; </section><section prefix="2">An order or ruling which excludes evidence that is substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding; </section><section prefix="3">An order or ruling which directs the disclosure of classified information; </section><section prefix="4">An order or ruling which imposes sanctions for nondisclosure of classified information; </section><section prefix="5">A refusal of the military judge to issue a protective order sought by the state to prevent the disclosure of classified information; and </section><section prefix="6">A refusal by the military judge to enforce an order described in subparagraph 5. of this paragraph that has previously been issued by the appropriate authority. </section></section><section prefix="b">An appeal of an order or ruling may not be taken unless the trial counsel provides the military judge with written notice of appeal from the order or ruling within seventy-two (72) hours of the order or ruling. The notice shall include a certification by the trial counsel that the appeal is not taken for the purpose of delay and, if the order or ruling appealed is one which excludes evidence, that the evidence excluded is substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding. </section><section prefix="c">An appeal under this section shall be diligently prosecuted as provided by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">An appeal under this section shall be forwarded to the court prescribed in KRS 35.333. In ruling on an appeal under this section, that court may act only with respect to matters of law. </section><section prefix="3">Any period of delay resulting from an appeal under this section shall be excluded in deciding any issue regarding denial of a speedy trial unless an appropriate authority determines that the appeal was filed solely for the purpose of delay with the knowledge that it was totally frivolous and without merit. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 67, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>