<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.305</section_number><catch_line>Alteration or removal of motor vehicle identification number prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall intentionally remove, deface, cover, destroy, alter, or obscure any vehicle identification number, or other distinguishing number, of a motor vehicle or trailer or any part thereof in this state, without written authorization from the Department of Kentucky State Police, nor shall any person place or stamp, in place of the original manufacturer's serial, motor, or other number or mark upon a vehicle, any number except one assigned thereto by the Department of Vehicle Regulation under the provisions of KRS 186.1911 or authorized agency of another state. </section><section prefix="2">This section does not prohibit the restoration by an owner of the original vehicle identification number when the restoration is authorized by the Department of Kentucky State Police, nor prevent any manufacturer from placing in the ordinary course of business numbers or marks upon new motor vehicles or new parts thereof. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to a scrap processor who loads, unloads, crushes, flattens, destroys, grinds up, handles, shreds, or otherwise reduces a motor vehicle or motor vehicle part into metallic scrap for the purpose of recycling such metallic content. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 207, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 58, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6198</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>