<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.2351</section_number><catch_line>Operation and maintenance of amusement rides and attractions -- Required submission of service manuals and records -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>2351</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All amusement rides and attractions shall be operated and maintained according to the most stringent specifications and recommendations of: <section prefix="a">The manufacturer's specifications and recommendations; </section><section prefix="b">The most recent National Electrical Code and National Fire Protection Association codes and standards; or </section><section prefix="c">Any other applicable state or federal laws. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations relating to the use of replacement parts for amusement rides and attractions. </section><section prefix="3">Amusement ride and attraction owners shall provide the department with the most recent manuals, service bulletins, or service and inspection records upon request by a department inspector. If any of these items are not immediately available to an inspector, the inspector may issue a stop operation order or postpone the application process until the materials are made available. Any department inspector may issue a stop operation order if the inspector finds that the provisions of the manuals or service bulletins are not being followed. </section><section prefix="4">The department may promulgate administrative regulations relating to amusement rides and attractions in accordance with the latest ASTM standards. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11613</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>