<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.420</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of council. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text>The duties and functions of the council shall be to: <section prefix="1">Counsel with the Commissioner of Agriculture on matters pertaining to agricultural and agri-business development and the marketing and distribution of agricultural products. </section><section prefix="2">Promote, to the fullest extent, coordination and cooperation among public and private agencies and organizations so that each may make the maximum contribution toward the attainment of a greater and improved agricultural economy. </section><section prefix="3">Make investigations, undertake such studies, and prepare such reports and recommendations regarding the elimination or alleviation of specific problems affecting farm gross and net income, the improvement of all phases of agriculture, and any other matters necessary and incidental to the stimulation of the development of a statewide agricultural program for acceleration of farm income. </section><section prefix="4">Promote the production and marketing of Kentucky farm products and services, on local, state, national and international levels, through research, education, and other promotional activities. </section><section prefix="5">Contract from time to time as appropriate with experts and consultants who may be utilized as deemed necessary and make other necessary purchases. </section><section prefix="6">Hold public and private hearings for the purpose of furthering the objectives of the council's programs. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 37, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 19, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 4. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 4(6) </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><former-history>  Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42c-31. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 247.420:</former-history-former-name><note>Former KRS 247.420, "Functions of commission", was recodified from 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942 from Ky. Stat. sec. 42c-31. -- This section was considered obsolete and was omitted from the 1948 edition of the KRS and subsequent editions. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11647</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>