<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.652</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>652</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall be governed by a board of directors. The board shall make policy, which shall be implemented. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the board shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">A member of the county legislative body of Sumner County, Tennessee, and Simpson County, Kentucky, chosen by their respective legislative bodies; </section><section prefix="b">The mayors of the cities of Portland, Tennessee, and Franklin, Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">A member of the city legislative bodies from the cities of Portland, Tennessee, and Franklin, Kentucky, chosen by the respective legislative bodies; </section><section prefix="d">A member of an industrial foundation board or equivalent, if one (1) exists, from Portland, Tennessee, and Franklin, Kentucky, as appointed by the respective boards; and </section><section prefix="e">A commissioner or designee chosen by the board of commissioners of the Simpson County water district. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Each local governmental entity which is authorized to designate one (1) of its members for membership on the board shall designate the member by an appropriate resolution or ordinance. </section><section prefix="b">Each participating governmental entity shall adopt an appropriate resolution or ordinance which shall state the intention of the local entity to participate in the authority; the resolution or ordinance shall also include a recitation of the participating entity's statutory authority for participation. </section><section prefix="c">The authority shall not convene or conduct business until the requirements of this subsection have been met. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any elected official's or his designated alternate's position on the board shall run concurrent with the official's elected term. </section><section prefix="5">Any nonelected official shall have a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="6">If a vacancy occurs on the board, the position shall be filled in the same manner as set forth in the original appointment. A vacancy shall occur when any board member no longer meets the requirements for appointment to the board. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall meet annually at a time and place designated by the board. The time, place, and date of this meeting shall be published in newspapers of general circulation in Sumner and Simpson Counties at least seven (7) days prior to the meeting. </section><section prefix="8">The board at their annual meeting shall adopt or amend bylaws, if any, adopt an annual budget, elect officers, and adopt any policies and work programs necessary for the operation of the authority and fulfillment of the purposes of the authority. </section><section prefix="9">Fifty percent (50%) of the membership of the board shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of the business of the authority. </section><section prefix="10">The act of fifty percent (50%) plus one (1) of all those voting shall be the act of the board for the execution of business. </section><section prefix="11">The board at its annual meeting shall elect as authority officers a chairman, vice chairman, and a secretary-treasurer who shall serve terms of one (1) year. The chairman shall alternate between members from Tennessee and Kentucky. When a member from one (1) of the states sits as chairman, no more than one (1) other member from the state can sit as vice chairman or secretary-treasurer. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>