<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.670</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 131.670 to 131.676. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text>As used in KRS 131.670 to 131.676: <section prefix="1">"Debt" means a liquidated debt as defined in KRS 45.241(1)(b); </section><section prefix="2">"Debtor" means any person liable for a debt; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="4">"Delinquent taxpayer" means a person who has been assessed for a tax, the collection of which is administered by the Department of Revenue, and who has not sought administrative or judicial review of the assessment as provided in KRS 131.110, or who has sought but exhausted all administrative and judicial review so that the assessment is final, due, and owing. For a person to be considered a "delinquent taxpayer," the following conditions must also be met: <section prefix="a">The tax remains unpaid after thirty (30) days from demand for payment by the department; and </section><section prefix="b">The person is not making current timely installment payments on the tax liability under agreement with the department; and </section></section><section prefix="5">"Financial institution" means: <section prefix="a">A depository institution and an institution-affiliated party as defined in 12 U.S.C. sec. 1813(c) and (u); </section><section prefix="b">Any federal or state credit union, including an institution-affiliated party as </section>defined in 12 U.S.C. secs. 1752 and 1786(r); or <section prefix="c">Any benefit association, insurance company, safe deposit company, money market mutual fund, brokerage firm, trust company, or similar entity authorized to do business in the Commonwealth. </section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XVII, sec. 1, effective April 25, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> April 25, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28191</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>