<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.752</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Gas Pipeline Authority established -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>752</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established within the Finance and Administration Cabinet a Kentucky Gas Pipeline Authority composed of the following nine (9) members: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="d">A member designated by the Kentucky Oil and Gas Association; </section><section prefix="e">A member designated by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers who shall have experience in oil and gas pipeline construction; </section><section prefix="f">A member designated by the Kentucky Gas Association representing a natural gas distribution company with a minimum annual throughput of ten billion (10,000,000,000) cubic feet; </section><section prefix="g">A citizen member appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="h">Two (2) nonvoting legislator members, one (1) appointed by the President of the Senate and one (1) by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. </section></section><section prefix="2">Members described in paragraphs (d), (e), (f), and (g) of subsection (1) of this section shall begin their terms on August 1, 2005. The initial terms of the members described in paragraphs (d) and (e) shall be two (2) years. The initial terms of the members described in paragraphs (f) and (g) shall be three (3) years and four (4) years, respectively. All subsequent terms for those members shall be four (4) years. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies occurring during the term of any member shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="4">The nine (9) members of the authority and their successors shall be a body corporate and politic, with perpetual succession, constituting a public corporation and a governmental agency and instrumentality of the Commonwealth. The authority shall have the power, in its corporate name, to contract and be contracted with, acquire and convey property, sue and be sued, have and use a corporate seal, and exercise all of the usual powers of corporations not inconsistent with the authority's specifically enumerated powers. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties under KRS 353.750 to 353.776. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall serve as chair, and the members of the authority shall elect a vice chair from their membership and appoint a secretary. </section><section prefix="7">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall designate an employee of his or her cabinet to serve as treasurer of the authority. The treasurer shall give bond to the authority for a faithful accounting for all funds coming into his or her custody, in the amount the authority may prescribe, drawn upon a surety company qualified to do business in the Commonwealth. The premium shall be paid by the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="8">The authority shall establish and maintain an office and keep accurate and complete records of the authority's actions and proceedings, which shall be available for public inspection in accordance with KRS 61.870 to 61.884. The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall provide the funds, staff, facilities, and materials required by the authority in the conduct of its duties and functions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1915, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 69, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33151</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>