<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.022</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of city's established population criteria not lost because of subsequent census population change or court judgment.   </catch_line><order_by>022</order_by><text>Once a city meets the population criteria established in KRS 67.750, 82.095, 92.281, 96.060, 96.189, 97.120, 99.615, 100.137, 100.209, 100.217, 100.253, 241.160, 242.125, 242.127, 242.1292, 243.072, 243.230, 244.290, 244.480, 244.540, and 281.014 under the most recent federal decennial census and has exercised the powers and duties pursuant to the section, the city shall not thereafter lose the ability to exercise the powers and duties provided in those sections because of an increase or decrease in population in a subsequent federal decennial census, or because of a judgment of a court pursuant to a petition to certify a city’s population as different than the federal decennial census made under KRS 81.006. The city shall be permitted to continue to exercise the powers and duties under the applicable section as if it still meets the population requirements provided by the section. However, if there is a conflict between a power or privilege established under a lower population limit and a higher population limit, then the city shall follow the provisions required by the higher population limit. </text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43595</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>