<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.140</section_number><catch_line>Form of application -- Change of address -- Lost or destroyed license -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The application for a commercial driver's license or commercial driver's instruction <section prefix="a">The full legal name, including nicknames, and present Kentucky resident </section><section prefix="b">A physical description of the applicant including sex, height, weight, eye </section><section prefix="c">The applicant's date of birth; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant's Social Security number; </section><section prefix="e">The applicant's signature; </section><section prefix="f">Certifications including those required by Title 49, Code of Federal </section><section prefix="g">A consent to release driving record information; </section><section prefix="h">A valid Class D operator's license issued pursuant to KRS 186.412; </section><section prefix="i">A birth certificate if the applicant does not hold a valid operator's license at </section><section prefix="j">The name of every jurisdiction in which the applicant has previously been </section><section prefix="k">Any other information required by the cabinet. </section></section>permit shall include the following information: address of the applicant. If the applicant's mailing address is different from the resident address, the mailing address shall also be included. If the applicant is not a resident, the application shall include the person's resident address in the person's state of domicile and the address of the Kentucky driver training school where the applicant is currently enrolled; color, and race; Regulations, secs. 383.71, 383.73, and 384.206, as adopted by the cabinet; the time of application; licensed to drive any type of motor vehicle during the ten (10) year period immediately preceding the date of the application; and <section prefix="2">The cabinet or state police may require any other information needed in order to process the application. </section><section prefix="3">When the holder of a commercial driver's license changes his or her name or residence, the information shall be reported to the cabinet within ten (10) days. The holder of a Class A, B, or C license shall make an application for a duplicate license within thirty (30) days of changing his name or address. </section><section prefix="4">Any person whose commercial driver's license has been legitimately lost or destroyed shall make an application for a duplicate: <section prefix="a">A person applying for the first duplicate within the time period for which the original license was issued, shall apply in the office of the circuit clerk in the county where the person resides. The person shall provide the clerk with proof of the person's identity and a notarized affidavit with a raised seal explaining in detail the loss or destruction of the original license. </section><section prefix="b">A person applying for a second or subsequent duplicate within the time period for which the original license was issued, shall apply to the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office. The person shall provide the cabinet with proof of the person's identity and a notarized affidavit with a raised seal explaining in detail the loss or destruction of the previous duplicate issued. The Transportation Cabinet shall, within thirty (30) days of receipt of the application, review the person's proof of identity and affidavit and determine if the person will be issued a duplicate. </section></section><section prefix="5">A person who is a resident of this state shall not drive a commercial motor vehicle under the authority of a commercial driver's license issued by another jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who knowingly falsifies information or certifications required to obtain a commercial driver's license, a commercial driver's license permit, or a duplicate commercial driver's license subsequent to an administrative hearing conducted in accordance with KRS 186.570, shall be subject to suspension, revocation, or cancellation of his commercial driver's license for a period of at least sixty (60) consecutive days. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 6, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 209, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 14, effective January 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14473</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>