<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-020</section_number><catch_line>Officers -- Executive committee. </catch_line><order_by>10-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall be the chairman of the board and upon his absence the secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet shall serve as chairman. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall elect from among the private sector members a vice chairman of the board. The initial term of office for the vice chairman shall expire December 31, 1994, and the subsequent terms of office of the vice chairman shall be for a period of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the absence of both the Governor and the secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet, the vice chairman shall serve as chairman. </section><section prefix="4">The board may establish an executive committee consisting of the chairman, the vice chairman, the secretary of the cabinet, and not more than three (3) additional board members selected jointly by the chairman and vice chairman. The executive committee shall have such authority as the board delegates to it, except that the board shall not delegate to the executive committee the authority to take actions requiring approval by a majority of the entire board under KRS 154.10-010(10). </section><section prefix="5">The secretary and other officers and employees of the cabinet shall not be required to disclose confidential information concerning existing businesses or business prospects with which the board or cabinet is dealing, including the identity of the businesses, to members of the board other than the executive committee. The executive committee shall provide advice and assistance to the secretary in negotiations with existing and prospective businesses. In the event the cabinet enters into an agreement with a business entity which requires approval by the General Assembly, the agreement shall be presented by the secretary to the board, which shall make a recommendation of approval or disapproval of the agreement to the General Assembly. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2599</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>