<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 198B.140, 198B.6671, or 198B.6672, the Uniform State Building Code, the Uniform State Residential Code, or any directive or order issued pursuant thereto, shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). Each day the violation continues shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 198B.310 to 198B.330 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or be imprisoned for not more than one (1) year, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 198B.410 to 198B.540, or regulation issued thereunder, shall be fined a sum of five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 198B.550 to 198B.630 or 198B.6401 to 198B.6417 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). Each day the violation continues shall constitute a separate offense. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 10, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 65, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>.  Although KRS 198B.990 was included in Acts 1982, ch. 308, sec. 7, the amended language was deleted by committee amendment.  (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 10, to be effective July 1, 2008, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be July 1, 2010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41125</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>