<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVII" order_by="37">SPECIAL PROCEEDINGS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="416" order_by="416">EMINENT DOMAIN </unit></structure><section_number>416.610</section_number><catch_line>Trial by court on pleadings -- Interlocutory judgment. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After the owner has been summoned twenty (20) days, the court shall examine the report of the commissioners to determine whether it conforms to the provisions of KRS 416.580.  If the report of the commissioners is not in the proper form the court shall require the commissioners to make such corrections as are necessary.  </section><section prefix="2">If no answer or other pleading is filed by the owner or owners putting in issue the right of the petitioner to condemn the property or the use and occupation thereof sought to be condemned, the court shall enter an interlocutory judgment which shall contain, in substance:  <section prefix="a">A finding that the petitioner has the right, under the provisions of KRS 416.550 to 416.670 and other applicable law to condemn the property or the use and occupation thereof;  </section><section prefix="b">A finding that the report of the commissioners conforms to the provisions of KRS 416.580;  </section><section prefix="c">An authorization to take possession of the property for the purposes and under the conditions and limitations, if any, set forth in the petition upon payment to the owner or to the clerk of the court the amount of the compensation awarded by the commissioners;  </section><section prefix="d">Proper provision for the conveyance of the title to the land and material, to the extent condemned, as adjudged therein in the event no exception is taken as provided in KRS 416.620(1).  </section></section><section prefix="3">Any exception from such interlocutory judgment by either party or both parties shall be confined solely to exceptions to the amount of compensation awarded by the commissioners.  </section><section prefix="4">If the owner has filed answer or pleading putting in issue the right of the petitioner to condemn the property or use and occupation thereof sought to be  condemned, the court shall, without intervention of jury, proceed forthwith to hear and determine whether or not the petitioner has such right.  If the court determines that petitioner has such rights, an interlocutory judgment, as provided for in subsection (2) of this section, shall be entered.  If the court determines that petitioner does not have such right, it shall enter a final judgment which shall contain, in substance:  <section prefix="a">A finding that the report of the commissioners conforms to the provisions of KRS 416.580;  </section><section prefix="b">A finding that the petitioner is not authorized to condemn the property or the use and occupation thereof for the purposes and under the conditions and limitations set forth in the petition, stating the particular ground or grounds on which the petitioner is not so authorized;  </section><section prefix="c">An order dismissing the petition and directing the petitioner to pay  all costs.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 9. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17966</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>