<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-315</section_number><catch_line>Center for Pollution Prevention -- Board of directors -- Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>46-315</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be established a Center for Pollution Prevention, which shall be a technical information and assistance office to be located at a state-owned university, which shall facilitate and promote the commercial implementation of pollution prevention technologies and procedures by providing technical and financial assistance, as available, to business and industry. The center shall be governed by a board of directors representing the following organizations: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or a designee of the secretary; </section><section prefix="b">The dean of the University of Louisville School of Engineering or a designee of the dean; </section><section prefix="c">The dean of the University of Kentucky School of Engineering or a designee of the dean; </section><section prefix="d">A representative of the industrial community appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="e">A representative of the environmental protection community appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="f">A representative of local government appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="g">An environmental engineer appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="h">An at-large member appointed by the Governor representing an industrial facility; </section><section prefix="i">An at-large member appointed by the Governor representing an agricultural producer; and </section><section prefix="j">An at-large member appointed by the Governor representing the public. </section></section><section prefix="2">Board members may designate proxies who shall have voting privileges at board meetings. The members identified in subsection (1)(a) to (1)(d) of this section shall serve as permanent members of the board. Of the six (6) members identified in subsections (1)(e) to (j) of this section, two (2) shall continue in office for two (2) years, two (2) shall continue in office for three (3) years, and two (2) shall continue in office for four (4) years, as the Governor designates. At the expiration of the original terms and for all succeeding terms, the Governor shall appoint a successor to the board for three (3) years. Members may be reappointed. The Governor shall appoint a chairperson for the board. </section><section prefix="3">Meetings of the board shall be held at least quarterly, but may be held more frequently if necessary. The chair or a majority of members may call a special meeting. Five (5) members of the board shall constitute a quorum for doing business. Each member shall have one (1) vote and a majority vote of the members present shall control on all questions. No member shall receive a salary, fee, or other remuneration for services as a member of the board, but each member shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of the member's duties. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Formulate policies and procedures necessary to carry out the purposes stated in KRS 224.46-305; </section><section prefix="b">Promulgate administrative regulations solely to carry out the purposes of KRS 224.46-320 to assure the proper distribution of funds available to the center; </section><section prefix="c">Review and authorize pollution prevention projects and programs to be undertaken and financed pursuant to KRS 224.46-305, 224.46-320, 224.46-330, and 224.46-580; </section><section prefix="d">Review and approve all progress and final research reports on projects authorized by KRS 224.46-305 and 224.46-320; </section><section prefix="e">Assure that funds available to the center are not diverted to any uses inconsistent with KRS 224.46-305 to 224.46-335 and KRS 224.46-580, and that all authorized projects are directed toward improvement of the environment, specifically toward pollution prevention and toward preserving and strengthening industry in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="f">Provide to the Governor and the General Assembly an annual report showing the status of funds appropriated for the purposes of KRS 224.46-305 to 224.46-335 and KRS 224.46-580 for pollution prevention and progress of the board in terms of its research and pollution prevention technology implementation efforts; </section><section prefix="g">Advise the Governor and the General Assembly each year of the need for continuation of the center and its board through levy of the hazardous waste assessment fund for the purpose of financing pollution prevention programs; </section><section prefix="h">Approve and release public statements relating to the progress and results of pollution prevention programs and research; </section><section prefix="i">Hire a technical advisor if deemed necessary; and </section><section prefix="j">Approve the budget and expenditures of the center. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 370, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.982. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10440</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>