<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.945</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 164.945 to 164.947.   </catch_line><order_by>945</order_by><text>As used in KRS 164.945 to 164.947, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">"College" means any educational facility or institution maintained or conducted by any person, association, partnership, corporation, or trust and operating as an institute, junior college, college, university, or entity of whatever kind which awards a degree, diploma, or other statement of recognition purporting to indicate a level of collegiate attainment beyond secondary school graduation. This definition includes private colleges located in Kentucky, private colleges located outside of Kentucky but which operate in Kentucky, and public colleges located outside of Kentucky but which operate in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="b">The term "college" does not include state-supported colleges and universities authorized by KRS 164.100, 164.290, 164.580, and 164.810, nor does it include colleges licensed or approved for establishment and operation under the statutory authority given to the Kentucky Board of Barbering under KRS 317.430, the Kentucky Board of Hairdressers and Cosmetologists under KRS 317A.030, the Kentucky Commission on Proprietary Education under KRS 165A.340, or the State Board of Nursing under KRS 314.121. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Degree" means any academic or honorary title of designation, mark, appellation, series of letters, numbers or words, such as, but not limited to, associate, bachelors, masters, doctorate, or fellow, which signifies, purports, or is generally taken to signify satisfactory completion of the requirements of an academic, educational, or professional program of study beyond the secondary school level. </section><section prefix="3">"Diploma" means a certificate, transcript, report, document, or title of designation, mark, appellation, series of letters, numbers, or words which signifies, purports, or is generally taken to signify attendance, progress, or achievement in an academic program. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 22, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 519, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40334</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>