<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.030</section_number><catch_line>Petition for interpersonal protective order.  </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>(1)A petition for an interpersonal protective order may be filed by:(a)A victim of dating violence and abuse;(b)A victim of stalking;(c)A victim of sexual assault; or(d)An adult on behalf of a victim who is a minor otherwise qualifying for reliefunder this subsection.(2)The petition may be filed in the victim's county of residence or a county wherethe victim has fled to escape dating violence and abuse, stalking, or sexualassault.(3)The petition shall be verified and contain:(a)The name, age, address, occupation, residence, and school orpostsecondary institution of the petitioner;(b)The name, age, address, occupation, residence, and school orpostsecondary institution of the person or persons who have engaged inthe alleged act or acts complained of in the petition;(c)The facts and circumstances which constitute the basis for the petition;and(d)The names, ages, and addresses of the petitioner's minor children, ifapplicable.(4)The petition shall be filed on forms prescribed by the Administrative Office ofthe Courts and provided to the person seeking relief by the circuit clerk or byanother individual authorized by the court to provide and verify petitions inemergency situations, such as law enforcement officers and Commonwealth'sor county attorneys.(5)All petitions requested, completed, and signed by persons seeking protectionunder this chapter shall be accepted and filed with the court.(6)(a)Jurisdiction over petitions filed under this chapter shall be concurrentbetween the District Court and Circuit Court.(b)The Court of Justice shall provide a protocol for twenty-four (24) houraccess to interpersonal protective orders in each county with anyprotocol, whether statewide or local, being subject to Supreme Courtreview and approval of the initial protocol and any subsequentamendments. This protocol may allow for petitions to be filed in ortransferred to a court other than those specified in paragraph (a) of thissubsection.(c)The Court of Justice may authorize by rule that petitions in a specificcounty be filed in accordance with a supplemental jurisdictional protocoladopted for that county. This protocol may provide for petitions to be filedin or transferred to a court other than those specified in paragraph (a) ofthis subsection.(7)Any judge to whom a petition is referred under subsection (6) of this sectionshall have full authority to review and hear a petition and subsequently grantand enforce an interpersonal protective order.(8)If the judge of a court in which there is a pending request for modification orenforcement of an existing order of protection is unavailable or unable to actwithin a reasonable time, the proceedings may be conducted by any judge ofthe county in accordance with court rules.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 21, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>