<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.415</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 146.410 to 146.530. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text>As used in KRS 146.410 to 146.530: <section prefix="1">"Natural area" means any area of land or water, or of both land and water, in public or private ownership, which either retains, or has reestablished to some degree in the judgment of the commission its natural character, though it need not be completely natural and undisturbed, or which has natural flora, fauna, biological, ecological, geological, scenic or archaeological features of scientific, aesthetic, cultural or educational interest; </section><section prefix="2">"Nature preserve" means a natural area, and land necessary for its protection, any estate, interest or right in which has been formally dedicated under the provisions of KRS 146.410 to 146.530 to be maintained as nearly as possible in its natural condition and to be used in a manner and under limitations consistent with its continued preservation, without impairment, disturbance or artificial development, for the public purposes of present and future scientific research, education, aesthetic enjoyment and habitat for plant and animal species and other natural objects; </section><section prefix="3">"Articles of dedication" means the writing by which any estate, interest or right in a natural area is formally dedicated, as provided in KRS 146.410 to 146.530; </section><section prefix="4">"Commission" means the Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission; </section><section prefix="5">"System" means the state system of nature preserves established under KRS 146.410 to 146.530; </section><section prefix="6">"Cabinet" means the Energy and Environment Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="7">"Director" means the director of the Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 133, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 1, effective June 1, 1988. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 114, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>