<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">B LONG-TERM POLICY RESEARCH </unit></structure><section_number>7B.040</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may: <section prefix="a">Use studies, surveys, plans, data, and other materials in the possession of any state agency. Upon request by the board, an agency shall make materials available to the board; </section><section prefix="b">Promulgate, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, administrative regulations necessary to carry out its planning and advisory functions as provided by this chapter; </section><section prefix="c">Conduct public hearings in furtherance of its general purposes at places designated by the board, at which it may request the appearance of officials of any state agency and solicit the testimony of interested groups and the general public; </section><section prefix="d">Establish advisory committees to assist in implementing the requirements of this chapter; </section><section prefix="e">Enter into contracts, pursuant to KRS Chapters 45 and 45A, necessary for the administration of this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">Disburse moneys accruing to the center's restricted agency fund account to pay for the expenses and operation of the center and to carry out the purposes of this chapter; </section><section prefix="g">Engage consultants, actuaries, managers, legal counsel, and auditors, to render professional, managerial, and technical assistance, as needed; </section><section prefix="h">Enter into agreements, as necessary, with any institution of higher education, the Commonwealth of Kentucky, any state or federal agency, or other entity; </section><section prefix="i">Solicit and accept grants, gifts, legislative appropriations, or other moneys from the Commonwealth, any unit of federal, state, or local government, or any other person, firm, partnership, or corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">At the request of the board, officials or personnel of any state agency, as well as any other person, may serve on advisory committees created by the board. State officials or personnel may serve on the committees without forfeiture of office or employment, and with no loss or diminution in the compensation, status, rights, and privileges they otherwise enjoy. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the board who are otherwise compensated by the Commonwealth shall receive no additional compensation as members of the board or for attendance at meetings. Members who are not otherwise compensated by the Commonwealth shall receive a per diem of one hundred dollars ($100) for attendance at each board meeting. </section><section prefix="4">All board members may be reimbursed for travel and other expenses incurred in carrying out board responsibilities. The scope of travel shall not be limited to the confines of the Commonwealth, but may extend to any place outside the Commonwealth, if authorized by the board by motion, resolution, or directive reciting the destination, necessity, and persons authorized to travel. </section></text><history> Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (3) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>