<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">A SPECIAL PURPOSE GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES </unit></structure><section_number>65A.080</section_number><catch_line>Annual budget -- Publication of information. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The governing body of each special purpose governmental entity shall annually adopt a budget conforming with the requirements established under KRS 65A.020 prior to the start of the fiscal year to which the budget applies. The adopted budget may be amended by the governing body of the special purpose governmental entity throughout the fiscal year using the same process that was used for adoption of the original budget. No moneys shall be expended from any source except as provided in the originally adopted or subsequently amended budget. </section><section prefix="2">In lieu of the publication requirements of KRS 424.220, but in compliance with other applicable provisions of KRS Chapter 424, each special purpose governmental entity shall, within sixty (60) days after the close of each fiscal year, publish the location where the adopted budget, financial statements, and most recent audit or attestation engagement reports may be examined by the public. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 4, effective March 19, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 8, effective March 21, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> March 19, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (3/19/2014). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 11 provides that the amendments to this statute made in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 4, shall apply retroactively beginning January 1, 2014. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>