<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14">DEPARTMENT OF STATE </unit></structure><section_number>14.250</section_number><catch_line>One-stop business portal -- Advisory committee -- Assessment, recommendations, and duties. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State, Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Cabinet for Economic Development, and the Commonwealth Office of Technology shall jointly establish a one-stop electronic business portal that shall serve as a single, unified entry point for business owners to access and complete initial and ongoing state services and requirements in relation to the creation or ongoing operation of a business located in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The agencies identified in this subsection shall coordinate, manage, and implement the portal based on the results of an assessment conducted by the One-Stop Business Portal Advisory Committee under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The One-Stop Business Portal Advisory Committee is hereby established to provide guidance in the creation and implementation of the one-stop business portal. The committee shall consist of the Secretary of State, the secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet, the secretary of the Economic Development Cabinet or his or her designee, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet or his or her designee, the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or his or her designee, the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet or his or her designee, the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet or his or her designee, the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or his or her designee, and the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or his or her designee. The Governor may appoint other members to the committee at his or her discretion. The committee shall be co-chaired by the Secretary of State and the secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The One-Stop Business Portal Advisory Committee shall prepare an assessment detailing recommendations for the creation, ongoing operation, and management of the one-stop business portal, to be presented to the Governor, the Secretary of State, and the Legislative Research Commission by December 31, 2011. This assessment shall include the following: <section prefix="a">An estimate of the costs for full implementation of the portal, including those associated with technology, maintenance, sharing agency data, information security, and other start-up costs; </section><section prefix="b">An estimate of the costs of establishing and maintaining a call center staffed with persons trained to answer questions and help businesses obtain information and services, along with a recommendation as to where the call center should be located and the number of staff necessary to operate it; </section><section prefix="c">Recommendations on the location, design, and functionality of the portal; </section><section prefix="d">Recommendations as to the roles of the state agencies identified in subsection (1) of this section regarding the day-to-day operational management of the portal; </section><section prefix="e">Recommendations on the time line for developing and testing the portal; </section><section prefix="f">Identification of any statutory or regulatory changes that need to be made to existing law to effectuate the portal's functionality; </section><section prefix="g">Identification of other state agencies that possess business-related functions and content so that those functions can be added to the portal; </section><section prefix="h">Identification of any impediments posed by federal law and recommended ways to address the impediment; </section><section prefix="i">A comprehensive analysis of the processes of all state agencies, with a view toward streamlining and reducing the paperwork necessary for businesses to interact with each agency; and </section><section prefix="j">Recommendations on the scope of services to be provided by the portal. At a minimum, services shall include: <section prefix="1">Application and renewal of business-related licenses and fees incident to the start-up and operation of a business; </section><section prefix="2">Electronic payment of taxes and related costs imposed by state law incident to the operation of a business; </section><section prefix="3">Filing of documents and papers imposed by state law associated with the operation of a business; and </section><section prefix="4">Creation of individual electronic accounts for each business which allows the business to monitor its filings, payments, and other business-compliance activities. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The One-Stop Business Portal Advisory Committee shall: <section prefix="a">Ensure that the portal has a Web site and the ability to process new business registrations as handled by the Secretary of State's Office, and will be in a testing phase for the Department of Revenue's tax registration application by December 31, 2012; and </section><section prefix="b">Ensure that subsequent and additional online business applications maintained by the Commonwealth shall be evaluated and prioritized. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (3/16/2011).  As created by 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, this statute contained a reference to the "Education and Workforce Cabinet" in subsection (2). However, the entity created by Executive Order 2008-530, which was confirmed by the General Assembly in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, is the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. This manifest clerical or typographical error and a manifest grammatical error in subsection (4) have been corrected in codification by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39511</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>