<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.415</section_number><catch_line>Conditions to be complied with before textbooks and programs adopted or purchased. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text>Before textbooks and programs offered for adoption and use in public schools of Kentucky may be lawfully recommended and listed by the State Textbook Commission or purchased by any board of education, the person, firm, or corporation offering the materials for adoption and use shall file with the chief state school officer: <section prefix="1">Copies of all textbooks and programs that the person, firm, or corporation desires to offer for adoption and use, with a sworn statement of the list price and the lowest wholesale price at which each of the titles is sold in any adopting unit; </section><section prefix="2">A statement that all the titles offered for sale, adoption, and use, do comply with the standards and specifications for textbooks designated by the chief state school officer as regards paper, binding, printing, illustrations, subject matter, and other items included in the standards and specifications; </section><section prefix="3">Copies of any revision or special editions of the textbooks and programs filed, with a statement describing in detail each point of difference from the regular edition filed, and the list price and the lowest wholesale price at which the revision or special edition is sold anywhere in the United States; </section><section prefix="4">A fee of five dollars ($5) for each book filed except when a series of books is filed, in which case the fee shall be five dollars ($5) for the first book and one dollar ($1) for each additional book in the series. The fee provided by this subsection shall be paid at each and every adoption period; </section><section prefix="5">A bond running to the Commonwealth of Kentucky, executed by a surety company authorized to do business in this state, in a sum not less than two thousand dollars ($2,000) nor more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), to be determined by the chief state school officer; and </section><section prefix="6">An affidavit certifying any textbook the publisher or manufacturer offers in the state to be free of factual error at the time the publisher or manufacturer executes a contract. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 149, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 4, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3180</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>