<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.660</section_number><catch_line>Specific powers and duties of guardian. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>A guardian of a disabled person shall have the following powers and duties, except as modified by order of the court:  <section prefix="1">To take custody of the ward and to establish his place of abode within the state, except that, if at any time a guardian places a ward in a licensed residential facility for developmentally disabled persons, the guardian shall, within thirty (30) days of such placement, file with the court notice of the placement, stating with specificity the reasons for such placement, and an interdisciplinary evaluation report detailing the social, psychological, medical or other considerations on which such placement is predicated, a description of the treatment or habilitation programs which will benefit the ward as a result of such placement, and a determination that such placement will provide appropriate treatment in the least restrictive available treatment and residential program. For purposes of this subsection, the interdisciplinary evaluation report may be one performed within two (2) months prior to the placement for purposes of determining whether such placement is necessary and appropriate, or may be an evaluation and assessment provided by the residential facility immediately after placement. Notice to the court shall not be required where the ward is transferred from one licensed residential facility to another.  </section><section prefix="2">To make provision for the ward's care, comfort, and maintenance and arrange for such educational, social, vocational, and rehabilitation services as are appropriate and as will assist the ward in the development of maximum self-reliance and independence.  </section><section prefix="3">To give any necessary consent or approval to enable the ward to receive medical or other professional care, counsel, treatment or service, except that a guardian may not consent on behalf of a ward to an abortion, sterilization, psychosurgery, removal of a bodily organ, or amputation of a limb unless the procedure is first approved by order of the court or is necessary, in an emergency situation, to preserve the life or prevent serious impairment of the physical health of the ward.  </section><section prefix="4">To act with respect to the ward in a manner which limits the deprivation of civil rights and restricts his personal freedom only to the extent necessary to provide needed care and services to him.  </section><section prefix="5">To expend sums from the financial resources of the ward reasonable and necessary to carry out the powers and duties assigned to him by the court and, unless a separate conservator has been appointed, to manage the financial resources of this ward.  </section>If a separate limited conservator or conservator has been appointed for the ward, the expenditure of funds by the limited guardian shall be consistent with the duties assigned to and procedures and policies established by such limited conservator or conservator. Conflicts arising between a limited guardian and a limited conservator or conservator regarding the expenditure of funds which are unable to be otherwise resolved shall be submitted to the court for resolution. </text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 17, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36056</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>