<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.902</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 342.900 to 342.912. </catch_line><order_by>902</order_by><text>As used in KRS 342.900 to 342.912, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Insolvent self-insurer" means either an individual self-insured employer or a self-insured group who has failed to pay compensation as a result of a declaration of bankruptcy or insolvency by a court of competent jurisdiction, and whose security deposit has been called by the commissioner, or who has failed to provide compensation and who has been issued a certificate of default by the commissioner and whose security deposit has been called by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="2">"Member" means a self-insured employer or self-insured group that participates in a guaranty fund created pursuant to KRS 342.900 to 342.912; </section><section prefix="3">"Guaranty fund" means one (1) of the three (3) guaranty funds established pursuant to KRS 342.900 to 342.912; </section><section prefix="4">"Directors" means the board of directors of a guaranty fund; and </section><section prefix="5">"Certificate of default" means a notice issued by the commissioner based upon a finding that a self-insured employer or self-insured group has failed to pay compensation required by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1857, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 47, effective March 1, 2005. -- Created 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 21, effective December 12, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>