<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.3801</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Heritage Council -- Members -- Officers -- Meetings -- Heritage division-- Reorganization prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>3801</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Kentucky Heritage Council (hereinafter referred to as "the council") which shall perform the functions specified in KRS 171.381. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the council shall consist of not more than sixteen (16) members who have an interest in the preservation and protection of Kentucky's heritage. On or before September 15, 1982, the Governor shall appoint not more than four (4) members for a term of one (1) year, not more than four (4) members for a term of two (2) years, not more than four (4) members for a term of three (3) years, and not more than four (4) members for a term of four (4) years. Thereafter, the Governor shall make all appointments for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="3">Council members shall receive no compensation for their services but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="4">From the council membership the Governor shall appoint a chairman and a vice chairman of the council. The council may elect by majority vote other officers deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall meet at the call of the chairman, but not less often than twice during each calendar year. A majority of the members appointed to the council shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall be attached to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="7">The Heritage Council shall include a heritage division, whose duties shall include providing staff services needed by the Heritage Council in order to perform its duties under KRS 171.381, including but not limited to preserving and protecting buildings, sites and other landmarks associated with the archaeological, cultural, economic, military, national, political and social aspects of Kentucky's history. </section><section prefix="8">The heritage division shall be headed by a director appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Heritage Council; and the Heritage Council and the heritage division shall not be subject to reorganization. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 45, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 36, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4803</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>