<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.720</section_number><catch_line>Taxes levied by district -- Maintenance of roads by county. </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the creation of a subdivision road district as provided in KRS 179.700 to 179.735, the trustees of such district are hereby authorized to levy a tax rate upon the property in said district, provided that said property is subject to county tax, and not exceeding ten cents ($0.10) per one hundred dollars ($100) of valuation as assessed for county taxes, for the purpose of defraying the expenses of the maintenance of roads within the subdivision district. The rate set in this subsection shall apply, notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 132.023. </section><section prefix="2">The trustees of a district may contract with the county containing the district to perform maintenance on or to provide personnel, materials or equipment for maintenance to be performed upon any road in the district. The county may maintain or provide personnel, materials or equipment for the maintenance of the roads of a district, so long as the district agrees to pay the county's total cost of providing services, personnel, materials or equipment. </section><section prefix="3">The property valuation administrator of the county or counties involved, with the cooperation of the board of trustees, shall note on the tax rolls the taxpayers and valuation of the property subject to such assessment. The county clerk shall compute the tax on the regular state and county tax bills in such manner as may be directed by regulation of the Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="4">Such taxes shall be subject to the same delinquency date, discounts, penalties and interest as are applied to the collection of ad valorem taxes and shall be collected by the sheriff of the county or counties involved and accounted for to the treasurer of the district. The sheriff shall be entitled to a fee of four percent (4%) of the amount collected by him. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 604, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5527</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>