<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLI" order_by="41">LAWS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="447" order_by="447">PUBLIC LAWS IN FORCE -- COURT RULES </unit></structure><section_number>447.030</section_number><catch_line>Acts and compilations of former laws, evidence. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The Session Acts and Resolutions of the General Assembly heretofore or hereafter published, the editions of the Statutes of Kentucky by Daniel Bradford, by William Littell, by Littell and Swigert, by Morehead and Brown, and in part by Preston S. Loughborough, the edition of the Virginia Statutes by William Waller Henning, Richard H. Stanton's new edition of the Revised Statutes of Kentucky, the supplement to the Revised Statutes by Harvey Myers, the General Statutes, the Codes of Practice, the various editions of Carroll's Kentucky Statutes and supplements thereto published prior to 1940, and the various editions of Carroll's Kentucky Codes and the supplements thereto, shall be received, in the courts and tribunals of this state, as evidence of the statute laws in force in this state at the time of their publication. </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2419, 2419a-1, 2419a-4, 2419a-5, 2419a-6, 2420a-1, 2420a-2, 2420a-3. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><note> 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 92 repealed this section to contingently become effective as provided in sec. 93 of that act. However, that repeal was repealed by sec. 31 of Acts 1992, ch. 324, effective July 1, 1992, which provided that: "The repeal of KRS 447.030, Acts and compilations of former laws, evidence," contained in 1990 Ky. Acts Ch. 88, Sec. 92, is hereby repealed." </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>