<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.355</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by distilled spirits and wine storage license --Application of federal law.   </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A distilled spirits and wine storage license may be issued as a primary license or as a supplementary license to the holder of a distiller's or rectifier's license. </section><section prefix="2">A distilled spirits and wine storage license may be issued to any person or entity operating a bonded warehouse for distilled spirits, and who does not at the same time, and for the same premises, hold a federal operating permit for distilling purposes, but who possesses only a federal operating permit for a bonded warehouse for distilled spirits as defined by federal law and the Internal Revenue Code. </section><section prefix="3">A licensee under this section may operate a bonded warehouse or warehouses for premises specifically designated, but this license shall become void if a federal operating permit for distilling purposes is issued for the same premises, and shall remain void while the federal permit remains in effect. Upon the granting of a federal operating permit for distilling purposes, the licensee of the premises previously licensed under this section shall obtain a license as set out in KRS 243.030(1). </section><section prefix="4">A distilled spirits and wine storage license may be issued to persons or entities not otherwise entitled under Kentucky law to store or warehouse distilled spirits or wine, but who are so authorized by the federal government. The license shall authorize the licensee to operate a warehouse or place of storage for distilled spirits or wine on the premises specifically designated. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 33, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42468</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>