<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.210</section_number><catch_line>Purchases of prison-made products by state agencies and political subdivisions. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">On and after June 17, 1954, all offices, departments, institutions, agencies, and all political subdivisions which are supported in whole or in part by the Commonwealth shall purchase, when economically feasible, from the department all articles or products required which are produced or manufactured by prison labor, as provided by KRS 197.200 to 197.250. No article or product shall be purchased by any office, department, institution, or agency, from any source except as specified in this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">Exceptions may be made in any case where, in the opinion of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the articles or products produced or manufactured do not meet the reasonable requirements of the offices, departments, institutions, agencies, or where the requisition cannot be reasonably complied with because of an insufficient supply of the articles or products required. However, no office, department, institution, or agency shall be allowed to evade the intent and meaning of KRS 197.200 to 197.250 by slight variations from standards adopted by the Office of Material and Procurement Services within the Office of the Controller, when the articles or products produced or manufactured by the department in accordance with the standards, are reasonably adapted to the actual needs of the office, department, institution, or agency. </section></section><section prefix="2">All purchases under KRS 197.200 to 197.250 shall be made through the Finance and Administration Cabinet upon requisition by the proper authority of the office, department, institution, agency, or political subdivision of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 619, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 58, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and Art V, sec. 24(14). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6889</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>