<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.275</section_number><catch_line>Public utilities in county containing city of first class or consolidated local government to give property valuation administrator information concerning customers. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text>Each gas, water, electric light, and telephone company operating in a county containing a city of the first class or consolidated local government shall furnish to the property valuation administrator a list showing the names and addresses of all persons, firms, or corporations receiving service from such utilities, and thereafter on every Monday, said utility companies shall furnish to said property valuation administrator a report containing the names of all persons, firms, or corporations who have, during the week immediately preceding, ordered gas, water, electric light, or telephone service to be installed, removed, or discontinued, with the addresses at which the services were ordered to be installed, removed, or discontinued. Such information shall be treated as confidential and shall be used by said property valuation administrator only for the purpose of making accurate records. Provided, however, that said property valuation administrator shall permit the city assessor of said city of the first class or consolidated local government and any other taxing bodies of the various governments to examine said records for official purposes only, and said units of government shall treat said information as confidential. </text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 165, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28252</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>