<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.4459</section_number><catch_line>Application to conduct referendum. </catch_line><order_by>4459</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any existing commission, council, board, association, or other agency, such as the Kentucky Milk Producers Association, fairly representative of the producers of the agricultural commodity referred to, may at any time after July 13, 1990, make application to the State Board of Agriculture on forms prescribed by the board for certification and approval for the purpose of conducting a referendum among the producers of the agricultural commodity, for commercial purposes, upon the question of levying an assessment under the provisions of KRS 247.4451 to 247.4483, collecting and utilizing the assessment for the purpose stated in the referendum. The application forms shall include, but not be limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">Applicant's name; </section><section prefix="b">Applicant's address; </section><section prefix="c">Date; </section><section prefix="d">Program to be undertaken for producers; </section><section prefix="e">Brief statement of how program is to be implemented; </section><section prefix="f">Referendum to be conducted on a statewide basis; </section><section prefix="g">Proposed effective date of program; and </section><section prefix="h">Signature of applicant. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon receipt of the application, the Commissioner shall publish the application through the medium of the public press in the state within ten (10) days of receipt. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11658</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>