<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.703</section_number><catch_line>Educational and vocational programs eligible for supportive services -- Prohibition against discontinuance of service to low income parents except under certain circumstances. </catch_line><order_by>703</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall honor parents' requests to volunteer for basic, secondary, post-secondary, and vocational education programs, including work study and internships; where: <section prefix="a">The activity is: <section prefix="1">Countable toward federal work participation rates; or </section><section prefix="2">Combined with work activity countable toward federal work participation rates; </section></section><section prefix="b">The activity is made part of a self-sufficiency plan in which it will lead to achievement of a specific employment goal; </section><section prefix="c">The parent meets admission criteria for the educational program; and </section><section prefix="d">The parent does not already have marketable skills sufficient to achieve at least  two hundred percent (200%) of the federal poverty threshold, adjusted by household size. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall honor parents' requests to continue current educational activities as defined under subsection (1) of this section, where the parent is making good and satisfactory progress based on standards normally applied by the educational or vocational programs to enrollees. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall inform all parents receiving public assistance of the option to engage in educational and vocational training activities, as defined under subsection (1) of this section, and receive supportive services: <section prefix="a">At least once per year, no less than six (6) weeks prior to the start of fall semester of the state university and community college system; </section><section prefix="b">During the initial and any subsequent self-sufficiency planning process; </section><section prefix="c">During conciliation in which the parent requests a change in placement; and </section><section prefix="d">At any time upon request of the parent. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall not require a parent who is currently participating in an education program to discontinue participation and shall not discontinue supportive services for education under subsection (1) of this section, except where: <section prefix="a">The parent is no longer making good or satisfactory progress; </section><section prefix="b">The parent fails to verify satisfactory attendance under standards normally applied by the educational program to enrollees; </section><section prefix="c">The parent in a noncountable education activity fails to participate in the additional required countable activity; </section><section prefix="d">The parent refuses an offer of employment paying at least two-hundred percent (200%) of the federal poverty threshold, adjusted for household size; or </section><section prefix="e">The parent becomes ineligible for public assistance for reasons unrelated to educational activity. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7799</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>