<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.646</section_number><catch_line>Prescription epinephrine auto-injectors.   </catch_line><order_by>646</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A health-care practitioner may prescribe epinephrine auto-injectors in the name of an authorized entity or to a certified individual for use in accordance with this section. </section><section prefix="2">A pharmacist may dispense epinephrine auto-injectors pursuant to a prescription issued in the name of an authorized entity or to a certified individual. </section><section prefix="3">The Department for Public Health, the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, the American Red Cross, or other training programs approved by the Department for Public Health may conduct in-person or on-line training for administering lifesaving treatment to persons believed in good faith to be experiencing severe allergic reactions and issue a certificate of training to persons completing the training. The training shall include instructions for recognizing the symptoms of anaphylaxis and administering an epinephrine auto-injector. </section><section prefix="4">An individual who has a certificate issued under this section may: <section prefix="a">Receive a prescription for epinephrine auto-injectors from a health-care practitioner; </section><section prefix="b">Possess prescribed epinephrine auto-injectors; and </section><section prefix="c">In an emergency situation when a physician is not immediately available and the certified individual in good faith believes a person is experiencing a severe allergic reaction regardless of whether the person has a prescription for an epinephrine auto-injector or has previously been diagnosed with an allergy: <section prefix="1">Administer an epinephrine auto-injector to the person; and </section><section prefix="2">Provide an epinephrine auto-injector to the person for immediate self-administration. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">An authorized entity that acquires and stocks a supply of epinephrine auto-injectors with a valid prescription shall: <section prefix="a">Store the epinephrine auto-injectors in accordance with manufacturer's instructions and with any additional requirements established by the department; and </section><section prefix="b">Designate an employee or agent who holds a certificate issued under this section to be responsible for the storage, maintenance, and general oversight of epinephrine auto-injectors acquired by the authorized entity. </section></section><section prefix="6">Any individual or entity who administers or provides an epinephrine auto-injector to a person who is experiencing a severe allergic reaction shall contact the local emergency medical services system as soon as possible. </section><section prefix="7">Any individual or entity who acquires and stocks a supply of epinephrine auto-injectors in accordance with this section shall notify an agent of the local emergency medical services system and the local emergency communications or vehicle dispatch center of the existence, location, and type of the epinephrine auto-injectors acquired if a severe allergic reaction has occurred. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 30, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 32 provides that this statute and KRS 311.645 and 311.647 created in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, secs. 29, 30, and 31 may be cited as the "Emergency Allergy Treatment Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44633</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>