<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who exercises any of the functions of a nonelective peace officer or deputy peace officer in violation of the provisions of KRS 61.300 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 61.360 shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or be imprisoned not less than ten (10) days nor more than sixty (60) days, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who willfully violates the provisions of KRS 61.102(1) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">A court, in rendering a judgment in an action filed under KRS 61.102 and 61.103, shall order, as it considers appropriate, reinstatement of the employee, the payment of back wages, full reinstatement of fringe benefits and seniority rights, exemplary or punitive damages, or any combination thereof. A court may also award the complainant all or a portion of the costs of litigation, including reasonable attorney fees and witness fees. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 43, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1(2), effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 188, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 10. </history><metadata><lrc-note>.  KRS 61.990(2) was formerly a part of KRS 61.300 as amended by Acts 1980, ch. 24, รยง 1, and was renumbered by the Reviser of Statutes in 1980. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23116</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>