<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="347" order_by="347">PERSONS WITH DEVELOPMENTAL DISABILITIES </unit></structure><section_number>347.040</section_number><catch_line>Joint statewide plan to serve developmentally disabled persons. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretaries of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet and the chief state school officer shall jointly develop and implement a statewide plan, with adequate opportunity for public comment, to serve all persons with developmental disabilities not otherwise entitled to and receiving the same services under another state or federal act, which will include provisions for: <section prefix="a">Identification and prompt and adequate interdisciplinary assessment; </section><section prefix="b">Case management services; and </section><section prefix="c">Services and residential alternatives as defined by this chapter in the least restrictive, individually appropriate environment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The first plan and annual updates shall be presented to the Legislative Research Commission which shall refer it to an appropriate committee for review and comment. </section><section prefix="3">The plan shall include: <section prefix="a">The number of institution residents on waiting lists for placement in the community; </section><section prefix="b">The number of persons outside institutions on waiting lists for placement in the institution; </section><section prefix="c">The number of persons for whom no placement is made nor services provided because of a lack of community resources; </section><section prefix="d">The number, type, nature, and cost of services necessary for placement to occur; </section><section prefix="e">The status of compliance with the plan; </section><section prefix="f">The cabinets' specific efforts to increase residential and institutional services and documentation of the success of these efforts; and </section><section prefix="g">The specific plans for new efforts to enhance the opportunities for persons with developmental disabilities to move into less restrictive environments. </section></section><section prefix="4">The state health plan shall be developed consistently with the plan required under this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 84, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 162, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 613, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 568, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 12, effective March 2, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32721</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>