<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.16-060</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet as agency for securing benefits of federal acts. </catch_line><order_by>16-060</order_by><text>The cabinet is hereby designated as the water pollution agency for this state and for any city, county, or district, or authority within this state for all purposes of the Water Pollution Control Act (Public Law 80-845 approved June 30, 1948), as amended, as air pollution agency for this state for all purposes of the Federal Air Quality Act (Public Law 90-148, approved November 21, 1948), as amended, and as solid waste agency for this state for all purposes of the Federal Solid Waste Disposal Act (Public Law 89-272, approved October 20, 1965), as amended, and as management agency for solid waste and hazardous waste for purposes of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976, as amended, (PL 94-580), and as the surface mining agency for this state for all purposes of the Federal Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act (Public Law 95-87, approved August 3, 1977), as amended. The cabinet may take all action necessary or appropriate to secure to this state and all cities, counties, districts, and authorities within this state the benefits of such federal acts. </text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 183, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 330, sec. 25, effective May 3, 1978 . -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.037. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10336</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>