<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.050</section_number><catch_line>Use of physical force in self-protection -- Admissibility of evidence of prior acts of domestic violence and abuse. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant believes that such force is necessary to protect himself against the use or imminent use of unlawful physical force by the other person. </section><section prefix="2">The use of deadly physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable under subsection (1) only when the defendant believes that such force is necessary to protect himself against death, serious physical injury, kidnapping, sexual intercourse compelled by force or threat, felony involving the use of force, or under those circumstances permitted pursuant to KRS 503.055. </section><section prefix="3">Any evidence presented by the defendant to establish the existence of a prior act or acts of domestic violence and abuse as defined in KRS 403.720 by the person against whom the defendant is charged with employing physical force shall be admissible under this section. </section><section prefix="4">A person does not have a duty to retreat prior to the use of deadly physical force. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 30, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19669</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>