<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-440</section_number><catch_line>Assessment of insurers. </catch_line><order_by>2-440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "insurer" means assessment or cooperative insurers, insurers, fraternal benefit societies, nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and health service corporations, health maintenance organizations, and prepaid dental plan organizations. </section><section prefix="2">If the commissioner finds that there are insufficient funds for operations of the department, the commissioner may make an assessment on all insurers not to exceed .000235 of net direct written premium from Kentucky as reported in insurers' annual statements for the immediately preceding calendar year. In making each assessment, the commissioner may establish a minimum assessment. Assessments made pursuant to this section shall be in addition to all other taxes, assessments, and fees. </section><section prefix="3">Overdue payment of any assessments shall bear interest at the tax interest rate as set forth in KRS 131.010(6) from the date due until paid. Any unpaid assessment may be recovered in an action brought thereon in the name of the department in the Franklin Circuit Court or in any other court of appropriate jurisdiction. Such interest penalty is separate from other penalties applicable to violations of KRS Chapter 299 and this chapter and such an action is separate from any other means of collecting an assessment under KRS Chapter 299 or this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">All funds derived from assessments made pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the insurance regulatory trust fund. However, funds derived from assessments made pursuant to this section shall not lapse to the general fund, but shall at all times be available to defray expenses of the department in discharge of its administrative and regulatory powers. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 957, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16695</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>