<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">B KENTUCKY PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175B.075</section_number><catch_line>Moneys received under chapter are trust funds -- Permitted investment of project revenue bond proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All moneys received under this chapter, whether as proceeds from the sale of project revenue bonds or revenues, shall be trust funds to be held and applied solely as provided in this chapter. The trust indenture or any other document authorizing the issuance of project revenue bonds or the collection of any revenues shall provide that any officer, bank, or trust company with which the moneys are deposited shall act as trustee of the moneys and shall hold and apply them for the purposes outlined in this chapter, subject to the provisions of this chapter and the proceedings or trust indenture. </section><section prefix="2">The proceeds of project revenue bonds shall only be invested in direct obligations of the United States of America and direct federal agency obligations or other similar obligations to the extent that the full faith and credit of the United States of America is pledged for the timely payment thereof. Direct obligations shall include money market mutual funds that invest solely in the obligations referenced in this subsection. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 89, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5148</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>