<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.170</section_number><catch_line>Form of licenses -- Limitations on licenses -- Administrative regulations -- Expiration.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commercial driver's license shall be marked "commercial driver's license" and "CDL" and shall be, to the maximum extent practicable, tamper proof. It shall include but is not limited to the following information: <section prefix="a">The name and present resident address of the licensee; </section><section prefix="b">The licensee's color photograph; </section><section prefix="c">A physical description of the licensee including sex, height, weight, and eye color; </section><section prefix="d">The licensee's date of birth; </section><section prefix="e">The licensee's signature; </section><section prefix="f">The class or type of commercial motor vehicle or vehicles that the person is authorized to drive together with any endorsements or restrictions; </section><section prefix="g">The name of this state; </section><section prefix="h">The dates between which the license is valid; and </section><section prefix="i">Any other information required by the cabinet, except for a person's Social Security number. </section></section><section prefix="2">A commercial driver's license shall be issued with classifications, endorsements, and restrictions. Vehicles that require an endorsement shall not be driven unless the proper endorsement appears on the license and the applicant has passed the knowledge and skills test required by the State Police. <section prefix="a">Classifications: <section prefix="1">Class A - Any combination of vehicles with a gross vehicle weight rating of twenty-six thousand and one (26,001) pounds or more, if the gross vehicle weight rating of the vehicle being towed is in excess of ten thousand (10,000) pounds. Licensees with an "A" classification may with the proper endorsement drive Class B and C vehicles. </section><section prefix="2">Class B - Any single vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating of twenty-six thousand and one (26,001) pounds or more, and any vehicle towing a vehicle not in excess of ten thousand (10,000) pounds. Licensees with a "B" classification may with the proper endorsements drive Class C vehicles. </section><section prefix="3">Class C - Any single vehicle with a gross weight rating of less than twenty-six thousand and one (26,001) pounds or any vehicle towing a vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating not in excess of ten thousand (10,000) pounds which includes: <section prefix="a">Vehicles designed to transport sixteen (16) or more passengers, including the driver; or </section><section prefix="b">Vehicles used in the transportation of hazardous materials which requires the vehicle to be placarded under Title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 172, sub-part F, as adopted by administrative regulations of the cabinet, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="4">Class D - All other vehicles not listed in any other class. </section><section prefix="5">Class E - Moped only. </section><section prefix="6">Class M - Motorcycles. Licensees with a "M" classification may also drive Class E vehicles. </section></section><section prefix="b">Endorsements: <section prefix="1">"H" - Authorizes the driver to operate a vehicle transporting hazardous materials. </section><section prefix="2">"T" - Authorizes operation of double trailers and triple trailers in those jurisdictions allowing the operation of triple trailers. </section><section prefix="3">"P" - Authorizes operation of vehicles carrying passengers. </section><section prefix="4">"N" - Authorizes operation of tank vehicles. </section><section prefix="5">"X" - Authorizes operation of combination of hazardous materials and tank vehicle endorsements. </section><section prefix="6">"R" - Authorizes operation of all other endorsements not otherwise specified. </section><section prefix="7">"S" - Authorizes operation of school buses. </section></section><section prefix="c">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to outline restrictions on the operation of commercial vehicles and the associated codes to identify such restrictions, which shall appear on the face of the commercial driver's license. </section></section><section prefix="3">Within ten (10) days after issuing a commercial driver's license, the cabinet shall notify the commercial driver's license information system of that fact, providing all information required to ensure identification of the person. </section><section prefix="4">A commercial driver's license issued to a resident pursuant to this chapter shall expire in four (4) years unless the license was issued to a resident under the age of twenty-one (21). A commercial driver's license issued to a person who is not a resident shall be issued for one (1) year and shall not be renewable. The fee for a commercial driver's license issued to a nonresident shall be the same as the fee charged to a resident. </section><section prefix="5">A person under the age of twenty-one (21) shall not be licensed to operate a Class A, B, or C vehicle unless he has an "I" restriction. A commercial driver with an "I" restriction shall not drive a commercial motor vehicle in interstate commerce, unless he is exempt pursuant to 49 C.F.R. 391.2. A commercial driver under the age of twenty-one (21) shall not be allowed to operate a school bus or a vehicle transporting hazardous material in intrastate commerce. </section><section prefix="6">The holder of a commercial driver's license shall be considered to hold a valid Kentucky driver's license issued under the provisions of KRS 186.412. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 9, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 481, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 5, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 17, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>