<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.127</section_number><catch_line>Service credits for work in community service program or within jail -- Withdrawal of earned credits for misconduct. </catch_line><order_by>127</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless precluded by written order of the sentencing court with regard to a specific inmate or inmates, the jailer or correctional services department may grant sentence credits to inmates confined in the county jail on conviction of misdemeanor charges for labor performed without the jail in a community service program or within the jail for the maintenance of the jail or for the operation of jail services such as food service. </section><section prefix="2">Credit, if granted, shall be uniform and shall be based on the following: <section prefix="a">For every eight (8) full hours of work, one (1) sentence credit shall be earned; </section><section prefix="b">For every five (5) of sentence credits earned, one (1) day of the sentence to be served by the inmate shall be deducted; and </section><section prefix="c">Sentence credits shall be deducted from the maximum expiration date of the sentence. </section></section><section prefix="3">If an inmate violates the rules of the jail or engages in other misconduct the jailer or correctional services department may withdraw sentence credits earned by the inmate. The jailer or correctional services department shall maintain a list of offenses and penalties for the ten (10) most common offenses and rule violations. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>