<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.090</section_number><catch_line>Fees charged by sheriffs. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Sheriffs may charge and collect the following fees from the Commonwealth and any of its agencies, including the Department of Kentucky State Police, when the source of payment is not otherwise specified, if the Commonwealth, any of its agencies, or the Department of Kentucky State Police makes a request that the sheriff perform any of the following: <section prefix="a">Executing and returning process ............................................................. $20.00; </section><section prefix="b">Serving an order of court and return  .......................................................... 3.00; </section><section prefix="c">Summoning or subpoenaing each witness, fee to be paid by requester </section> to sheriff before service  ........................................................................... 10.00; <section prefix="d">Summoning an appraiser or reviewer  ........................................................ 2.00; </section><section prefix="e">Attending a surveyor, when ordered by a </section> court, per deputy or sheriff assigned  ........................................................ 20.00; <section prefix="f">Taking any bond that he is authorized or </section> required to take in any action  ..................................................................... 5.00; <section prefix="g">Collecting money under execution or distress warrant, if the debt is paid or the property sold, or a delivery bond given and not complied with, six percent (6%) on the first three hundred dollars ($300) and three percent (3%) on the residue; when he or she levies an execution or distress warrant, and the defendant replevies the debt, or the writ is stayed by legal proceedings or by the order of the plaintiff, half of the above commissions, to be charged to the plaintiff and collected as costs in the case; </section><section prefix="h">Taking a recognizance of a witness  ........................................................... 3.00; </section><section prefix="i">Levying an attachment  ............................................................................... 5.00; </section><section prefix="j">When property attached is sold by an officer other than the officer levying the attachment, the court shall, in the judgment, make the officer an additional and reasonable allowance for levying the attachment, and the fee of the officer selling the property shall be lessened by that sum. Reasonable charges for removing and taking care of attached property shall be allowed by order of court; </section><section prefix="k">Summoning a garnishee  ............................................................................. 3.00; </section><section prefix="l">Summoning a jury in a misdemeanor case, attending the trial, and </section> conducting the defendant to jail, to be paid by the party  convicted   .................................................................................................. 8.00; <section prefix="m">Serving process or arresting the party in </section> misdemeanor cases, to be paid by the plaintiff  ........................................ 30.00; <section prefix="n">Serving an order or process of revivor  ....................................................... 3.00; </section><section prefix="o">Executing a writ of possession against each tenant or defendant  .............. 7.00; </section><section prefix="p">Executing a capias ad satisfaciendum, the same commission as collecting money on execution. If the debt is not paid, but stayed or secured, half commission; </section><section prefix="q">Summoning and attending a jury in a case of forcible entry and </section> detainer, besides fees for summoning witnesses  ....................................... 8.00; <section prefix="r">Collecting militia fines and fee-bills, ten percent (10%), to be deducted out of the fee-bill or fine; </section><section prefix="s">Levying for a fee-bill  ................................................................................. 3.00; </section><section prefix="t">Serving a notice .......................................................................................... 2.00; </section><section prefix="u">Serving summons, warrants or process of arrest in cases of </section> children born out of wedlock  ..................................................................... 6.00; <section prefix="v">Serving a civil summons in a nonsupport case  ........................................ 10.00; </section><section prefix="w">Serving each order appointing surveyors of </section> roads, to be paid out of the county levy  ..................................................... 5.00; <section prefix="x">Serving each summons or order of court in applications concerning </section> roads, to be paid out of the county levy if the road is established,  and in all other cases to be paid by the applicant  ....................................... 5.00; <section prefix="y">Like services in cases of private passways to </section> be paid by the applicant  ............................................................................. 5.00; <section prefix="z">Executing each writ of habeas corpus, to be </section> paid by the petitioner  ................................................................................. 3.00; (aa) All services under a writ issued under  KRS 381.460 to 381.570  ......................................................................... 10.00; (bb) Fingerprinting persons for professional, trade, or commercial  purposes, or for personal use, per set of impressions ............................... 10.00; (cc) Taking or copying photographs for professional, trade, or commercial purposes, or for personal use, per photograph .............. 5.00; and (dd) For services in summoning grand and petit jurors and performing his or her duties under KRS Chapter 29A the sheriff shall be allowed, for each person so summoned, and paid out of the State Treasury for constructive service the sum of $1.50 and for personal service the sum of $3.00. </section><section prefix="2">Sheriffs may charge and collect a fee of forty dollars ($40) from any person not requesting the service of the sheriff on behalf of the Commonwealth, any of its agencies, or the Department of Kentucky State Police for the services provided in subsection (1) of this section where a percentage, commission, or reasonable fee is not otherwise allowed. If a percentage, commission, or reasonable fee is allowed, that amount shall be paid. If payment is specified from a person other than the person who requested the service, then the person specified shall be responsible for payment. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 137, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 385, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 77, effective January 1, 1978. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 354, 357, 1726. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43524</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>