<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.27-050</section_number><catch_line>Release of sales tax incentives under tax incentive agreement -- Monitoring, tracking, and reporting requirements. </catch_line><order_by>27-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department may release to an approved company any sales tax incentives under KRS 139.517 and 154.27-070 after review of the request for incentives required by KRS 139.517 and determination of the amount due regardless of whether the minimum capital investment has been made as required by the tax incentive agreement. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall monitor all tax incentive agreements. The authority may seek assistance from the Department for Energy Development and Independence, the Department of Revenue, the Center for Applied Energy Research, or other entities or individuals in performing its monitoring functions. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall track the amount of revenues released and incentives received for each eligible project under each tax incentive agreement and shall provide the authority the information upon request. </section><section prefix="4">By November 1 of each year, the authority and the department shall jointly prepare a report for the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission, as required in KRS 154.12-2035. The report shall include a list of all companies with which tax incentive agreements have been entered into and a summary of the terms of each agreement, including the type of facility approved, product to be produced, estimated output upon completion, required minimum capital investment and maximum recovery, incentives approved by type of tax and amount, activation date, and termination date. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 202, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 5, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43521</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>