<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.065</section_number><catch_line>Governor's Executive Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretaries of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, the Public Protection Cabinet, the Transportation Cabinet, the Cabinet for Economic Development, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the Labor Cabinet, the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, the Personnel Cabinet, the Governor's Executive Cabinet, the chief information officer, the state budget director, the Governor's chief of staff, and the Lieutenant Governor shall constitute the Governor's Executive Cabinet. There shall be a vice chairman appointed by the Governor who shall serve in an advisory capacity to the Executive Cabinet. The Governor shall be the chairman, and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall be a second vice chairman of the Executive Cabinet. The Governor may designate others to serve as vice chairman. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall meet not less than once every two (2) months and at other times on call of the Governor. The Executive Cabinet shall be a part of the Office of the Governor and shall not constitute a separate department or agency of the state. Members of the cabinet shall be the major assistants to the Governor in the administration of the state government and shall assist the Governor in the proper operation of his office and perform other duties the Governor may require of them. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall consider matters involving policies and procedures the Governor or any member may place before it. The cabinet shall advise and consult with the Governor on all matters affecting the welfare of the state. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005; ch 95, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 99, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 154, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426 sec. 60, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 414, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 2, effective April 9, 1982; ch. 393, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 396, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 186, sec. 19, effective March 29, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. I, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 89, sec. 8, and 138, sec. 1, which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>