<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-042</section_number><catch_line>Coverage for newly born children from moment of birth. </catch_line><order_by>17-042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All individual health insurance policies providing coverage on an expense incurred basis regardless of whether the policies are issued for nonfamily or family coverage, shall, provide that health insurance benefits shall be payable with respect to a newly born child of the insured from the moment of birth. </section><section prefix="2">The coverage for newly born children shall consist of coverage of injury or sickness including the necessary care and treatment of medically diagnosed congenital defects and birth abnormalities. </section><section prefix="3">If payment of a specific premium or fee is required to provide coverage for a child the policy or contract may require that notification of birth of a newly born child and payment of the required premium or fees must be furnished to the insurer within thirty-one (31) days after the date of birth in order to have the coverage continue beyond such thirty-one (31) day period. </section><section prefix="4">The requirements of this section shall apply to all health insurance policies delivered in this state on and after July 15, 1994. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17290</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>