<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-150</section_number><catch_line>Project status reports by authority -- Annual overview report -- Construction activity report. </catch_line><order_by>20-150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before October 1, 1992, and on or before the first day of every third month thereafter, the authority shall provide a written project status report to the Legislative Research Commission, and the authority shall be compelled to send a representative to testify on the project status report and the authority shall provide additional information on any projects upon request by the Legislative Research Commission. The written project status report shall include but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">The current status of each project under consideration by the authority, the proposed cost of a project, for each project under consideration, including any proposed financial obligations of the authority, the number of jobs to be created or retained by each project under consideration, and a description of the applicants with respect to each project under consideration; and </section><section prefix="b">The current status of each project, along with an updated cost for each project in progress, including any financial obligations of the authority and a description of the principals with respect to each project in progress. </section></section><section prefix="2">On or before November 1 of each year, the authority shall submit an overview report to the Legislative Research Commission and the Governor as required in KRS 154.12-2035, on the success or failure of each completed project, in order to determine the effectiveness of the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the project status report, all construction, reconstruction, or alteration, financed or facilitated in whole or in part by the authority shall be reported to the Office of Employment and Training within the Department of Workforce Investment in the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet and to the Kentucky Legislative Research Commission not later than fifteen (15) days following the end of the month in which the agreement or contract facilitating or permitting such activity was executed. This construction activity report shall be subject to public information requests as provided by KRS 61.878. Reports shall list subject construction activity by location of project site, and shall specify the type of construction, project owner, estimated cost of project, and estimated starting and completion dates if known. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 35, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 67, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 21, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 154.180 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43520</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>