<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.265</section_number><catch_line>County clerk and employees to be trained and certified in system use. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county clerk, or county clerk-elect, shall, before utilizing or permitting his employees to utilize the automated vehicle registration and titling system, ensure that he and his employees have satisfactorily completed an orientation course regarding the forms, procedures and use of the system as instructed by the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk, or county clerk-elect, shall certify to the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation, those of his employees or prospective employees, who, together with himself, having satisfactorily completed the required orientation, will utilize the automated system under his direction. </section><section prefix="3">His certification shall be made by printing or typing upon a form supplied by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, the name of his county, and as to himself and each of his employees who will utilize the system, their last name, first name, and where available middle initial, their birth date, and Social Security account number, as to each person shown upon the certificate. The county clerk shall sign and date the certificate following a preprinted statement that shall read:  I certify under penalty of forgery in the second degree that the persons whose names appear above have satisfactorily completed an orientation on use of the automated vehicle registration and titling system as provided by this chapter and that the information supplied is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. I will not willfully permit anyone other than those persons shown hereon, or on another certificate of this same type executed by me, and persons authorized in writing by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, to use telecommunications terminals linked to the automated system and under my control. </section><section prefix="4">Each county clerk shall promptly notify the Department of Vehicle Regulation on a form supplied by it, of the name of any employee whose authorization to utilize the automated system has been terminated by him or whose employment by such clerk has ceased. </section><section prefix="5">Every county clerk and each of his employees who is authorized to utilize the automated system shall promptly report to the Department of Vehicle Regulation any attempted, actual, or suspected misuse of the automated system of which they become aware. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6189</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>