<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.080</section_number><catch_line>Applicator's license -- Fees -- Aerial applications. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 217B.090, it shall be unlawful for any person to act as an employee of a pesticide operator or dealer and apply pesticides manually, or as the applicator directly in charge of any equipment which is licensed or should be licensed under the provisions of this chapter for the application of any pesticide, without having obtained an applicator's license from the department. An applicator's license shall be in addition to any other license or permit required by law for the operation or use of any equipment. Any person applying for an applicator's license shall file an application on a form prescribed by the department on or before January 1 of each year. Application for a license to apply pesticides shall be accompanied by a license fee of ten dollars ($10). The provisions of this section shall not apply to any individual who has passed the examination provided for in KRS 217B.060(3), and is a licensed pesticide operator. If the department finds the applicant qualified to apply pesticides in the classifications he has applied for after examinations as provided for in KRS 217B.060(3), and if the applicant applying for a license to engage in aerial applications of pesticides has met all of the requirements of the Federal Aviation Agency and the Transportation Cabinet to operate the equipment described in the application, the department shall issue a pesticide applicator license limited to the classifications for which he is qualified which shall expire at the end of the calendar year of issue unless it has been revoked or suspended prior to that by the department for cause as provided for in KRS 217B.120. </section><section prefix="2">No license shall be issued unless the applicant holds a valid certification within this category. </section><section prefix="3">No license shall be issued unless the applicant is employed or supervised by a person who holds a valid operator's license. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 70, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 7. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9531</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>