<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.015</section_number><catch_line>Dogs, cats, and ferrets to be vaccinated against rabies -- Issuance and distribution of certificates -- Tags for dogs -- Requirements for compliance by qualified persons -- Cat and ferret owners -- Feral cats. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every owner shall have his dog, cat, or ferret initially vaccinated against rabies by the age of four (4) months and revaccinated at the expiration of the immunization period as certified by the veterinarian. The veterinarian who vaccinates a dog, cat, or ferret shall issue to the owner a vaccination certificate on a form approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. The vaccination certificate shall be prepared and issued in duplicate, one (1) copy to be retained by the issuing veterinarian and one (1) copy to be given to the owner of the dog, cat, or ferret vaccinated. Each certificate shall bear the name and address of the veterinarian who issued it. The veterinarian shall also furnish each dog owner with a rabies tag bearing a serial number corresponding to the vaccination certificate with the year of immunization. The tag shall be affixed to a collar or harness furnished by the owner and shall be worn by the dog for which the tag was issued. No one except the owner or his duly authorized agent shall remove the tag. </section><section prefix="2">Every qualified person who vaccinates his own dog shall comply with the vaccination certificate and tag requirement provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Every owner of a cat or ferret shall show proof of a valid rabies vaccination upon request of an animal control officer or peace officer. </section><section prefix="4">Any person with feral cats on his premises shall make a reasonable effort to capture or vaccinate the cats. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 569, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 515, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>