<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-720</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of compliance or exemption certificates -- Certificate required for registration renewal -- Exception -- Inspection of state vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>20-720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A compliance certificate shall be issued for each vehicle which meets and passes the annual inspection requirements. An exemption certificate may be issued under conditions adopted by the issuing authority, except that vehicles registered to military personnel on active duty whose duty station is outside of a county where a vehicle exhaust testing program is implemented shall receive an exemption certificate. A certificate shall be issued to a vehicle only at an official emissions inspection station established and operated under a valid permit issued by the cabinet. All certificates shall be serially numbered or otherwise identified. Certificates shall be strictly accounted for by the issuing authority. </section><section prefix="2">No vehicle registered in counties required by the cabinet to have a vehicle emission control program shall have its registration renewed pursuant to KRS Chapter 186 without a valid compliance certificate or exemption certificate issued pursuant to KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. Vehicles with state or official registration routinely operating in these counties shall be inspected at the same frequency as privately owned registered vehicles. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.466. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10366</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>