<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.848</section_number><catch_line>Medical emergency -- Approval of additional physician assistants -- Emergency permit. </catch_line><order_by>848</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "medical emergency" means a real and substantial threat to public health or the health of an individual as determined by the executive director of the board that requires additional professional resources. </section><section prefix="2">In a medical emergency, the board may approve an additional physician assistant for a supervising physician practicing in this Commonwealth for a period not to exceed thirty (30) days who: <section prefix="a">Submits satisfactorily completed forms to the board; and </section><section prefix="b">Is licensed and in good standing in this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">In a medical emergency, the board may issue an emergency permit to a physician assistant who: <section prefix="a">Is credentialed and in good standing in another state or Canadian province; </section><section prefix="b">Submits satisfactorily completed forms to the board; and </section><section prefix="c">Based on verifiable information, meets the requirements for licensure under KRS 311.844. </section></section><section prefix="4">An emergency permit: <section prefix="a">Shall be valid for a period of time not to exceed thirty (30) days; </section><section prefix="b">Shall not be renewed or reissued and shall be immediately canceled if a medical emergency no longer exists; </section><section prefix="c">May be canceled by the executive director upon reasonable cause without a prior hearing; and </section><section prefix="d">Shall not authorize a physician assistant to practice beyond a specified geographical area, beyond the scope of practice encompassed by the medical emergency, or without the supervision of a supervising physician. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 27, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 11, provides: "A physician assistant who is certified in Kentucky and in good standing on the effective date of this Act [July 12, 2006] shall automatically be licensed under Sections 1 to 10 of this Act [KRS 311.840, 311.842, 311.844, 311.845, 311.846, 311.848, 311.850, 311.852, 311.856, and 311.862] and shall be issued a physician assistant license upon annual renewal." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30652</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>