<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-430</section_number><catch_line>Form of application -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>4-430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each application for a license under this subtitle shall be made in writing, under oath or affirmation, in such form as the commissioner prescribes. </section><section prefix="2">The application shall contain: <section prefix="a">In the case of an individual, his name and the address of his residence and place of business; </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a partnership or association, the name and address of every member thereof and the address of the place where the business is to be conducted; </section><section prefix="c">In the case of a corporation, the names and addresses of the principal officers and directors thereof and the address of the place where the business is to be conducted; and </section><section prefix="d">Such additional information as the commissioner prescribes. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 658, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204 sec. 3, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.430.</former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14632</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>