<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.400</section_number><catch_line>Mine rules. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The licensee of any mine may adopt special rules consistent with KRS Chapter 351 and this chapter for the government and operation of his mine, and covering all the work pertaining thereto in and out of the mine. Before the rules are put into effect they shall be approved in writing by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">The mine rules shall be printed in a form prescribed by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee shall furnish each employee a copy of the mine rules, and each employee shall sign a statement indicating his receipt of a copy of the rules and his agreement to comply with them. </section><section prefix="4">The mine rules shall be included in the subjects taught during annual retraining of the mine's employees. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 26, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 45, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 21. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-54. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33021</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>