<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-010</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority -- Members -- Officers. </catch_line><order_by>20-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established within the cabinet, subject to the authority of the board, the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority as an agency, instrumentality, and political subdivision of the Commonwealth and a public body corporate and politic with all powers, duties, and responsibilities delegated to it by the board or as otherwise provided by law, including all programs, powers, duties, rights, and obligations of the Kentucky Development Finance Authority and the Kentucky Rural Economic Development Authority. </section><section prefix="2">Any interest, right, or cause of action held in whole or in part by any person, corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, government agency, or other entity under any agreement, contract, lease, mortgage, guarantee, bond, note, refund bond, or other financial transaction or obligation, made, issued, or otherwise entered into by any of the authorities, programs, or funds specified in subsection (1) of this section or that may be delegated to the authority by the board, shall not be impaired or otherwise diminished. </section><section prefix="3">Any interest, right, or cause of action held in whole or in part by any of the authorities, programs, or funds specified in subsection (1) of this section shall not be impaired or otherwise diminished, but shall be assumed by the authority, for and on behalf of the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall consist of a committee of seven (7) persons, including six (6) persons appointed by the board who shall be private citizens of the Commonwealth, and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet who shall serve ex officio. Any person appointed to the committee shall have experience and expertise in business or finance. </section><section prefix="5">Two (2) members initially appointed to the committee shall have a term of one (1) year each, two (2) members initially appointed to the committee shall have a term of two (2) years each, and two (2) members initially appointed to the committee shall have a term of three (3) years each, except that any person appointed to fill a vacancy shall serve only for the remainder of the unexpired term. All subsequent appointments shall be for a term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="6">Any person appointed to the committee shall be eligible for reappointment, including any member of the committee appointed prior to July 15, 1994. </section><section prefix="7">The members of the committee shall elect biennially from the committee's private citizen membership the following officers: chairman, vice chairman, secretary-treasurer, and any assistant secretaries and assistant treasurers the committee deems necessary. </section><section prefix="8">A majority of the members of the committee, determined by excluding any existing vacancies from the total number of members, shall constitute a quorum. A majority vote of the members present at a duly called meeting of the committee shall be required for the purposes of conducting its business and exercising its powers and for all other purposes. </section><section prefix="9">The committee shall prepare bylaws and procedures applicable to the operations of the authority and submit them to the board to be promulgated as administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="10">Members of the committee shall be entitled to compensation for their services in an amount of one hundred dollars ($100) for each regular meeting of the committee and shall be entitled to reimbursement for all necessary expenses in connection with the performance of their duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 213, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2662</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>