<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-110</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Forest Products Council. </catch_line><order_by>47-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To encourage the continued development of Kentucky's primary and secondary wood products industries, the Kentucky Forest Products Council is established. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall work with members of the primary and secondary wood products industries and owners of forest resources to foster cooperation in the planning and implementation of forest resources technical assistance and education efforts, including, but not limited to, silvicultural best management practices, a forest stewardship program, a master logger program, guidelines for water quality management, forest fire prevention and other technical assistance and education efforts focused on sustaining the development and productivity of the Commonwealth's forest resources. </section><section prefix="3">The council shall be comprised of the following members: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or his designee, who shall serve ex officio; </section><section prefix="b">The director of the Division of Forestry or his designee; </section><section prefix="c">The chairman of the University of Kentucky Department of Forestry or his designee; </section><section prefix="d">The chairman of the Kentucky Soil and Water Conservation Commission or his designee; </section><section prefix="e">A representative of the Kentucky Forest Industries Association appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="f">A representative of the primary wood products industry appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="g">A representative of the secondary wood products industry appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="h">A representative of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="i">A certified tree farmer or forest steward appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="j">A representative of the Kentucky paper products industry appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="k">Two representatives of public interest groups active in natural resource conservation or environmental protection issues appointed by the Governor from three (3) nominees, one (1) from the Cumberland Chapter of the Sierra Club, one (1) from the Kentucky Resources Council; and one (1) from Kentuckians for the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="4">The initial term of office of members appointed by the Governor shall be staggered so that the three (3) members shall serve for two (2) years each, two (2) members shall serve for three (3) years each, and two (2) members shall serve a four (4) year term. Subsequent appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years each. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as for the original appointment. Members appointed by the Governor may be reappointed by the Governor for succeeding terms. </section><section prefix="5">The council chairperson shall be appointed from the membership by the Governor for a term of two (2) years and may be reappointed by the Governor for succeeding terms. </section><section prefix="6">The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall provide staff services to the council. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 206, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 18, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 224, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was created by 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, and ch. 224, sec. 19, which are substantively identical and have been codified together. In resolving minor variations, Acts ch. 224, the later enactment, has been given precedence. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2949</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>