<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.068</section_number><catch_line>Transit tag for transporting motor vehicle out of state -- Administrative regulations -- Exclusion of motor vehicle dealers and distributors.    </catch_line><order_by>068</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Individual sellers or owners of motor vehicles that would ordinarily be registered under KRS 186.050(3) may obtain a transit tag from the Transportation Cabinet in order to transport the motor vehicle out of state. The fee for each transit tag issued shall be five dollars ($5). </section><section prefix="2">A transit tag issued under this section shall be issued only for a motor vehicle which is ineligible for: <section prefix="a">Registration under KRS 186.050; or </section><section prefix="b">Temporary registration under KRS 186A.100. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to establish application forms and procedures for the issuance of transit tags. The application for a transit tag under this section shall be accompanied by proof of vehicle ownership and proof of insurance coverage in compliance with KRS 304.39-080. </section><section prefix="4">A transit tag issued under this section shall be placed on a motor vehicle in the same manner as a regular license plate. </section><section prefix="5">Transit tags issued under this section shall expire fifteen (15) days from the date of issuance, and shall be designed in a manner that clearly identifies the expiration date on the face of the tag in a tamper-resistant manner. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to motor vehicle dealers or distributors licensed under </section>KRS Chapter 190. </text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>