<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.4977</section_number><catch_line>Grants to local school districts for family resource and youth services centers -- Supplemental grant program to provide health services. </catch_line><order_by>4977</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Grants shall be awarded to eligible local school districts to implement family resource and youth services centers as defined in KRS 156.496. </section><section prefix="2">Grant proposal instructions shall be developed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. The instructions shall be contained in a grant application package and distributed to each local public school district in which there are qualifying schools. </section><section prefix="3">A proposal review team comprised of at least three (3) members shall review proposals and score each application in accordance with training provided and scoring procedures established by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Proposal reviewers shall be selected by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. The reviewers shall submit the scored proposals to the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Written notification of the secretary's final decision on proposals shall be provided by the secretary to each applicant school district. </section><section prefix="4">The application from each qualifying school or school consortium shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">A statement of need; </section><section prefix="b">Proposed goals and outcomes; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the actual services and activities to be provided at the center and how they shall be provided; </section><section prefix="d">A description of how the children and families with the most urgent needs will be served first; </section><section prefix="e">Written agreements with other service providers; </section><section prefix="f">A description of the development, composition, and role of the local advisory council; </section><section prefix="g">The strategies to disseminate information; </section><section prefix="h">A training plan; </section><section prefix="i">A description of procedures to be followed to obtain parental permission for services and for sharing confidential information with other service providers. Procedures shall be developed pursuant to federal law and the Kentucky Revised Statutes including, but not limited to, KRS 210.410, 214.185, 222.441, 645.030, and Chapters 620 and 635 and shall require that no family resource center or youth services center offer contraceptives to minor students prior to receiving the express consent of the student's parent or legal guardian; </section><section prefix="j">A plan to minimize stigma; </section><section prefix="k">A work plan for each of the core components and optional components; </section><section prefix="l">Job descriptions for staff; </section><section prefix="m">A description of the center location and school accessibility; </section><section prefix="n">A description of the hours of operation of the center; </section><section prefix="o">A financial strategy and budget; </section><section prefix="p">A program evaluation plan; and </section><section prefix="q">Letters of endorsement and commitment to the center from community agencies and organizations. </section></section><section prefix="5">Grant proposal instruction and scoring procedures shall be made available to all qualifying schools. </section><section prefix="6">As funding becomes available, a supplemental grant program may fund the employment of a physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311 or nurse licensed under KRS Chapter 314 to provide health services as defined in KRS 156.4975 in a family resource or youth services center. <section prefix="a">The supplemental grant program shall be managed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and schools that have a family resource or youth services center may apply for grant funds under the guidelines and criteria established by promulgation of administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="b">The supplemental grant program may receive state appropriations, federal funds, gifts, or other contributions for the purposes specified under this subsection. </section><section prefix="c">A supplemental grant shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of a grant awarded under subsection (1) of this section, and a supplemental grant shall not reduce the amount of a grant awarded to a local school district under subsection (1) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008; and ch. 179, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 128, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective March 27, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 334, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994.– Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 2, effective April 15, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  This section was amended by 2008 Ky. Acts chs. 120 and 179, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>