<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.560</section_number><catch_line>Board of review -- Appointment -- Manner of deciding each claim -- Compensation -- Dissolution. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a board of review consisting of nine (9) persons who are residents and qualified voters of the Commonwealth, appointed by the Governor without limitation as to political affiliation, religion, race, sex, or past or present service in the Armed Forces, except that six (6) members of this board shall be veterans. The name of said board shall be "The Vietnam Veterans' Bonus Board of Review." The Governor shall designate a chairman and a secretary from among the membership. </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) members and no more shall constitute a board of review, and shall by concurrence of two (2) members decide any claim which comes before the board in the manner provided in KRS 40.520. The chairman of the board shall designate three (3) members to consider and decide each claim, having due regard for availability for service so that delay may be avoided. </section><section prefix="3">The chairman and secretary shall devote their full time to the affairs of the board and shall receive compensation at the rate to be fixed in accordance with personnel standards fixed by the commissioner of personnel until the functions of the board are performed and the board is dissolved as hereinafter provided. Other members of the board shall be compensated fifty dollars ($50) per diem, but only for actual time served in considering and deciding claims for veterans' bonuses pursuant to designation by the chairman. All members of the board shall be reimbursed for necessary travel to and from their places of residence, and in performance of duties pursuant to assignment, at the rate of eighteen cents ($0.18) per mile. </section><section prefix="4">Each claim coming before the board shall promptly be considered and decided by the three (3) members designated for that purpose. In every case, the board shall either affirm the decision of the administrator, or determine that a veterans' bonus should be paid, and to what persons and in what amounts. No written opinions or recitations of reasons for any decision need be made. A statement of the decision made shall be signed by at least two (2) of the three (3) members designated to decide the claim, and upon concurrence of two (2) members, a decision shall be final and not subject to reconsideration. </section><section prefix="5">When, after the thirty-first day of January, 1992, the board of review shall have decided all cases coming before it for decision, the chairman shall report such fact to the Governor in writing. The Governor shall thereupon declare that the board of review is dissolved, and shall so notify the members, and the functions and duties of the board shall be deemed to have been fully performed. </section></text><history>Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 6, effective March 1, 1991. --Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective>: March 1, 1991</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21878</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>