<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.810</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 164.810 to 164.870. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 164.810 to 164.870, the following terms shall have, unless the context shall otherwise indicate, the following meanings: <section prefix="a">"University of Louisville" means the university which is situated in a city of the first class, and which has heretofore constituted a municipal university within the meaning and application of KRS 165.010 et seq.; </section><section prefix="b">"Council" means the Council on Postsecondary Education in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">Consistent with the provisions of KRS 164.026 and Chapter 239 of the 1968 Kentucky Acts, the University of Louisville shall be maintained as a state institution effective July 1, 1970, subject to its qualification to receive the benefits of such status in the manner set forth in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The University of Louisville, having been chartered by Chapter 137, Acts of 1845-6, approved February 7, 1846, effective in accordance with its terms on March 15, 1846; having become subject to the laws of the Commonwealth generally applicable to corporations of the same category according to the import of subsection seventeen of Section 59 of the present Constitution of the Commonwealth; and having duly filed in the office of the Secretary of State its acceptance of the present Constitution of the Commonwealth in accordance with Section 190 thereof; may qualify to receive the benefits of its status as a state institution, as provided in KRS 164.810 to 164.870, by action of its board of trustees in adopting and causing to be filed for public record such proceedings as are required by law, amending its charter or articles of incorporation in such manner as to conform to the provisions of KRS 164.810 to 164.870. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 123, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 126, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>