<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.001</section_number><catch_line>Use of Kentucky Public Health Improvement Plan. </catch_line><order_by>001</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Public health stakeholders can be expected to use the Kentucky Public Health Improvement Plan in the following ways: <section prefix="a">As a guide for public health and local public health departments to plan their activities and budget their resources. </section><section prefix="b">As a guide for public health to educate the public about the activities and goals of the Department, its resource needs, and the progress it has made in achieving public health goals. </section><section prefix="c">As a guide for health-planning purposed by public and private health providers, such as hospitals, nursing homes, by provider associations, such as hospital associations, professional associations; and by health and social service organizations, including funding sources, and nonprofit human services agencies. </section><section prefix="d">As a guide for local groups and coalitions of health and health-related providers, and by local human services and other agencies, as for example, public schools, in the development of innovative efforts to provide community assessment, policy development, and assurance. </section><section prefix="e">As a resource for health policy analysts and academicians to devise and evaluate innovative health programs and services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Public Health Improvement Plan will be considered in health budget decisions. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Public Health Improvement Plan will be used as a measure of the adequacy of funding available for public health purposes. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6632</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>