<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="249" order_by="249">TREES, PLANTS, WEEDS, AND PESTS </unit></structure><section_number>249.430</section_number><catch_line>Authority of division. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text>In order to perform the duties listed in KRS 249.420, the division may: <section prefix="1">Utilize the services of a state advisory committee on Johnson grass control to be composed of persons interested in Johnson grass control appointed by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="2">Issue and enforce regulations for the eradication and control of noxious weeds, including Johnson grass, and pests; </section><section prefix="3">Cooperate with county agricultural agents, vocational agricultural teachers, University of Kentucky extension specialists, civic groups, or any federal, state or county agency in promoting county programs and organizations to control and eradicate noxious weeds and pests; </section><section prefix="4">Conduct or assist any governmental agency in conducting local or county-wide surveys to determine the degree of Johnson grass infestation; </section><section prefix="5">Cooperate with federal or state agencies in research and educational work in the field of pest and noxious weed control; </section><section prefix="6">Assist counties in qualifying for cost-sharing programs to control Johnson grass or other noxious weeds; </section><section prefix="7">Publicize the threat of noxious weeds and pests and methods of combating them; </section><section prefix="8">Cooperate with the Department of Highways, county fiscal courts, transportation and industrial organizations in controlling Johnson grass and other noxious weeds on their premises and rights-of-way; </section><section prefix="9">Accept funds or contributions to carry out the purposes of KRS 249.400 to 249.430. </section></text><history>Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1960</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>