<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">A RESPIRATORY CARE PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>314A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Respiratory care" includes "respiratory therapy," "inhalation therapy," or other "cardiopulmonary" terms. </section><section prefix="2">"Practice of respiratory care" means the procedures employed in the therapy, management, rehabilitation, gathering of assessment information, or other procedures administered to patients with deficiencies or abnormalities which affect their cardiopulmonary system and associated aspects of cardiopulmonary and other system functions. This includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">Provision of respiratory care procedures to ensure the safety, comfort, personal hygiene, protection of patients, and the performance of disease prevention and restorative measures; </section><section prefix="b">The administration of pharmacologic and therapeutic agents related to the cardiopulmonary care necessary for treatment, disease prevention, or rehabilitation regimes prescribed by a physician; and </section><section prefix="c">Observation of signs and symptoms of cardiopulmonary illness, reactions to treatment, general physical condition; determination of whether such signs, symptoms, reactions, behavior, or general appearance exhibit abnormal characteristics; and performance of standard procedures according to observed abnormalities, or reporting them to the physician in charge or other caretakers; initiating standard or emergency procedures. </section></section><section prefix="3">"Respiratory care practitioner" means a person who holds a mandatory certificate approved by the board. The term "respiratory care practitioner" includes the following: <section prefix="a">A "registered respiratory therapist" means an individual who has successfully completed a training program accredited by the American Medical Association's Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education or its equivalent in collaboration with the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care or its equivalent, and who has successfully completed the registry examination for advanced respiratory therapists administered by the National Board for Respiratory Care, Incorporated or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="b">A "certified respiratory therapist" means an individual who has successfully completed a training program accredited by the American Medical Association's Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education or its equivalent in collaboration with the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care or its equivalent, and who has successfully completed the entry level certification examination for respiratory therapists administered by the National Board for Respiratory Care, Incorporated or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="c">A "graduate respiratory care practitioner" means an individual who has graduated from an approved educational program and is eligible to sit for the entry level certification examination that will be administered by the National Board for Respiratory Care, Incorporated or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="d">A "student respiratory care practitioner" means: <section prefix="1">An individual enrolled in an education and training program, accredited by the American Medical Association's Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education or its equivalent and the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care or its equivalent, for respiratory care practitioners and whose sponsoring educational institution assumes responsibility for the supervision of and the services rendered by the student respiratory care practitioner while the student is functioning in a clinical training capacity; or </section><section prefix="2">An individual enrolled in an education and training program, accredited by the American Medical Association's Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education or its equivalent and the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care or its equivalent, and who is also employed for compensation to provide respiratory care services as outlined in KRS 314A.112. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Respiratory Care. </section><section prefix="5">"Accredited program" means a training program accredited by the American Medical Association's Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health or its equivalent in collaboration with the Committee on Accreditation for Respiratory Care or its equivalent which qualifies the graduate to sit for the registry examination or the entry level examination administered by the National Board for Respiratory Care or its equivalent. </section><section prefix="6">"Mandatory certification" means the board's official authorization to practice respiratory care for the time specified by the mandatory certification. </section><section prefix="7">"Continuing education" means educational activities primarily designed to keep respiratory care practitioners informed of developments in the respiratory care field or any special areas of practice engaged in by such persons. </section><section prefix="8">"Documented competency" means adherence to guidelines established by health facilities, medical staff, or accreditation agencies. These guidelines shall be in accordance with national standards of practice deemed appropriate by the American Association for Respiratory Care or its equivalent. </section><section prefix="9">"Medical director" means a licensed physician who is knowledgeable in the diagnosis, treatment, and assessment of respiratory problems and whose responsibilities are established by statutes and regulations governing the operation of facilities licensed under KRS Chapter 216B, as well as statutes and regulations dealing with hospice, home health, and other settings where respiratory care services may be delivered. </section><section prefix="10">"Direct supervision" means supervision by a holder of a mandatory certificate who shall be on the premises where respiratory care services are provided and who shall be available for immediate consultation. </section><section prefix="11">"Indirect supervision" means supervision by a holder of a mandatory certificate who shall be available by telephone and who shall have a response time, if needed, of thirty (30) minutes or less. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>