<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-236</section_number><catch_line>Total amounts of tax credit that may be awarded -- Administrative regulations -- Contract for administration and management of certification and application procedure. </catch_line><order_by>20-236</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The total amount of tax credit that may be awarded by the authority in each calendar year, pursuant to KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240, to: <section prefix="a">All qualified investors shall be no more than three million dollars ($3,000,000); and </section><section prefix="b">Any individual qualified investor shall be no more than two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000). </section></section><section prefix="2">The total amount of tax credit that may be awarded by the authority to: <section prefix="a">All qualified investors pursuant to KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240; and </section><section prefix="b">All investors in all investment funds pursuant to KRS 154.20-250 to 154.20-284; </section></section> shall be no more than forty million dollars ($40,000,000) in total for all years. Once this total amount of tax credit has been awarded by the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240 and KRS 154.20-250 to 154.20-284, no further awards of any tax credit shall be made. <section prefix="3">The authority shall, by promulgation of an administrative regulation, develop a standard procedure for: <section prefix="a">Small businesses and investors to request certification for participation in the program; </section><section prefix="b">Qualified investors to request certification of a planned investment as being a qualified investment, and to apply for a credit; and </section><section prefix="c">The award of credits to qualified investors making qualified investments. </section></section><section prefix="4">At a minimum, the procedure shall: <section prefix="a">Require small businesses and investors to demonstrate to the authority that they, and any planned investment, satisfy all requirements provided in KRS 154.20-234; </section><section prefix="b">Provide small businesses and investors with a standard written application form to request certification and apply for a credit; </section><section prefix="c">Require the payment of a fee; and </section><section prefix="d">Mandate a time period for the duration of certifications granted to small businesses and investors, and the procedures for recertification thereof. </section></section><section prefix="5">The amount of credit awarded shall be equal to: <section prefix="a">Forty percent (40%) of the amount of the qualified investment, if the principal place of business of the qualified small business is outside an enhanced incentive county; or </section><section prefix="b">Fifty percent (50%) of the amount of the qualified investment, if the principal place of business of the qualified small business is in an enhanced incentive county. </section></section><section prefix="6">Upon approval of a credit, the authority shall reduce the amount of available credit by the amount of credit approved to the qualified investor. </section><section prefix="7">The authority may, in effectuating this section, contract with a science and technology organization as defined in KRS 164.6011 to administer and manage the certification and application procedure established by the authority. However, the final approval of all credits shall be made solely by the authority. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 24, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>