<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.322</section_number><catch_line>Custody, visitation, and inheritance rights denied parent convicted of felony sexual offense from which victim delivered a child -- Waiver -- child support obligation. </catch_line><order_by>322</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth recognizes that certain victims of sexual assault may conceive a child as a result of the sexual assault and may choose to bear and raise the child. The Commonwealth also recognizes that victims of a sexual assault who have elected to raise a child born as a result of the sexual assault, as well as that child, may suffer serious emotional or physical trauma if the perpetrator of the assault is granted parental rights with the child. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, any person who has been convicted of a felony offense under KRS Chapter 510, in which the victim of that offense has conceived and delivered a child, shall not have custody or visitation rights, or the rights of inheritance under KRS Chapter 391 with respect to that child. </section><section prefix="3">The mother of the child may waive the protection afforded under subsection (2) of this section regarding visitation and request that the court grant reasonable visitation rights with the child if paternity has been acknowledged. </section><section prefix="4">Unless waived by the mother and, if applicable, the public agency substantially contributing to the support of the child, a court shall establish a child support obligation against the father of the child pursuant to KRS 403.211. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>