<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.0445</section_number><catch_line>Outpatient health facility operated by hospital -- Licensure -- Certificate of need. </catch_line><order_by>0445</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, if the Federal Health Care Financing Administration issues a final regulation establishing an outpatient Medicare prospective payment system for hospitals that requires that an outpatient health facility operated by the hospital be under the same license as the hospital to achieve provider-based status, the cabinet shall, at the hospital's request, issue a new license to a hospital that owns and operates an existing or newly established outpatient health facility that lists each location operated by the hospital. </section><section prefix="2">Any outpatient health facility listed on the hospital's license under subsection (1) of this section shall: <section prefix="a">Comply with the applicable licensure regulations that pertain to the type of health services provided; and </section><section prefix="b">Prior to the establishment of a health facility, the operation of a health facility, or the provision of health services or the addition of a health service at a location other than the hospital's main campus, obtain a certificate of need if a certificate of need would otherwise be required in the absence of subsection (1) of this section. Licensure of the outpatient health facility or service under the same license as the hospital pursuant to subsection (1) of this section shall not eliminate the requirement for a certificate of need. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 4, effective April 4, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> April 4, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9196</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>