<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.095</section_number><catch_line>Division of Women's Health -- Receipt of gifts, grants, and bequests.   </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services a Division of Women's Health for the purpose of: <section prefix="a">Serving as a repository for data and information affecting women's physical and mental health issues; </section><section prefix="b">Analyzing and communicating trends in women's health issues and mental health; </section><section prefix="c">Recommending to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and to any advisory committees created under KRS 216.2923, data elements affecting women's physical and mental health. The division shall advise and direct which data elements should be collected, analyzed, and reported in a timely manner under KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929; </section><section prefix="d">Cooperating and collaborating with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in receiving and disseminating through all forms of media including the Internet relevant aggregate data findings under KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929 which affect women; and </section><section prefix="e">Planning, developing, and administering a Women's Health Resource Center within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to focus on targeted preventive care and comprehensive health education. </section></section><section prefix="2">The division may accept gifts, grants, and bequests in support of its mission and duties specified in subsection (1) of this section. All money received shall be administered by the cabinet, which shall administer these funds through appropriate trust and agency accounts. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 154, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 427, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40937</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>