<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.020</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of state highway engineer -- Divisions within the department. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With prior approval of the Governor and the secretary in writing, the commissioner of highways shall appoint as state highway engineer, a civil engineer who has had at least six (6) years executive engineering experience in the design, supervision, and construction of highways. He shall be the technical advisor to the commissioner of highways, and under the direction of the commissioner, he shall supervise all construction and maintenance work of the department and perform such other duties as are assigned to him by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">With prior approval of the secretary and pursuant to KRS Chapter 12, the department shall be divided into such divisions as the commissioner of highways may deem necessary to perform the duties and functions of the department. Each division shall perform the duties assigned to it by the commissioner of highways and shall be headed by a director who shall act under the direction and supervision of the commissioner of highways. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 17. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 19. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356t-2, 4618-99. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>