<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise provides: <section prefix="1">"Advertising and promotional direct mail" means direct mail the primary purpose of which is to attract public attention to a product, person, business, or organization, or to attempt to sell, popularize, or secure financial support for a product, person, business, or organization. As used in this definition, "product" means tangible personal property, an item transferred electronically, or a service; </section><section prefix="2">"Business" includes any activity engaged in by any person or caused to be engaged in by that person with the object of gain, benefit, or advantage, either direct or indirect; </section><section prefix="3">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">"Digital audio-visual works" means a series of related images which, when shown in succession, impart an impression of motion, with accompanying sounds, if any. </section><section prefix="b">"Digital audio-visual works" includes movies, motion pictures, musical videos, news and entertainment programs, and live events. </section><section prefix="c">"Digital audio-visual works" shall not include video greeting cards, video games, and electronic games; </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">"Digital audio works" means works that result from the fixation of a series of musical, spoken, or other sounds. </section><section prefix="b">"Digital audio works" includes ringtones, recorded or live songs, music, readings of books or other written materials, speeches, or other sound recordings. </section><section prefix="c">"Digital audio works" shall not include audio greeting cards sent by electronic mail; </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">"Digital books" means works that are generally recognized in the ordinary and usual sense as books, including any literary work expressed in words, numbers, or other verbal or numerical symbols or indicia if the literary work is generally recognized in the ordinary or usual sense as a book. </section><section prefix="b">"Digital books" shall not include digital audio-visual works, digital audio works, periodicals, magazines, newspapers, or other news or information products, chat rooms, or Web logs; </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Digital code" means a code which provides a purchaser with a right to obtain one (1) or more types of digital property. A "digital code" may be obtained by any means, including electronic mail messaging or by tangible means, regardless of the code's designation as a song code, video code, or book code. </section><section prefix="b">"Digital code" shall not include a code that represents: <section prefix="1">A stored monetary value that is deducted from a total as it is used by the purchaser; or </section><section prefix="2">A redeemable card, gift card, or gift certificate that entitles the holder to select specific types of digital property; </section></section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">"Digital property" means any of the following which is transferred electronically: <section prefix="1">Digital audio works; </section><section prefix="2">Digital books; </section><section prefix="3">Finished artwork; </section><section prefix="4">Digital photographs; </section><section prefix="5">Periodicals; </section><section prefix="6">Newspapers; </section><section prefix="7">Magazines; </section><section prefix="8">Video greeting cards; </section><section prefix="9">Audio greeting cards; </section><section prefix="10">Video games; </section><section prefix="11">Electronic games; or </section><section prefix="12">Any digital code related to this property. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Digital property" shall not include digital audio-visual works or satellite radio programming; </section></section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">"Direct mail" means printed material delivered or distributed by United States mail or other delivery service to a mass audience or to addressees on a mailing list provided by the purchaser or at the direction of the purchaser when the cost of the items are not billed directly to the recipient. </section><section prefix="b">"Direct mail" includes tangible personal property supplied directly or indirectly by the purchaser to the direct mail retailer for inclusion in the package containing the printed material. </section><section prefix="c">"Direct mail" does not include multiple items of printed material delivered to a single address; </section></section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">"Finished artwork" means final art that is used for actual reproduction by photomechanical or other processes or for display purposes. </section><section prefix="b">"Finished artwork" includes: <section prefix="1">Assemblies; </section><section prefix="2">Charts; </section><section prefix="3">Designs; </section><section prefix="4">Drawings; </section><section prefix="5">Graphs; </section><section prefix="6">Illustrative materials; </section><section prefix="7">Lettering; </section><section prefix="8">Mechanicals; </section><section prefix="9">Paintings; and </section><section prefix="10">Paste-ups; </section></section></section><section prefix="12"><section prefix="a">"Gross receipts" and "sales price" mean the total amount or consideration, including cash, credit, property, and services, for which tangible personal property, digital property, or services are sold, leased, or rented, valued in money, whether received in money or otherwise, without any deduction for any of the following: <section prefix="1">The retailer's cost of the tangible personal property or digital property sold; </section><section prefix="2">The cost of the materials used, labor or service cost, interest, losses, all costs of transportation to the retailer, all taxes imposed on the retailer, or any other expense of the retailer; </section><section prefix="3">Charges by the retailer for any services necessary to complete the sale; </section><section prefix="4">Delivery charges, which are defined as charges by the retailer for the preparation and delivery to a location designated by the purchaser including transportation, shipping, postage, handling, crating, and packing; and </section><section prefix="5">Any amount for which credit is given to the purchaser by the retailer, other than credit for tangible personal property or digital property traded when the tangible personal property or digital property traded is of like kind and character to the property purchased and the property traded is held by the retailer for resale. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Gross receipts" and "sales price" shall include consideration received by the retailer from a third party if: <section prefix="1">The retailer actually receives consideration from a third party and the consideration is directly related to a price reduction or discount on the sale to the purchaser; </section><section prefix="2">The retailer has an obligation to pass the price reduction or discount through to the purchaser; </section><section prefix="3">The amount of consideration attributable to the sale is fixed and determinable by the retailer at the time of the sale of the item to the purchaser; and </section><section prefix="4">One (1) of the following criteria is met: <section prefix="a">The purchaser presents a coupon, certificate, or other documentation to the retailer to claim a price reduction or discount where the coupon, certificate, or documentation is authorized, distributed, or granted by a third party with the understanding that the third party will reimburse any seller to whom the coupon, certificate, or documentation is presented; </section><section prefix="b">The price reduction or discount is identified as a third-party price reduction or discount on the invoice received by the purchaser or on a coupon, certificate, or other documentation presented by the purchaser; or </section><section prefix="c">The purchaser identifies himself or herself to the retailer as a member of a group or organization entitled to a price reduction or discount. A "preferred customer" card that is available to any patron does not constitute membership in such a group. </section></section></section><section prefix="c">"Gross receipts" and "sales price" shall not include: <section prefix="1">Discounts, including cash, term, or coupons that are not reimbursed by a third party and that are allowed by a retailer and taken by a purchaser on a sale; </section><section prefix="2">Interest, financing, and carrying charges from credit extended on the sale of tangible personal property, digital property, or services, if the amount is separately stated on the invoice, bill of sale, or similar document given to the purchaser; </section><section prefix="3">Any taxes legally imposed directly on the purchaser that are separately stated on the invoice, bill of sale, or similar document given to the purchaser; or </section><section prefix="4">The amount charged for labor or services rendered in installing or applying the tangible personal property, digital property, or service sold, provided the amount charged is separately stated on the invoice, bill of sale, or similar document given to the purchaser. </section></section><section prefix="d">As used in this subsection, "third party" means a person other than the purchaser; </section></section><section prefix="13">"In this state" or "in the state" means within the exterior limits of the Commonwealth and includes all territory within these limits owned by or ceded to the United States of America; </section><section prefix="14"><section prefix="a">"Lease or rental" means any transfer of possession or control of tangible personal property for a fixed or indeterminate term for consideration. A lease or rental shall include future options to: <section prefix="1">Purchase the property; or </section><section prefix="2">Extend the terms of the agreement and agreements covering trailers where the amount of consideration may be increased or decreased by reference to the amount realized upon sale or disposition of the property as defined in 26 U.S.C. sec. 7701(h)(1). </section></section><section prefix="b">"Lease or rental" shall not include: <section prefix="1">A transfer of possession or control of property under a security agreement or deferred payment plan that requires the transfer of title upon completion of the required payments; </section><section prefix="2">A transfer of possession or control of property under an agreement that requires the transfer of title upon completion of the required payments and payment of an option price that does not exceed the greater of one hundred dollars ($100) or one percent (1%) of the total required payments; or </section><section prefix="3">Providing tangible personal property and an operator for the tangible personal property for a fixed or indeterminate period of time. To qualify for this exclusion, the operator must be necessary for the equipment to perform as designed, and the operator must do more than maintain, inspect, or setup the tangible personal property. </section></section><section prefix="c">This definition shall apply regardless of the classification of a transaction under generally accepted accounting principles, the Internal Revenue Code, or other provisions of federal, state, or local law; </section></section><section prefix="15"><section prefix="a">"Machinery for new and expanded industry" means machinery: <section prefix="1">Used directly in a manufacturing or processing production process; </section><section prefix="2">Which is incorporated for the first time into a plant facility established in this state; and </section><section prefix="3">Which does not replace machinery in the plant facility unless that machinery purchased to replace existing machinery: <section prefix="a">Increases the consumption of recycled materials at the plant facility by not less than ten percent (10%); </section><section prefix="b">Performs different functions; </section><section prefix="c">Is used to manufacture a different product; or </section><section prefix="d">Has a greater productive capacity, as measured in units of production, than the machinery being replaced. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">The term "machinery for new and expanded industry" does not include repair, replacement, or spare parts of any kind regardless of whether the purchase of repair, replacement, or spare parts is required by the manufacturer or vendor as a condition of sale or as a condition of warranty. </section><section prefix="c">The term "processing production" shall include the processing and packaging of raw materials, in-process materials, and finished products; the processing and packaging of farm and dairy products for sale; and the extraction of minerals, ores, coal, clay, stone, and natural gas; </section></section><section prefix="16">"Manufacturing" means any process through which material having little or no commercial value for its intended use before processing has appreciable commercial value for its intended use after processing by the machinery. The manufacturing or processing production process commences with the movement of raw materials from storage into a continuous, unbroken, integrated process and ends when the product being manufactured is packaged and ready for sale; </section><section prefix="17"><section prefix="a">"Occasional sale" includes: <section prefix="1">A sale of tangible personal property or digital property not held or used by a seller in the course of an activity for which he or she is required to hold a seller's permit, provided such sale is not one (1) of a series of sales sufficient in number, scope, and character to constitute an activity requiring the holding of a seller's permit. In the case of the sale of the entire, or a substantial portion of the nonretail assets of the seller, the number of previous sales of similar assets shall be disregarded in determining whether or not the current sale or sales shall qualify as an occasional sale; or </section><section prefix="2">Any transfer of all or substantially all the tangible personal property or digital property held or used by a person in the course of such an activity when after such transfer the real or ultimate ownership of such property is substantially similar to that which existed before such transfer. </section></section><section prefix="b">For the purposes of this subsection, stockholders, bondholders, partners, or other persons holding an interest in a corporation or other entity are regarded as having the "real or ultimate ownership" of the tangible personal property or digital property of such corporation or other entity; </section></section><section prefix="18"><section prefix="a">"Other direct mail" means any direct mail that is not advertising and promotional direct mail, regardless of whether advertising and promotional direct mail is included in the same mailing. </section><section prefix="b">"Other direct mail" includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">Transactional direct mail that contains personal information specific to the addressee, including but not limited to invoices, bills, statements of account, and payroll advices; </section><section prefix="2">Any legally required mailings, including but not limited to privacy notices, tax reports, and stockholder reports; and </section><section prefix="3">Other nonpromotional direct mail delivered to existing or former shareholders, customers, employees, or agents, including but not limited to newsletters and informational pieces. </section></section><section prefix="c">"Other direct mail" does not include the development of billing information or the provision of any data processing service that is more than incidental to the production of printed material; </section></section><section prefix="19">"Person" includes any individual, firm, copartnership, joint venture, association, social club, fraternal organization, corporation, estate, trust, business trust, receiver, trustee, syndicate, cooperative, assignee, governmental unit or agency, or any other group or combination acting as a unit; </section><section prefix="20">"Permanent," as the term applies to digital property, means perpetual or for an indefinite or unspecified length of time; </section><section prefix="21">"Plant facility" means a single location that is exclusively dedicated to manufacturing or processing production activities. For purposes of this section, a location shall be deemed to be exclusively dedicated to manufacturing activities even if retail sales are made there, provided that the retail sales are incidental to the manufacturing activities occurring at the location. The term "plant facility" shall not include any restaurant, grocery store, shopping center, or other retail establishment; </section><section prefix="22">"Prewritten computer software" means: <section prefix="a">Computer software, including prewritten upgrades, that are not designed and developed by the author or other creator to the specifications of a specific purchaser. The combining of two (2) or more prewritten computer software programs or portions thereof does not cause the combination to be other than prewritten computer software; </section><section prefix="b">Software designed and developed by the author or other creator to the specifications of a specific purchaser when it is sold to a person other than the original purchaser; or </section><section prefix="c">Any portion of prewritten computer software that is modified or enhanced in any manner, where the modification or enhancement is designed and developed to the specifications of a specific purchaser. When a person modifies or enhances computer software of which the person is not the author or creator, the person shall be deemed to be the author or creator only of the modifications or enhancements the person actually made. In the case of modified or enhanced prewritten software, if there is a reasonable, separately stated charge on an invoice or other statement of the price to the purchaser for the modification or enhancement, then the modification or enhancement shall not constitute prewritten computer software; </section></section><section prefix="23">"Purchase" means any transfer of title or possession, exchange, barter, lease, or rental, conditional or otherwise, in any manner or by any means whatsoever, of tangible personal property or digital property transferred electronically for a consideration and includes: <section prefix="a">When performed outside this state or when the customer gives a resale certificate, the producing, fabricating, processing, printing, or imprinting of tangible personal property for a consideration for consumers who furnish either directly or indirectly the materials used in the producing, fabricating, processing, printing, or imprinting; </section><section prefix="b">A transaction whereby the possession of tangible personal property or digital property is transferred but the seller retains the title as security for the payment of the price; and </section><section prefix="c">A transfer for a consideration of the title or possession of tangible personal property or digital property which has been produced, fabricated, or printed to the special order of the customer, or of any publication; </section></section><section prefix="24">"Recycled materials" means materials which have been recovered or diverted from the solid waste stream and reused or returned to use in the form of raw materials or products; </section><section prefix="25">"Recycling purposes" means those activities undertaken in which materials that would otherwise become solid waste are collected, separated, or processed in order to be reused or returned to use in the form of raw materials or products; </section><section prefix="26"><section prefix="a">"Repair, replacement, or spare parts" means any tangible personal property used to maintain, restore, mend, or repair machinery or equipment. </section><section prefix="b">"Repair, replacement, or spare parts" does not include machine oils, grease, or industrial tools; </section></section><section prefix="27"><section prefix="a">"Retailer" means: <section prefix="1">Every person engaged in the business of making retail sales of tangible personal property, digital property, or furnishing any services included in KRS 139.200; </section><section prefix="2">Every person engaged in the business of making sales at auction of tangible personal property or digital property owned by the person or others for storage, use or other consumption, except as provided in paragraph (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="3">Every person making more than two (2) retail sales of tangible personal property or digital property during any twelve (12) month period, including sales made in the capacity of assignee for the benefit of creditors, or receiver or trustee in bankruptcy; </section><section prefix="4">Any person conducting a race meeting under the provision of KRS Chapter 230, with respect to horses which are claimed during the meeting. </section></section><section prefix="b">When the department determines that it is necessary for the efficient administration of this chapter to regard any salesmen, representatives, peddlers, or canvassers as the agents of the dealers, distributors, supervisors or employers under whom they operate or from whom they obtain the tangible personal property or digital property sold by them, irrespective of whether they are making sales on their own behalf or on behalf of the dealers, distributors, supervisors or employers, the department may so regard them and may regard the dealers, distributors, supervisors or employers as retailers for purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Any person making sales at a charitable auction for a qualifying entity shall not be a retailer for purposes of the sales made at the charitable auction if: <section prefix="a">The qualifying entity, not the person making sales at the auction, is sponsoring the auction; </section><section prefix="b">The purchaser of tangible personal property at the auction directly pays the qualifying entity sponsoring the auction for the property and not the person making the sales at the auction; and </section><section prefix="c">The qualifying entity, not the person making sales at the auction, is responsible for the collection, control, and disbursement of the auction proceeds. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the conditions set forth in subparagraph 1. of this paragraph are met, the qualifying entity sponsoring the auction shall be the retailer for purposes of the sales made at the charitable auction. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this paragraph, "qualifying entity" means a resident: <section prefix="a">Church; </section><section prefix="b">School; </section><section prefix="c">Civic club; or </section><section prefix="d">Any other nonprofit charitable, religious, or educational organization; </section></section></section></section><section prefix="28">"Retail sale" means any sale, lease, or rental for any purpose other than resale, sublease, or subrent; </section><section prefix="29"><section prefix="a">"Ringtones" means digitized sound files that are downloaded onto a device and that may be used to alert the customer with respect to a communication. </section><section prefix="b">"Ringtones" shall not include ringback tones or other digital files that are not stored on the purchaser's communications device; </section></section><section prefix="30"><section prefix="a">"Sale" means the furnishing of any services included in KRS 139.200; any transfer of title or possession, exchange, barter, lease, or rental, conditional or otherwise, in any manner or by any means whatsoever, of tangible personal property; or digital property transferred electronically for a consideration, and includes: <section prefix="1">The producing, fabricating, processing, printing, or imprinting of tangible personal property or digital property for a consideration for purchasers who furnish, either directly or indirectly, the materials used in the producing, fabricating, processing, printing, or imprinting; </section><section prefix="2">A transaction whereby the possession of tangible personal property or digital property is transferred, but the seller retains the title as security for the payment of the price; and </section><section prefix="3">A transfer for a consideration of the title or possession of tangible personal property or digital property which has been produced, fabricated, or printed to the special order of the purchaser. </section></section><section prefix="b">This definition shall apply regardless of the classification of a transaction under generally accepted accounting principles, the Internal Revenue Code, or other provisions of federal, state, or local law; </section></section><section prefix="31">"Seller" includes every person engaged in the business of selling tangible personal property, digital property, or services of a kind, the gross receipts from the retail sale of which are required to be included in the measure of the sales tax, and every person engaged in making sales for resale; </section><section prefix="32"><section prefix="a">"Storage" includes any keeping or retention in this state for any purpose except sale in the regular course of business or subsequent use solely outside this state of tangible personal property or digital property purchased from a retailer. </section><section prefix="b">"Storage" does not include the keeping, retaining, or exercising any right or power over tangible personal property for the purpose of subsequently transporting it outside the state for use thereafter solely outside the state, or for the purpose of being processed, fabricated, or manufactured into, attached to, or incorporated into, other tangible personal property to be transported outside the state and thereafter used solely outside the state; </section></section><section prefix="33">"Tangible personal property" means personal property which may be seen, weighed, measured, felt, or touched, or which is in any other manner perceptible to the senses and includes natural, artificial, and mixed gas, electricity, water, steam, and prewritten computer software; </section><section prefix="34">"Taxpayer" means any person liable for tax under this chapter; </section><section prefix="35">"Transferred electronically" means accessed or obtained by the purchaser by means other than tangible storage media; and </section><section prefix="36"><section prefix="a">"Use" includes the exercise of any right or power over tangible personal property or digital property incident to the ownership of that property, or by any transaction in which possession is given, or by any transaction involving digital property where the right of access is granted. </section><section prefix="b">"Use" does not include the keeping, retaining, or exercising any right or power over tangible personal property or digital property for the purpose of: <section prefix="1">Selling tangible personal property or digital property in the regular course of business; or </section><section prefix="2">Subsequently transporting tangible personal property outside the state for use thereafter solely outside the state, or for the purpose of being processed, fabricated, or manufactured into, attached to, or incorporated into, other tangible personal property to be transported outside the state and thereafter used solely outside the state. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2011. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2009; and ch. 86, sec. 13, effective August 1, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 4, effective August 1, 2008. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 1, effective February 5, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (8/1/2009).  The Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering of subsection (26) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1 under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39929</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>