<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.1-060</section_number><catch_line>Principal place of administration. </catch_line><order_by>1-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Without precluding other means for establishing a connection with the designated jurisdiction, terms of a trust designating the principal place of administration are valid and controlling if: <section prefix="a">A trustee’s principal place of business is located in or a trustee is a resident of the designated jurisdiction; or </section><section prefix="b">All or part of the administration occurs in the designated jurisdiction. </section></section><section prefix="2">A trustee is under a continuing duty to administer the trust at a place appropriate to its purposes, its administration, and the interests of the beneficiaries. </section><section prefix="3">Without precluding the right of the court to order, approve, or disapprove a transfer, the trustee, in furtherance of the duty prescribed by subsection (2) of this section, may transfer the trust’s principal place of administration to another state or to a jurisdiction outside of the United States. </section><section prefix="4">The trustee shall notify the qualified beneficiaries of a proposed transfer of a trust’s principal place of administration not less than sixty (60) days before initiating the transfer. The notice of proposed transfer shall include: <section prefix="a">The name of the jurisdiction to which the principal place of administration is to be transferred; </section><section prefix="b">The address and telephone number at the new location at which the trustee can be contacted; </section><section prefix="c">An explanation of the reasons for the proposed transfer; </section><section prefix="d">The date on which the proposed transfer is anticipated to occur; and </section><section prefix="e">The date, not less than sixty (60) days after the giving of the notice, by which the qualified beneficiary shall notify the trustee of an objection to the proposed transfer. </section></section><section prefix="5">The authority of a trustee under this section to transfer a trust’s principal place of administration ends if a qualified beneficiary notifies the trustee of an objection to the proposed transfer on or before the date specified in the notice. </section><section prefix="6">In connection with a transfer of the trust’s principal place of administration, the trustee may transfer some or all of the trust property to a successor trustee designated in the terms of the trust or appointed under KRS 386B.7-040. </section><section prefix="7">The District Court shall have exclusive jurisdiction over matters under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43069</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>