<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.210</section_number><catch_line>Riverport financial assistance trust fund -- Contributions -- Purpose -- Grants -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a riverport financial assistance trust fund, to be administered by the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The riverport financial assistance trust fund may receive appropriations, federal funds, contributions, gifts, and donations. </section><section prefix="3">The purpose of the riverport financial assistance trust fund shall be to improve riverport facilities and infrastructure, to capture the economic and trade potential offered by water transportation. To the extent funds are available, the fund shall make grants to riverport authorities for new construction and major replacement or repair projects, including but not limited to improvement of docks, wharves, equipment, port buildings, storage facilities, roads and railroads to facilitate the flow of commerce through the port, other on-site improvements, and related professional services. Eligible projects shall not include routine operations, maintenance, or repair activities. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, moneys remaining in the fund at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall carry forward into the succeeding fiscal year. Interest earned on any moneys in the fund shall accrue to the fund. Amounts from the fund shall be disbursed and expended in accordance with this section. </section><section prefix="5">To be eligible for a grant under this section, the applicant shall provide at least a twenty percent (20%) match, which may be obtained from any public or private source. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Grant applications shall be reviewed and awarded annually. </section><section prefix="b">The Transportation Cabinet shall submit all applications to the Water Transportation Advisory Board established by KRS 174.200 for evaluation and recommendations prior to awarding any grant funding under this section. </section><section prefix="c">Priority shall be given to applicants with a riverport master plan, for capital-intensive projects for which permits have been obtained, and for projects for which matching funds have been obtained. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Transportation Cabinet shall submit on an annual basis a report detailing all grants awarded under this section to the Water Transportation Advisory Board, the Interim Joint Committee on Transportation, and the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note>(9/24/2015). The phrase "Notwithstanding KRS 45.299" in subsection (4) of this statute has been changed to "Notwithstanding KRS 45.229." This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-12-09</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5020</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>