<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.685</section_number><catch_line>Stalking.   </catch_line><order_by>685</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person subject to this code is guilty of stalking and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct who: <section prefix="a">Wrongfully engages in a course of conduct directed at a specific person that would cause a reasonable person to fear death or bodily harm, including sexual assault, to himself or herself or a member of his or her immediate family; </section><section prefix="b">Has knowledge, or should have knowledge, that the specific person will be placed in reasonable fear of death or bodily harm, including sexual assault, to himself or herself or a member of his or her immediate family; and </section><section prefix="c">Induces reasonable fear in the specific person or bodily harm, including sexual assault, to himself or herself or to a member of his or her immediate family, through the person's actions. </section></section><section prefix="2">In this section: <section prefix="a">"Course of conduct" means: <section prefix="1">A repeated maintenance of visual or physical proximity to a specific person; or </section><section prefix="2">A repeated conveyance of verbal threat, written threats, or threats implied by conduct, or a combination of these threats, directed at or towards a specific person; </section></section><section prefix="b">"Repeated," with respect to conduct, means two (2) or more occasions of that conduct; and </section><section prefix="c">"Immediate family," in the case of a specific person, means a spouse, parent, child, or sibling of the person, or any other family member, relative, or intimate partner of the person who regularly resides in the household of the person or who within the six (6) months preceding the commencement of the course of conduct regularly resided in the household of the person. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 123, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42004</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>