<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6671</section_number><catch_line>Permit required for installation of initial system -- Contents of application and permit -- Exemptions.  </catch_line><order_by>6671</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding KRS 198B.030 to the contrary, any person who installs an initial heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system shall apply for a permit prior to beginning the installation. No installation shall begin before the application for the permit has been filed. In no event, however, shall a person exempt under KRS 198B.674 be required to possess or show proof of a heating, ventilation, or air conditioning license in order to obtain the permit required by this section. </section><section prefix="2">The applicant for a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning permit, by the act of applying for the permit, shall be deemed to consent to inspection of the installation by authorized inspectors of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and of the relevant city, county, urban-county, charter county, unified local government, or consolidated local government. </section><section prefix="3">The permit shall give: <section prefix="a">The name of the person performing the work; </section><section prefix="b">The full extent of the work to be performed; </section><section prefix="c">The name of the owner or owners of the property where the work is to be performed; </section><section prefix="d">The location of the property where the work is to be performed, including county and street address; and </section><section prefix="e">The master license number, if the work is required to be performed by a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor. </section></section><section prefix="4">No permit shall be required for any installation performed on a manufactured home as defined by KRS 227.550(7), by a manufactured home retailer licensed pursuant to KRS 227.610, or by a manufacturer as defined by KRS 227.550(9). </section><section prefix="5">No permit or inspection shall be required for the installation of window unit air conditioners or space heaters. </section><section prefix="6">No permit or inspection shall be required for the installation of a heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system except in buildings designed for human occupancy. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, to be effective July 1, 2008, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F., 16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be July 1, 2010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>