<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.120</section_number><catch_line>Refund of portion of fee when motor vehicle destroyed. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any motor vehicle other than a commercial vehicle upon which the license tax has been paid is destroyed by fire or accident, so that the vehicle is rendered entirely useless the owner shall be entitled to have refunded to him a part of the license fee paid by him proportionate to the registration period for which the license was granted. </section><section prefix="2">If any commercial vehicle upon which the license tax has been paid is destroyed by fire or accident so that the vehicle is rendered entirely useless the owner is entitled to have refunded to him that portion of the tax which he had theretofore paid allocable to the remaining complete quarters of the unexpired period for which the tax was paid. </section><section prefix="3">To obtain the refund, the owner whose motor vehicle has been destroyed shall apply to the Transportation Cabinet, submitting his affidavit and the affidavits of two (2) reputable persons, attesting to the fact that the vehicle has been destroyed, and the manner of destruction, and shall return the original license plates to the Transportation Cabinet. The Transportation Cabinet shall examine all applications and investigate the claims for refund, and if a claim is found to be correct, it shall approve it for payment, whereupon the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall draw a warrant upon the State Treasurer in favor of the owner of the destroyed vehicle, and charge the amount of it to the state road fund. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 7, effective June 19, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(9). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 9, effective January 1, 1967. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1963. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-2e, 2739g-2f. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1976</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>