<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.110</section_number><catch_line>Entry of forms, affidavits, and orders of protection into LawInformation Network of Kentucky.  </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>(1)All forms, affidavits, and orders of protection issued or filed pursuant to thischapter which require entry into the Law Information Network of Kentucky shallbe entered on forms prescribed by the Administrative Office of the Courts afterconsultation with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. If the provisions of aninterpersonal protective order are contained in an order which is narrative innature, the prescribed form shall be used in addition to the narrative order.(2)The circuit clerk, in cooperation with the court, shall cause a copy of eachsummons or order issued pursuant to this chapter, or foreign protective order,fully completed and authenticated pursuant to this chapter, to be forwarded, bythe most expedient means reasonably available and within twenty-four (24)hours following its filing with the clerk, to the appropriate agency designated forentry of interpersonal protective order records into the Law Information Networkof Kentucky and to the agency assigned service. Any order or court recordsuperseding, modifying, or otherwise affecting the status of an earliersummons or order shall likewise be forwarded by the circuit clerk to theappropriate Law Information Network of Kentucky entering agency and to theagency assigned service, if service is required. The clerk and the court shallcomply with all provisions and guidelines of the Law Information Network ofKentucky for entry of the records.(3)Each agency designated for entry of summonses and orders issued pursuantto this chapter, or foreign protective orders authenticated pursuant to thischapter, into the Law Information Network of Kentucky shall, consistent withthe provisions and guidelines of the Law Information Network of Kentucky,enter the records immediately upon receipt of copies forwarded to the agencyin accordance with subsection (2) of this section.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 29, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44777</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>