<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.040</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of certificate of registration -- Plates -- Clerk's fee -- Donations to child care assistance account -- Additional fees and distribution. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon receiving the application and fee, the county clerk shall issue to the owner a certificate of registration containing the information required by subsection (2) of this section and a registration plate. If the cabinet finds that there is a shortage of materials suitable for making plates, or that a substantial saving will result, it may require by regulation with the approval of the Governor that previously issued plates continue to be used for a designated period. Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, for services performed, the owner shall pay the county clerk the sum of six dollars ($6) for each registration, or if the registration exceeds a twelve (12) month period, the clerk shall receive a fee of nine dollars ($9). </section><section prefix="2">The certificate of registration shall contain the registration number, the name and post office address of the owner, and such other information as the cabinet may require. </section><section prefix="3">An owner who registers a vehicle under KRS 186.050 that has a declared gross vehicle weight with any towed unit of forty-four thousand and one (44,001) pounds or greater shall pay the county clerk thirty dollars ($30) for each registration. The clerk shall retain the thirty dollar ($30) fee for services performed under this subsection. </section><section prefix="4">Any person requesting a certificate of registration or renewal of registration of any type of motor vehicle shall have the opportunity to donate one dollar ($1) to the child care assistance account. The one dollar ($1) donation shall be added to the regular fee for vehicle registration. One donation may be made per issuance or renewal of vehicle registration. Donation to the child care assistance account shall be voluntary and may be refused by the applicant at the time of the issuance or renewal of any vehicle registration. </section><section prefix="5">The county clerk may retain five percent (5%) of fees collected for the child care assistance account under subsection (4) of this section. The remaining funds shall be deposited into a trust and agency account in the State Treasury to the credit of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for the exclusive use as follows: <section prefix="a">Funds shall be made available to the agencies that administer child care subsidy funds; and </section><section prefix="b">Funds shall be used as determined by the cabinet for working families whose income exceeds the state income eligibility limits for child day care assistance. </section></section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in addition to the registration fee provided for county clerks in subsections (1) and (3) of this section, an additional three dollars ($3) per registration shall be collected by the county clerk at the time of registration. This additional fee shall be distributed as follows: <section prefix="a">One dollar ($1) shall be placed in an agency fund to provide additional funds exclusively for technological improvements or replacement of the AVIS system. The operation and maintenance of AVIS shall remain as currently provided for from the operational budget of the Transportation Cabinet and shall not be reduced below the 2005-2006 funding level; </section><section prefix="b">One dollar ($1) shall be placed in an agency trust fund to provide funds exclusively for technological improvements to the hardware and software in county clerk offices related to the collection and administration of road fund taxes. The Transportation Cabinet, in consultation with county clerks, shall allocate funds as necessary from this fund to be used for this exclusive purpose; and </section><section prefix="c">One dollar ($1) shall be placed in a trust fund to be maintained by the Transportation Cabinet to provide an unrestricted revenue supplement, for operations of the office related to the collection and administration of road fund taxes, to county clerk offices in counties containing a population of less than twenty thousand (20,000), as determined by the decennial census, and for no other purpose. Annually, by March 1, the Transportation Cabinet shall calculate the amount collected in the previous calendar year and distribute the entire fund proportionate to each county that qualifies under this paragraph based on population. This revenue shall be considered current year revenue when paid to the clerk and shall not be identified as excess fees from the previous year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 144, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 41, effective July 1, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 544, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 102, effective July 1, 1987. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 40, Part IV, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1967. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1960. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 78, secs. 4 and 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-10. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5923</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>