<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.730</section_number><catch_line>Challenge of contents of record -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Parents or eligible students may challenge the content of a student record to ensure that the record or report is not inaccurate, misleading, or otherwise in violation of privacy or other rights of the student. The right to challenge shall also provide the opportunity for rebuttal to, and the correction, deletion, or expunction of, any inaccurate, misleading, or inappropriate information. </section><section prefix="2">A challenge to the record may take the form of an informal discussion among the parents, student, and school officials. Any agreement between these parties shall be reduced in writing, signed by all parties, and placed in the student's records. If no agreement can be reached, either party may request a formal hearing to the challenge which shall be conducted in accordance with procedures established by rules and regulations of the Department of Education and the Council on Postsecondary Education for educational institutions under their jurisdiction. The rules and regulations shall provide that a formal hearing be conducted within a reasonable time after the request for a hearing; and an official of the educational institution who has no direct interest in the outcome of the challenge shall conduct the hearing and render a decision on the challenge within a reasonable time after the hearing. All parties to the challenge shall be afforded a full and fair opportunity to present evidence relevant to the issues raised. Furthermore, school officials shall take the necessary action to implement the decision. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 64, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3820</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>