<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="252" order_by="252">APIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>252.190</section_number><catch_line>Rules and regulations for control of bee diseases -- Destruction of infected bees, hives, etc. -- Reporting and publication of information -- Registration fees -- Failure to comply a violation of statutes. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commissioner may make and enforce such rules and orders as in his judgment may be necessary to control, eradicate or prevent the introduction, spread or dissemination of any and all bee diseases. In the control or eradication of dangerous bee diseases the Commissioner may destroy by burning or otherwise any infected bees, hives, honey or appliances that he may deem necessary for such control or eradication, without remuneration to the owner. Such infected bees, hives, honey and appliances shall be deemed a public nuisance. </section><section prefix="2">The Commissioner may publish information concerning the inspection of bees or bee diseases as he deems necessary to the carrying out of KRS 252.180 to 252.240. </section><section prefix="3">The Commissioner may order persons owning or possessing bees to report information the Commissioner deems necessary for the discharge of his duties under the provisions of KRS 252.180 to 252.240. </section><section prefix="4">The Commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations concerning how moneys are received and dispensed in the Kentucky beekeeping fund established in KRS 252.185. </section><section prefix="5">The Commissioner may establish a schedule of registration fees to be used for carrying out the provisions of KRS 252.180 to 252.240. </section><section prefix="6">Any person failing to comply with the rules and orders of the Commissioner shall be guilty of a violation of KRS 252.180 to 252.240. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>