<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.6-110</section_number><catch_line>Action by beneficial owner.   </catch_line><order_by>6-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A beneficial owner may maintain a direct action against a statutory trust or a trustee to redress an injury sustained by, or to enforce a duty owed to, the beneficial owner if the beneficial owner can prevail without showing an injury or breach of duty to the trust. </section><section prefix="2">A beneficial owner may maintain a derivative action to redress an injury sustained by or enforce a duty owed to a statutory trust if: <section prefix="a">The beneficial owner first makes a demand on the trustees, requesting that the trustees cause the trust to bring an action to redress the injury or enforce the right, and the trustees do not bring the action within a reasonable time; or </section><section prefix="b">A demand would be futile. </section></section><section prefix="3">A derivative action on behalf of a statutory trust may be maintained only by a person that is a beneficial owner at the time the action is commenced and who: <section prefix="a">Was a beneficial owner when the conduct giving rise to the action occurred; or </section><section prefix="b">Acquired the status as a beneficial owner by operation of law or pursuant to the terms of the governing instrument from a person that was a beneficial owner at the time of the conduct giving rise to the action occurred. </section></section><section prefix="4">In a derivative action on behalf of the statutory trust, the complaint must state with particularity: <section prefix="a">The date and content of the plaintiff’s demand and the trustees’ response to the demand; or </section><section prefix="b">The reason the demand should be excused as futile. </section></section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (6) of this section: <section prefix="a">Any proceeds or other benefits of a derivative action on behalf of a statutory trust, whether by judgment, compromise or settlement, are the property of the trust and not of the plaintiff; and </section><section prefix="b">If the plaintiff receives any proceeds or other benefits, the plaintiff shall immediately remit them to the trust. </section></section><section prefix="6">A derivative action on behalf of a statutory trust may not be voluntarily dismissed or settled without the court’s approval. </section><section prefix="7">The proper venue for a direct action under subsection (1) of this section or a derivative action in which the action is brought solely against one (1) or more trustees shall be an appropriate court. </section><section prefix="8">A beneficial owner associated with a series, if the series may pursuant to KRS 386A.4-010(4) be sued in its own name, may bring an action pursuant to subsection (1) or (2) of this section against only that series, the trustees associated with the series, or both. If brought only against a series or the trustees associated with the series, any demand made pursuant to subsection (2)(a) of this section shall be upon the trustees associated with the series. </section><section prefix="9">On termination of the proceeding brought pursuant to this section, the court may: <section prefix="a">Require the plaintiff to pay any defendant’s reasonable expenses, including counsel fees, incurred in defending the proceeding to the extent it finds that the proceeding or any portion thereof was commenced without reasonable cause or for an improper purpose; and </section><section prefix="b">Require the statutory trust, or as appropriate a series thereof, to pay the plaintiff’s reasonable expenses, including counsel fees, incurred in the proceeding if it finds that the proceeding has resulted in a substantial benefit to the statutory trust or to a series thereof. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 55, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40397</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>