<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152">ENERGY DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>152.713</section_number><catch_line>Center for Renewable Energy Research and Environmental Stewardship -- Duties -- Membership and duties of board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>713</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, "renewable energy" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.20-400. </section><section prefix="2">The Center for Renewable Energy Research and Environmental Stewardship is hereby created and attached to the Energy and Environment Cabinet for administrative purposes. The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall provide consultation, coordination services, technical assistance, and staff support to the board of directors created in subsection (4) of this section, on an as-needed basis, and perform other necessary administrative functions until the center is deemed fully operational. The secretary of the cabinet or his or her designee shall coordinate the development of the center and act as the chair of the board of directors created in subsection (4) of this section until the board is established and is operational. </section><section prefix="3">The Center for Renewable Energy Research and Environmental Stewardship shall: <section prefix="a">Provide leadership, research, support, and policy development in renewable energy; </section><section prefix="b">Advance the goal of renewable energy; </section><section prefix="c">Promote technologies, practices, and programs that increase efficiency in energy utilization in homes, businesses, and public buildings; </section><section prefix="d">Emphasize energy policies that would result in cost-conscious, responsible development of Kentucky's energy resources and a commitment to environmental quality; </section><section prefix="e">Promote partnerships among the state's postsecondary education institutions, private industry, and nonprofit organizations to actively pursue federal research and development resources that are dedicated to renewable energy; </section><section prefix="f">Promote the continued development of public-private partnerships dedicated to promoting energy efficiency through education and outreach; </section><section prefix="g">Establish research priorities with approval of the board of directors created in subsection (4) of this section, relating to renewable energy, and develop procedures and processes for awarding research grants to eligible recipients as defined by the board and to the extent that funding is available; </section><section prefix="h">Collaborate with the Department for Energy Development and Independence to avoid duplication of efforts, provide appropriate data and information, and support the implementation of Kentucky's comprehensive energy strategy; and </section><section prefix="i">Carry out other activities to further the efficient and environmentally responsible use of renewable energy. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">There is hereby created a governing board of directors to provide policy direction, establish a strategic research agenda and operating policies, and provide financial and operational oversight for the Center for Renewable Energy Research and Environmental Stewardship. The initial board shall be appointed within sixty (60) days following July 15, 2008. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall consist of thirteen (13) members: <section prefix="1">One (1) member to represent the Department for Energy Development and Independence as designated by its commissioner; </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) members representing postsecondary education interests who shall be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member to be designated by the governing body of the Kentucky Science and Technology Corporation; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) member from an energy conservation organization who shall be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="5">The secretary of the Economic Development Cabinet or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="6">One (1) member who shall be a recognized consumer advocate to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="7">Three (3) members to represent companies that are focused on renewable energy who shall be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="8">One (1) member who shall represent environmental interests to be appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="9">One (1) member who shall be selected to represent local government interests to be appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="c">The members appointed by the Governor shall serve two (2) year terms and may be reappointed. The members representing specific agencies shall serve for as long as the respective agencies determine appropriate. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Adopt operating procedures, including a meeting schedule; </section><section prefix="b">Meet at least quarterly; </section><section prefix="c">Select a chair and co-chair annually who may be reelected, not to exceed three (3) consecutive terms; </section><section prefix="d">Establish working groups or subcommittees of the board as the board determines is needed; </section><section prefix="e">Establish qualifications and job descriptions, set the compensation and benefits, and employ staff as it determines necessary to carry out its responsibilities under this section; and </section><section prefix="f">Provide an annual program and financial report to the Legislative Research Commission within ninety (90) days of the close of each fiscal year. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted ch. 5, sec. 19, effective February 25, 2010; and amended ch. 24, sec. 185, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24 and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5. Notwithstanding KRS 446.260, these Acts do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2345</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>