<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.514</section_number><catch_line>Exempted service not to be subsidized by nonexempted, regulated telecommunications services. </catch_line><order_by>514</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Revenues derived from nonexempted, regulated telecommunications services, whether essential or nonessential, shall not be used to subsidize or otherwise give advantage to any person providing an exempted service. The commission shall require a provider of any exempted service to keep separate accounts, to allocate cost in accordance with procedures established by the commission, and may require other acts that will assist the commission in enforcing this section. Any person requesting an exemption or providing a service exempted pursuant to KRS 278.512 shall have the burden of proof to show compliance with this requirement. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in subsection (2)(b) of this section, any telecommunications utility that willfully violates subsection (1) of this section shall be subject to a penalty no greater than the revenue requirement effect of moneys determined to have been misallocated in the violation. For the purpose of calculating the penalty under this section, the commission shall not use a period longer than five (5) years. </section><section prefix="b">A local exchange carrier with fewer than thirty-five thousand (35,000) access lines who willfully violates subsection (1) of this section shall be subject to the penalties prescribed in KRS 278.990(1). </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14143</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>