<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.887</section_number><catch_line>Powers. </catch_line><order_by>887</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each TVA or commission officer appointed and commissioned pursuant to KRS 61.886 to 61.892 throughout every county in the Commonwealth in which TVA or the commission operates or owns or controls property, including leasehold interests: <section prefix="a">Shall have and exercise the powers of sheriffs in making arrests for public offenses committed upon, about, or against such property or on public roads and the rights-of-way passing through or over such property; </section><section prefix="b">Shall have and exercise the powers of sheriffs in making arrests in any situation in which a person is placed in imminent danger of death or serious injury; </section><section prefix="c">Shall have authority to carry weapons for the reasonable purposes of his or her office and in performance of his or her assigned duties; </section><section prefix="d">While in pursuit of a person fleeing after committing an act described in paragraph (a) or (b) of this subsection, may pursue the person and make arrest anywhere in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="e">Shall be subject to all the liabilities of sheriffs. </section></section><section prefix="2">TVA officers appointed and commissioned pursuant to KRS 61.886 to 61.892 may, throughout any county in the Commonwealth in which TVA operates or owns or controls property, including leasehold interests, have and exercise the powers of sheriff in that county if the sheriff of that county provides prior written authorization to the TVA defining the extent of supplemental authority being granted. Any supplemental authority granted pursuant to this subsection shall expire with the officer's commission granted under KRS 61.886 and may be renewed, as provided in this subsection, upon renewal of the commission authorized under KRS 61.886. </section><section prefix="3">When countywide authority has not been granted under subsection (2) of this section, a sheriff of a county in which the TVA has property, the chief of police of a city within the county, or the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police may extend peace officer authority within the city or county, as appropriate, during a disaster or other emergency. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>