<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="269" order_by="269">MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS AS TO DITCHES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION </unit></structure><section_number>269.130</section_number><catch_line>Oath of commissioners -- Filling of vacancy -- Quorum -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before entering upon the duties of his office, each member of the board of commissioners shall take the following oath before the clerk of the Circuit Court: "I, .... do solemnly swear that I will faithfully perform the duties of commissioner to assess, apportion and rate taxes under KRS 269.120 to 269.230; that I will impartially perform the duties of my office; that I am in no way interested in the company, nor holder or owner of any land within its boundary; and that I am a landowner and resident of .... County, Kentucky, and over twenty-five years of age." Any vacancy on the board of commissioners shall be filled by the county judge/executive, but the failure of the county judge/executive to appoint a person to fill the vacancy shall not invalidate the proceedings of the board of commissioners or prevent it from acting. Two (2) members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="2">A member of the board of commissioners may be removed pursuant to KRS 65.007. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 424, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2417a-7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>