<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.360</section_number><catch_line>Discharge of liens by deed or mortgage -- Assignment of mortgage -- Effect. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Liens by deed or mortgage may be discharged by an entry acknowledging their satisfaction on the margin of the record thereof, or in the alternative, at the option of the county clerk, in a marginal entry record, signed by the person entitled thereto, or his or her personal representative or agent, and attested by the clerk, or may be discharged by a separate deed of release, which shall recite the date of the instrument and deed book and the page wherein it is recorded. Such release in the case of a mortgage or deed of trust shall have the effect to reinstate the title in the mortgagor or grantor or person entitled thereto. Each entry in the marginal entry record shall be linked to its respective referenced instrument in the indexing system for the referenced instruments. </section><section prefix="2">If a lien or mortgage is released by a deed of release, the clerk shall immediately, at the option of the clerk, either link the release and its filing location to its respective referenced instrument in the indexing system for the referenced instrument, or endorse on the margin of the record wherein the lien is retained "Released by deed of release (stating whether in whole or in part) lodged for record (giving date, deed book and page wherein such deed of release may be found)" and the clerk shall also attest such certificate. The clerk shall cause the original deed of release to be delivered to the mortgagor or grantor or person entitled thereto. </section><section prefix="3">When a mortgage is assigned to another person, the assignee shall file the assignment for recording with the county clerk within thirty (30) days of the assignment and the county clerk shall attest the assignment and shall note the assignment in the blank space, or in a marginal entry record, beside a listing of the book and page of the document being assigned. Provided, however, that an assignee that reassigns the note prior to the thirtieth day after first acquiring the assignment may request that the subsequent assignee file the unfiled assignment with the new reassignment. </section><section prefix="4">Delivering an assignment to the assignee or a lien release to the mortgagor shall not substitute for filing the assignment or release with the county clerk, as required by this section. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section, nothing in this chapter shall require the legal holder of any note secured by lien in any deed or mortgage to file a release of any mortgage when the mortgage securing such paid note also secures a note or other obligation which remains unpaid. </section><section prefix="6">Failure of an assignee to record a mortgage assignment shall not affect the validity or perfection, or invalidity or lack of perfection, of a mortgage lien under applicable law. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 17, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 323, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 498. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>