<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.050</section_number><catch_line>Collection of fees and payment after leaving office. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the term of any county clerk in counties of seventy-five thousand (75,000) population or over expires, or he dies or resigns, or is removed from office, he or his personal representative, trustee, or committee, as the case may be, shall at once deliver to his successor in office all accounts, claims, and fees due him in his official capacity. The successor shall have the fees, claims, and accounts collected, or the Department for Local Government may, in its discretion, when said accounts, fees, and claims are so delivered to the successor, appoint a person to collect them. If a collector is appointed, the successor shall at once, or when demanded by the collector, deliver to him all accounts, fees, and claims uncollected. The successor or collector, as the case may be, shall, every sixty (60) days after receiving the accounts, fees, and claims, report to the Department for Local Government, under oath, the amount collected thereon, and at the same time pay to the Department for Local Government the amount so collected, and shall continue to so report for three (3) years, unless the accounts, fees, and claims are sooner collected. </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Local Government shall, upon each payment, draw a warrant on the State Treasurer in favor of the person collecting, for an amount equal to twenty percent (20%) of the amount so paid in, which shall be the full compensation allowed for the collection. </section><section prefix="3">If the amount paid to any clerk during his term or incumbency was not sufficient to pay the salaries and office expenses of the clerk, the Department for Local Government shall, out of the money collected and paid in as provided in subsection (1) of this section, pay to the clerk, or to the person entitled to receive the same, an amount sufficient to supply the deficit due for salaries and expenses, not exceeding seventy-five percent (75%) of the amount of fees accrued during his official term and which have been collected and paid to the Department for Local Government. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 41, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 35, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 27. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1767 to 1769. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23184</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>