<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.510</section_number><catch_line>Statement of causes of revocation to be furnished licensee. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall print and furnish to each licensee under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 a statement of the causes for which licenses may be revoked. That statement shall be prepared by the state director and delivered to the licensee with his license, or as soon after that as may be practical. The director shall take from each licensee a signed receipt stating that he has received and read the statement. </section><section prefix="2">Any changes in or additions to the causes for which licenses may be revoked shall also be sent by the director to each licensee at his address as it appears in his application or the last amendment to his application, as soon as may be practical after such changes in or additions to the causes for which licenses may be revoked become effective. </section><section prefix="3">Failure of the department to furnish the statement or to send notice of changes, or the failure of the licensee to receive or read the statement, or any error contained in the statement or notice of changes shall not be an excuse or justification for any violation of law, or prevent, remit or decrease any penalty for a violation. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 580, effective July 15, 2010. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-137. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>