<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.162</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Labor-Management Advisory Council. </catch_line><order_by>162</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Commonwealth of Kentucky Labor-Management Advisory Council which shall consist of eighteen (18) members. One (1) member of the council shall be the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, and one (1) member shall be the secretary of economic development, who shall be ex officio nonvoting members of the council. The other members of the council shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of four (4) years and until their successors have been appointed and have qualified. </section><section prefix="2">Vacancies shall be filled by appointment by the Governor for the unexpired term of the member whose office is vacant and the appointment shall be made within sixty (60) days of the occurrence of the vacancy. </section><section prefix="3">In making appointments to the council, the Governor shall appoint eight (8) members representing management and eight (8) members representing labor. The secretary of the Labor Cabinet shall serve as chairman of the council. </section><section prefix="4">Upon the expiration of the terms of members appointed in 1978 the next appointments shall be made as follows: Two (2) labor and two (2) management members shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year; two (2) labor and two (2) management members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years; two (2) labor and two (2) management members shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years; and two (2) labor and two (2) management members shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. Thereafter all appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years. Such appointments shall be made by the Governor within thirty (30) days after the expiration of the term of any member. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall meet at least two (2) times each year and at other times on call of the chairman or a majority of the members. Nine (9) members of the council shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall be attached to the Labor Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1717, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 53, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32010</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>