<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.784</section_number><catch_line>Nomination of locations and objects for military heritage designation -- Rescission. </catch_line><order_by>784</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person or organization may nominate a geographic location for designation as a military heritage site or to rescind a designation as a military heritage site. </section><section prefix="2">Any person or organization may nominate an object for designation as a military heritage object or to rescind a designation as a military heritage object. </section><section prefix="3">Private property shall not be designated as a military heritage site or as a military heritage object unless: <section prefix="a">The nomination is made by the owner of the property if held by a single owner or by all owners of the property if the property is held jointly; or </section><section prefix="b">The nomination is approved, in writing, by the owner of the property if held by a single owner or by all owners of the property if the property is held jointly. </section></section><section prefix="4">The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations with regard to the process of designation of a military heritage site and a military heritage object and the characteristics of a qualifying site and qualifying object. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall meet not less than two (2) times per year to act upon nominations of geographic locations proposed as military heritage sites and nominations of objects as military heritage objects. The commission at any meeting may also act on requests to rescind any designation of a military heritage site or military heritage object. </section><section prefix="6">To designate a site as a military heritage site or to designate an object as a military heritage object requires a majority vote of the members of the commission. </section><section prefix="7">To rescind the designation of a site as a military heritage site or to rescind the designation of an object as a military heritage object requires a unanimous vote of the members of the commission. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4860</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>