<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.8943Quality-based</section_number><catch_line>graduated early care and education program rating system -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>8943Quality-based</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Federally funded time-limited employee" has the same meaning as in KRS 18A.005; </section><section prefix="b">"Primary school program" has the same meaning as in KRS 158.031(1); and </section><section prefix="c">"Public-funded" means a program which receives local, state, or federal funding. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Early Childhood Advisory Council shall, in consultation with early care and education providers, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and others, including but not limited to child-care resource and referral agencies and family resource centers, Head Start agencies, and the Kentucky Department of Education, develop a quality-based graduated early care and education program rating system for public-funded licensed child-care and certified family child-care homes, public-funded preschool, and Head Start, based on but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Classroom and instructional quality; </section><section prefix="b">Administrative and leadership practices; </section><section prefix="c">Staff qualifications and professional development; and </section><section prefix="d">Family and community engagement. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall, in consultation with the Early Childhood Advisory Council, promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement: <section prefix="a">The quality-based graduated early childhood rating system for public-funded child-care and certified family child-care homes, public-funded preschool, and Head Start developed under subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Agency time frames of reviews for rating; </section><section prefix="c">An appellate process under KRS Chapter 13B; and </section><section prefix="d">The ability of providers to request reevaluation for rating. </section></section><section prefix="4">The quality-based early childhood rating system shall not be used for enforcement of compliance or in any punitive manner. </section><section prefix="5">The Early Childhood Advisory Council, in consultation with the Kentucky Center for Education and Workforce Statistics, shall report by October 1 of each year to the Interim Joint Committee on Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare on the implementation of the quality-based graduated early childhood rating system. The report shall include the following quantitative performance measures as data becomes available: <section prefix="a">Program participation in the rating system; </section><section prefix="b">Ratings of programs by program type; </section><section prefix="c">Changes in student school-readiness measures; </section><section prefix="d">Longitudinal student cohort performance data tracked through student completion of the primary school program; and </section><section prefix="e">Long-term viability recommendations for sustainability at the end of the Race to the Top-Early Learning Challenge grant. </section></section><section prefix="6">By November 1, 2017, the Early Childhood Advisory Council and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare on recommendations and plans for sustaining program quality after the depletion of federal Race to the Top-Early Learning Challenge grant funds. </section><section prefix="7">Any federally funded time-limited employee personnel positions created as a result of the federal Race to the Top-Early Learning Challenge grant shall be eliminated upon depletion of the grant funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 195, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 15, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44069</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>