<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.151</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority -- Membership -- Officers -- Compensation -- Expenses -- Quorum. </catch_line><order_by>151</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority is hereby created and established as an agency of state government charged with the responsibility for regulatory oversight and the establishment of sound policies and procedures governing the conduct of boxing, wrestling, and other full contact competitive bouts within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The authority shall be attached to the Public Protection Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall consist of five (5) members appointed by the Governor. <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet, or the secretary's designee, who shall serve as an ex officio voting member; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a medical doctor; and </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall be appointed from the state at large, one (1) of whom shall have no financial interest in the business or industry regulated. </section></section> One (1) member shall be appointed to serve as the authority's chairperson. The Governor shall further designate a second member to serve as vice chair with authority to act in the absence of the chair. A majority of the members of the authority shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. <section prefix="3">The appointed members of the authority shall serve for a term of three (3) years at the pleasure of the Governor, with initial terms staggered. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring other than by expiration of a term shall be appointed for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the authority shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each meeting attended and shall be reimbursed for all expenses paid or incurred in the discharge of official business. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 441, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 22, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>