<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.106</section_number><catch_line>Education and training program -- Alcohol and substance abuse training and education -- Retraining and reeducation requirements -- Administrative regulations -- Implementation of program for training and examination -- Records.   </catch_line><order_by>106</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Mining Board shall establish criteria and standards for a program of education and training to be required of prospective miners, miners, and all certified persons. This education and training shall be provided in a manner determined by the commissioner to be adequate to meet the standards established by the board, which shall include as a minimum the requirements of KRS 351.102 and the requirements of the federal government for the training of miners for new work assignments, and at least sixteen (16) hours of annual retraining and reeducation for all certified persons, of which thirty (30) minutes annually shall be dedicated to alcohol and substance abuse education. Effective January 1, 2009, in addition, six (6) hours of annual training on changes in mine safety laws, safe retreat mining practices, disciplinary cases litigated before the Mine Safety Review Commission, changes in mine safety technology, and ways to improve safe working procedures shall be required for all mine foremen. This annual training for mine foremen shall be provided exclusively by the division. </section><section prefix="2">One (1) hour of initial substance abuse training and education shall be required as part of the certified miner's first annual retraining conducted in a classroom that occurs after August 1, 2006. This requirement shall not apply to certified persons who received the one (1) hour initial substance abuse training and education as part of their forty (40) hour or twenty-four (24) hour new miner training. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the thirty (30) minutes of annual alcohol and substance abuse education required for certified miners, supervisory personnel shall be required to receive an additional thirty (30) minutes of alcohol and substance abuse awareness training annually. </section><section prefix="4">Beginning with the first full calendar year after the effective date established by the board and during each calendar year thereafter, each certified miner shall receive at least sixteen (16) hours of retraining and reeducation. </section><section prefix="5">Newly hired experienced miner training shall satisfy the miner's annual retraining requirement if a time lapse occurs between the miner's last training anniversary date and the next scheduled training anniversary date for the mine where he is newly employed, if the miner has complied with the annual retraining requirements within the last twelve (12) months from the date of his newly hired experienced miner training. </section><section prefix="6">Retraining and reeducation sessions shall be conducted at times and in numbers to reasonably assure each certified miner an opportunity to attend. </section><section prefix="7">The licensee shall pay all certified miners their regular wages and benefits while they receive training required by the department. </section><section prefix="8">Willful failure of a working miner to complete annual retraining and reeducation requirements shall constitute grounds for revocation, suspension, or probation of his certificate. </section><section prefix="9">If the department discovers a miner working without proper training or the licensee cannot provide proof of training, the miner shall be withdrawn immediately from the mine and the licensee shall pay the miner his regular wages until the training is administered and properly documented. </section><section prefix="10">When employment is terminated, the licensee shall provide the employee a copy of his training records, upon request. If the employee does not request his training records immediately, the licensee shall, within fifteen (15) days, provide the employee with those training records. </section><section prefix="11">The board may, upon its own motion or whenever requested to do so by the commissioner, deem applicable certificates issued by other states to be proof of training and education equal to the requirements of KRS 351.102 or deem training provided by appropriate federal agencies to be adequate to meet training and education requirements established by the board, if the training and education meet the minimum requirements of this chapter. </section><section prefix="12">The secretary may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to establish a program to implement the provisions of this chapter according to the criteria and standards established by the board. This program shall include but not be limited to implementation of a program of instruction and the conduct of examinations to test each applicant's knowledge and understanding of the training and instruction. </section><section prefix="13">The commissioner shall keep and maintain current records on all certified miners, all of which shall be maintained by computer for ready access. The commissioner shall not grant certification to any person that, at the time of application, had his or her miner certification, foreman certification, electrician certification, or any other mining specialty certification suspended or revoked by another state. If a person has his or her miner certification, foreman certification, electrician certification, or other mining specialty certification probated in another state, the commissioner or the Mining Board may, at his or its discretion, grant the equivalent certification. However, that certification shall be placed on probation in Kentucky until the probationary period in the other state has expired. </section><section prefix="14">The commissioner is authorized and directed to utilize state mine safety specialists, private and public institutions of education, and other qualified persons available to him in implementing the program of instruction and examination. </section><section prefix="15">The commissioner may make recommendations to the board as he may deem appropriate. The commissioner shall provide information to the board at the board's request. The commissioner is authorized and directed to utilize state and federal moneys and personnel that may be available to the department for educational and training purposes in the implementation of the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="16">All training and education required by this section may be conducted in classrooms, on the job, or in simulated mines. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 16, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 9, effective March 20, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 8, effective April 9, 1996. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>