<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.605</section_number><catch_line>Conciliation -- Agreement -- Final investigative report. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text><section prefix="1">During the period beginning with the filing of a discriminatory housing practice complaint and ending with the filing of a charge or a dismissal by the commission, the commission shall, to the extent feasible, engage in conciliation with respect to a complaint. </section><section prefix="2">A conciliation agreement arising out of the conciliation shall be an agreement between the respondent and the complainant, and shall be subject to approval by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">A conciliation agreement may provide for binding arbitration of the dispute arising from the complaint. Any arbitration that results from a conciliation agreement may award appropriate relief, including monetary relief. </section><section prefix="4">Each conciliation agreement shall be made public unless the complainant and respondent otherwise agree and the commission determines that disclosure is not required to further the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">At the end of each investigation under this section, the commission shall prepare a final investigative report containing: <section prefix="1">The names and dates of contacts with witnesses; </section><section prefix="2">A summary and the dates of correspondence and other contacts with the complainant and the respondent; </section><section prefix="3">A summary description of other pertinent records; </section><section prefix="4">A summary of witness statements; and </section><section prefix="5">Answers to interrogatories. </section></section><section prefix="b">A final report under this paragraph may be amended if additional evidence is later discovered. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32661</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>