<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.38A-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>38A-010</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Enrollee" means an individual who is enrolled in a limited health services benefit plan; </section><section prefix="2">"Evidence of coverage" means any certificate, agreement, contract, or other document issued to an enrollee stating the limited health services to which the enrollee is entitled. All coverages described in an evidence of coverage issued by a limited health service organization are deemed to be "limited health services benefit plans" to the extent defined in KRS 304.17C-010 unless exempted by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="3">"Limited health service" means dental care services, vision care services, mental health services, substance abuse services, chiropractic services, pharmaceutical services, podiatric care services, and such other services as may be determined by the commissioner to be limited health services. Limited health service shall not include hospital, medical, surgical, or emergency services except as these services are provided incidental to the limited health services set forth in this subsection; </section><section prefix="4">"Limited health service contract" means any contract entered into by a limited health service organization with a policyholder to provide limited health services; </section><section prefix="5">"Limited health service organization" means a corporation, partnership, limited liability company, or other entity that undertakes to provide or arrange limited health service or services to enrollees. A limited health service organization does not include a provider or an entity when providing or arranging for the provision of limited health services under a contract with a limited health service organization, health maintenance organization, or a health insurer; and </section><section prefix="6">"Provider" means the same as defined in KRS 304.17A-005(23). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1515, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30013</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>