<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">SPECIALISTS IN HEARING INSTRUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>334.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Licensing Board for Specialists in Hearing Instruments. </section><section prefix="2">"License" means a license issued by the board under this chapter to specialists in hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="3">"Apprentice permit" means a permit issued while the applicant is in training to become a licensed specialist in hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="4">"Hearing instrument" means any wearable instrument or device designed for or represented as aiding or improving defective human hearing and any parts, attachments, or accessories of such an instrument or device. </section><section prefix="5">"Practice of fitting hearing instruments" means the measurement of human hearing by means of an audiometer for the purpose of making selections, adaptions, and adjustments of hearing instruments. The term also includes the making of ear mold impressions and custom earmolds. </section><section prefix="6">"Sell or sale" means any transfer of title or transfer of the right to use by lease, bailment, or any other means. </section><section prefix="7">A used or not new hearing instrument is one (1) that has been the subject of a sale and the title to which was held by the client for a period longer than thirty (30) days. </section><section prefix="8">"Client" means the user or purchaser of the hearing instrument. </section><section prefix="9">"Specialist in hearing instruments" means any individual licensed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="10">"Apprentice" means any applicant in training to become a licensed specialist in hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="11">"Sponsor" means a licensed specialist in hearing instruments qualified under KRS 334.090(8) who assumes professional responsibility for an apprentice. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 272, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 58. --Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31867</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>