<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.5-730</section_number><catch_line>Filing fee for reports -- Examination fees. </catch_line><order_by>5-730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each report required of associations by this subtitle shall be made to the commissioner and the association making the report shall pay to the commissioner a filing fee of two dollars ($2). </section><section prefix="2">Each association shall pay the following fee to the commissioner immediately upon completion of its examination: <section prefix="a">Associations having assets of twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) or less shall pay twenty dollars ($20); </section><section prefix="b">Associations having assets of over twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) but less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) shall pay twenty-five dollars ($25); </section><section prefix="c">Associations having assets of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) but not over one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) shall pay thirty-five dollars ($35); </section><section prefix="d">Associations having assets of more than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) shall pay thirty-five dollars ($35) for the first one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) and five dollars for each additional one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) or fraction thereof. </section></section><section prefix="3">No association shall be required to pay for more than one (1) examination each year, unless such examination is necessary because of the association's failure to file reports required by this subtitle. </section></text><history>Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 1, effective June 13, 1968. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 62, effective June 18, 1964. </history><metadata><effective>June 13, 1968</effective><former-codification> KRS 289.730. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14737</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>