<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.340</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 99.330 to 99.510. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text>The following words or terms shall have the following meanings wherever used in KRS 99.330 to 99.510, unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context: <section prefix="1">"Slum area" means an area in which there is at least one-fourth (1/4) of all buildings or a predominance of improvements which by reason of dilapidation, deterioration, age or obsolescence, inadequate provision for ventilation, light, sanitation, or open spaces, high density of population and overcrowding, or any combination of such factors, are unsafe or unfit to occupy; are conducive to ill health, transmission of disease, infant mortality, juvenile delinquency, or crime; injuriously affect the entire area; or constitute a menace to the public health, safety and welfare. A slum area may include lands, structures, or improvements, the acquisition of which is necessary in order to assure the proper clearance and redevelopment of the entire area and to prevent the spread or recurrence of slum conditions thereby protecting the public health, safety, and welfare; </section><section prefix="2">"Blighted area" means an area (other than a slum area as defined in this section) where by reason of the predominance of defective or inadequate street layout, faulty lot layout in relation to size, adequacy, accessibility, or usefulness, submergency of lots by water or other unsanitary or unsafe conditions, deterioration of site improvements, diversity of ownership, tax delinquency, defective or unusual conditions of title, improper subdivision or obsolete platting, or any combination of such reasons, development of such blighted area (which may include some incidental buildings or improvements) into predominantly housing uses is being prevented; </section><section prefix="3">"Redevelopment" means the planning or replanning, design or redesign, acquisition, clearance, development, disposal, rehabilitation, historic preservation, or any combination of these, of a development area and the preparation of such area for such residential, commercial, industrial, public, recreational, or other structures, works, improvements, facilities, or spaces as may be appropriate or necessary. "Redevelopment" and derivatives thereof shall mean develop as well as redevelop; </section><section prefix="4">"Community" means any city or county; </section><section prefix="5">"Mayor" means the mayor of a city or the county judge/executive of a county, or the officer thereof having the duties customarily imposed upon the executive head of a city or county; </section><section prefix="6">"Council" means the legislative authority of a city or the fiscal court of a county; </section><section prefix="7">"Redevelopment project" means any or a combination of one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">Acquisition of a slum area or a blighted area (as defined in this section); </section><section prefix="b">Demolition, removal, rehabilitation, or historic preservation of structures and improvements; </section><section prefix="c">Installation, construction, or reconstruction of streets, utilities, and other site improvements essential to the preparation of sites for uses in accordance with the development plan; and </section><section prefix="d">Making the land available for development or redevelopment by private enterprise or public bodies for uses in accordance with the development plan; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Development area" means the area of a redevelopment project; </section><section prefix="9">"Development plan" means a plan for the redevelopment of all or any part of a development area; </section><section prefix="10">"Agency" means a public corporate body created pursuant to KRS 99.350; </section><section prefix="11">"Public body" means any city, county, commission, district authority, or other public body or political subdivision of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="12">"Area of operation" means: <section prefix="a">In the case of a city, the area within the city and the area within five (5) miles of the territorial boundaries thereof, except that the area of operation of a city under KRS 99.330 to 99.510 shall not include any area which lies within the territorial boundaries of another city unless a resolution has been adopted by the council of the other city declaring a need therefor; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a county, the area within the county, except that the area of operation of a county shall not include any area which lies within the territorial boundaries of a city unless a resolution has been adopted by the council of the city declaring a need therefor; </section></section><section prefix="13">"Real property" includes all lands, including improvements and fixtures thereon, and property of any nature appurtenant thereto, or used in connection therewith, and every estate, interest, and right, legal or equitable, therein, including terms for years and liens by way of judgment, mortgage, or otherwise and the indebtedness secured by such liens; </section><section prefix="14">"Planning commission" means a city, county, or joint city-county planning and zoning commission or a planning commission established pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 100 having authority and responsibility with respect to the area of the community; and </section><section prefix="15">"Bonds" means any bonds, notes, interim certificates, debentures, or other obligations. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 84. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26534</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>