<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.450</section_number><catch_line>Approval required for remodeling or reconstruction of existing facilities -- When approval not required.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any political subdivision, combination of subdivisions, or regional jail authority desiring to remodel or reconstruct an existing local correctional facility wherein the construction will involve physical change of the structure shall obtain the approvals required by KRS 441.420 to 441.440 and shall reconstruct or modify the local correctional facility in accordance with the approval. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, existing local correctional facilities may be renovated without the approval of the construction authority. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">If the renovation includes an increase in the square footage of an existing local correctional facility to add prisoner bed space, that renovation shall be deemed an expansion and shall require the approval of the construction authority as provided in KRS 441.420 to 441.450. </section><section prefix="b">If the renovation includes an increase in the square footage of an existing local correctional facility, the authority shall not approve the application unless the resulting renovation of the local correctional facility results in a facility with a bed capacity of one hundred fifty (150) inmate beds or more. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.81, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40920</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>