<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.190</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>In the enforcement of this chapter, the Commission on Human Rights shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="1">To maintain an office in the city of Louisville and other offices within the state as may be deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="2">To meet and exercise its powers at any place within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Within the limitations provided by law, to appoint an executive director, attorneys, hearing examiners, clerks, and other employees and agents as it may deem necessary. At the direction of the commission, attorneys appointed under this section may appear for and represent the commission in any court. The commission may, by written order, delegate the authority given by this subsection to its executive director, except as that authority relates to the appointment of its executive director. </section><section prefix="4">To promote the creation of local commissions on human rights, to cooperate with state, local, and other agencies, both public and private, and individuals, and to obtain upon request and utilize the services of all governmental departments and agencies. </section><section prefix="5">To cooperate with the United States Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, created by Section 705 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (78 Stat. 241), in order to achieve the purposes of that act, and with other federal and local agencies in order to achieve the purposes of that act, and with other federal and local agencies in order to achieve the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="6">To accept gifts or bequests, grants, or other payments, public or private, to help finance its activities. </section><section prefix="7">To accept reimbursement pursuant to Section 709(b) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (78 Stat. 241) for services rendered to assist the Federal Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. </section><section prefix="8">To receive, initiate, investigate, seek to conciliate, hold hearings on, and pass upon complaints alleging violations of this chapter. </section><section prefix="9">At any time after a complaint is filed, to require answers to interrogatories, compel the attendance of witnesses, examine witnesses under oath or affirmation in person or by deposition, and require the production of documents relevant to the complaint. The commission may make rules authorizing any member or individual designated to exercise these powers in the performance of official duties. </section><section prefix="10">To furnish technical assistance requested by persons subject to this chapter to further their compliance with this chapter or an order issued thereunder. </section><section prefix="11">To make studies appropriate to effectuate the purposes and policies of this chapter and to make the results thereof available to the public. </section><section prefix="12">To render annual written reports to the Governor and the Legislature. The reports may contain recommendations of the commission for legislative or other action to effectuate the purposes and policies of this chapter. </section><section prefix="13">To create local or statewide advisory agencies that in its judgment will aid in effectuating the purpose of this chapter. The commission may empower these agencies (a) to study and report on problems of discrimination because of race, color, religion, or national origin, (b) to foster, through community effort or otherwise, goodwill among the groups and elements of the population of the state, and (c) to make recommendations to the commission for the development of policies and practices that will aid in carrying out the purposes of this chapter. Members of such committees shall serve without pay but shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred in such service. The commission may make provision for technical and clerical assistance to the committees. </section><section prefix="14">To adopt, promulgate, amend, and rescind regulations to effectuate the purposes and provisions of this chapter, including regulations requiring the posting of notices prepared or approved by the commission. </section><section prefix="15">To purchase liability insurance for the protection of all members of the commission to protect them from liability arising in the course of pursuing their duties as members of the commission and for all full-time employees to protect them from liability arising in the course or scope of their employment. This insurance shall be purchased with money contained in the agency appropriated budget. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 8. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 5, sec. 502. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>