<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-145</section_number><catch_line>Conditions under which cabinet may propose or submit a plan establishing carbon dioxide emission reduction performance standards for existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units -- Administrative regulations -- Conditions under which performance standards plan is a legal nullity. </catch_line><order_by>20-145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall not propose or submit to the United States Environmental Protection Agency any plan establishing performance standards for existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units unless the plan is: <section prefix="a">Consistent with KRS 224.20-140 to 224.20-146; and </section><section prefix="b">Prepared in consultation with the Kentucky Public Service Commission to ensure that the plan: <section prefix="1">Minimizes the impacts on current and future industrial, commercial, and residential consumers; and  </section><section prefix="2">Does not threaten the affordability of Kentucky's rates or the reliability of electricity service. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations for the establishment and implementation of any state plan to regulate emissions of carbon dioxide emissions from existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units under 42 U.S.C. sec. 7411(d). </section><section prefix="3">Any state plan established by the cabinet to regulate emissions of carbon dioxide pursuant to KRS 224.20-140 to 224.20-146 shall have no legal effect if: <section prefix="a">The United States Environmental Protection Agency: <section prefix="1">Fails to issue federal rules or guidelines for reducing carbon dioxide </section>emissions from existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units under 42 U.S.C. sec. 7411(d); or <section prefix="2">Withdraws its federal rules or guidelines for reducing carbon dioxide emissions from existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units; or </section></section><section prefix="b">A court of competent jurisdiction invalidates the United States Environmental Protection Agency's federal rules or guidelines issued to regulate emissions of carbon dioxide from existing fossil fuel-fired electric generating units. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43014</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>