<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.040</section_number><catch_line>Corporation income tax -- Exemption -- Rate. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every corporation doing business in this state, except those corporations listed in paragraphs (a) to (i) of this subsection, shall pay for each taxable year a tax to be computed by the taxpayer on taxable net income or the alternative minimum calculation computed under this section at the rates specified in this section: <section prefix="a">Financial institutions, as defined in KRS 136.500, except bankers banks organized under KRS 286.3-135; </section><section prefix="b">Savings and loan associations organized under the laws of this state and under the laws of the United States and making loans to members only; </section><section prefix="c">Banks for cooperatives; </section><section prefix="d">Production credit associations; </section><section prefix="e">Insurance companies, including farmers or other mutual hail, cyclone, windstorm, or fire insurance companies, insurers, and reciprocal underwriters; </section><section prefix="f">Corporations or other entities exempt under Section 501 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="g">Religious, educational, charitable, or like corporations not organized or conducted for pecuniary profit; </section><section prefix="h">Corporations whose only owned or leased property located in this state is located at the premises of a printer with which it has contracted for printing, provided that: <section prefix="1">The property consists of the final printed product, or copy from which the printed product is produced; and </section><section prefix="2">The corporation has no individuals receiving compensation in this state as provided in KRS 141.120(8)(b); and </section></section><section prefix="i">For all taxable years except those beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, S corporations. </section></section><section prefix="2">For tax years ending before January 1, 1990, the following rates shall apply: <section prefix="a">Three percent (3%) of the first twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) of taxable net income; </section><section prefix="b">Four percent (4%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000), but not in excess of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000); </section><section prefix="c">Five percent (5%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000), but not in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); </section><section prefix="d">Six percent (6%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), but not in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000); and </section><section prefix="e">Seven and twenty-five one hundredths percent (7.25%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000). </section></section><section prefix="3">For tax years beginning after December 31, 1989, and before January 1, 2005, the following rates shall apply: <section prefix="a">Four percent (4%) of the first twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) of taxable net income; </section><section prefix="b">Five percent (5%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) but not in excess of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000); </section><section prefix="c">Six percent (6%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000), but not in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); </section><section prefix="d">Seven percent (7%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), but not in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000); and </section><section prefix="e">Eight and twenty-five one hundredths percent (8.25%) of the amount of taxable net income in excess of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000). </section></section><section prefix="4">For tax years beginning before January 1, 1990, and ending after December 31, 1989, the tax shall be the sum of the amounts determined in paragraphs (a) and (b) as follows: <section prefix="a">Apply the tax rates in subsection (2) of this section to the taxable net income for the year and multiply the result by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days from the first day of the taxable year through December 31, 1989, and the denominator of which is the total number of days of the taxable year; and </section><section prefix="b">Apply the tax rates in subsection (3) of this section to the taxable net income for the year and multiply the result by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days from January 1, 1990, through the last day of the taxable year and the denominator of which is the total number of days of the taxable year. </section></section><section prefix="5">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, corporations subject to the tax imposed by this section shall pay the greater of the tax computed under paragraph (a) of this subsection, the tax computed under paragraph (b)1. or 2. of this subsection, or the minimum tax imposed by subsection (7) of this section. The tax computed under this subsection is as follows: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Four percent (4%) of the first fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) of taxable net income; </section><section prefix="2">Five percent (5%) of taxable net income over fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) up to one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); and </section><section prefix="3">Seven percent (7%) of taxable net income over one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); or </section></section><section prefix="b">An alternative minimum calculation of an amount equal to the lesser of the amount computed under subparagraph 1. or 2. of this paragraph: <section prefix="1">The gross receipts calculation contained in subsection (11) of this section; or </section><section prefix="2">The gross profits calculation contained in subsection (12) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007, the following rates shall apply: <section prefix="a">Four percent (4%) of the first fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) of taxable net income; </section><section prefix="b">Five percent (5%) of taxable net income over fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) up to one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); and </section><section prefix="c">Six percent (6%) of taxable net income over one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000). </section></section><section prefix="7">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2005, and before January 1, 2007, a minimum of one hundred seventy-five dollars ($175) shall be due for the taxable year from each corporation subject to the tax imposed by this section, regardless of the application of any tax credits provided under this chapter or any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes for which the business entity may qualify. </section><section prefix="8">The alternative minimum calculation portion of the tax computation provided in subsection (5) of this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Public service corporations subject to tax under KRS 136.120; </section><section prefix="b">Open-end registered investment companies organized under the laws of this state and registered under the Investment Company Act of 1940; </section><section prefix="c">Any property or facility which has been certified as a fluidized bed energy production facility as defined in KRS 211.390; </section><section prefix="d">An alcohol production facility as defined in KRS 247.910; and </section><section prefix="e">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2005, and before January 1, 2007, political organizations as defined in Internal Revenue Code Section 527 and related regulations. </section></section><section prefix="9">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007: <section prefix="a">As used in this subsection, "qualified exempt organization" means an entity listed in subsection (1)(a) to (h) of this section and shall not include any entity whose exempt status has been disallowed by the Internal Revenue Service. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section or KRS 141.010, any corporation of the type listed in KRS 141.010(24)(b)2. to 8. that is owned in whole or in part by a qualified exempt organization shall, in calculating its taxable net income, gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits, exclude the proportionate share of its taxable net income, gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits attributable to the ownership interest of the qualified exempt organization. </section><section prefix="c">Any corporation that reduces taxable net income, gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits in accordance with paragraph (b) of this subsection shall disregard the ownership interest of the qualified exempt organization in determining the amount of credit available under KRS 141.420. </section><section prefix="d">The Department of Revenue may promulgate an administrative regulation to further define "qualified exempt organization" to include an entity for which exemption is constitutionally or legally required, or to exclude any entity created primarily for tax avoidance purposes with no legitimate business purpose. </section></section><section prefix="10">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007: <section prefix="a">To the extent that a corporation identified in KRS 141.010(24)(b)2. to 8. is doing business in this state, any member, shareholder or partner of the corporation may elect to pay, on behalf of the corporation, his, her or its proportionate share of the tax imposed by this section against the corporation. If an election is made, the electing member, shareholder or partner shall be treated in the same manner as the corporation regarding the proportionate part of the tax paid by the member, shareholder or partner. An election made pursuant to this subsection shall not: <section prefix="1">Be used by the Department of Revenue or the taxpayer to assert that the party making the election is doing business in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">Result in an increase of the amount of credit allowable under KRS 141.420; or </section><section prefix="3">Apply to any corporation that is required to be included in a consolidated return under KRS 141.200(2) to (5) and (9) to (12). </section></section><section prefix="b">The Department of Revenue shall prescribe forms and promulgate regulations to execute and administer the provisions of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="11">The alternative minimum calculation for gross receipts shall be: <section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2005, and before January 1, 2006, nine and one-half cents ($0.095) per one hundred dollars ($100) of the corporation's Kentucky gross receipts; and </section><section prefix="b">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2006, and before January 1, 2007: <section prefix="1">If the corporation's gross receipts from all sources are three million dollars ($3,000,000) or less, the alternative minimum calculation shall be zero; </section><section prefix="2">If the corporation's gross receipts from all sources are greater than three million dollars ($3,000,000) but less than six million dollars ($6,000,000), the alternative minimum calculation shall be nine and one-half cents ($0.095) per one hundred dollars ($100) of the corporation's Kentucky gross receipts, reduced by an amount equal to two thousand eight hundred fifty dollars ($2,850) multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is six million dollars ($6,000,000) less the amount of the corporation's Kentucky gross receipts for the taxable year, and the denominator of which is three million dollars ($3,000,000), but in no case shall the result be less than zero; </section><section prefix="3">If the corporation's gross receipts from all sources are equal to or greater than six million dollars ($6,000,000), the alternative minimum calculation shall be nine and one-half cents ($0.095) per one hundred dollars ($100) of the corporation's Kentucky gross receipts. </section>In determining eligibility for the reductions contained in this paragraph when the alternative minimum calculation is computed on a consolidated return, the gross receipts of the affiliated group shall include the total gross receipts from all sources of the affiliated group, including eliminating entries for transactions among the group. </section></section><section prefix="12">The alternative minimum calculation for gross profits shall be: <section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2005, and before January 1, 2006, seventy-five cents ($0.75) per one hundred dollars ($100) of the corporation's Kentucky gross profits; and </section><section prefix="b">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2006, and before January 1, 2007: <section prefix="1">If the corporation's gross profits from all sources are three million dollars ($3,000,000) or less, the tax shall be zero; </section><section prefix="2">If the corporation’s gross profits from all sources are at least three million dollars ($3,000,000) but less than six million dollars ($6,000,000), the tax shall be seventy-five cents ($0.75) per one hundred dollars ($100) of the corporation’s Kentucky gross profits, reduced by an amount equal to twenty-two thousand five hundred dollars ($22,500) multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which is six million dollars ($6,000,000) less the amount of the corporation’s Kentucky gross profits, and the denominator of which is three million dollars ($3,000,000), but in no case shall the result be less than zero; </section><section prefix="3">If the corporation’s gross profits from all sources are equal to or greater than six million dollars ($6,000,000), the tax shall be seventy-five cents ($0.75) per one hundred dollars ($100) on all of the corporation’s Kentucky gross profits. </section>In determining eligibility for the reductions contained in this paragraph when the alternative minimum calculation is computed on a consolidated return, the gross profits of the affiliated group shall include the total gross profits from all sources of the affiliated group, including eliminating entries for transactions among the group. </section></section><section prefix="13">As used in subsections (11) and (12) of this section: <section prefix="a">"Kentucky gross receipts" means an amount equal to the computation of the numerator of the sales factor under the provisions of KRS 141.120(8)(c); </section><section prefix="b">"Gross receipts from all sources" means an amount equal to the computation of the denominator of the sales factor under the provisions of KRS 141.120(8)(c); and </section><section prefix="c">The terms defined in KRS 141.0401(1)(d) to (l) shall have the same meaning as provided in KRS 141.0401. </section></section><section prefix="14"><section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007, an S corporation shall pay income tax on the same items of income and in the same manner as required for federal purposes, except to the extent required by differences between this chapter and the federal income tax law and regulations. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">If the S corporation is required under Section 1363(d) of the Internal Revenue Code to submit installments of tax on the recapture of LIFO benefits, installments to pay the Kentucky tax due shall be paid on or before the due date of the S corporation's return, as extended, if applicable. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 141.170(3), no interest shall be assessed on the installment payment for the period of extension. </section></section><section prefix="c">If the S corporation is required under Section 1374 or 1375 of the Internal Revenue Code to pay tax on built-in gains or on passive investment income, the amount of tax imposed by this subsection shall be computed by applying the highest rate of tax for the taxable year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 251, secs. 46 and 47, effective April 25, 2006; and ch. 252, Pt. XIII, sec. 1, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 7, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. VII C, sec. 629, effective April 11, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 332, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 459, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, Pt. III, sec. 18, effective July 29, 1985. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 8. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 62, Part III. sec. 2; and ch. 121, sec. 4. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 5. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 176, Part 1, sec. 4; and ch. 255, sec. 137. -- Amended 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 4. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 5. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4281b-14, 4281b-14a. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 251 and 252, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 instructs the Reviser of Statutes to adjust KRS references throughout the statutes to conform with the 2006 renumbering of the Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. Such an adjustment has been made in this statute. (6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007."  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>