<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.11-010</section_number><catch_line>Member's dissociation.   </catch_line><order_by>11-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person has the power to dissociate as a member at any time, rightfully or wrongfully, by express will. </section><section prefix="2">Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, a member’s dissociation from a limited cooperative association is wrongful only if the dissociation: <section prefix="a">Breaches an express provision of the organic rules; or </section><section prefix="b">Occurs before the termination of the limited cooperative association and: <section prefix="1">The person is expelled as a member under subsection (4)(c) or (d) of this section; or </section><section prefix="2">In the case of a person that is not an individual, trust other than a business trust, or estate, the person is expelled or otherwise dissociated as a member because it dissolved or terminated in bad faith. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, a person that wrongfully dissociates as a member is liable to the limited cooperative association for damages caused by the dissociation. The liability is in addition to any other debt, obligation, or liability of the person to the association. </section><section prefix="4">A member is dissociated from the limited cooperative association as a member when: <section prefix="a">The association receives notice in a record of the member’s express will to dissociate as a member, or if the member specifies in the notice an effective date later than the date the association received notice, on that later date; </section><section prefix="b">An event stated in the organic rules as causing the member’s dissociation as a member occurs; </section><section prefix="c">The member is expelled as a member under the organic rules; </section><section prefix="d">The member is expelled as a member by the board of directors because: <section prefix="1">It is unlawful to carry on the association’s activities with the member as a member; </section><section prefix="2">There has been a transfer of all the member’s financial rights in the association, other than: <section prefix="a">A creation or perfection of a security interest; or </section><section prefix="b">A charging order in effect under KRS 272A.6-050 which has not been foreclosed; </section></section><section prefix="3">The member is a limited liability company, association, or partnership, which has been dissolved, and its business is being wound up; </section><section prefix="4">The member is a corporation or cooperative and: <section prefix="a">The member filed articles of dissolution or the equivalent, or the jurisdiction of formation revoked its charter or right to conduct business; </section><section prefix="b">The association sends a notice to the member that it will be expelled as a member for a reason described in subdivision a. of this subparagraph; and </section><section prefix="c">Not later than ninety (90) days after the notice was sent under subdivision b. of this subparagraph, the member did not revoke its articles of dissolution or the equivalent, or the jurisdiction of formation did not reinstate the corporation’s or cooperative’s charter or right to conduct business; or </section></section><section prefix="5">The member is an individual and is adjudged incompetent; </section></section><section prefix="e">In the case of a member who is an individual, the individual dies; </section><section prefix="f">In the case of a member that is a trust or is acting as a member by virtue of being a trustee of a trust, all the trust’s financial rights in the association are distributed; </section><section prefix="g">In the case of a member that is an estate, the estate’s entire financial interest in the association is distributed; </section><section prefix="h">In the case of a member that is not an individual, partnership, limited liability company, cooperative, corporation, trust, or estate, the member is terminated; or </section><section prefix="i">The association’s participation in a merger if, under the plan of merger, the member ceases to be a member. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 85, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>