<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.110</section_number><catch_line>Certification of petition for referendum -- Publication of act. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within five (5) days after the filing of the petition for referendum, the Secretary of State shall transmit to the county judge/executive of each county in which petitioners reside the sheets containing the names of the petitioners of that county. The county judge/executive shall thereupon set a date not less than ten (10) nor more than fifteen (15) days thereafter when interested persons may appear and present proof as to the genuineness of signatures and the qualification of petitioners. After hearing proof, the county judge/executive shall determine the number of legal voters of his county who have signed the petition, cause the same to be entered upon the order book and certify it to the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">Within thirty (30) days after receiving from the county judges/executive certification that a number of legal voters constituting in the aggregate five percent (5%) of the vote of the entire state have signed a petition for referendum, the Secretary of State shall cause the proposed act or the parts thereof affected and the fact that the act will be submitted to the voters for their acceptance or rejection at the next general election to be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 257, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 133. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4019b-2, 4019b-3. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>