<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-750</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 304.17A-750 to 304.17A-770 and 304.47-020. </catch_line><order_by>17A-750</order_by><text>As used in KRS 304.17A-750 to 304.17A-770 and 304.47-020, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Eligible employee" means any full time or part time employee who is actively engaged in the conduct of business of the employer, who has satisfied any employer waiting period requirements, and who has been given a voucher by the employer to purchase a health benefit plan; </section><section prefix="2">"Eligible person" means an employer, eligible employee, self-employed person, unemployed person, or retiree who is not eligible for Medicare; </section><section prefix="3">"Employer" means any corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other business entity doing business in Kentucky that provides a voucher for a health benefit plan to its eligible employees to purchase a health benefit plan; </section><section prefix="4">"Insurance purchasing outlet" means a business entity licensed as an administrator in accordance with Subtitle 9 of Chapter 304, which collects premiums and vouchers from or on behalf of health purchasing outlet members, and which is issued a certificate of registration in accordance with KRS 304.17A-750 to 304.17A-770 and 304.47-020; </section><section prefix="5">"Insurance purchasing outlet member" means an eligible person, including a dependent of an eligible person, who is enrolled in a health benefit plan offered through an insurance purchasing outlet by a participating insurer; </section><section prefix="6">"Participating insurer" means an authorized insurer that contracts with an insurance purchasing outlet to provide coverage to insurance purchasing outlet members under a health benefit plan; and </section><section prefix="7">"Voucher" means an instrument that is issued to an eligible employee by an employer to purchase a health benefit plan. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>