<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.861</section_number><catch_line>Meetings -- Compensation of members -- Staff services by Department of Agriculture and University of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station.   </catch_line><order_by>861</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall meet quarterly and may meet more often upon the call of the chair or by a majority of the members. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall be appointed and conduct the first meeting by July 1, 2001. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in KRS 18A.200, members of the commission shall receive actual traveling expenses while attending meetings of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">Research and development related services for the commission shall be provided by the University of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station. Administrative support services shall be provided to the commission by the Department of Agriculture at the request of the commission, including but not limited to services relating to: <section prefix="a">Testing of industrial hemp; </section><section prefix="b">The processing of documents relating to the program of licensure; </section><section prefix="c">Financial accounting and recordkeeping, and other budgetary functions; and </section><section prefix="d">Meeting coordination and staffing. </section></section><section prefix="5">Administrative expenses of the commission, including but not limited to expenses for the services outlined in subsection (4) of this section, shall be paid from the industrial hemp program fund established in KRS 260.869 as approved by the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 6, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>