<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.110</section_number><catch_line>Petition -- Guardian ad litem -- Summons -- Notice -- Hearing -- Report to court -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petition by the cabinet for emergency protective services shall be verified by an authorized representative of the cabinet and shall set forth the name, age, and address of the adult in need of protective services; the nature of the disability of the adult, if determinable; the proposed protective services; the petitioner's reasonable belief, together with the facts supportive thereof, as to the existence of the facts, and the facts showing the petitioner's attempts to obtain the adult's consent to the services and the outcomes of such attempts. The petition and all subsequent court documents shall be entitled: "In the interest of----- , an adult in need of protective services." The petition shall be filed in the court of the adult's residence, or if filed pursuant to KRS 209.130, the court of the county in which the adult is physically located. </section><section prefix="2">When a petition for emergency protective services is filed, the court or the clerk shall immediately appoint a guardian ad litem to represent the interest of the adult. The duties of a guardian ad litem representing an adult for whom a petition for emergency protective services has been filed shall include personally interviewing the adult, counseling with the adult with respect to this chapter, informing him of his rights and providing competent representation at all proceedings, and such other duties as the court may order. </section><section prefix="3">Following the filing of a petition, a summons shall be issued and served with a copy of the petition, and notice of the time, date and location of the hearing to be held on the petition. Service shall be made upon the adult and his guardian or, if none, his caretaker. Should the adult have no guardian or caretaker, service shall be made upon the adult's guardian ad litem. Notice of the hearing shall be given to the adult's spouse, or, if none, to his adult children or next of kin, unless the court is satisfied that notification would be impractical. Service shall not be made upon any person who is believed to have perpetrated the abuse, neglect, or exploitation. Service of the petition shall be made at least three (3) calendar days prior to the hearing for emergency protective services. </section><section prefix="4">The hearing on the petition for an emergency order for protective services shall be heard under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The hearing on the petition, in the interests of expedition, may be held in any county within the judicial district or circuit served by the court. The court shall give priority to the holdings of the hearings pursuant to petitions filed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">The adult or his representative may present evidence and cross-examine witnesses; and </section><section prefix="c">The adult or his representative may petition the court to have any order which is entered pursuant to this chapter, set aside or modified for good cause. </section></section><section prefix="5">Where protective services are rendered on the basis of an order pursuant to this section, the cabinet shall submit a report to the court describing the circumstances including the name, place, date, and nature of the services. Such report shall be made at least once or on a monthly basis if protective services are provided the adult for a period of longer than one (1) month. </section><section prefix="6">The fee of the guardian ad litem shall be paid by the cabinet not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300). This fee is not to be paid to attorneys employed by government funded legal services programs. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 66, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 372, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(11/9/93).  Prior references to the "department" in this statute were changed to "cabinet" pursuant to 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 50(5), and KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8191</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>