<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.175</section_number><catch_line>Abduction of children -- Kentucky Amber alert system -- Department to operate in cooperation with other agencies. </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police, in cooperation with the Transportation Cabinet, the Division of Emergency Management, the Kentucky Broadcasters Association, and the Kentucky Press Association, shall operate a system to notify the public when a child has been abducted and the department determines that public notification might aid in the recovery of the child. The system shall be known as the Kentucky Amber alert system. </section><section prefix="2">The system shall utilize existing resources, including but not limited to electronic highway signs, the emergency broadcast system, law enforcement communications systems, and local, regional, and statewide media providers. </section><section prefix="3">No public alert using the system shall be issued unless the department, in consultation with the law enforcement agency in the jurisdiction in which the abduction of a minor occurred, has determined: <section prefix="a">That the minor has actually been abducted or that all available evidence strongly indicates that the minor has been abducted; </section><section prefix="b">That public notification is the most appropriate method of recovering the child in a safe and efficient manner; and </section><section prefix="c">The geographic area in which the notification shall be made. </section></section><section prefix="4">If it is determined by the department that public notification shall be initiated, the department shall notify the public and private agencies and organizations which will actually provide the notification and shall provide those organizations and agencies with the information which the department deems necessary. </section><section prefix="5">All law enforcement agencies in the Commonwealth shall cooperate with the department in the provision and dissemination of information regarding any abducted minor. </section><section prefix="6">No law enforcement agency, other than the department, shall activate the notification system specified in this section without the authority of the department. </section><section prefix="7">The system shall be operated by all agencies of the Commonwealth within existing budgetary appropriations. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 67, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1111</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>