<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.020</section_number><catch_line>Levy of income tax on individuals -- Rate of normal tax -- Tax credits -- Income of nonresidents subject to tax -- Election to pay tax imposed by KRS 141.023.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An annual tax shall be paid for each taxable year by every resident individual of this state upon his entire net income as defined in this chapter. The tax shall be determined by applying the rates in subsection (2) of this section to net income and subtracting allowable tax credits provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2005, the tax shall be determined by applying the following rates to net income: <section prefix="1">Two percent (2%) of the amount of net income up to three thousand dollars ($3,000); </section><section prefix="2">Three percent (3%) of the amount of net income over three thousand dollars ($3,000) and up to four thousand dollars ($4,000); </section><section prefix="3">Four percent (4%) of the amount of net income over four thousand dollars ($4,000) and up to five thousand dollars ($5,000); </section><section prefix="4">Five percent (5%) of the amount of net income over five thousand dollars ($5,000) and up to eight thousand dollars ($8,000); and </section><section prefix="5">Six percent (6%) of the amount of net income over eight thousand dollars ($8,000). </section></section><section prefix="b">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, the tax shall be determined by applying the following rates to net income: <section prefix="1">Two percent (2%) of the amount of net income up to three thousand dollars ($3,000); </section><section prefix="2">Three percent (3%) of the amount of net income over three thousand dollars ($3,000) and up to four thousand dollars ($4,000); </section><section prefix="3">Four percent (4%) of the amount of net income over four thousand dollars ($4,000) and up to five thousand dollars ($5,000); </section><section prefix="4">Five percent (5%) of the amount of net income over five thousand dollars ($5,000) and up to eight thousand dollars ($8,000); </section><section prefix="5">Five and eight-tenths percent (5.8%) of the amount of net income over eight thousand dollars ($8,000) and up to seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000); and </section><section prefix="6">Six percent (6%) of the amount of net income over seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000). </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2014, the following tax credits, when applicable, shall be deducted from the result obtained under subsection (2) of this section to arrive at the annual tax: <section prefix="1">Twenty dollars ($20) for an unmarried individual; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty dollars ($20) for a married individual filing a separate return and an additional twenty dollars ($20) for the spouse of taxpayer if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the spouse, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, had no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; or forty dollars ($40) for married persons filing a joint return, provided neither spouse is the dependent of another taxpayer. The determination of marital status for the purpose of this section shall be made in the manner prescribed in Section 153 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty dollars ($20) credit for each dependent. No credit shall be allowed for any dependent who has made a joint return with his spouse; </section><section prefix="4">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit if the taxpayer has attained the age of sixty-five (65) before the close of the taxable year; </section><section prefix="5">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit for taxpayer's spouse if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the taxpayer's spouse has attained the age of sixty-five (65) before the close of the taxable year, and, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, has no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; </section><section prefix="6">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit if the taxpayer is blind at the close of the taxable year; </section><section prefix="7">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit for taxpayer's spouse if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the taxpayer's spouse is blind, and, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, has no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; </section><section prefix="8">In the case of nonresidents, the tax credits allowable under this subsection shall be the portion of the credits that are represented by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by KRS 141.010(10), without the adjustments contained in (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the taxpayer's adjusted gross income as defined in Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code. However, in the case of a married nonresident taxpayer with income from Kentucky sources, whose spouse has no income from Kentucky sources, the taxpayer shall determine allowable tax credit(s) by either: <section prefix="a">The method contained above applied to the taxpayer's tax credit(s), excluding credits for a spouse and dependents; or </section><section prefix="b">Prorating the taxpayer's tax credit(s) plus the tax credits for the taxpayer's spouse and dependents by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by KRS 141.010(10), without the adjustments contained in (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the total joint federal adjusted gross income of the taxpayer and the taxpayer's spouse; </section></section><section prefix="9">In the case of an individual who becomes a resident of Kentucky during the taxable year, the tax credits allowable under this subsection shall be the portion of the credits represented by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by subsection (10) of KRS 141.010, without the adjustments contained in paragraphs (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the taxpayer's adjusted gross income as defined in Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="10">In the case of a fiduciary, other than an estate, the allowable tax credit shall be two dollars ($2); </section><section prefix="11">In the case of an estate, the allowable tax credit shall be twenty dollars ($20); and </section><section prefix="12">An additional twenty dollars ($20) credit shall be allowed if the taxpayer is a member of the Kentucky National Guard at the close of the taxable year. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2014, the following tax credits, when applicable, shall be deducted from the result obtained under subsection (2) of this section to arrive at the annual tax: <section prefix="a">Ten dollars ($10) for an unmarried individual; </section><section prefix="b">Ten dollars ($10) for a married individual filing a separate return and an additional ten dollars ($10) for the spouse of taxpayer if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the spouse, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, had no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; or twenty dollars ($20) for married persons filing a joint return, provided neither spouse is the dependent of another taxpayer. The determination of marital status for the purpose of this section shall be made in the manner prescribed in Section 153 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="c">Ten dollars ($10) credit for each dependent. No credit shall be allowed for any dependent who has made a joint return with his spouse; </section><section prefix="d">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit if the taxpayer has attained the age of sixty-five (65) before the close of the taxable year; </section><section prefix="e">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit for taxpayer's spouse if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the taxpayer's spouse has attained the age of sixty-five (65) before the close of the taxable year, and, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, has no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; </section><section prefix="f">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit if the taxpayer is blind at the close of the taxable year; </section><section prefix="g">An additional forty dollars ($40) credit for taxpayer's spouse if a separate return is made by the taxpayer and if the taxpayer's spouse is blind, and, for the calendar year in which the taxable year of the taxpayer begins, has no Kentucky gross income and is not the dependent of another taxpayer; </section><section prefix="h">In the case of a fiduciary, other than an estate, the allowable tax credit shall be two dollars ($2); </section><section prefix="i">In the case of an estate, the allowable tax credit shall be ten dollars ($10); and </section><section prefix="j">An additional twenty dollars ($20) credit shall be allowed if the taxpayer is a member of the Kentucky National Guard at the close of the taxable year. </section></section><section prefix="2">In the case of nonresidents, the tax credits allowable under this subsection shall be the portion of the credits that are represented by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by KRS 141.010(10), without the adjustments contained in paragraphs (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the taxpayer's adjusted gross income as defined in Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code. However, in the case of a married nonresident taxpayer with income from Kentucky sources, whose spouse has no income from Kentucky sources, the taxpayer shall determine allowable tax credit(s) by either: <section prefix="a">The method contained above applied to the taxpayer's tax credit(s), excluding credits for a spouse and dependents; or </section><section prefix="b">Prorating the taxpayer's tax credit(s) plus the tax credits for the taxpayer's spouse and dependents by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by KRS 141.010(10), without the adjustments contained in paragraphs (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the total joint federal adjusted gross income of the taxpayer and the taxpayer's spouse. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the case of an individual who becomes a resident of Kentucky during the taxable year, the tax credits allowable under this subsection shall be the portion of the credits represented by the ratio of the taxpayer's Kentucky adjusted gross income as determined by KRS 141.010(10), without the adjustments contained in paragraphs (f) and (g) of that subsection, to the taxpayer's adjusted gross income as defined in Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">An annual tax shall be paid for each taxable year as specified in this section upon the entire net income except as herein provided, from all tangible property located in this state, from all intangible property that has acquired a business situs in this state, and from business, trade, profession, occupation, or other activities carried on in this state, by natural persons not residents of this state. A nonresident individual shall be taxable only upon the amount of income received by the individual from labor performed, business done, or from other activities in this state, from tangible property located in this state, and from intangible property which has acquired a business situs in this state; provided, however, that the situs of intangible personal property shall be at the residence of the real or beneficial owner and not at the residence of a trustee having custody or possession thereof. The remainder of the income received by such nonresident shall be deemed nontaxable by this state. </section><section prefix="5">Subject to the provisions of KRS 141.081, any individual may elect to pay the annual tax imposed by KRS 141.023 in lieu of the tax levied under this section. </section><section prefix="6">An individual who becomes a resident of Kentucky during the taxable year is subject to taxation as prescribed in subsection (4) of this section prior to establishing residence and as prescribed in subsection (1) of this section following the establishment of residence. </section><section prefix="7">An individual who becomes a nonresident of Kentucky during the taxable year is subject to taxation, as prescribed in subsection (1) of this section, during that portion of the taxable year that the individual is a resident and, as prescribed in subsection (4) of this section, during that portion of the taxable year when the individual is a nonresident. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 5, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. VII D, sec. 632, effective April 11, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 77, Pt. I, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Pt. II, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 5. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 176, Part I, sec. 3. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. III, sec. 2. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 2. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 2. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 2. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4281b-14. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42430</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>