<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.055</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for voting in primary election. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text>Before a person shall be qualified to vote in a primary election, he shall possess all the qualifications required of voters in a regular election. In addition, he shall be a registered member of the party in whose primary election he seeks to vote, and shall have been registered as a member of that party on December 31 immediately preceding the primary election, or, in the case of new registrations made after December 31 immediately preceding the primary election, he shall have registered and remained registered as a member of that party. No person shall be allowed to vote for any party candidates or slates of candidates other than that of the party of which he is a registered member. The qualifications shall be determined as of the date of the primary, without regard to the qualifications or disqualifications as they may exist at the succeeding regular election, except that minors seventeen (17) years of age who will become eighteen (18) years of age on or before the day of the regular election shall be entitled to vote in the primary if otherwise qualified. However, any registered voter, whether registered as a member of a party, political organization, political group, or as an independent, shall be qualified to vote in primary elections for candidates listed in all nonpartisan races. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 34, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 20, effective March 10, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 5, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>