<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.8-170</section_number><catch_line>Places where records required to be kept -- Examination by commissioner -- Fee -- Access to records -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>8-170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every mortgage loan company and mortgage loan broker shall keep at its principal office correct and complete records of its business transactions, books of accounts, and minutes of proceedings of its directors, principals, or partners. Complete records of all business transactions at the principal office shall be maintained at the principal office. Each branch office shall keep detailed records of all transactions at such branch office and shall furnish full control records to the principal office. </section><section prefix="2">No mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker by any system of accounting or any device of bookkeeping shall, either directly or indirectly, enter any of its assets upon its books in the name of any person, partnership, association, or corporation, or under any title, designation, or value that is not thoroughly descriptive of any assets. </section><section prefix="3">The affairs of every mortgage loan company, mortgage loan broker, mortgage loan originator, and mortgage loan processor, and the records required to be maintained by KRS 286.8-160 are subject at any time or from time to time to such periodic, special, or other examinations by the executive director or an examiner of the commissioner within or without this state and with or without notice to the person being examined, as the commissioner deems necessary or appropriate in the public interest. All records of the person being examined shall be subject to the commissioner's inspection. </section><section prefix="4">The examiner shall make a thorough examination into the condition, workings and affairs of the person being examined and report any violation of law or any unauthorized unsafe practices or any failure to keep and have correct any required books and records as he or she may find to the commissioner. </section><section prefix="5">A mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker shall pay a fee for each such examination of its operations or employees based on fair compensation for time and actual expense. For the purpose of avoiding unnecessary duplication of examinations, the commissioner, insofar as he or she deems it practicable in administering this section, may cooperate and exchange information with any agency of the state or federal government, other states, the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry, or the federal National Mortgage Association, Government National Mortgage Association, and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and may accept such examinations in whole or in part in lieu of an examination by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner or the commissioner's examiners or designated representative shall have access to all records of a mortgage loan company, mortgage loan broker, mortgage loan originator, and mortgage loan processor which relate to their business, and records kept by any officers, agents, or employees, relating to or upon which any record of its business is kept. </section><section prefix="7">A mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor shall make available and grant access to the commissioner, or an examiner of the commissioner, the records relating to its operations. A mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker shall make available and grant access to all records of its current and former employees and contractors relating to its operations. </section><section prefix="8">Any person subject to this subtitle shall make or compile reports or prepare other information as directed by the commissioner or an examiner of the commissioner to include: <section prefix="a">Accounting compilations; </section><section prefix="b">Information lists and data concerning loan transactions in a format prescribed by the commissioner or an examiner of the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="c">Such other information deemed necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. </section></section><section prefix="9">No mortgage loan company, mortgage loan broker, mortgage loan originator, or mortgage loan processor shall impede the commissioner or an examiner of the commissioner from interviewing its officers, principals, members, employees, independent contractors, agents, or customers. </section><section prefix="10">In making any examination or investigation authorized by this subtitle, the commissioner may control access to any documents and records of the licensee or person under examination or investigation. The commissioner may take possession of the documents and records, or place a person in exclusive charge of the documents and records in the place where they are usually kept. During the period of control, no individual or person shall remove or attempt to remove any of the documents and records except pursuant to a court order or with the consent of the commissioner. Unless the commissioner has reasonable grounds to believe the documents or records of the licensee have been, or are at risk of being, altered or destroyed for purposes of concealing a violation of this subtitle, the licensee or owner of the documents and records shall have access to the documents or records as necessary to conduct its ordinary business affairs. </section><section prefix="11">It shall be unlawful for any person subject to investigation or examination under this subtitle to knowingly withhold, abstract, alter, remove, mutilate, destroy, or secrete any books, records, or other information. </section><section prefix="12">In order to carry out the purposes of this subtitle, the commissioner may: <section prefix="a">Retain attorneys, accountants, or other professionals and specialists as examiners, auditors, or investigators to conduct or assist in the conduct of examinations or investigations; </section><section prefix="b">Enter into agreements or relationships with other government officials or regulatory associations in order to improve efficiencies and reduce regulatory burden by sharing resources, standardized or uniform methods or procedures, and documents, records, information, or evidence obtained under this subtitle; and </section><section prefix="c">Use, hire, contract, or employ public or privately available analytical systems, methods, or software to examine or investigate the persons subject to this subtitle. </section></section><section prefix="13">The authority of this section shall remain in effect, whether a person acts or claims to act under any licensing or registration law of this subtitle, or claims to act without such authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 782, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 461, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 294.170. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>