<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.110</section_number><catch_line>Incompatible licenses.     </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, each kind of license listed in KRS 243.030 shall be incompatible with every other kind listed in that section and no person or entity holding a license of any of those kinds shall apply for or hold a license of another kind listed in KRS 243.030. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each kind of license listed in KRS 243.040(1), (3), or (4) shall be incompatible with every other kind listed in KRS 243.040(1), (3), or (4), and no person holding a license of any of those kinds shall apply for or hold a license of any other kind listed in KRS 243.040(1), (3), or (4). </section><section prefix="b">A brewery holding a license listed in KRS 243.040(6) or (9) shall not apply for or hold a license listed in KRS 243.040(3) or (4). </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The holder of a quota retail package license may also hold a quota retail drink license, an NQ2 retail drink license, or a special nonbeverage alcohol license. </section><section prefix="b">The holder of a transporter's license may also hold a distilled spirits and wine storage license. </section><section prefix="c">The holder of a distiller's license may also hold a rectifier's license, a special nonbeverage alcohol license, or a winery license. </section><section prefix="d">A commercial airline system or charter flight system retail license, a commercial airline system or charter flight system transporter's license, and a retail drink license if held by a commercial airline or charter flight system may be held by the same person or corporation. </section><section prefix="e">A Sunday retail drink license and supplemental license may be held by the holder of a primary license. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person may hold two (2) or more licenses of the same kind. </section><section prefix="5">A person or entity shall not evade the prohibition against applying for or holding licenses of two (2) kinds by applying for a second license through or under the name of a different person or entity. The state director shall examine the ownership and management of applicants, and shall deny the application for a license if the applicant is substantially interested in a person or entity that holds an incompatible license. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 58, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 2; and ch. 381, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-128, 2554b-130. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>