<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.915</section_number><catch_line>Information to be provided by state agencies. </catch_line><order_by>915</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Employees of state agencies shall provide the committee or its staff with necessary information for the performance of its duties, with any assistance needed to properly conduct the research or study, and with timely access in order to conduct the following functions, necessary to conduct any duly authorized study: <section prefix="a">Reviewing, copying, or inspecting any public or confidential information either written or electronic; </section><section prefix="b">Interviewing personnel; and </section><section prefix="c">Inspecting or observing facilities, equipment, or operations. </section></section><section prefix="2">Adequate facilities shall be provided for on-site research at the agency. Open access to original agency records and data shall be provided during normal working hours, without any restrictions or conditions imposed by the agency, and at the time and in the form requested by the committee or its staff. </section><section prefix="3">The contents of interviews with agency personnel conducted by the committee or its staff or information supplied at the request of the committee or its staff, which is not specifically restricted under KRS 61.878, may be classified as confidential by the public agency and not subject to release under KRS 61.872. This subsection does not apply to reports or documents routinely maintained by the agency and subject to release under KRS 61.872. </section><section prefix="4">Employees of state agencies or programs shall cooperate with the committee or its staff and shall not withhold, destroy, or alter any documents or information requested or given to the committee or its staff. </section><section prefix="5">No state agency or employee may interfere with any person complying with this section or take any punitive, administrative, or retaliatory action against a person for complying with this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 4, effective July 14 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 3, effective March 30, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>