<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.102</section_number><catch_line>Requirement for library media center -- Employment of librarian. </catch_line><order_by>102</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of education for each local school district shall establish and maintain a library media center in every elementary and secondary school to promote information literacy and technology in the curriculum, and to facilitate teaching, student achievement, and lifelong learning. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Schools shall employ a school media librarian to organize, equip, and manage the operations of the school media library. The school media librarian shall hold the appropriate certificate of legal qualifications in accordance with KRS 161.020 and 161.030. A certified school media librarian may be employed to serve two (2) or more schools in a school district with the consent of the school councils. </section><section prefix="b">If a vacancy occurs, the school council may fill the vacancy on a temporary basis by employing: <section prefix="1">A person who is pursuing certification as a school media librarian in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the Education Professional Standards Board; or </section><section prefix="2">A temporary employee for a period not to exceed sixty (60) days. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3437</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>