<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.100</section_number><catch_line>Application, procedure, and use for temporary motor vehicle registration.   </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A motor vehicle dealer licensed under KRS 186.070 who sells a vehicle for use upon the highways of this state shall equip the vehicle with a temporary tag executed in the manner prescribed below, which shall be valid for thirty (30) days from the date the vehicle is delivered to the purchaser. The cost of the tag shall be two dollars ($2), of which the clerk shall retain one dollar ($1). A motor vehicle dealer licensed under KRS 186.070 shall apply to the county clerk of the county in which the dealer maintains his principal place of business for issuance of temporary tags. Application shall be made for such tags on forms supplied to the county clerk by the Transportation Cabinet. If the purchaser has not received his certificate of registration within thirty (30) days from the date of delivery, the purchaser may obtain another temporary tag from the dealer. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk of any county who receives a proper application for issuance of temporary tags shall record the number of each tag issued upon the application of the dealer for such tags, or if a group of consecutively numbered temporary tags are issued to a dealer in connection with a single application, record the beginning and ending numbers of the group on the application. </section><section prefix="3">The clerk shall retain, for a period of two (2) years, one (1) copy of the dealer's temporary tag application, and ensure that it reflects the numbers appearing on the tags issued with respect to such application. </section><section prefix="4">If the owner of a motor vehicle submits to the county clerk a properly completed application for Kentucky certificate of title and registration pursuant to KRS 186A.120, any motor vehicle required to be registered and titled in Kentucky, that is not currently registered and titled in Kentucky, may be equipped with a temporary tag, which shall be valid for thirty (30) days from the date of issuance, issued by the county clerk for the purpose of operating the vehicle in Kentucky while assembling the necessary documents in order to title and register the vehicle in Kentucky. The Transportation Cabinet may establish administrative regulations governing this section. </section><section prefix="5">The county clerk may issue a temporary tag to the owner of a motor vehicle that is currently registered and titled in Kentucky. A temporary tag authorized by this subsection shall be used for emergency or unusual purposes as determined by the clerk for the purpose of maintaining the owner's current registration. A temporary tag authorized by this subsection may only be issued by the county clerk and shall be valid for a period of between twenty-four (24) hours and seven (7) days, as determined is necessary by the clerk. A county clerk shall not issue a temporary tag authorized by this subsection unless the owner of the motor vehicle applying for the tag presents proof of motor vehicle insurance pursuant to KRS 304.39-080. On and after January 1, 2006, if the motor vehicle is a personal motor vehicle as defined in KRS 304.39-087, proof of insurance shall be determined by the county clerk as provided in KRS 186A.042. A temporary tag issued pursuant to this subsection shall not be reissued by the county clerk for the same owner and same motor vehicle within one (1) year of issuance of a temporary tag. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 113, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012).The amendment of this statute in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5 was to be effective January 1, 2013, pursuant to Section 7 of that Act. However, in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 7, was repealed, and a new effective date of January 1, 2014, was established for the 2011 amendment of this statute, pursuant to 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2. .  Subsection (4) of this section was created in 1988 Acts Ch. 105, Section 1, to provide for the issuance of a fifteen-day temporary tag by the county clerk for out-of-state vehicles being registered in Kentucky. Although this conformed with the existing fifteen-day temporary tag issued by dealers pursuant to (1), subsection (1) was later amended by 1988 Acts Ch. 113, Section 3, to extend the temporary tag period to thirty days. Inadvertently, in the later enactment, (4) was not amended to conform. Pursuant to KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has made a technical correction in order to make the subsections consistent. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>