<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.241</section_number><catch_line>Commission's duties with respect to executive agency lobbying. </catch_line><order_by>241</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall keep on file the statements required by KRS 11A.211, 11A.216, and 11A.221. These statements are public records and open to public inspection, and the commission shall computerize them so the information contained in them is readily accessible to the general public. The commission shall provide copies of the statements to the public on request and may charge a reasonable fee not to exceed the cost of copying and delivering the statement. </section><section prefix="2">Not later than the last day of August of each year, the commission shall compile from the registration statements filed with it a complete and updated list of registered executive agency lobbyists and their employers, and real parties in interest and distribute the list to each elected executive branch official and the secretary of each cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, who shall distribute the list to the appropriate personnel under their jurisdiction. The commission shall provide copies of the list to the public upon request and may charge a reasonable fee not to exceed the cost of copying and delivering the list. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall maintain a list of all executive agency lobbyists. The commission shall provide copies of the list to the public on request and may charge a reasonable fee not to exceed the cost of copying and delivering the document. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall prescribe and make available an appropriate form for the filings required by KRS 11A.211, 11A.216, and 11A.221. The form shall contain the following notice in boldface type: "ANY PERSON WHO KNOWINGLY FILES A FALSE STATEMENT IS IN VIOLATION OF STATE LAW AND SUBJECT TO FINES AND OTHER PENALTIES." </section><section prefix="5">Any rules adopted by the commission to implement KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246 shall be adopted by administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall publish a handbook that explains in clear and concise language the provisions of KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246 and make it available free of charge to executive agency lobbyists, employers, real parties in interest, and any other interested persons. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 542, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 53, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=615</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>