<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.215</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Arts Council -- Functions -- Purpose -- Members -- Compensation -- Officers -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Kentucky Arts Council (hereinafter referred to as "the council") which shall perform functions pursuant to KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the council shall be to develop and promote a broadly conceived state policy of support for the arts in Kentucky pursuant to KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </section><section prefix="3">The membership of the council shall consist of not more than sixteen (16) members who have an interest in the arts. On July 1, 1972, the Governor shall appoint not more than four (4) members for a term of one (1) year; not more than four (4) members for a term of two (2) years; not more than four (4) members for a term of three (3) years; and not more than four (4) members for a term of four (4) years. Thereafter the Governor shall make all appointments for a term of four (4) years, except that of the members appointed after July 15, 1998, four (4) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 1, 1999, shall serve until February 1, 2000; four (4) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 1, 2000, shall serve until February 1, 2001; four (4) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 1, 2001, shall serve until February 1, 2002; and members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 1, 2002, shall serve until February 1, 2003; and subsequent appointments shall be for four (4) year terms ending on February 1. </section><section prefix="4">Council members shall not receive any compensation for their services, but may be reimbursed in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 44 and 45 for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties under KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </section><section prefix="5">From the council membership the Governor shall appoint a chairman and a vice chairman of the council. The council may elect by majority vote other officers deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall meet at the call of the chairman, but not less often than twice during each calendar year. A majority of the members appointed to the council shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="7">The council shall be attached to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet as an independent administrative body. </section><section prefix="8">The council shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet upon recommendation of the council. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 34, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 30, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 283, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2(2) to (8). </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2459</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>