<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">D CONTINUITY OF GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>39D.010</section_number><catch_line>Temporary seat of state government -- Acts valid and binding. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When, during a state of emergency, it becomes imprudent, inexpedient, or impossible to conduct the affairs of state government at the state capital, the Governor shall, as often as the exigencies of the situation require, by proclamation, designate a temporary location for the seat of government at the place within this Commonwealth deemed advisable, and shall take action and issue orders necessary for an orderly transition of the affairs of state government to the temporary location. If practicable, the temporary location designated by the Governor shall conform to that provided for in the current Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan. The temporary location shall remain as the seat of government until the Governor establishes a new location under this section, or until the emergency is ended and the seat of government is returned to its normal location. </section><section prefix="2">While the seat of government remains at the temporary location, all official acts required by law to be performed at the seat of government by any officer, independent agency, division, or authority of this Commonwealth, including the convening and meeting of the General Assembly in regular or special session, shall be as valid and binding when performed at that temporary location as if performed at the normal location. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21763</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>