<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">A KENTUCKY UNIFORM UNINCORPORATED NONPROFIT ASSOCIATION ACT </unit></structure><section_number>273A.020</section_number><catch_line>Statement of authority as to real property.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An interest in real property held in the name of an unincorporated nonprofit association may be transferred by a person authorized to do so in a statement of authority recorded by the association in the office in the county in which a transfer of the property would be recorded. </section><section prefix="2">A statement of authority shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the unincorporated nonprofit association; </section><section prefix="b">The address in this Commonwealth, including the street address, if any, of the association or, if the association does not have an address in this Commonwealth, its out-of-state address; </section><section prefix="c">That the association is an unincorporated nonprofit association; </section><section prefix="d">The name and title or position of a person authorized to transfer an interest in real property held in the name of the association; and </section><section prefix="e">An affirmation by the person executing the statement that they are duly authorized to do so. </section></section><section prefix="3">A statement of authority shall be executed by a person other than the person authorized in the statement to transfer the interest. </section><section prefix="4">A filing officer may collect a fee for recording a statement of authority in the amount of ten dollars ($10). </section><section prefix="5">A document amending, revoking, or canceling a statement of authority or stating that the statement is unauthorized or erroneous shall meet the requirements for executing and recording an original statement. </section><section prefix="6">Unless canceled earlier, a recorded statement of authority and its most recent amendment expire five (5) years after the date of the most recent recording. </section><section prefix="7">If the record title to real property is in the name of an unincorporated nonprofit association and the statement of authority is recorded in the office of the county in which a transfer of the property would be recorded, the authority of the person named in the statement to transfer is conclusive in favor of a person that gives value without notice that the person lacks authority. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 15, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44328</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>