<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.740</section_number><catch_line>KRS 183.630 to 183.730 constitutes alternate method of acquisition -- Effect of other statutes. </catch_line><order_by>740</order_by><text>KRS 183.630 to 183.730 shall constitute a method for the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing or improvement of air navigation facilities or airport facilities or any part thereof or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom, by governmental units or the Commonwealth in addition or as an alternate, to any other method authorized by statute. It is intended to authorize the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing, or improvement of additional facilities for an airport acquired under authority of KRS 183.133 or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom, as well as the original acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing, or improvement of land and other facilities for an airport. Governmental units shall have all authority conferred by KRS 183.133 for the acquisition, construction, maintenance, expansion, financing or improvement of air navigation facilities or airport facilities, or any part thereof or interest therein, or contract for services therefrom. Except as otherwise provided in KRS 183.630 to 183.730, the provisions of KRS 183.133 to 183.138 shall apply to the operation of airport facilities acquired under KRS 183.630 to 183.730. </text><history>Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 6. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 15. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 51. -- Created 1945 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 13. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5815</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>