<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.410</section_number><catch_line>Duties of mine superintendent, mine manager, and licensee. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each superintendent or mine manager shall, on behalf and at the expense of the licensee, keep on hand at or within convenient distance of the mine, not to exceed five hundred (500) feet, a sufficient quantity of all materials and supplies required to preserve the safety of employees, as ordered by the mine foreman and required by law. If the superintendent or mine manager cannot procure the necessary materials or supplies, he shall at once notify the mine foreman, who shall withdraw the men from the mine until the materials or supplies are received. </section><section prefix="2">The superintendent or mine manager shall, at least once each week, read and examine carefully and countersign all reports entered in the mine record book of the mine foreman. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee, superintendent, or mine manager shall cooperate with the mine foreman and other officials in the fulfillment of their duties under KRS Chapter 351 and this chapter, and shall direct that the mine foreman and all other employees under him comply with the law, especially when his attention is called by the mine inspector or by the commissioner to any violations of the laws. </section><section prefix="4">The superintendent or mine manager shall keep on hand at the mine a supply of printed rules, notices, and record books required by this chapter. The superintendent or mine manager shall see that rules, notices, and record books are delivered to the proper persons at the mine and are properly cared for, and that the rules and notices are posted in conspicuous places at or near the entrance to the mine and kept legible. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 24, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 22. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 37. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-50. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33022</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>