<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.090</section_number><catch_line>Schedule III controlled substances. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text>Unless otherwise rescheduled by regulation of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the controlled substances listed in this section are included in Schedule III: <section prefix="1">Unless listed in another schedule, any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances having a potential for abuse associated with a depressant effect on the central nervous system: Any substance which contains any quantity of a derivative of barbituric acid, or any salt of a derivative of barbituric acid; chlorhexadol; glutethimide; lysergic acid; lysergic acid amide; methyprylon; sulfondiethylmethane; sulfonethylmethane; sulfonmethane. </section><section prefix="2">Nalorphine. </section><section prefix="3">Pentazocine (parenteral or injectable form only). </section><section prefix="4">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing limited quantities of any of the following narcotic drugs, or any salts thereof: <section prefix="a">Not more than one and four-fifths (1.8) grams of codeine, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than ninety (90) milligrams per dosage unit, with an equal or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium; </section><section prefix="b">Not more than one and four-fifths (1.8) grams of codeine, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than ninety (90) milligrams per dosage unit, with one (1) or more active nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; </section><section prefix="c">Not more than three hundred (300) milligrams of dihydrocodeinone, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than fifteen (15) milligrams per dosage unit, with a fourfold or greater quantity of an isoquinoline alkaloid of opium; </section><section prefix="d">Not more than three hundred (300) milligrams of dihydrocodeinone, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than fifteen (15) milligrams per dosage unit, with one (1) or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; </section><section prefix="e">Not more than one and four-fifths (1.8) grams of dihydrocodeine, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than ninety (90) milligrams per dosage unit, with one (1) or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; </section><section prefix="f">Not more than three hundred (300) milligrams of ethylmorphine, or any of its salts per one hundred (100) milliliters or not more than fifteen (15) milligrams per dosage unit, with one (1) or more ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; </section><section prefix="g">Not more than five hundred (500) milligrams of opium per one hundred (100) milliliters or per one hundred (100) grams, or not more than twenty-five (25) milligrams per dosage unit, with one (1) or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts; </section><section prefix="h">Not more than fifty (50) milligrams of morphine, or any of its salts, per one hundred (100) milliliters or per one hundred (100) grams with one (1) or more active, nonnarcotic ingredients in recognized therapeutic amounts. </section><section prefix="i">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may except by regulation any compound, mixture, or preparation containing any stimulant or depressant substance listed in subsection (1) from the application of all or any part of this chapter if the compound, mixture, or preparation contains one (1) or more active medicinal ingredients not having a stimulant or depressant effect on the central nervous system, and if the admixtures are included therein in combinations, quantity, proportion, or concentration that vitiate the potential for abuse of the substances which have a stimulant or depressant effect on the central nervous system. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing any quantity of any of the following anabolic steroid substances, or any isomer, ester, salt, or derivative thereof: <section prefix="a">Boldenone; </section><section prefix="b">Clostebol; </section><section prefix="c">Dehydrochlormethyltestosterone; </section><section prefix="d">Drostanolone; </section><section prefix="e">Ethylestrenol; </section><section prefix="f">Fluoxymesterone; </section><section prefix="g">Formebulone; </section><section prefix="h">Mesterolone; </section><section prefix="i">Methandienone; </section><section prefix="j">Methandriol; </section><section prefix="k">Methenolone; </section><section prefix="l">Methyltestosterone; </section><section prefix="m">Mibolerone; </section><section prefix="n">Nandrolone; </section><section prefix="o">Norethandrolone; </section><section prefix="p">Oxandrolone; </section><section prefix="q">Oxymesterone; </section><section prefix="r">Oxymetholone; </section><section prefix="s">Stanolone; </section><section prefix="t">Stanozolol; </section><section prefix="u">Testolactone; </section><section prefix="v">Testosterone; and </section><section prefix="w">Trenbolone. </section></section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to any material, compound, mixture, or preparation containing any quantity of an anabolic steroid substance, or any isomer, ester, salt, or derivative thereof that is expressly intended for administration through implant to livestock or other nonhuman species, and that is approved by the United States Food and Drug Administration for such use. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 534, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 477, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>