<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.350</section_number><catch_line>Land-use regulations, what they may include. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the board determines that uncontrolled soil erosion on some lands within the district is causing damage to other lands within the district, it may propose regulations governing the use of lands within the district in the interest of conserving soil and soil resources and preventing and controlling soil erosion. The board may conduct such public meetings and public hearings upon tentative regulations as may be necessary to assist it in this work.  </section><section prefix="2">Land-use regulations may include:  <section prefix="a">Requirements for the carrying out of necessary engineering operations, including the construction of terraces, terrace outlets, check dams, dikes, ponds, ditches and other necessary structures;  </section><section prefix="b">Requirements for the observance of particular methods of cultivation, including contour cultivating, contour furrowing, lister furrowing, sowing, planting, strip cropping, seeding and planting of lands to water-conserving and erosion-preventing plants, trees and grasses, forestation and reforestation;  </section><section prefix="c">Specifications of cropping programs and tillage practices to be observed;  </section><section prefix="d">Requirements for the retirement from cultivation of highly erosive areas or of areas on which erosion may not be adequately controlled if cultivation is carried on; and  </section><section prefix="e">Provisions for such other measures and programs as may assist conservation of soil resources and prevent or control soil erosion in the district, with regard to KRS 262.020. </section></section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42i-9. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12744</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>