<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="333" order_by="333">MEDICAL LABORATORIES </unit></structure><section_number>333.150</section_number><catch_line>Human specimens to be examined only on request of authorized persons -- Transmission of medical laboratory results -- Compliance with HIPPA -- Contents of lab report. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A medical laboratory shall examine human specimens only at the request of a licensed physician, podiatrist, dentist, or other person authorized by law to use the findings of medical laboratory examinations. The results of a test shall be reported to the licensed health care provider who requested it. </section><section prefix="2">Medical laboratory results may be transmitted to: <section prefix="a">Any health care provider who is treating the patient; </section><section prefix="b">An electronic health information exchange or network for the purposes of transmitting medical laboratory results to the ordering provider and to any other provider for the purposes of treatment, payment, or operations if patient consent has been obtained under the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-191; and </section><section prefix="c">An electronic health information exchange or network for the purpose of meeting the requirements of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, Pub. L. No. 111-5, and its related federal regulations. </section></section><section prefix="3">All transactions under subsection (2) of this section shall be in compliance with the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-191. </section><section prefix="4">Laboratory reports shall include the name of the director and the name and address of the medical laboratory in which the test was actually performed. All specimens accepted by a medical laboratory shall be tested on the premises except that specimens for infrequently performed tests may be forwarded for examination to another medical laboratory licensed under this chapter or to a medical laboratory located outside this state if licensed or approved by the appropriate agency of the state concerned. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 17. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>