<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.360</section_number><catch_line>Engineer to examine toll bridges -- Owner to repair bridge -- Engineer to repair bridge when owner fails. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever complaint in writing, on oath, is made to the county engineer that a privately owned toll bridge in the county is unsafe for public use, the county engineer shall immediately cause an examination of the bridge to be made, and if he finds that the bridge is unsafe for public use, he shall immediately notify the owner of the toll bridge or an agent of the owner that he has carefully examined the bridge on complaint and found it unsafe for public use. The owner shall immediately commence repairing the bridge and cause the necessary repairs to be made within one (1) week from the day the notice is given, or within reasonable time thereafter. No toll shall be charged for the use of the bridge until it is fully repaired. </section><section prefix="2">When the owner fails to repair the bridge as provided in subsection (1) of this section, the county engineer shall cause the repairs to be made and the owners of the bridge shall be liable for the expense thereof and for the services of a foreman at three dollars ($3) per day, and upon the neglect or refusal to pay such expenses upon presentation of any account thereof, the county engineer may recover expenses by action in the name of the county. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356c. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>