<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.100</section_number><catch_line>Program required to be provided by school district -- Additional programs permitted -- Refugee or legal alien students. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any statute to the contrary, each school district shall provide an approved preschool school program through twelve (12) grade school service. An approved preschool school program through eight (8) grade school service shall be provided for the children residing in the district by maintaining schools. An approved high school service for all children of high school grade under twenty-one (21) years of age residing in the district shall be provided either by maintaining the schools within the district or by contract with another district. The board of education of any school district, subject to the approval of the chief state school officer, may establish night schools, industrial schools, and other schools for the residents of the district as it deems advisable. </section><section prefix="2">A school district may provide an approved high school program to a student who is a refugee or legal alien until the student graduates or until the end of the school year in which the student reached the age of twenty-one (21), whichever occurs first. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3480-1, 3480-2, 4363-5a, 4399-2, 4399-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>