<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91">A FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>91A.370</section_number><catch_line>Tourist and convention commission in county containing city of first class or consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the commission established pursuant to KRS 91A.350(1) shall be composed of nine (9) members to be appointed by the mayor of the largest city in the county, the county judge/executive and the Governor of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the mayor of the largest city in the county shall appoint three (3) commissioners in the following manner: <section prefix="a">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the local city hotel and motel association; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the chamber of commerce of the largest city in the county; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the local restaurant association or associations. </section></section><section prefix="3">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the county judge/executive shall, with the approval of the fiscal court, appoint three (3) commissioners in the following manner: <section prefix="a">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the local county hotel and motel association, provided that if only one (1) local hotel and motel association exists which covers both the city and county, then the local hotel and motel association shall submit a list to the county judge/executive; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the board of directors of the largest incorporated Thoroughbred horse racing concern in the county, which list shall contain only directors, officers, or employees of that corporation; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) commissioner who is a resident of the county and who has an active interest in the convention and tourist industry. </section></section><section prefix="4">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the Governor shall appoint three (3) commissioners in the following manner: <section prefix="a">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the State Fair Board; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) commissioner from a list submitted by the local countywide air board; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) commissioner shall be appointed, in those counties not containing a consolidated local government, who is a resident of the county. In those counties containing a consolidated local government, one (1) commissioner shall be appointed who is a resident of the area comprising the consolidated local government. </section></section><section prefix="5">Vacancies shall be filled in the manner that original appointments are made. </section><section prefix="6">When a list as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section contains less than three (3) names or when a selection from such list is not made, the appointing authority shall request in writing the submission of a new list of names. </section><section prefix="7">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the commissioners shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years, provided that in making the initial appointments, the mayor, county judge/executive, and Governor of the Commonwealth shall each appoint one (1) commissioner for a term of one (1) year, one (1) commissioner for a term of two (2) years, and one (1) commissioner for a term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="8">Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing such city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the commission shall have nine (9) members. Six (6) members of the commission shall be appointed by the mayor of the consolidated local government pursuant to the provisions of KRS 67C.139 for a term of three (3) years. The Governor of the Commonwealth shall appoint three (3) members of the commission for a term of three (3) years. Incumbent members upon the establishment of the consolidated local government shall continue to serve as members of the board for the time remaining of their current term of appointment. </section><section prefix="9">The commission shall elect from its membership a chairman and a treasurer, and may employ such personnel and make such contracts as are necessary to effectively carry out the purposes of KRS 91A.350 to 91A.390. Such contracts may include but shall not be limited to the procurement of promotional services, advertising services, and other services and materials relating to the promotion of tourist and convention business; provided, contracts of the type enumerated shall be made only with persons, organizations, and firms with experience and qualifications for providing promotional services and materials such as advertising firms, chambers of commerce, publishers, and printers. </section><section prefix="10">The books of the commission shall be audited by an independent auditor who shall make a report to the commission, to the organizations submitting names from which commission members are selected, and to the mayor of a city or a consolidated local government, the county judge/executive in counties not containing a consolidated local government, and the Governor of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="11">Commission members appointed by the Governor shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. Commission members appointed by the mayor of a city or a consolidated local government or the county judge/executive may be removed as provided by KRS 65.007. </section><section prefix="12">The commission shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 39, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 103, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 83.346. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41719</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>