<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.140</section_number><catch_line>Regulations. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner, after a public hearing thereon, shall make, promulgate, and enforce regulations setting forth minimum general standards covering the design, construction, location, installation, and operation of equipment for storing, handling, transporting by tank truck, tank trailer, and utilizing liquefied petroleum gases, and specifying the odorization of said gases and the degree thereof. Said regulations shall be such as are reasonably necessary for the protection of the health, welfare and safety of the public and persons using such materials, and shall be in substantial conformity with the generally accepted standards of safety concerning the same subject matter. Regulations concerning the construction of buildings relating to liquefied petroleum gases shall conform to the uniform state building code after said code is promulgated. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall promulgate any additional rules and regulations which he or she deems necessary to provide for the safe storage, handling, transportation and use of liquefied petroleum gas. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 498, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 26, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10991</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>