<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.015</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky State Board of Chiropractic Examiners; </section><section prefix="2">Subject to the limitations of subsection (4) of this section "chiropractic" means the science of diagnosing and adjusting or manipulating the subluxations of the articulations of the human spine and its adjacent tissues; </section><section prefix="3">Subject to the limitations of subsection (4) of this section "chiropractor" means one qualified by experience and training and licensed by the board to diagnose his patients and to treat those of his patients diagnosed as having diseases or disorders relating to subluxations of the articulations of the human spine and its adjacent tissues by indicated adjustment or manipulation of those subluxations and by applying methods of treatment designed to augment those adjustments or manipulation. The terms "chiropractic," "doctor of chiropractic," and "chiropractor" shall be synonymous, and shall be construed to mean a practitioner of chiropractic as defined in this section. </section><section prefix="4">"Peer review" means an evaluation, based upon generally accepted standards, by a peer review committee established in KRS 312.200 or by other persons performing peer review pursuant to KRS 312.200(3), of the appropriateness, quality, utilization, and cost of chiropractic health care and health service provided to a patient. </section><section prefix="5">The practice of chiropractic shall not include the practice of medicine or osteopathy as defined in KRS 311.550, the practice of podiatry as defined in KRS 311.380, the practice of dentistry as defined in KRS 313.010, the practice of optometry as defined in KRS 320.210, the practice as a nurse as defined in KRS 314.011, or the practice of pharmacy by persons licensed and registered under KRS 315.050. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1, effective June 14, 1962. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>