<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.110</section_number><catch_line>Responsibility of bidders and offerors -- Determination -- Right of nondisclosure. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A written determination of responsibility of a bidder or offeror shall be made and it shall be made in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. A reasonable inquiry to determine the responsibility of a bidder or offeror may be conducted. The failure of a bidder or offeror to promptly supply information in connection with such an inquiry may be grounds for a determination of nonresponsibility with respect to such a bidder or offeror. </section><section prefix="2">A written determination of responsibility of a bidder or offeror shall not be made until the bidder or offeror provides the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet with his sworn statement made under penalty of perjury that he has not knowingly violated any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth and that the award of a contract to a bidder or offeror will not violate any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth. "Knowingly" means, with respect to conduct or to a circumstance described by a statute defining an offense, that a person is aware or should have been aware that his conduct is of that nature or that the circumstance exists. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided by law, information furnished by a bidder or offeror pursuant to this section may not be disclosed outside of the Division of State Purchasing or the purchasing agency administering the contract without prior written consent of the bidder or offeror. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 23, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22348</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>