<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.782Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Military Heritage Commission -- Membership -- Request for designation of sites and objects -- Administrative regulations -- Funding -- Employees.   </catch_line><order_by>782Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Military Heritage Commission is hereby established as an independent agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky which is attached to the Kentucky Heritage Council for administrative and support purposes. The Heritage Council may request and receive additional administrative aid and support from the Kentucky Historical Society, the Department of Military Affairs, the Commission on Military Affairs, and the Department of Veterans' Affairs. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Military Heritage Commission shall consist of the adjutant general, the executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society, the state historic preservation officer, the executive director of the commission on Military Affairs, and the commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs or their designees, whose names shall be provided in writing. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall receive requests for designation of a geographic site as a military heritage site and for designation of an object as a military heritage object in accordance with KRS 171.780 to 171.788 and the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out KRS 171.780 to 171.788 and to protect military heritage sites and military heritage objects. </section><section prefix="5">The commission may seek funding from any source, public or private, and may expend funds for the operation of the commission and for the protection of military heritage sites and military heritage objects. </section><section prefix="6">The commission may employ such persons as it deems necessary, consistent with available funding, to carry out the duties of the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44497</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>