<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.062</section_number><catch_line>Inspection -- Notice -- Asbestos agency account. </catch_line><order_by>062</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall cause an inspection to be made of all buildings owned, leased or operated by the Commonwealth for the presence of friable materials.  If friable materials are found as a result of such inspection, the cabinet shall have samples of the friable materials analyzed for asbestos in accordance with testing methods established by the Environmental Protection Agency, as provided in 40 CFR 763.109 as amended. </section><section prefix="2">When friable asbestos-containing materials are identified in a state building, a notice shall be conspicuously posted on each entrance to the building informing the users of the building of their presence.  The notice shall include the following warning: </section>  WARNING: THIS BUILDING HAS BEEN INSPECTED FOR FRIABLE (EASILY CRUMBLED) MATERIALS WHICH CONTAIN ASBESTOS.  FRIABLE ASBESTOS-CONTAINING MATERIALS MAY CAUSE HEALTH PROBLEMS AND ARE PRESENT IN THIS BUILDING. A RECORD OF THE INSPECTION AND A DIAGRAM OF THE LOCATION OF FRIABLE ASBESTOS-CONTAINING MATERIALS ARE AVAILABLE IN ROOM ----- OF THIS BUILDING. <section prefix="3">The cabinet shall provide to all persons employed in state buildings found to contain friable asbestos-containing materials a written notice of the location, by room or building area, of all friable asbestos-containing materials in the building. </section><section prefix="4">When friable asbestos-containing materials are not found as a result of inspection, the following notice shall be conspicuously posted on each entrance to the building: </section>  THIS BUILDING HAS BEEN INSPECTED FOR FRIABLE (EASILY CRUMBLED) MATERIALS WHICH CONTAIN ASBESTOS.  FRIABLE ASBESTOS-CONTAINING MATERIAL MAY CAUSE HEALTH PROBLEMS.  THIS BUILDING DOES NOT CONTAIN FRIABLE ASBESTOS-CONTAINING MATERIALS. <section prefix="5">When inspections identify asbestos-containing material that is not friable, the cabinet shall cause an annual inspection of the building to be made to determine if the asbestos-containing material has become friable. </section><section prefix="6">When inspections identify asbestos in a building which has been enclosed or encapsulated to prevent its spread, a notice shall be posted in the custodial offices of the building informing maintenance personnel of the location of such materials. </section><section prefix="7">When asbestos-containing materials have been removed from a building, any notice previously posted in such building pursuant to this section regarding the asbestos-containing materials so removed may be removed. </section><section prefix="8">Expenditures required to implement this section may be paid from the asbestos agency account established within the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>