<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.3-010</section_number><catch_line>Entity name.   </catch_line><order_by>3-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as authorized by subsection (24) of this section, the real name of an entity or foreign entity shall be distinguishable from any name of record with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">The real name of a corporation or nonprofit corporation shall: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">End with the word "corporation," "company," or "limited" or the abbreviation "Corp.," "Inc.," "Co.," or "Ltd." or words or abbreviations of like import in another language, provided, however, that if a nonprofit corporation's name includes the word "company" or the abbreviation "Co.," it may not be immediately preceded by the word "and" or the abbreviation "&amp;"; or </section><section prefix="2">If a professional service corporation, shall end with the words "professional service corporation" or the abbreviation "P.S.C."; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Shall not contain language stating or implying that the corporation is organized for a purpose other than that permitted by its organic act and its articles of incorporation. </section></section><section prefix="3">The real name of a limited liability company shall end with the phrase "limited liability company" or "limited company" or the abbreviation "LLC" or "LC," provided, however, if the company is a professional limited liability company the name shall end with the phrase "professional limited liability company" or "professional limited company" or the abbreviation "PLLC" or "PLC." In the name of either a limited liability company or a professional limited liability company, the word "limited" may be abbreviated as "Ltd." and the word "Company" may be abbreviated as "Co." </section><section prefix="4">The real name of a limited liability partnership registered pursuant to KRS 362.555 shall contain the phrase "Registered Limited Liability Partnership" or the abbreviation "LLP" as the last words or letters of its name. </section><section prefix="5">The real name of a partnership subject to KRS 362.1-101 to 362.1-975, the "Kentucky Revised Uniform Partnership Act (2006)": <section prefix="a">Shall not contain the word "corporation" or "incorporated" or the abbreviation "Corp." or "Inc."; and </section><section prefix="b">May contain the word "limited" or the abbreviation "Ltd." only if the partnership has filed a statement of qualification. </section></section><section prefix="6">The real name of a limited liability partnership that has filed a statement of qualification pursuant to KRS 362.1-931 shall end with the phrase "Registered Limited Liability Partnership" or "Limited Liability Partnership" or the abbreviation "R.L.L.P.," "L.L.P.," "RLLP," or "LLP." </section><section prefix="7">The real name of a limited partnership subject to KRS 362.401 to 362.525, the "Kentucky Revised Uniform Limited Partnership Act," shall: <section prefix="a">Contain the word "Limited" or the abbreviation "Ltd." unless the limited partnership was formed under any statute of the Commonwealth prior to the adoption of the Kentucky Revised Uniform Limited Partnership Act; and </section><section prefix="b">Not contain the name of a limited partner unless: <section prefix="1">That name is also the name of a general partner; or </section><section prefix="2">The business of the limited partnership had been carried on under that name before the admission of that limited partner. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">The real name of a limited partnership subject to KRS 362.2-102 to 362.2-977, the "Kentucky Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2006)," that is not a limited liability limited partnership may contain the name of any partner and shall: <section prefix="a">End with the phrase "limited partnership" or "limited" or the abbreviation "L.P.," "LP," or "Ltd."; and </section><section prefix="b">Not contain the phrase "limited liability limited partnership" or the abbreviation "L.L.L.P." or "LLLP." </section></section><section prefix="9">The real name of a limited partnership subject to KRS 362.2-102 to 362.2-977, the "Kentucky Uniform Limited Partnership Act (2006)," that is a limited liability limited partnership may contain the name of any partner and shall: <section prefix="a">End with the phrase "limited liability limited partnership" or the abbreviation "L.L.L.P." or "LLLP"; and </section><section prefix="b">Not contain only the phrase "limited partnership" or the abbreviation "L.P." or "LP." </section></section><section prefix="10">Subject to KRS 362.2-974, subsections (8) and (9) of this section shall not apply to a limited partnership formed under any statute of this Commonwealth prior to July 15, 1988. </section><section prefix="11">The real name of a rural telephone cooperative corporation: <section prefix="a">Shall contain the word "Telephone," "Telecommunications," "Company," or "Corporation" and the abbreviation "Inc.," unless in an affidavit made by its president or vice president, and filed with the Secretary of State, or in an affidavit made by a person signing articles of incorporation, consolidation, merger, or conversion which relate to that cooperative, and filed, together with any such articles, with the Secretary of State, it shall appear that the cooperative desires to do business in another state and is or would be precluded there from by reason of the inclusion of such words or either thereof in its name; and </section><section prefix="b">May include the word "Cooperative." </section></section><section prefix="12">The phrase "Rural Electric Cooperative" may not be used in the name of any entity or foreign entity except for one formed under KRS Chapter 279. </section><section prefix="13">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the word "cooperative" may not be used in the name of any entity doing business in this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="14">The name of a limited cooperative association shall end with the words "limited cooperative association" or "limited cooperative" or the abbreviation "L.C.A." or "LCA." "Limited" may be abbreviated as "Ltd.," "Cooperative" may be abbreviated as "Co-op" or "Coop," and "Association" may be abbreviated as "Assoc." or "Assn." </section><section prefix="15">There are no required identifiers for a business trust or a statutory trust, but the name of a business or statutory trust may include "Limited" or "Ltd." and may not include any of "incorporated," "corporation," "Inc.," "Corp.," "partnership," or "cooperative." </section><section prefix="16">The real name of an unincorporated nonprofit association that has filed a certificate of association with the Secretary of State shall end with "Limited" or "Ltd.," and the real name of an unincorporated nonprofit association that has not filed a certificate of association with the Secretary of State shall not include "Limited" or "Ltd." No unincorporated nonprofit association shall include in its name any of "incorporated," "corporation," "Inc.," "Corp.," "company," "partnership," or "cooperative." </section><section prefix="17">This chapter does not control the use of assumed names. </section><section prefix="18">The filing of articles of incorporation, articles of organization, articles of association, a statement of qualification, a certificate of limited partnership, a declaration or certificate of trust, a certificate of association, an application to transact authority in the Commonwealth, a statement of foreign qualification, a name registration, or name reservation under a particular name shall not automatically prevent the use of that name or protect that name from use by other persons. </section><section prefix="19">The provisions of subsection (2)(a) of this section shall not affect the right of any nonprofit corporation existing on June 13, 1968, to continue the use of its name as then in effect. </section><section prefix="20">The assumption of a nonprofit corporate name in violation of this section shall not affect or vitiate the corporate existence, but the courts of this Commonwealth having equity jurisdiction may, upon the application of the Commonwealth or of any person interested or affected, enjoin such corporation from doing business under a name assumed in violation of this section, although a certificate of incorporation may have been issued. </section><section prefix="21">This section shall not apply to any domestic or foreign telephone cooperative which became subject to KRS 279.310 to 279.600 by complying with the provisions of KRS 279.470 or which does business in this Commonwealth pursuant to KRS 279.570 and which elects to retain a name which does not comply with this section. </section><section prefix="22">Nothing in this section shall limit the ability of a professional regulatory board to promulgate rules governing entities and foreign entities under its jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="23">The real name of a foreign entity will be determined according to KRS 365.015. For entities not covered by that statute, the real name of the foreign entity will be the real name of the entity as so recognized in the jurisdiction of its origination. </section><section prefix="24">The real name of a partnership, other than that of a limited liability partnership as set forth on a statement of qualification or a registration as a limited liability partnership filed pursuant to KRS 362.555 or that of a foreign limited liability partnership as set forth on a statement of foreign qualification, need not be distinguishable from any name of record with the Secretary of State. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 82, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 160, sec. 126, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 23, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 23, in subsection (13), which deals with the business names of cooperative corporations and associations, contains a reference to KRS 271.020 to 272.050. It is apparent from context that this reference should be to KRS 272.020 to 272.050. This change has been made by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>