<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.215</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for transfer of vehicle ownership. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an owner transfers his interest in a vehicle, he shall, at the time of the delivery of the vehicle, execute an assignment and warranty of title to the transferee in the space provided therefor on the certificate of title, except if the space provided therefor on the owner's certificate of title fails to meet the Kentucky requirements for lawful conveyance of title or if the space provided therefor on the owner's certificate of title fails to meet the requirements for the owner to execute an odometer disclosure statement as required by federal law in effect at the time transferor executes an assignment and warranty of title. Pursuant to the exceptions provided by this subsection and in other cases where applicable, the transferor shall execute an assignment and warranty of title to the transferee by executing the application as provided by the Department of Vehicle Regulation and available from the county clerk. The transferor shall cause the application with the certificate of title attached to be delivered to the transferee. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the transferee shall, promptly after delivery to him of the vehicle, execute the application for a new certificate of title and registration. If an application is required by subsection (1) of this section, the transferee shall execute the applicable portions provided to him by his transferor. Any unexpired registration shall remain valid upon transfer of said vehicle to the transferee. </section><section prefix="3">The application with its supporting documentation attached shall promptly be submitted to the county clerk as provided in KRS 186A.115, together with the required fees. </section><section prefix="4">If it comes to the attention of a transferor that a transferee did not promptly submit the necessary document within fifteen (15) calendar days to the county clerk as required by law in order to complete the transfer transaction, a transferor shall submit to the county clerk, in his county of residence, an affidavit that he has transferred his interest in a specific vehicle, and the clerk shall enter appropriate data into the AVIS system which shall restrict any registration transaction from occurring on that vehicle until the transfer has been processed. The Transportation Cabinet may adopt administrative regulations governing this subsection. This subsection shall not apply to any transactions involving licensed Kentucky motor vehicle dealers. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not apply to a vehicle which has had the title surrendered to a county clerk or a hulk vehicle. Hulk vehicle shall mean a vehicle or part thereof that is: <section prefix="a">In a rusted, wrecked, discarded, worn out, extensively damaged, dismantled, and mechanically inoperative condition; or </section><section prefix="b">Of an apparent value of less than two hundred dollars ($200). </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6179</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>