<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.395</section_number><catch_line>Leave time for state employee who is disaster services volunteer -- Short title. </catch_line><order_by>395</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Disaster" means disasters designated at level III and above in the American National Red Cross Regulations and Procedures; and </section><section prefix="b">"State agency" means all departments, offices, commissions, boards, institutions, and political and corporate bodies of the state, including the offices of the clerk of the Supreme Court, clerks of the appellate courts, the several courts of the state, and the legislature, its committees, or commissions. </section></section><section prefix="2">An employee of a state agency who is a certified disaster services volunteer of the American Red Cross may be granted leave from work with pay for not to exceed thirty (30) work days in any twelve (12) month period to participate in specialized disaster relief services for the American Red Cross for the services of that employee and upon the approval of that employee's agency, without loss of seniority, pay, vacation time, sick time, compensatory time, or earned overtime accumulation. The agency shall compensate an employee granted leave under this section at the regular rate of pay for those regular work hours during which the employee is absent from work. </section><section prefix="3">This section may be cited as the Disaster Services Volunteer Leave Act. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22938</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>