<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.670</section_number><catch_line>Mapping of property -- Biennial review by Department of Revenue. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Revenue shall prepare detailed maps identifying every parcel of real property within each county of the state. Each county shall furnish to the department adequate facilities in the county courthouse in which to work. The Department of Revenue shall prescribe methods and specifications for the mapping of property. Personnel authorized to assist in making property identification maps under this section may be given the same authority as a deputy property valuation administrator. Locally employed mapping project personnel shall be compensated in the same manner as deputies or assistants in the property valuation administrator's office. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Revenue shall conduct a biennial review of the quality of maps and ownership records in each county. If, in the first review conducted under these provisions, the maps and records in any county fail to meet the minimum standards established by the department, the department shall assume responsibility for remapping, revision, and updating under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. Minimum maintenance standards to be followed by each property valuation administrator shall be established by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 217, effective June 20, 2005. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 330, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 29. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 186, Art. I, sec. 15, effective June 16, 1960. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1. -- Created 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>