<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.786Membership</section_number><catch_line>of board -- Terms -- Vacancies.   </catch_line><order_by>786Membership</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The independent district board of health shall be composed of the following members: <section prefix="a">The judge/executive or his designee as an ex officio member from each participating county; </section><section prefix="b">The chairman from each participating local board of health as an ex officio member; and </section><section prefix="c">Additional members appointed by the judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court including, at least to the extent practicable, from the following professions: <section prefix="1">Registered nurses; </section><section prefix="2">Licensed veterinarians; </section><section prefix="3">Licensed dentists; </section><section prefix="4">Licensed physicians; </section><section prefix="5">Licensed podiatrists; </section><section prefix="6">Licensed optometrists; </section><section prefix="7">Mental health professionals; </section><section prefix="8">Public health professionals; </section><section prefix="9">Consumers; and </section><section prefix="10">Licensed pharmacists. </section></section></section> The appointments under paragraph (c) of this subsection shall be made taking into consideration the need for a balanced representation on the board of the professions listed under paragraph (c) of this subsection. Each member shall serve a term of two <section prefix="2">years with a maximum of three (3) consecutive terms, except ex officio </section>members who shall continue to serve. (2) The judge/executive, or his designee and the chairman of the local board of health shall serve as ex officio members of the district board of health. Additional appointments shall be based on population. Each county shall have an appointment of one (1) member for thirty thousand (30,000) population or portion thereof. Additional members shall be at a rate of one (1) member per whole increment of thirty thousand (30,000) population. The mayor of each city containing a population equal to or greater than fifteen thousand (15,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, or his or her designee, shall serve as an ex officio member of the district board of health and shall count against the population-based appointees. <section prefix="3">All appointments made prior to June 24, 2015, shall remain unaffected, and the appointed members shall serve the remainder of their terms. The most recent estimates published by the United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census shall be used for appointments based on population made after June 24, 2015. </section><section prefix="4">The judge/executive shall fill all vacancies occurring by reason of death, resignation, or disqualification and do so for the unexpired term. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 273, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44513</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>