<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.505</section_number><catch_line>Pest Control Advisory Board. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text>There shall be established a seven (7) member Pest Control Advisory Board which shall consist of the following members: <section prefix="1">President of KPCA or his designated representative from the KPCA board of directors. </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member of KPCA appointed by the Governor from a list of persons in the pest control industry submitted by the KPCA, who shall be residents of the Commonwealth. This member shall serve a two (2) year term. </section><section prefix="3">The chairman of the University of Kentucky Department of Entomology or his designated representative. </section><section prefix="4">One (1) other member of the University of Kentucky Department of Entomology appointed by the chairman of the Department of Entomology. </section><section prefix="5">Two (2) members of the department appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture. </section><section prefix="6">One (1) consumer member appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture. This member shall serve a two (2) year term. </section><section prefix="7">If a vacancy occurs on the board, it shall be filled in the manner designated in this section. </section><section prefix="8">At the first meeting of the Pest Control Advisory Board, a chairman, a vice chairman, and a secretary shall be elected for one (1) year. They shall serve at the pleasure of the board. The chairman or the vice chairman shall preside at all meetings and vote as any other member. The secretary of the board shall maintain accurate minutes of each meeting of the board. </section><section prefix="9">Five (5) members of the board shall constitute a quorum and any action or order of the board shall require the presence of a quorum and the approval of a simple majority of the members present. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall meet on the first Thursday of alternate months beginning with January at Frankfort or such other place in Kentucky as the chairman shall direct. If the first Thursday falls on a holiday, the meeting shall take place the following Thursday. The secretary of the board shall notify members of upcoming meetings ten (10) days prior to the meeting. However, four (4) members of the board may call a special meeting of the board on ten (10) days' notice to the other members. </section><section prefix="11">Members of the board shall serve without compensation; however, members who are not employees of the Commonwealth shall be entitled to reimbursement by the department for actual expenses incurred in carrying out the duties of the board. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 66, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9562</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>