<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.9485</section_number><catch_line>Duty of postsecondary institution to submit statement of policies concerning campus safety and security. </catch_line><order_by>9485</order_by><text>Effective September 1, 2000, and each year thereafter, each postsecondary education institution shall submit to the Council on Postsecondary Education a statement of current policies concerning campus safety and security including, but not limited to: <section prefix="1">The enforcement authority of security personnel, including their working relationship with state and local police agencies; </section><section prefix="2">A description of programs designed to inform students and employees about the campus safety and security procedures and practices, how to report crimes, and how to prevent crimes; and </section><section prefix="3">Statistics concerning the occurrence of crimes on campus during the most recent calendar year. The statistical data shall be reported by the number of occurrences based on: <section prefix="a">Location, broken down in the following classifications: <section prefix="1">Total number on campus: <section prefix="a">Subtotal of occurrences indicating specifically those in dormitories or other residential facilities; </section><section prefix="b">Subtotal of occurrences indicating specifically those in or on noncampus buildings or property; and </section></section><section prefix="2">On public property contiguous to the campus. </section></section><section prefix="b">Category of crime committed: <section prefix="1">As defined in KRS 164.948; and </section><section prefix="2">By category of prejudice, any crime reported to local police agencies or to a campus security authority, that manifests evidence that the victim was intentionally selected because of the victim's actual or perceived race, gender, religion, sexual orientation, ethnicity, or disability. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4506</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>