<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.99-130</section_number><catch_line>Penalties for violation of Subtitle 29. </catch_line><order_by>99-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A fraternal benefit society neglecting to file the annual statement in the form and within the time provided for in Subtitle 29 of this chapter shall forfeit one hundred dollars ($100) for each day during which such neglect continues, and, upon notice by the commissioner to that effect, its authority to do business in this state shall cease while such default continues. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who willfully makes a false or fraudulent statement or statements in or relating to an application for membership or for the purpose of obtaining money from or a benefit in any fraternal benefit society, shall upon conviction be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisonment in the county jail of not less than thirty (30) days nor more than one (1) year, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who willfully makes a false or fraudulent statement in any verified report or declaration under oath required or authorized by Subtitle 29 of this chapter, or of any material fact or thing contained in a sworn statement concerning the death or disability of a member for the purpose of procuring payment of a benefit named in the certificate, shall be guilty of perjury and shall be subject to the penalties therefor prescribed by law. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who solicits membership for, or in any manner assists in procuring membership in, any fraternal benefit society not licensed to do business in this state shall upon conviction be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1661, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 40, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>