<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.750</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 186.750 and 186.752.   </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>As used in this section and KRS 186.752: <section prefix="1">"Bi-fuel system" means the power system of motor vehicles that are powered by gasoline and either CNG or LNG; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="3">"Clean transportation fuel" means: <section prefix="a">Propane, CNG, LNG, bi-fuel systems, or electricity when they are used as motor vehicle fuel; or </section><section prefix="b">Other transportation fuels determined by the division to be comparable with respect to emissions; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Compressed natural gas" or "CNG" means pipeline quality natural gas that is compressed and provided for sale or use as a motor vehicle fuel; </section><section prefix="5">"Conversion" means: <section prefix="a">Repowering a motor vehicle or special mobile equipment by replacing its original gasoline or diesel powered engine with one capable of operating on clean transportation fuel; or </section><section prefix="b">Retrofitting a motor vehicle or special mobile equipment with parts that enable its original gasoline or diesel powered engine to operate on clean transportation fuel; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Division" means the Division for Air Quality within the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="7">"Liquefied natural gas," "liquid natural gas," or "LNG" means pipeline-quality natural gas treated to remove water, hydrogen sulfide, carbon dioxide, and other components that will freeze and condensed into liquid form for sale or use as a motor vehicle fuel; </section><section prefix="8">"Liquefied petroleum gas," "propane," or "LPG" means a hydrocarbon mixture produced as a by-product of natural gas processing and petroleum refining and condensed into liquid form for sale or use as a motor fuel; </section><section prefix="9">"Motor vehicle" means a self-propelled device by which a person or property may be transported upon a public highway, except a device moved by human or animal power or used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks, or which derives its power from overhead wires; and </section><section prefix="10">"Special mobile equipment" means a motor vehicle or mobile equipment not designed or used primarily to transport people, including but not limited to construction or maintenance equipment. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42402</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>