<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.383</section_number><catch_line>Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>383</order_by><text>The State Board of Elections shall prescribe rules and regulations which shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Achieve and maintain the maximum degree of correctness, impartiality, and efficiency of the procedures of voting; </section><section prefix="2">Count, tabulate, and record votes; </section><section prefix="3">Establish a method for placing items on the electronic voting device, which shall, as closely as possible, follow the requirements pertaining to ballot labels; </section><section prefix="4">Design the ballot cards, including a numerical system to insure an accurate record of all voting activities; </section><section prefix="5">Instruct voters in the use of the voting device; </section><section prefix="6">Provide for checking the accuracy of the equipment; </section><section prefix="7">Provide necessary supplies, including those necessary for a write-in vote and secrecy envelopes for punch cards or data processing cards to insure voter privacy; </section><section prefix="8">As part of the official canvass, provide for a manual recount of randomly selected precincts representing three percent (3%) to five percent (5%) of the total ballots cast in each election; </section><section prefix="9">Provide a method for maintaining sufficient documents and records so that votes can be recounted. Such documents and records shall include any material other than a ballot card which is imprinted with the names of candidates and issues voted upon. Records shall be maintained in such a manner that a specific piece of printed material listing issues and candidates can be matched with the specific ballot cards which were marked in reliance upon such printed material. Except as otherwise required in this chapter that certain records and papers relating to specified elections be retained for twenty-two (22) months, such documents and records shall be maintained for thirty (30) days following an election. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 5, effective March 2, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27447</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>