<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.605</section_number><catch_line>Resumption of employment by retired member -- Continuation of retirement allowance -- Waiver of annuity -- Nonteaching employment. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text>Any member retired by reason of service may return to work in a position covered by the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System and continue to receive his or her retirement allowance under the following conditions: <section prefix="1">Any member who is retired with thirty (30) or more years of service may return to work in a full-time or a part-time position covered by the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System and earn up to a maximum of seventy-five percent (75%) of the member’s last annual compensation measured on a daily rate to be determined by the board of trustees. For purposes of determining whether the salary of a member returning to work is seventy-five percent (75%) or less of the member’s last annual compensation, all remuneration paid and benefits provided to the member, on an actual dollar or fair market value basis as determined by the retirement system, shall be considered. Members who were retired on or before June 30, 2002, shall be entitled to return to work under the provisions of this section as if they had retired with thirty (30) years of service. Nonqualified service credit purchased under the provisions of KRS 161.5465 or elsewhere with any state-administered retirement system shall not be used to meet the thirty (30) year requirement set forth in this subsection. Out-of state teaching service provided in public schools for kindergarten through grade twelve (12) may count toward the thirty (30) year requirement set forth in this subsection even if it is not purchased as service credit, if the member obtains from his or her out-of-state employer certification of this service on forms prescribed by the retirement system; </section><section prefix="2">Any member who is retired with less than thirty (30) years of service after June 30, 2002, may return to work in a full-time or part-time position covered by the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System and earn up to a maximum of sixty-five percent (65%) of the member’s last annual compensation measured on a daily rate to be determined by the board of trustees. For purposes of determining whether the salary of a member returning to work is sixty-five percent (65%) or less of the member’s last annual compensation, all remuneration paid and benefits provided to the member, on an actual dollar or fair market value basis as determined by the retirement system, shall be considered; </section><section prefix="3">Reemployment of a retired member under subsection (1) or (2) of this section in a full-time teaching or nonteaching position in a local school district shall be permitted only if the employer certifies to the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System that there are no other qualified applicants available to fill the teaching or nonteaching position. The employer may use any source considered reliable including but not limited to data provided by the Education Professional Standards Board and the Department of Education to determine whether other qualified applicants are available to fill the teaching or nonteaching position. The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish procedures to determine whether other qualified applicants are available to fill a teaching or nonteaching position and, if not, for filling the position with a retired member who will then be permitted to return to work in that position under subsection (1) or (2) of this section. The administrative regulations shall assure that a retired member shall not be hired in a teaching or nonteaching position by a local school district until the superintendent of the school district assures the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System that every reasonable effort has been made to recruit other qualified applicants for the position on an annual basis; </section><section prefix="4">Under this section, an employer may employ full-time a number of retired members not to exceed three percent (3%) of the membership actively employed full-time by that employer. The board of trustees may reduce this three percent (3%) cap upon recommendation of the retirement system’s actuary if a reduction is necessary to maintain the actuarial soundness of the retirement system. The board of trustees may increase the three percent (3%) cap upon a determination that an increase is warranted to help address a shortage in the number of available teachers and upon the determination of the retirement system's actuary that the proposed cap increase allows the actuarial soundness of the retirement system to be maintained. For purposes of this subsection, "full-time" means the same as defined by KRS 161.220(21). A local school district may exceed the quota established by this subsection by making an annual written request to the Kentucky Department of Education which the department may approve on a year-by-year basis if the statewide quota has not been met. A district's written request to exceed its quota shall be submitted no sooner than two (2) weeks after the start of the school year; </section><section prefix="5">A member returning to work in a full-time or part-time position under subsection (1) or (2) of this section will contribute to an account with the retirement system that will be administered independently from and with no reciprocal impact with the member’s original retirement account, or any other account from which the member is eligible to draw a retirement allowance. A member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall make contributions to the retirement system at the rate provided under KRS 161.540. The new account shall independently meet the five (5) year vesting requirement as well as all other conditions set forth in KRS 161.600(1) before any retirement allowance is payable from this account. The retirement allowance accruing under this new account shall be calculated pursuant to KRS 161.620(1)(b). This new account shall not entitle the member to a duplication of the benefits offered under KRS 161.620(7) or 161.675, nor shall this new account provide the benefits offered by KRS 161.520, 161.525, 161.620(3), 161.655, 161.661, or 161.663. A member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall waive his or her medical insurance with the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System during the period of reemployment and shall receive the medical insurance coverage that is generally provided by the member’s active employer to the other members of the retirement system that the active employer employs. If medical insurance coverage is not available from the employer, the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System may provide coverage for the member. A member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall not be eligible to purchase service credit for any service provided after the member's effective date of retirement but prior to the date that the member returns to work. A member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall not be eligible to purchase service credit that the member would have otherwise been eligible to purchase prior to the member's initial retirement. A member who returns to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section, or in the event of the death of the member, the member’s estate or applicably designated beneficiary, shall be entitled, within ninety (90) days of the posting of the annual report submitted by the employer, to a refund of contributions as permitted and limited by KRS 161.470; </section><section prefix="6">The board of trustees may annually, on July 1, adjust the current daily rate of a member’s last annual compensation, for each full twelve (12) month period that has elapsed subsequent to the member earning his or her last annual compensation, by the percentage increase in the annual average of the consumer price index for all urban consumers for the calendar year preceding the adjustment as published by the Federal Bureau of Labor Statistics, not to exceed five percent (5%) annually. Each annual adjustment shall become part of the member's daily rate base. Failure to comply with the salary limitations set forth in subsections (1) and (2) of this section as may be adjusted by this subsection shall result in a reduction of the member’s retirement allowance or any other benefit to which the member would otherwise be entitled on a dollar-for-dollar basis for each dollar that the member exceeds these salary limitations. Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, a member retiring from a local school district who returns to work for a local school district under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall be entitled, without any reduction to his or her retirement allowance or any other retirement benefit, to earn a minimum amount equal to one hundred seventy dollars ($170) per day; </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">A retired member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall have separated from service for a period of at least one (1) year if returning to work for the same employer on a full-time basis, and at least three (3) months if returning to work for a different employer on a full-time basis. A retired member returning to work under subsection (1) or (2) of this section on a part-time basis shall have separated from service for a period of at least three (3) months before returning to work for any employer. </section><section prefix="b">As an alternative to the separation-from-service requirements in paragraph (a) of this subsection, a retired member who is returning to work for the same employer in a full-time position under subsections (1) and (2) of this section may elect a separation-from-service of not less than two (2) months followed by a forfeiture of the retired member's retirement allowance on a month-to-month basis for each month that the member has separated from service for less than twelve (12) full months. A retired member returning to work for the same employer in a part-time position, or for a different employer in a full-time position, may elect an alternative separation-from-service requirement of at least two (2) months followed by a forfeiture of the member's retirement allowance for one (1) month. During the period that the member forfeits his or her retirement allowance and thereafter, member and employer contributions shall be made to the retirement system as a result of employment in any position subject to membership in the retirement system. The member shall contribute to an account with the retirement system subject to the conditions set forth in subsection (5) of this section. For purposes of measuring the separation-from-service requirements set forth throughout this section, a member's separation-from-service begins on the first day following the last day of paid employment for the member prior to retirement. </section><section prefix="c">Failure to comply with the separation-from-service requirements in this subsection voids a member’s retirement and the member shall be required to return all the retirement benefits he or she received, with interest, for the period of time that the member returned to work without a sufficient separation from service; </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">Effective July 1, 2004, local school districts may employ retired members in full-time or part-time teaching or administrative positions without limitation on the compensation of the retired members that is otherwise required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section. Under provisions of this subsection, a local school district may only employ retired members to fill critical shortage positions for which there are no other qualified applicants as determined by the local superintendent. The number of retired members that a local school district may employ under this subsection shall be no more than two (2) members per local school district or one percent (1%) of the total active members employed by the local school district on a full-time basis as defined under KRS 161.220(21), whichever number is greater. Retired members returning to work under this subsection shall be subject to the separation-from-service requirements set forth in subsection (7) of this section. Retired members returning to work under this subsection shall waive their medical insurance coverage with the retirement system during their period of reemployment and receive medical insurance coverage that is offered to other full-time members employed by the local school district. Retired members returning to work under this subsection shall contribute to an account subject to the conditions set forth in subsection (5) of this section. Retired members returning to work under this subsection shall make contributions to the retirement system at the rate provided under KRS 161.540. The employer shall make contributions at the rate provided under KRS 161.550. Local school districts shall make annual payments to the retirement system on the compensation paid to the reemployed retirees at the rates determined by the retirement system's actuary that reflect any accrued liability resulting from the reemployment of these members. </section><section prefix="b">The Department of Education may employ retired members in full-time or part-time teaching or nonteaching positions without the limitations on compensation otherwise required by subsections (1) and (2) of this section to fill critical shortage areas in the schools it operates, including the Kentucky School for the Blind, the Kentucky School for the Deaf, and the Kentucky Virtual High School, and to serve on audit teams. The department shall be subject to the same requirements as local school districts as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection, except the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System shall determine the maximum number of employees that may be employed under this paragraph; </section></section><section prefix="9">The return to work limitations set forth in this section shall apply to retired members who are returning to work in the same position from which they retired, or a position substantially similar to the one from which they retired, or a position described in KRS 161.046 or any position listed in KRS 161.220(4) which requires membership in the retirement system. Positions which generally require certification or graduation from a four (4) year college or university as a condition of employment which are created, or changed to remove the position from coverage under KRS 161.220(4) are also subject to the return to work limitations set forth in this section. The board of trustees shall determine whether employment in a nonteaching position is subject to this subsection; </section><section prefix="10">The provisions of subsections (1) to (8) of this section are not subject to KRS 161.714; </section><section prefix="11">Any member retired by reason of service may waive his or her annuity and return to full-time employment in a position covered by the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The member shall receive no annuity payments while employed in a covered position, shall waive his or her medical insurance coverage with the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System during the period of reemployment, and shall receive the medical insurance coverage that is generally offered by the member's active employer to the other members of the retirement system employed by the active employer. The member's estate or, if there is a beneficiary applicably designated by the member, then the beneficiary, shall continue to be eligible for life insurance benefits as provided in KRS 161.655. Service subsequent to retirement shall not be used to improve an annuity, except as provided in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="b">Any member who waives regular annuity benefits and returns to teaching or covered employment shall be entitled to make contributions on the salaries received for this service and have his retirement annuity recalculated as provided in the regular retirement formula in KRS 161.620(1), less any applicable actuarial discount applied to the original retirement allowance due to the election of a joint and last survivor option. Retirement option and beneficiary designation on original retirement shall not be altered by postretirement employment, and dependents and spouses of the members shall not become eligible for benefits under KRS 161.520, 161.525, or 161.661 because of postretirement employment; </section><section prefix="c">When a member returns to full-time teaching or covered employment as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the employer is required to withhold and remit regular retirement contributions. The member must be employed full-time for at least one (1) consecutive contract year to be eligible to improve an annuity. The member shall be returned to the annuity rolls on July 1 following completion of the contract year or on the first day of the month following the month of termination of service if full-time employment exceeds one (1) consecutive contract year. Any discounts applied at the time of the original retirement due to service or age may be reduced or eliminated due to additional employment if full-time employment is for one (1) consecutive contract year or longer; and </section><section prefix="d">A member retired by reason of service who has been employed the equivalent of twenty-five (25) days or more during a school year under KRS 161.605 may waive the member's retirement annuity and return to regular employment covered by the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System during that school year a maximum of one (1) time during any five (5) year period, beginning with that school year; </section></section><section prefix="12">Retired members may be employed in a part-time teaching capacity by an agency described in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or (n), not to exceed the equivalent of twelve (12) teaching hours in any one (1) fiscal year. Retired members may be employed for a period not to exceed the equivalent of one hundred (100) days in any one (1) fiscal year in a part-time administrative or nonteaching capacity by an agency described in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or (n) in a position that would otherwise be covered by the retirement system. The return to work provisions set forth in subsections (1) to (8) of this section shall not apply to retired members who return to work solely for an agency described in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or (n). Calculation of the number of days and teaching hours for part-time teaching, substitute teaching, or part-time employment in a nonteaching capacity under this section shall not exceed the ratio between a school year and the actual months of retirement for the member during that school year. The board of trustees by administrative regulation may establish fractional equivalents of a day of teaching service. Any member who exceeds the twelve (12) hour or one hundred (100) day limitations of this subsection shall be subject to having his or her retirement voided and be required to return all retirement allowances and other benefits paid to the member or on the member's behalf since the effective date of retirement. In lieu of voiding a member's retirement, the system may reduce the member's retirement allowance or any other benefit to which the member would otherwise be entitled on a dollar-for-dollar basis for each dollar of compensation that the member earns in employment exceeding twelve (12) hours, one hundred (100) days, or any apportionment of the two (2) combined; </section><section prefix="13">When a retired member returns to employment in a part-time teaching capacity or in a nonteaching capacity as provided in subsection (12) of this section, the employer shall contribute annually to the retirement system on the compensation paid to the retired member at rates determined by the retirement system actuary that reflect accrued liability for retired members who return to work under subsection (12) of this section; and </section><section prefix="14">For retired members who return to work during any one (1) fiscal year in both a position described in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or (n) and in a position described under another provision under KRS 161.220(4), and for retired members who return to work in a position described under KRS 161.220(4)(b) or (n) in both a teaching and an administrative or nonteaching capacity, the board of trustees shall adopt a methodology for a pro rata apportionment of days and hours that the retired member may work in each position. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 9, effective July 1, 2010. -- Amended 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 38, effective June 27, 2008. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 14, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 16, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 25, effective July 1, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 477, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 498, sec. 16, effective July 1, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 515, sec. 11, effective July 1, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 14, effective July 1, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 11, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 442, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 562, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 19. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 14. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2010 </effective><lrc-note>(7/1/2004)  In subsection (13) of this statute, two references to "subsection (11) of this section" have been changed to read "subsection (12) of this section." When the statute was amended in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 16, the subsections were renumbered, but the references to subsection (11) were not changed to conform. The Reviser of Statutes has made the conforming change under the authority of KRS 7.136.  (7/1/2004)  2004 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 27, provides that "The provisions of subsection (8) of Section 16 of this Act [KRS 161.605] supersede the provisions relating to critical shortage positions set forth in 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1 [Executive Branch Budget Bill]."  (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts ch. 476, pursuant to sec. 653(1) of Acts ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>