<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.131</section_number><catch_line>Board of Trustees of University of Kentucky -- Membership -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>131</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The government of the University of Kentucky is vested in a board of trustees appointed for a term set by law pursuant to Section 23 of the Constitution of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="b">All persons appointed after May 30, 1997, shall be required to attend and complete an orientation program prescribed by the council under KRS 164.020, as a condition of their service. </section><section prefix="c">The board shall periodically evaluate the institution's progress in implementing its missions, goals, and objectives to conform to the strategic agenda. Officers and officials shall be held accountable for the status of the institution's progress. </section><section prefix="d">Board members may be removed by the Governor for cause, which shall include neglect of duty or malfeasance in office, after being afforded a hearing with counsel before the council and a finding of fact by the council. </section><section prefix="e">The board shall consist of sixteen (16) members appointed by the Governor, two (2) members of the faculty of the University of Kentucky, one (1) member of the University of Kentucky nonteaching personnel, and one (1) member of the student body of the University of Kentucky. The voting members of the board shall select a chairperson annually. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The terms of the appointed members shall be for six (6) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified; except the initial appointments shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) members shall serve one (1) year terms; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) members shall serve two (2) year terms, one (1) of whom shall be a graduate of the university, selected from a list of three (3) names submitted by the alumni of the university according to rules established by the board of trustees; </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) members shall serve three (3) year terms; </section><section prefix="4">Three (3) members shall serve four (4) year terms, one (1) of whom shall be a graduate of the university, selected as under subparagraph 2. of this subsection; </section><section prefix="5">Three (3) members shall serve five (5) year terms; and </section><section prefix="6">Three (3) members shall serve six (6) year terms, one (1) of whom shall be a graduate of the university, selected as under subparagraph 2. of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Three (3) of the appointments shall be graduates of the university and may include one (1) graduate of the institution who resides outside the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) shall be representative of agricultural interests; and </section><section prefix="3">Ten (10) shall be other distinguished citizens representative of the learned professions and may include one (1) who resides outside of Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="c">The Governor shall make the appointments so as to reflect proportional representation of the two (2) leading political parties of the Commonwealth based on the state's voter registration and to reflect no less than proportional representation of the minority racial composition of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="d">Appointments to fill vacancies shall be made for the unexpired term in the same manner as provided for the original appointments. </section></section><section prefix="3">The two (2) University of Kentucky faculty members shall be of the rank of assistant professor or above. They shall be elected by secret ballot by all University of Kentucky faculty members of the rank of assistant professor or above. Faculty members shall serve for terms of three (3) years and until their successors are elected and qualified. Faculty members shall be eligible for reelection, but they shall be ineligible to continue to serve as members of the board of trustees if they cease to be members of the faculty of the university. Elections to fill vacancies shall be for the unexpired term in the same manner as provided for original elections. </section><section prefix="4">The nonteaching personnel member shall be any full-time staff member, excluding the president, vice-presidents, academic deans, and academic department chairpersons. The staff member shall represent all nonteaching university employees including but not limited to building facilities and clerical personnel. The staff member shall be elected by secret ballot by the nonteaching employees. The staff member shall serve a term of three (3) years and until a successor is elected and qualified. The staff member shall be eligible for reelection, but a staff member who ceases being an employee of the university shall not be eligible to continue to serve as a member of the board. Elections to fill vacancies shall be for the unexpired term and shall be held in the same manner as provided for the original election. </section><section prefix="5">The student member shall be the president of the student body of the university during the appropriate academic year and may be an out-of-state resident if applicable. If the student member does not maintain his position as student body president or his status as a full-time student at any time during that academic year, a special election shall be held to select a full-time student. The student member shall serve for a term of one (1) year beginning with the first meeting of the fiscal year which contains that academic year. </section><section prefix="6">The number of student and employee trustees of the University of Kentucky elected to the board shall not exceed four (4). </section><section prefix="7">Unless specifically approved by the board of trustees under the provisions of KRS 164.367, no member of the administrative staff of the university shall be directly or indirectly interested in any contract with the university for the sale of property, materials, supplies, equipment, or services, with exception of compensation to the two (2) faculty members, and the one (1) nonteaching personnel member. </section><section prefix="8">New appointees of the board shall not serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. Board members serving as of May 30, 1997, may be reappointed at the end of their existing terms and may serve two (2) additional full consecutive terms. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 86, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4211</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>