<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-860</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for person registered as an accumulator, transporter, or processor. </catch_line><order_by>50-860</order_by><text>A person required to register as an accumulator, transporter, or processor of waste tires shall: <section prefix="1">Manage the waste tires in accordance with the registration approved by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">Manage the waste tires in accordance with environmental performance standards established by the cabinet for waste sites or facilities; </section><section prefix="3">Store waste tires in a manner that allows fire fighting equipment access to the waste tires; </section><section prefix="4">Establish fire breaks to prevent the spread of fire; </section><section prefix="5">Prevent mosquito infestations and entrapment of water in the waste tires; </section><section prefix="6">Store waste tires stored outdoors in closed containers, in adjacent covered areas, or in windrows no greater than twenty-five (25) feet wide, ten (10) feet high, and seventy-five (75) feet long, with at least fifty (50) feet of open, unoccupied ground between windrows; </section><section prefix="7">Unless the waste tires are stored in buildings, in adjacent covered areas, or closed containers, store them no closer than: <section prefix="a">Thirty (30) feet from a utility easement, property line, or highway right-of-way; </section><section prefix="b">Two hundred fifty (250) feet from a residence; or </section><section prefix="c">Two hundred fifty (250) feet from a karst feature, surface water of the Commonwealth, or unplugged water well; </section></section><section prefix="8">Store waste tires on a surface with a grade of five percent (5%) or less which is free of vegetation and other flammable materials; </section><section prefix="9">Display a permanent sign legible at one hundred (100) feet which identifies the name, address, and emergency telephone number of the person with the registration, the hours of operation, and the cabinet's emergency telephone number; </section><section prefix="10">Comply with the recordkeeping system established by KRS 224.50-874; and </section><section prefix="11">Transfer waste tires only to a person who presents a letter from the cabinet approving a registration issued under KRS 224.50-858 or a copy of a solid waste disposal facility permit issued by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10493</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>