<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.570</section_number><catch_line>Contents of contract. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in contracts exempted in accordance with KRS 45.590, all government contracting agencies of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, any county, city, town, school district, water district, hospital district, or other political subdivision of the state shall include in every directly or indirectly publicly funded contract for supplies, materials, services, or equipment hereinafter entered into the following provisions: </section><section prefix="2">During the performance of this contract, the contractor agrees as follows: <section prefix="a">The contractor shall not discriminate against any employee or applicant for employment because of race, color, religion, sex, age forty (40) and over, disability, veteran status, or national origin; </section><section prefix="b">The contractor shall take affirmative action in regard to employment, upgrading, demotion, transfer, recruitment, recruitment advertising, lay-off, termination, rates of pay or other forms of compensation, and selection for training, so as to ensure that applicants are employed and that employees during employment are treated without regard to their race, color, religion, sex, age forty (40) and over, disability, veteran status, or national origin; </section><section prefix="c">The contractor shall state in all solicitations or advertisements for employees placed by or on behalf of the contractor that all qualified applicants shall receive consideration for employment without regard to race, color, religion, sex, age forty (40) and over, disability, veteran status, or national origin; </section><section prefix="d">The contractor shall post notices in conspicuous places, available to employees and applicants for employment, setting forth the provisions of the nondiscrimination clauses required by this section; and </section><section prefix="e">The contractor shall send a notice to each labor union or representative of workers with which he has a collective bargaining agreement or other contract or understanding advising the labor union or workers' representative of the contractor's commitments under the nondiscrimination clauses. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 172, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 172, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22284</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>