<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.480</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for denial, refusal to renew, suspension, probation or revocation of license. </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text>The board may refuse to license or renew, or may suspend, probate or revoke the license of any podiatrist or in addition to such punishment or in lieu thereof may impose a fine not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense, upon proof that he: <section prefix="1">Has been convicted of a felony; </section><section prefix="2">Has been convicted of a misdemeanor involving moral turpitude or conduct likely to deceive or defraud the public; </section><section prefix="3">Has employed, hired, procured or induced a person not licensed to practice podiatry in this state so to practice; </section><section prefix="4">Has aided or abetted in the practice of podiatry a person not licensed to practice podiatry in this state; </section><section prefix="5">Has been granted a license upon a mistake of a material fact; </section><section prefix="6">Has violated any provision of KRS 311.390 to 311.510; </section><section prefix="7">Has become drug addicted; </section><section prefix="8">Has become a chronic or persistent alcoholic; </section><section prefix="9">Has developed such physical or mental disability, or other condition whereby continued practice is dangerous to patients or to the public; </section><section prefix="10">Has violated any order of suspension, or the terms or the conditions of any order of probation, issued by the board; </section><section prefix="11">Has engaged in, or attempted to engage in the practice of podiatry under a false or assumed name; </section><section prefix="12">Has willfully violated a confidential communication; </section><section prefix="13">Has acted in a grossly negligent or willful manner which is inconsistent with the practice of podiatry; </section><section prefix="14">Is unfit or incompetent to practice podiatry by reason of gross negligence or other causes including but not limited to being unable to practice podiatry with reasonable skill or safety; </section><section prefix="15">Has a license to practice as a podiatrist denied, limited, suspended, probated or revoked in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license to be denied, limited, suspended, probated or revoked in this Commonwealth; or </section><section prefix="16">Has engaged in conduct likely to deceive or defraud the public. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 15. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 10. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>