<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.8091</section_number><catch_line>Warning notices to be posted where agritourism activities are conducted.   </catch_line><order_by>8091</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every agritourism professional shall post and maintain signs that contain the warning notice specified in subsection (2) of this section. The signs shall be placed in a clearly visible location at the entrance to the agritourism location and at the site of the agritourism activity. The warning notice shall consist of a sign in black letters, with each letter to be a minimum of one (1) inch in height. Every written contract entered into by an agritourism professional for the provision of professional services, instruction, or the rental of equipment to a participant, whether or not the contract involves agritourism activities on or off the location or at the site of the agritourism activity, shall contain in clearly readable print the warning notice specified in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The signs and contracts described in subsection (1) of this section shall contain the following notice of warning: "WARNING </section> Under Kentucky law, there is no liability for an injury to or death of a participant in an agritourism activity conducted at this agritourism location if the injury or death results exclusively from the inherent risks of the agritourism activity and in the absence of negligence. You are assuming the risk of participating in this agritourism activity." <section prefix="3">Failure to comply with the requirements concerning warning signs and notices provided in this section shall prevent an agritourism professional from invoking the privileges of immunity provided by KRS 247.809. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40520</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>