<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.020</section_number><catch_line>Legislative finding as to infrastructure projects. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky finds as a fact that the polluting and befouling of the waters of the state has harmed, and is presently harming and injuring, the state's abundant water resources, and, if unabated, will continue to harm such state water resources, and will endanger the health, safety, welfare and well-being of the general public, and the ability of the state to provide essential governmental services for the benefit of the public, and that such situation, if allowed to continue unchecked, will destroy the natural chemical, physical, and biological integrity of the waters of the state. Further, the conservation, development and proper use of the water resources of the state are of vital importance as a result of population expansion and concentration, industrial growth and technological advances. It is hereby found and determined to be essential to the preservation of the natural water resources, economic potential, and general well-being of the state that, to the maximum and greatest extent possible, the state should and must actively engage in a program of assistance to governmental agencies whereby infrastructure projects may be more economically provided so as to better serve the general public of the state. </text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 2. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>March 31, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>