<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.020</section_number><catch_line>Certificates required of school employees -- Filing requirements -- Validity and terms for renewal. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">No person shall be eligible to hold the position of superintendent, principal, teacher, supervisor, director of pupil personnel, or other public school position for which certificates may be issued, or receive salary for services rendered in the position, unless he or she holds a certificate of legal qualifications for the position, issued by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="b">No person seeking initial employment as a school finance officer on or after July 1, 2015, shall be eligible to hold the position of school finance officer unless the person holds a certificate of legal qualification for the position, issued by the Kentucky Department of Education. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person shall enter upon the duties of a position requiring certification qualifications until his or her certificate has been filed or credentials registered with the local district employer. </section><section prefix="3">The validity and terms for the renewal of any certificate shall be determined by the laws and regulations in effect at the time the certificate was issued. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 6, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 55, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4502-6, 4502-10, 4502-11, 4503-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43530</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>