<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.050</section_number><catch_line>Contracts by fire units or districts, cities and counties, for fire protection. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>Any fire protection district created as provided in KRS 75.010, and any fire protection district or fire prevention district hereafter created pursuant to present or future law, and any municipal corporation, volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit, may, through its governing body, make and enter into contracts with any other fire protection district, fire prevention district, municipal corporation, volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit, either within the same county or within an adjoining county in an area adjacent to the boundary line between the counties, for the furnishing or receiving of fire protection services for all property within the confines of the area included in and covered by the contract or contracts, where such fire protection is not otherwise provided by some division of government or governmental agency. Similar contracts may be made and entered into between any county and an adjoining county, or between any county and any one (1) or more municipalities or districts, departments or units of the character above mentioned, located either within the county or within an adjoining county in an area adjacent to the boundary line between the counties. The personnel and equipment of a contracting party, in going to and returning from a fire, or in answering and responding to a false fire alarm or call, and while endeavoring to extinguish fires within the area covered by the contract, shall be deemed and hereby is declared to be engaged in the exercise of a governmental function. </text><history>Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 5. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24441</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>