<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.810</section_number><catch_line>State Advisory Council on Libraries. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky State Advisory Council on Libraries is hereby created and shall be composed of twenty-one (21) members, appointed by the Governor for a term of four (4) years, except that of the twenty-one (21) members initially appointed, six (6) shall serve terms of four (4) years, five (5) shall serve terms of three (3) years, five (5) shall serve terms of two (2) years, and five (5) shall serve terms of one (1) year. The Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall appoint from this membership a chairman and co-chairman to serve for periods of two (2) years each. The council shall be attached to the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">Of the twenty-one (21) members, four (4) shall represent public libraries, two (2) shall represent school libraries, two (2) shall represent college or university libraries, four (4) shall represent special and institutional libraries, two (2) shall represent library users with disabilities, and seven (7) members, at least one (1) of whom shall be representative of disadvantaged persons, shall represent library users. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies shall be filled by the Governor in the same manner as initial appointments are made. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the Kentucky State Advisory Council on Libraries shall be compensated for actual and necessary expenses. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall be the state advisory council on libraries for the purposes of advising the Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives on federal and state library development issues. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 58, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 14, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4988</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>