<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.807</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>807</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall be governed by a board of directors. The board shall exercise complete jurisdiction over the authority. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of the: <section prefix="a">Secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Secretary of the Personnel Cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Secretary of the Labor Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="d">Seven (7) at-large members appointed by the Governor, subject to confirmation by the Senate. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any vacancy which occurs prior to the expiration of a term shall be filled by the Governor in the same manner as the initial appointment was made, and the new appointee shall serve only the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall serve on the board who: <section prefix="a">Fails to meet or comply with the conflict of interest policies established by the board and KRS 304.24-270; </section><section prefix="b">Is not bondable; </section><section prefix="c">Is an employee, attorney, or contractor of a competing insurer providing workers' compensation insurance in the Commonwealth; or </section><section prefix="d">Is not a resident of this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="5">In making the appointments to the board, subject to Senate confirmation, the Governor shall ensure adequate representation from the major sectors of the economy and workforce in the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1854, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 12, sec. 42, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32563</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>