<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.898</section_number><catch_line>Rights for children in child-care programs and their parents, custodians, or guardians -- Posting and distribution requirements. </catch_line><order_by>898</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All children receiving child-care services in a day-care center licensed pursuant to KRS 199.896, a family child-care home certified pursuant to KRS 199.8982, or from a provider or program receiving public funds shall have the following rights: <section prefix="a">The right to be free from physical or mental abuse; </section><section prefix="b">The right not to be subjected to abusive language or abusive punishment; and </section><section prefix="c">The right to be in the care of adults who shall meet their health, safety, and developmental needs. </section></section><section prefix="2">Parents, custodians, or guardians of children specified in subsection (1) of this section shall have the following rights: <section prefix="a">The right to have access to their children at all times the child is in care and access to the provider caring for their children during normal hours of provider operation and whenever the children are in the care of the provider; </section><section prefix="b">The right to be provided with information about child-care regulatory standards, if applicable; where to direct questions about regulatory standards; and how to file a complaint; </section><section prefix="c">The right to file a complaint against a child-care provider without any retribution against the parent, custodian, guardian, or child; </section><section prefix="d">The right to obtain information from the cabinet regarding any type of licensure denial, suspension, or revocation of an operator, and cabinet reports that have found abuse or neglect by any child-care provider or any employee of a child care provider. Identifying information regarding children and their families shall remain confidential; </section><section prefix="e">The right to obtain information from the cabinet regarding the inspections and plans of correction of the day-care center, the family child-care home, or the provider or program receiving public funds within the past year; and </section><section prefix="f">The right to review and discuss with the provider any state reports and deficiencies revealed by such reports. </section></section><section prefix="3">The child-care provider who is licensed pursuant to KRS 199.896 or certified pursuant to KRS 199.8982 shall post these rights in a prominent place and shall provide a copy of these rights to the parent, custodian, or guardian of the child at the time of the child's enrollment in the program. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 524, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7243</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>