<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="338" order_by="338">OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH OF EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>338.071</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission -- Membership -- Terms -- Quorum -- Hearings -- Regulations -- Compensation -- Employees. </catch_line><order_by>071</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission consisting of three (3) members appointed by the Governor on the basis of their experience and competence in the fields of occupational safety and health. The members selected shall be qualified to represent the interest of employers, employees, and the occupational safety and health profession with a minimum of five (5) years experience in their respective fields. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the review commission shall serve terms of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed. </section><section prefix="3">The review commission shall hold monthly meetings and additional meetings as deemed necessary. A majority of the review commission constitutes a quorum for the transaction of business. Special meetings of the review commission may be called upon reasonable notice by the commissioner or by any two (2) members of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">The review commission shall hear and rule on appeals from citations, notifications, and variances issued under the provisions of this chapter and adopt and promulgate rules and regulations with respect to the procedural aspect of its hearings. </section><section prefix="5">The review commission shall have the authority to employ a secretary, hearing officers, and other employees as may become necessary. </section><section prefix="6">The chairman of the commission and each of the other two (2) members shall be paid a salary fixed under KRS 64.640. </section><section prefix="7">The secretary of the commission shall be paid a salary to be fixed by the commission, with the approval of the Governor. The commission shall fix the compensation of all its other employees. </section><section prefix="8">The commissioners and the secretary and employees of the commission are entitled to all necessary expenses incurred in traveling on business of the commission. </section><section prefix="9">The commission shall be attached to the Labor Cabinet for administrative purposes only. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1755, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 38, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32128</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>