<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.215</section_number><catch_line>Program for decontamination of bird roosts. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall operate a program for the decontamination of bird roosts. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to the decontamination of a bird roost, the cabinet shall, at a minimum, make the following determinations: <section prefix="a">The bird roost has tested positive to the presence of histoplasma capsulatum; </section><section prefix="b">The bird roost presents a potential health hazard; </section><section prefix="c">The landowner has requested in writing to the cabinet that the cabinet have the land area associated with the bird roost decontaminated; and </section><section prefix="d">That there are sufficient state funds to pay for the decontamination of the area, including any assistance which may be given by local governmental units, volunteer fire departments, or other organizations. </section></section><section prefix="3">If one (1) or more of the determinations made by the cabinet in subsection (2) of this section is made in the negative, the bird roost shall not be decontaminated by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall ensure that the decontamination of a bird roost is conducted in a safe manner. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may secure the services of local governmental units, volunteer fire departments, or other organizations as long as they are qualified to conduct the decontamination in a safe manner. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet may issue administrative regulations to implement this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 349, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 293, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective April 2, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8366</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>