<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272">COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>272.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any corporation, association or company using the word "cooperative" as part of its name in violation of KRS 272.044 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), and may be enjoined from doing business under that name by any corporation, or stockholder thereof, organized under KRS 272.020 to 272.044. </section><section prefix="2">Any individual or any corporation whose officers or employees knowingly induce or attempt to induce any member to break his marketing contract with an association or who maliciously and knowingly spreads false reports about the finances or management of any association shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each offense, and shall be liable to the association aggrieved in a civil suit in the penal sum of five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense. </section><section prefix="3">Any person conducting a warehouse in this state who persuades or permits any member of any association to breach his marketing contract with the association by receiving his products for sale, auction or display contrary to the terms of any marketing contract of which the offender has notice shall be liable to the association aggrieved in a civil suit in the penal sum of five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense, and shall also pay the association a reasonable attorney's fee and all the costs of the action against him. The association may obtain an injunction against such warehouseman to prevent further breaches and a multiplicity of actions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 139, effective January 1, 2011. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 883d-9, 883f-26, 883f-27. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36666</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>