<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.050</section_number><catch_line>Registration fees -- Voluntary donation for wildlife management and conservation activities and the agricultural program trust fund.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The annual registration fee shall be eleven dollars fifty cents ($11.50) for: <section prefix="a">Motor vehicles, including pickup trucks and passenger vans; and </section><section prefix="b">Motor carrier vehicles, as defined in KRS 281.010, primarily designed for carrying passengers or passengers for hire and having been designed or constructed to transport not more than fifteen (15) passengers, including the operator. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 186.041 and 186.162, the annual registration fee for each motorcycle shall be nine dollars ($9). </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">All motor vehicles having a declared gross weight of vehicle and any towed unit of ten thousand (10,000) pounds or less, except those mentioned in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, are classified as commercial vehicles and the annual registration fee, except as provided in subsections (4) to (14) of this section, shall be eleven dollars and fifty cents ($11.50). </section><section prefix="b">All motor vehicles, except those mentioned in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, and those engaged in hauling passengers for hire which are designed or constructed to transport more than fifteen (15) passengers including the operator, whose registration fee shall be one hundred dollars ($100), are classified as commercial vehicles and the annual registration fee, except as provided in subsections (3)(a) and (4) to (14) of this section, shall be as follows: </section> Declared Gross Weight of Vehicle  Registration   and Any Towed Unit  Fee    10,001-14,000  30.00    14,001-18,000  50.00    18,001-22,000  132.00    22,001-26,000  160.00    26,001-32,000  216.00    32,001-38,000  300.00    38,001-44,000  474.00    44,001-55,000  669.00    55,001-62,000  1,007.00    62,001-73,280  1,250.00    73,281-80,000  1,410.00 </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Any farmer owning a truck having a gross weight of twenty-six thousand (26,000) pounds or less may have it registered as a farmer's truck and obtain a license for eleven dollars and fifty cents ($11.50). The applicant's signature upon the certificate of registration and ownership shall constitute a certificate that he is a farmer engaged in the production of crops, livestock, or dairy products, that he owns a truck of the gross weight of twenty-six thousand (26,000) pounds or less, and that during the next twelve (12) months the truck shall not be used in for-hire transportation and may be used in transporting persons, food, provender, feed, machinery, livestock, material, and supplies necessary for his farming operation, and the products grown on his farm. </section><section prefix="2">Any farmer owning a truck having a gross weight of twenty-six thousand one (26,001) pounds to thirty-eight thousand (38,000) pounds may have it registered as a farmer's truck and obtain a license for eleven dollars and fifty cents ($11.50). The applicant's signature upon the certificate of registration and ownership shall constitute a certificate that he is a farmer engaged in the production of crops, livestock, or dairy products, that he owns a truck of the gross weight between twenty-six thousand one (26,001) pounds and thirty-eight thousand (38,000) pounds, and that during the next twelve (12) months the truck shall not be used in for-hire transportation and may be used in transporting persons, food, provender, feed, machinery, livestock, material, and supplies necessary for his farming operation and the products grown on his farm. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any farmer owning a truck having a declared gross weight in excess of thirty-eight thousand (38,000) pounds shall not be required to pay the fee set out in subsection (3) of this section and, in lieu thereof, shall pay forty percent (40%) of the fee set out in subsection (3) of this section and shall be exempt from any fee charged under the provisions of KRS 281.752. The applicant's signature upon the registration receipt shall be considered to be a certification that he is a farmer engaged solely in the production of crops, livestock, or dairy products, and that during the current registration year the truck will be used only in transporting persons, food, provender, feed, and machinery used in operating his farm and the products grown on his farm. </section><section prefix="c">An initial applicant for, or an applicant renewing, his or her registration pursuant to this subsection, may at the time of application make a voluntary contribution to be deposited into the agricultural program trust fund established in KRS 246.247. The recommended voluntary contribution shall be set at ten dollars ($10) and automatically added to the cost of registration or renewal unless the individual registering or renewing the vehicle opts out of contributing the recommended amount. The county clerk shall collect and forward the voluntary contribution to the cabinet for distribution to the Department of Agriculture. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any person owning a truck or bus used solely in transporting school children and school employees may have the truck or bus registered as a school bus and obtain a license for eleven dollars fifty cents ($11.50) by filing with the county clerk, in addition to other information required, an affidavit stating that the truck or bus is used solely in the transportation of school children and persons employed in the schools of the district, that he has caused to be printed on each side of the truck or bus and on the rear door the words "School Bus" in letters at least six (6) inches high, and of a conspicuous color, and the truck or bus will be used during the next twelve (12) months only for the purpose stated. </section><section prefix="6">Any church or religious organization owning a truck or bus used solely in transporting persons to and from a place of worship or for other religious work may have the truck or bus registered as a church bus and obtain a license for eleven dollars and fifty cents ($11.50) by filing with the county clerk, in addition to other information required, an affidavit stating that the truck or bus will be used only for the transporting of persons to and from a place of worship, or for other religious work, and that there has been printed on the truck or bus in large letters the words "Church Bus," with the name of the church or religious organization owning and using the truck or bus, and that during the next twelve (12) months the truck or bus will be used only for the purpose stated. </section><section prefix="7">Any person owning a motor vehicle with a gross weight of fourteen thousand (14,000) pounds or less on which a wrecker crane or other equipment suitable for wrecker service has been permanently mounted may register the vehicle and obtain a license for eleven dollars fifty cents ($11.50) by filing with the county clerk, in addition to other information required, an affidavit that a wrecker crane or other equipment suitable for wrecker service has been permanently mounted on such vehicle and that during the next twelve (12) months the vehicle will be used only in wrecker service. If the gross weight of the vehicle exceeds fourteen thousand (14,000) pounds, the vehicle shall be registered in accordance with subsection (3) of this section. The gross weight of a vehicle used in wrecker service shall not include the weight of the vehicle being towed by the wrecker. </section><section prefix="8">Motor vehicles having a declared gross weight in excess of eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds, which when operated in this state are used exclusively for the transportation of property within the limits of the city named in the affidavit hereinafter required to be filed, or within ten (10) miles of the city limits of the city if it is a city with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, or within five (5) miles of its limits if it is a city with a population of less than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, or anywhere within a county containing an urban-county government, shall not be required to pay the fee as set out in subsection (3) of this section, and in lieu thereof shall pay seventy-five percent (75%) of the fee set forth in subsection (3) of this section and shall be exempt from any fee charged under the provisions of KRS 281.752. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit any right of nonresidents to exemption from registration under any other provisions of the laws granting reciprocity to nonresidents. Operations outside of this state shall not be considered in determining whether or not the foregoing mileage limitations have been observed. When claiming the right to the reduced fee, the applicant's signature on the certificate of registration and ownership shall constitute a certification or affidavit stating that the motor vehicle when used within this state is used only for the transportation of property within the city to be named in the affidavit and the area above set out and that the vehicle will not be used outside of a city and the area above set out during the current registration period. </section><section prefix="9">Motor vehicles having a declared gross weight in excess of eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds, which are used exclusively for the transportation of primary forest products from the harvest area to a mill or other processing facility, where such mill or processing facility is located at a point not more than fifty (50) air miles from the harvest area or which are used exclusively for the transportation of concrete blocks or ready-mixed concrete from the point at which such concrete blocks or ready-mixed concrete is produced to a construction site where such concrete blocks or ready-mixed concrete is to be used, where such construction site is located at a point not more than thirty (30) air miles from the point at which such concrete blocks or ready-mixed concrete is produced shall not be required to pay the fee as set out in subsection (3) of this section, and in lieu thereof, shall pay seventy-five percent (75%) of the fee set out in subsection (3) of this section and shall be exempt from any fee charged under the provisions of KRS 281.752. The applicant's signature upon the certificate of registration and ownership shall constitute a certification that the motor vehicle will not be used during the current registration period in any manner other than that for which the reduced fee is provided in this section. </section><section prefix="10">Any owner of a commercial vehicle registered for a declared gross weight in excess of eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds, intending to transfer same and desiring to take advantage of the refund provisions of KRS 186.056(2), may reregister such vehicle and obtain a "For Sale" certificate of registration and ownership for one dollar ($1). Title to a vehicle so registered may be transferred, but such registration shall not authorize the operation or use of the vehicle on any public highway. No refund may be made under the provisions of KRS 186.056(2) until such time as the title to such vehicle has been transferred to the purchaser thereof. Provided, however, that nothing herein shall be so construed as to prevent the seller of a commercial vehicle from transferring the registration of such vehicle to any purchaser thereof. </section><section prefix="11">The annual registration fee for self-propelled vehicles containing sleeping or eating facilities shall be twenty dollars ($20) and the multiyear license plate issued shall be designated "Recreational vehicle." The foregoing shall not include any motor vehicle primarily designed for commercial or farm use having temporarily attached thereto any sleeping or eating facilities, or any commercial vehicle having sleeping facilities. </section><section prefix="12">The registration fee on any vehicle registered under this section shall be increased fifty percent (50%) when the vehicle is not equipped wholly with pneumatic tires. </section><section prefix="13"><section prefix="a">The Department of Vehicle Regulation is authorized to negotiate and execute an agreement or agreements for the purpose of developing and instituting proportional registration of motor vehicles engaged in interstate commerce, or in a combination of interstate and intrastate commerce, and operating into, through, or within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The agreement or agreements may be made on a basis commensurate with, and determined by, the miles traveled on, and use made of, the highways of this Commonwealth as compared with the miles traveled on and use made of highways of other states, or upon any other equitable basis of proportional registration. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 186.020, the cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations concerning the registration of motor vehicles under any agreement or agreements made under this section and shall provide for direct issuance by it of evidence of payment of any registration fee required under such agreement or agreements. Any proportional registration fee required to be collected under any proportional registration agreement or agreements shall be in accordance with the taxes established in this section. </section><section prefix="b">Any owner of a commercial vehicle who is required to title his motor vehicle under this section shall first title such vehicle with the county clerk pursuant to KRS 186.020 for a state fee of one dollar ($1). Title to such vehicle may be transferred; however title without proper registration shall not authorize the operation or use of the vehicle on any public highway. Any commercial vehicle properly titled in Kentucky may also be registered in Kentucky, and, upon payment of the required fees, the department may issue an apportioned registration plate to such commercial vehicle. </section><section prefix="c">Any commercial vehicle that is properly titled in a foreign jurisdiction, which vehicle is subject to apportioned registration, as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection, may be registered in Kentucky, and, upon proof of proper title and payment of the required fees, the department may issue an apportioned registration plate to the commercial vehicle. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with this section. </section></section><section prefix="14">Any person seeking to obtain a special license plate for an automobile that has been provided to him pursuant to an occupation shall meet both of the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The automobile shall be provided for the full-time exclusive use of the applicant; and </section><section prefix="b">The applicant shall obtain permission in writing from the vehicle owner or lessee on a form provided by the cabinet to use the vehicle and for the vehicle to bear the special license plate. </section></section><section prefix="15">An applicant for any motor vehicle registration issued pursuant to this section shall have the opportunity to make a donation of two dollars ($2) to promote a hunger relief program through specific wildlife management and conservation efforts by the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources in accordance with KRS 150.015. If an applicant elects to make a contribution under this subsection, the two dollar ($2) donation shall be added to the regular fee for any motor vehicle registration issued pursuant to this section. One (1) donation may be made per issuance of each registration. The fee shall be paid to the county clerk and shall be transmitted by the State Treasurer to the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources to be used exclusively for the purpose of wildlife management and conservation activities in support of hunger relief. The county clerk may retain up to five percent (5%) of the fees collected under this subsection for administrative costs associated with the collection of this donation. Any donation requested under this subsection shall be voluntary and may be refused by the applicant at the time of issuance or renewal of a license plate. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 38, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 266, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2, effective March 6, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 190, effective July 12, 2006 -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 42, effective July 1, 2003. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 150, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 175, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 184, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 287, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 4, effective April 1, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 239, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(2); ch. 90, sec. 2; and ch. 368, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 268, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 40, Part IV, sec. 2. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1967. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1963; and ch. 96, sec. 4, effective March 9, 1962. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 24. -- Amended 1956 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 3. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 3. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-2c(2), 2739g-2d. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44187</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>