<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.454</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for accepting and dispensing legend drug or administration supplies. </catch_line><order_by>454</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A legend drug or supplies used to administer a legend drug may be accepted and dispensed under the program established in KRS 194A.452 only if the following requirements are met: <section prefix="a">The legend drug or supplies needed to administer the legend drug is in its original, unopened, sealed, and tamper-evident unit dose packaging or, if packaged in single-unit doses, the single-unit dose packaging is unopened; </section><section prefix="b">The legend drug is not classified as a controlled substance; </section><section prefix="c">The legend drug or supplies needed to administer a legend drug is not adulterated or misbranded, as determined by a pharmacist employed by, or under contract with, the health facility or pharmacy, who shall inspect the drug or supplies needed to administer a legend drug before the drug or supplies are dispensed; and </section><section prefix="d">The legend drug or supplies needed to administer a legend drug are prescribed by a physician, advanced practice registered nurse, or physician assistant and dispensed by a pharmacist. </section></section><section prefix="2">No legend drug or supplies needed to administer a legend drug that are donated for use under this section may be resold. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 32, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>