<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the sheriff fails to renew the bond required of him by KRS 70.020 when ordered to do so by the county judge/executive, the county judge/executive shall suspend him from acting until he conforms with the order, or may vacate his office. </section><section prefix="2">If the sheriff violates any of the provisions of KRS 70.140, he shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="3">Any sheriff who knowingly makes a false or illegal return on any process or fee-bill, by color of his office, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor and liable to the person injured for treble the damage caused thereby. </section><section prefix="4">If the constable fails to give additional security or to renew his bond when ordered to do so by the county judge/executive, the county judge/executive shall enter an order declaring his office vacant. </section><section prefix="5">Any constable who executes any process, other than a fee-bill for his own service, in which he is personally interested shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="6">Any constable who violates any of the provisions of KRS 70.390 shall be guilty of a violation. If he violates subsections (1) or (2) of KRS 70.390, he shall be liable for the amount of the claim. </section><section prefix="7">Any constable or deputy constable in any county containing a population of over 250,000 who violates any of the provisions of KRS 70.440 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="8">If the constable fails to return any process, placed in his hands, by the return day, the plaintiff may recover five dollars ($5) from him upon motion before the court from which the process issued. </section><section prefix="9">If a constable fails without reasonable excuse to return process placed in his hands for collection within twenty (20) days after the return day, he shall be liable for the amount of the process plus ten percent (10%). </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 169, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 427, 433, 435, 439, 440, 1083a-14, 4557, 4574, 4587. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24263</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>