<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.700</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 198A.700 to 198A.730. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>As used in KRS 198A.700 to 198A.730, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Homeless individual" means a person who: <section prefix="a">Lacks a fixed, regular, or adequate nighttime residence; </section><section prefix="b">Is at risk of becoming homeless in a rural or urban area because the residence is not safe, decent, sanitary, or secure; </section><section prefix="c">Has as a primary nighttime residence a publicly- or privately-operated shelter designed to provide temporary living accommodations; </section><section prefix="d">Has as a primary nighttime residence a public or private place not designed for, or ordinarily used as, a regular sleeping accommodation for human beings; or </section><section prefix="e">Is a family or a person who does not have access to normal accommodations due to violence or the threat of violence from a cohabitant. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Nonprofit organization" means an organization duly organized and validly existing as a not-for-profit organization under the laws of the Commonwealth, any other state, or the United States and whose purpose includes the development, construction, rehabilitation, or acquisition of housing. </section><section prefix="3">"Technical assistance" means activities that are directly related to a nonprofit organization's ability to provide housing for very low-income persons in assisted projects under KRS 198A.700 to 198A.730, and includes land use and planning costs, design and engineering services, finance services, loan packaging assistance, program development assistance, construction consultation, and marketing assistance for developers, and budgeting assistance, independent living skill development, homeownership, tenant education, and self-sufficiency development for renters and homeowners. </section><section prefix="4">"Trust fund" means the affordable housing trust fund. </section><section prefix="5">"Very low-income" means the income of individuals or families that is below sixty percent (60%) of the area median income for the Commonwealth as determined by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6956</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>