<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.975</section_number><catch_line>Regulation of the use of educational property.   </catch_line><order_by>975</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The governing boards of public institutions of postsecondary education, each having the power and authority to govern and control the method and purpose of use of property owned or occupied by their respective institution, including travel over such property, is each hereby confirmed in its authority to regulate the traffic and parking of motor vehicles, bicycles or other vehicles as well as the traffic of pedestrians on, over and across the streets, roads, paths and grounds of real property owned, used or occupied by such institution. Such regulations applicable to traffic and parking may include, but not be limited to, the following provisions: <section prefix="a">Provisions governing the registration, speed, operation, parking and times, places and manner of use of motor vehicles, bicycles and other vehicles. </section><section prefix="b">Provisions prescribing penalties for the violation of such regulations, which penalties may include the imposition of reasonable charges, the removing and impounding (at the expense of the violator) of vehicles which are operated or parked in violation of such regulations, and the denial of permission to operate vehicles on the property of such institution. </section><section prefix="c">Provisions establishing reasonable charges and fees for the registration of vehicles and for the use of parking spaces or facilities owned or occupied by such institution. Provided, however, that nothing herein contained shall be deemed to limit or restrict the powers of any other governmental authority having jurisdiction over public streets, roads, alleys or ways. </section></section><section prefix="2">Motor vehicle moving violations of regulations issued under this section shall be deemed violations of the appropriate equivalent sections of the motor vehicle laws of the Commonwealth and may be prosecuted in the courts having territorial jurisdiction over the physical location of the offense. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41828</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>