<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.6855</section_number><catch_line>Application of assessments -- Employer's duties. </catch_line><order_by>6855</order_by><text>For any development area for which increments do not include revenues from the Commonwealth: <section prefix="1">The employees of any company choosing to locate in a development area shall be subject to any assessments levied against them, and the company shall not have the authority to reject an assessment. </section><section prefix="2">Each employer in the development area shall: <section prefix="a">Collect the assessment from its employees by deducting the assessment from each paycheck of its employees; </section><section prefix="b">Promptly remit the assessment to the official charged with collecting revenues in the development area; </section><section prefix="c">Make its payroll books and records available to the official charged with collecting revenues in the development area at a reasonable time as specified by the governing body; and </section><section prefix="d">File with the official charged with collecting revenues in the development area any documentation with regard to the assessment as required by the governing body. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23454</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>