<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.281</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Real Estate Commission -- Members -- Terms -- Vacancies -- Duties -- Mandatory continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>281</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Real Estate Commission. The Governor shall appoint five (5) persons, at least four (4) of whom, immediately prior to the date of their appointment have been residents of the state for ten (10) years and whose vocation for a period of at least ten (10) years shall have been that of an active real estate licensee. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. The term of the members of the commission shall be for four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify, except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">All appointments shall be for the specified four (4) year term. No person appointed after July 14, 2000, shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="3">For each appointment or vacancy, the Kentucky Association of Realtors shall supply a list of not less than three (3) names of licensees to the Governor each year from which the broker or sales associate appointments shall be made. The Governor may fill vacancies arising in the middle of the year from those remaining on the list or from a new list supplied by the association. </section><section prefix="4">There shall not be more than three (3) of any one (1) political party serving on the commission at the same time. Appointees to fill vacancies shall be appointed for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="5">It shall be the duty of the commission to promulgate administrative regulations; to hold disciplinary hearings concerning matters in controversy as provided by this chapter; to conduct examinations for applicants eligible under this chapter or alternatively to contract with an entity to conduct examinations; to conduct necessary educational seminars and courses directed toward continuing education within the real estate field; to investigate or cause to be investigated any irregularities in violation of this chapter or the promulgated and authorized administrative regulations of the commission; to participate with any other agency of the Commonwealth or the authorized agency of another state for the betterment or improvement of the administration of the statutes or administrative regulations governing this commission. Any action taken by the commission under this subsection shall be appealable as are other actions of the commission under this chapter. </section><section prefix="6">The commission, at its discretion, may use the funds necessary to purchase liability insurance for members and executive officers of the commission, inspectors, and for members of the staff exempted from classified service of the state by KRS 18A.115. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall require all actively-licensed agents, except for those agents who were licensed prior to June 19, 1976, to successfully complete mandatory continuing education as a condition of license renewal. </section><section prefix="8">The commission shall, by the promulgation of administrative regulations, develop a review process by which continuing education courses may be approved for credit. An applicant may seek the commission's approval for credit for courses not previously approved by the commission by submitting sufficient information describing the course to the commission for review. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 22, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 20, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 143, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 352, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1; and ch. 100, sec. 20. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 3. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>