<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="339" order_by="339">CHILD LABOR </unit></structure><section_number>339.450</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of law -- Right to enter and inspect premises and records. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the Department of Workplace Standards and of the inspectors and agents of said department, with the assistance of the school directors of pupil personnel, police officers and juvenile session of District Court probation officers, to enforce the provisions of KRS 339.210 to 339.450, to make complaints against persons violating the provisions of those sections, and to prosecute violations thereof. The Department of Workplace Standards, its inspectors and agents shall have authority to enter and inspect at any time any place or establishment covered by KRS 339.210 to 339.450, and to have access to age certificates kept on file by the employer and such other records as may aid in the enforcement of KRS 339.210 to 339.450. School directors of pupil personnel are likewise empowered to visit and inspect places where minors may be employed, and shall report any cases of employment that they find in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450 to the Department of Workplace Standards. </section><section prefix="2">Any person authorized to enforce KRS 339.210 to 339.450 may require an employer of a minor for whom an age certificate is not on file either to furnish him or her within ten (10) days the evidence showing that the minor is at least eighteen (18) years of age or to cease to employ or permit or suffer such minor to work. Proof of the making of such demand and of failure to deliver such proof of age shall be prima facie evidence, in any prosecution brought for violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450, that such minor is under eighteen (18) years of age and is unlawfully employed. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1775, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 414, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1984 -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 178, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 15. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 24. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32207</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>