<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.011</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 219.011 to 219.081.   </catch_line><order_by>011</order_by><text>As used in KRS 219.011 to 219.081: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or its designee; </section><section prefix="3">"Hotel" means every building or structure kept, used, maintained, advertised, or held out to the public as a place where sleeping accommodations are furnished to the public, and includes motels, tourist homes, and similar establishments, but excludes boarding houses and rooming houses; </section><section prefix="4">"Person" means an individual, or a firm, partnership, company, corporation, trustee, association, or any public or private entity owning or operating a hotel; </section><section prefix="5">"Bed and breakfast establishment" means a one (1) family dwelling unit, but which also has guest rooms or suites used, rented, or hired out for occupancy or which are occupied for sleeping purposes by persons not members of the single-family unit. The innkeeper shall reside on the premises or property adjacent to the premises during periods of occupancy. The building shall be known as either a bed and breakfast home or a bed and breakfast inn; </section><section prefix="6">"Bed and breakfast home" means a bed and breakfast establishment: <section prefix="a">Having five (5) or fewer guest rooms or suites for occupancy; </section><section prefix="b">In which breakfast and other meals may be served to guests; and </section><section prefix="c">Whose innkeeper resides on the premises or property adjacent to the premises during periods of occupancy; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Bed and breakfast inn" means a private inn or other unique residential facility: <section prefix="a">Having six (6) or more guest rooms or suites for occupancy; </section><section prefix="b">In which breakfast and other meals may be served to the guests; and </section><section prefix="c">Whose innkeeper resides on the premises or property adjacent to the premises during periods of occupancy; and </section></section><section prefix="8">"Farmstay" means a bed and breakfast establishment at a farm location whose focus includes agritourism as defined in KRS 247.800. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 553, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 493, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 247 sec. 14, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (10), (11), and (22). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). Although subsection (8) of this statute, as amended by 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, contains the phrase, "agritourism as defined in KRS 247.800," that reference is no longer accurate because 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 100 deleted that definition in KRS 247.800 and created a new definition of "agritourism" in KRS 247.801. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>