<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.315Headquarters</section_number><catch_line>of society -- Priority for maintenance.   </catch_line><order_by>315Headquarters</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The headquarters of the Kentucky Historical Society shall be located in the Thomas D. Clark Center for Kentucky History, and the society shall control in all respects the manner in which the grounds surrounding the center, the building, and the space therein, shall be used. The society shall exercise the same control over the Old State Capitol Building, and the society shall use the Old State Capitol Building for purposes of the society as it shall deem necessary and proper. The grounds around the Old State Capitol Building and its annex, the grounds being now bounded by Broadway, Clinton, and Lewis Streets, and adjoining the federal property occupied by the John C. Watts Building, shall be subject to the control of the society and be used by the society, for purposes of the society as it shall deem necessary and proper. Major alterations or other changes concerning the building, annex, or grounds shall be made under the authority of the governing board of the Kentucky Historical Society and under the general supervision of the executive director who shall determine the nature and extent of any work to be done so as to protect the architectural integrity of the original structures. The maintenance and security of the building, annex, and grounds shall be the responsibility of the Finance and Administration Cabinet and shall be of highest priority among the other responsibilities of the state for capital construction, maintenance, or security. At the direction of the governing board, the executive director of the society may request the Finance and Administration Cabinet to perform, or cause to be performed, any work he deems necessary for the proper preservation and protection of the properties. The work shall either be undertaken within no less than sixty (60) days from the date of notification to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or the secretary of the cabinet shall show cause, in writing, to the governing board and the executive director why such work was not undertaken. </section><section prefix="2">No part of, or interest in, the real property hereinabove specified shall be leased, sold, or otherwise disposed of under any circumstances. The real property, including the building interiors, shall be maintained and preserved in a manner consistent with the best interests of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>