<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74">WATER DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>74.190</section_number><catch_line>Collection of unpaid installments -- Sale of land -- Redemption -- Settlement with collecting officers -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the first Monday after an installment is due, the commission shall meet and ascertain the parties whose installments are in default and shall within sixty (60) days issue warrants directing the sheriff or other collecting officer to collect the installments that are in default. The collecting officer shall collect the installments, with interest due on them and deferred installments, together with a penalty of six percent (6%), in the same way state and county taxes are collected, and the collecting officer shall settle with the commission within sixty (60) days from the time the installments were certified to him. </section><section prefix="2">All lands upon which the installments have not been collected at the end of sixty (60) days shall be advertised and sold by the collecting officer in the same manner as in the case of state and county taxes. The sale so made shall be subject to the future installments of the assessments, and at the expiration of ninety (90) days from the date of the original certification of the installments to the collecting officer, the collecting officer shall make final settlement with the commission and pay to them all the moneys in his hands. If the collecting officer fails to make a settlement, the commission may compel him to make the settlement by order against him issued by the district court, after giving him five (5) days' notice in writing. In case any land is not purchased at the sale, the collecting officer shall bid in the land for the district and in his final settlement with the commission shall take credit therefor. The collecting officer shall certify each of the sales to the county clerk as required in the sale of lands for state and county taxes, and the clerk shall record each sale in a book kept by him. For collecting the assessments certified to him the collecting officer shall be paid by the water commission the same fees allowed him for collecting state and county taxes and in the same manner. For recording the certificate of sale the clerk shall be allowed and paid the same fees allowed him by law for similar work in reference to state and county taxes. </section><section prefix="3">The owner of such real estate, or his representatives, heirs or assigns, shall have the right to redeem the land from the sale as is provided for the redemption of lands sold for state and county taxes, but only upon the same terms and conditions and within the same time as allowed in such case. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 187, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 65, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 938g-13. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24385</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>