<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.863</section_number><catch_line>Recommendations and annual report of commission.   </catch_line><order_by>863</order_by><text>In addition to the report required in KRS 260.853, the commission shall report to the Governor and to the Legislative Research Commission with respect to industrial hemp policies and practices that will result in the proper legal growing, management, use, and marketing of the state's potential industrial hemp industry. These policies and practices shall, at a minimum, address the following: <section prefix="1">Federal laws and regulatory constraints; </section><section prefix="2">The economic and financial feasibility of an industrial hemp market in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">Kentucky businesses that utilize industrial hemp; </section><section prefix="4">Examination of research on industrial hemp production and utilization; </section><section prefix="5">The potential for globally marketing Kentucky industrial hemp; </section><section prefix="6">Feasibility study of private funding for the Kentucky industrial hemp research program; </section><section prefix="7">Law enforcement concerns; </section><section prefix="8">Statutory and regulatory schemes for growing of industrial hemp by private producers; and </section><section prefix="9">Technical support and education about industrial hemp. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 7, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>