<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.073</section_number><catch_line>Commercial trailer temporary registration placard -- Application process -- Uses -- Record of use -- Activation. </catch_line><order_by>073</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section, "semitrailer" and "trailer" shall have the same meaning as established in KRS 186.650. </section><section prefix="2">Any manufacturer, dealer, or distributor engaged in the business of manufacturing, selling, or customizing commercial semitrailers or commercial trailers may obtain a commercial trailer temporary registration placard from the Department of Vehicle Regulation. The fee for each placard shall be five dollars ($5) per placard and each applicant shall specify the number of placards to be issued. A company may make additional requests for temporary placards at any time it exhausts the placards supplied by the department. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner shall prescribe the application form for the commercial trailer temporary registration placard, require each applicant to submit proof of eligibility to receive the placard, and certify that the applicant has need of the placard in the ordinary course of business, and may request other information as part of the application process. </section><section prefix="4">The commercial trailer temporary registration placard shall be placed on a semitrailer or trailer in the same manner as a regular trailer license plate. The temporary placard shall be issued if a permanent registration issued pursuant to KRS 186.655 cannot be obtained. </section><section prefix="5">The use of a commercial trailer temporary registration placard shall be limited to the following activities: <section prefix="a">A demonstration of the semitrailer or trailer to a prospective purchaser; </section><section prefix="b">The transportation of the semitrailer or trailer to a facility engaged in the customizing of a motor vehicle for eventual use on the highway; </section><section prefix="c">The transportation of the semitrailer or trailer to a trade show or other activity designed to promote the selling of the product; </section><section prefix="d">The transportation of the semitrailer or trailer by a purchaser to a location outside Kentucky, provided that the semitrailer or trailer is not eligible to be registered in Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="e">Transportation of a trailer or semitrailer from the manufacturer to a place of business in Kentucky in order to obtain a permanent registration issued pursuant to KRS 186.655. </section></section><section prefix="6">Each manufacturer, dealer, or distributor receiving the temporary placards shall maintain a record of use for each temporary placard to include the following: <section prefix="a">The make and model of each semitrailer or trailer and the vehicle identification number or other identification number of each vehicle on which a placard is used; </section><section prefix="b">The date the placard was issued and the registration number of the placard; and </section><section prefix="c">The address of the final destination and reason for movement of the semitrailer or trailer receiving the temporary placard. </section></section><section prefix="7">A commercial trailer temporary registration placard shall not be activated until it is placed upon the semitrailer or trailer and used in a manner as authorized by subsection (5) of this section. The commercial trailer temporary registration placard shall expire thirty (30) days after it is activated and placed in use on a semitrailer or trailer and shall be designed in a manner that an expiration date shall be noted clearly on the face of the placard. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  While the lead-in language for this statute in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 2 provided that "A NEW SECTION OF KRS 186 (sic) IS AMENDED TO READ AS FOLLOWS:" it is clear that a new statute was actually being created and the Reviser of Statutes has codified it as such to effectuate that intent. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5950</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>