<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.560</section_number><catch_line>Assistance to urban renewal by communities and other public bodies. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text>Any community or other public body is hereby authorized (without limiting any provision in the preceding section) to do any and all things necessary to aid and cooperate in the planning and undertaking of an urban renewal project in the area in which such community or public body is authorized to act, including the furnishing of such financial and other assistance as the community or public body is authorized by KRS 99.330 to 99.510 to furnish for or in connection with a redevelopment plan or redevelopment project. An agency is hereby authorized to delegate to a community or other public body any of the powers or functions of the agency with respect to the planning or undertaking of an urban renewal project in the area in which such community or public body is authorized to act, and such community or public body is hereby authorized to carry out or perform such powers or functions for the agency. Any public body is hereby authorized to enter into agreements (which may extend over any period, notwithstanding any provision or rule of law to the contrary) with any other public body or bodies respecting action to be taken pursuant to any of the powers granted by KRS 99.330 to 99.510 and KRS 99.520 to 99.590, including the furnishing of funds or other assistance in connection with an urban renewal plan or urban renewal project.  </text><history>Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 15, effective February 28, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>February 28, 1956</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26557</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>