<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.605</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text>As used in KRS 15.610 to 15.635 unless the context requires otherwise:  <section prefix="1">"Inspection" means any regular, on-site investigation periodically conducted, or any request for information periodically solicited in lieu of an on-site investigation, by or on behalf of any public agency for the purpose of determining whether to award, renew, alter, suspend or revoke a license, permit, accreditation or rating of a public or private organization, or of any property employed by a public or private organization in conducting its business, in the Commonwealth. The term shall not include inspections conducted by or on behalf of an urban-county department of health or special investigations conducted by law enforcement officers or grand juries, or, upon specific complaint, by public agencies with competent jurisdiction of the subject matter of the complaint, or by members of legislative bodies.  </section><section prefix="2">"Duplicative inspection" or "an inspection that duplicates" means one of two or more inspections that are conducted at different times during the same calendar year and that inquire into the same condition of the premises of, or business conducted by, the same public or private organization.  </section><section prefix="3">"Inspecting agency" means any agency of the state government or of a political subdivision of the state, other than an urban-county department of health, that conducts inspections within the Commonwealth.  </section><section prefix="4">"Conflicting standard" or "a standard that conflicts" means one of two or more standards relating to the quality of a public or private organization, or of the business conducted by such organization, or of property used by such organization in conducting its business, that are employed in the same inspection or in duplicative inspections and which cannot be met simultaneously.  </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1,, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=976</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>