<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.356</section_number><catch_line>Operation of emergency system for advanced registration of volunteer health practitioners -- Relationship between Cabinet for Health and Family Services and other organizations -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>356</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall operate the emergency system for advanced registration of volunteer health practitioners. The system shall: <section prefix="a">Accept applications for the registration of volunteer health practitioners before or during an emergency; </section><section prefix="b">Include information about the licensure and good standing of health practitioners that is accessible by authorized persons; and </section><section prefix="c">Be capable of confirming the accuracy of information concerning whether a health practitioner is licensed and in good standing before health services are provided under KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366. </section></section><section prefix="2">The following organizations may maintain a list consisting of trained and equipped emergency response, public health, and medical personnel: <section prefix="a">Local units formed under Section 300hh of Title 42 of the United States Code; </section><section prefix="b">Disaster relief organizations; </section><section prefix="c">Licensing boards; </section><section prefix="d">National or regional associations of licensing boards of health practitioners; </section><section prefix="e">Health facilities that provide comprehensive inpatient and outpatient health-care services, including a tertiary care and teaching hospital; or </section><section prefix="f">Governmental entities. </section></section><section prefix="3">The organizations listed in subsection (2) of this section shall develop a collaborative relationship with the cabinet for the purposes of KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366 and for the purposes of being recognized by the cabinet as a voluntary response resource. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and any other public or private funds to establish or maintain the registration system established in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">While an emergency declaration is in effect, representatives of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or a host entity may confirm whether volunteer health practitioners utilized in this state are registered with the registration system that complies with subsection (1) of this section. Confirmation is limited to obtaining identities of the practitioners from the system and determining whether the system indicates that the practitioners are licensed and in good standing. </section><section prefix="6">Upon request of a person in this state authorized under subsection (2) of this section, or a similarly authorized person in another state, a registration system located in this state shall notify the person of the identities of volunteer health practitioners and whether the practitioners are licensed and in good standing. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>  (6/26/2007) 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96 (2007 House Bill 287) "established" KRS Chapter 39G and created new sections thereof. However, at the time that House Bill 287 was enacted another KRS Chapter 39G was already in existence. The Reviser of Statutes determined that the newly created sections would be more appropriately placed in KRS Chapter 39A and has placed Sections 1 to 9 of Acts ch. 96 within KRS Chapter 39A, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21731</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>