<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.060</section_number><catch_line>Improper use of physical force in self-protection. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 503.050, the use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is not justifiable when: <section prefix="1">The defendant is resisting an arrest by a peace officer, recognized to be acting under color of official authority and using no more force than reasonably necessary to effect the arrest, although the arrest is unlawful; or </section><section prefix="2">The defendant, with the intention of causing death or serious physical injury to the other person, provokes the use of physical force by such other person; or </section><section prefix="3">The defendant was the initial aggressor, except that his use of physical force upon the other person under this circumstance is justifiable when: <section prefix="a">His initial physical force was nondeadly and the force returned by the other is such that he believes himself to be in imminent danger of death or serious physical injury; or </section><section prefix="b">He withdraws from the encounter and effectively communicates to the other person his intent to do so and the latter nevertheless continues or threatens the use of unlawful physical force. </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 31, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>