<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3">GRANTS TO UNITED STATES OF LANDS AND RIGHTS TO ACQUIRE </unit></structure><section_number>3.070</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction of land for Mammoth Cave National Park ceded. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The United States is authorized to acquire, pursuant to the provisions of this section, as well as in pursuance to KRS 148.111, 148.121, 148.141 and 148.151, the lands, including the caves and caverns underlying the same, within the area hereinafter referred to, as well as any lands contiguous or adjacent thereto which may hereafter be duly authorized for acquisition for national park purposes, for the purpose of converting same into, and for the establishment and maintenance thereon of, a national park as contemplated and provided for by the Act of Congress entitled "An Act to provide for the establishment of the Mammoth Cave National Park in the State of Kentucky, and for other purposes," approved May 25, 1926 (44 Stat. 635), and any amendments thereto. The lands, consisting of approximately 70,618 acres, are situated in the counties of Edmonson, Barren and Hart, in Kentucky. The general boundaries thereof are set forth in the report of the Southern Appalachian National Park Commission to the Secretary of the Interior, under the date of April 8, 1926. </section><section prefix="2">The jurisdiction of Kentucky is ceded to the United States over, within and under all the territory so acquired by the United States. Kentucky reserves the right to tax sales of gasoline and other motor conveyance fuels and oils for use in motor conveyances, except to the extent that such gasoline and other fuels and oils are used by the United States and its agents in the administration, protection, improvement, maintenance, development and operation of the land, and the right to tax persons, their franchises and properties, on the land so acquired. Persons residing on the land shall have the right to vote at all elections within the respective counties of their residence the same as if the land had not been acquired by the United States. Jurisdiction shall not vest in the United States until the United States, through the Secretary of the Interior, notifies the Governor of Kentucky that the United States assumes police jurisdiction over the land so acquired. </section></text><history>Amended 1966, ch. 255, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1966. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766e-16 to 3766e-18. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1966</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=89</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>