<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="306" order_by="306">HOTELS </unit></structure><section_number>306.020</section_number><catch_line>Limited liability when safe is provided. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The proprietor of any hotel may provide a safe in a convenient place, for the safekeeping of money, jewelry, furs, securities or other valuable papers or other valuable property of small compass belonging to the guests, and post a copy of this section in a public and conspicuous place and manner in the office, public rooms and public parlors of the hotel, notifying the guests that a safe is provided in which such property may be deposited. Then, if the guests neglect to deliver such property to the person in charge of the office for deposit in the safe, the proprietor shall not be liable for any loss of such property sustained by the guests by negligence of the proprietor or hotel employees, or by fire, theft, burglary or any other cause. </section><section prefix="2">However, no proprietor of any hotel shall be obligated to receive property on deposit for safekeeping exceeding three hundred dollars ($300) in value. If guests deliver property of a greater value to the person in charge of the office for deposit in the safe, the proprietor shall not be liable for the loss or damage thereof sustained in any sum exceeding three hundred dollars ($300), notwithstanding the property may be of greater value, unless the guests make a special agreement in writing with the proprietor. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2176a. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30304</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>