<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17B-023</section_number><catch_line>Duties of GAP participating insurer and department to report and to provide information -- Payment of GAP losses -- Examination of insurers to determine accuracy of information provided. </catch_line><order_by>17B-023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After the end of each calendar year, a GAP participating insurer shall report the following information for the previous calendar year: <section prefix="a">The total earned premium in the individual, small group, large group, and association markets; </section><section prefix="b">The number of GAP policies in force as of December 31; </section><section prefix="c">The amount of the insurer's GAP premiums received during the calendar year covered by the report; </section><section prefix="d">The amount of the insurer's GAP claims paid during the calendar year covered by the report; </section><section prefix="e">The amount of the insurer's GAP losses; and </section><section prefix="f">Other information as the department may require to be reported. </section></section><section prefix="2">After the end of each calendar year, and based upon the reports filed under subsection (1) of this section, the department shall calculate and provide to each insurer who filed a report the following information relating to the calendar year: <section prefix="a">The amount of each reporting insurer's market share; </section><section prefix="b">The total amount of GAP premiums for all reporting insurers; </section><section prefix="c">The total amount of GAP claims paid by all reporting insurers; </section><section prefix="d">The amount of total actual GAP losses; </section><section prefix="e">The amount of the insurer's assessment or refund; and </section><section prefix="f">Other information as the department may elect to calculate and report. </section></section> The department shall complete its calculation and provide each insurer the results of its calculation within sixty (60) days after receiving all required information. <section prefix="3">The department shall pay GAP losses to GAP participating insurers in accordance with this section and KRS 304.17B-021(5). </section><section prefix="4">The department shall conduct examinations of insurers participating in Kentucky Access as are reasonably necessary to determine if the information provided by the insurers is accurate. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1284, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29396</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>