<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-087</section_number><catch_line>Definition -- Submission of vehicle identification numbers and names of policyholders to Department of Vehicle Regulation -- Limitation of liability. </catch_line><order_by>39-087</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise, "personal motor vehicle" means: <section prefix="a">A private passenger motor vehicle that is not used as a public or livery conveyance for passengers, nor rented to others; and </section><section prefix="b">Any other four-wheel motor vehicle that weighs six thousand (6,000) pounds or less which is not used in the occupation, profession, or business of the insured. </section></section><section prefix="2">Beginning January 1, 2006, every insurance company that writes liability insurance on personal motor vehicles in Kentucky shall, between the first and fifteenth day of each month, send to the Department of Vehicle Regulation a list of the vehicle identification numbers (VINs) of each personal motor vehicle covered by liability insurance issued by the insurer as of the last day of the preceding month and the name of each personal motor vehicle insurance policyholder. The information shall be submitted either electronically or by paper copy at the option of the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="3">In the absence of malice, fraud, or gross negligence, any insurer and any authorized employee of an insurer shall not be subject to civil liability for libel, slander, or any other relevant tort, and no civil cause of action of any nature shall arise against the insurer or authorized employee, for submission of the information required by subsection (2) of this section, including submission of inaccurate or incomplete information. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30035</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>