<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Individual with an intellectual disability" means a person with significantly subaverage general intellectual functioning existing concurrently with deficits in adaptive behavior and manifested during the developmental period. </section><section prefix="2">"Mental illness" means a diagnostic term that covers many clinical categories, typically including behavioral or psychological symptoms, or both, along with impairment of personal and social function, and specifically defined and clinically interpreted through reference to criteria contained in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (Third Edition) and any subsequent revision thereto, of the American Psychiatric Association. </section><section prefix="3">"Chronic" means that clinically significant symptoms of mental illness have persisted in the individual for a continuous period of at least two (2) years, or that the individual has been hospitalized for mental illness more than once in the last two (2) years, and that the individual is presently significantly impaired in his ability to function socially or occupationally, or both. </section><section prefix="4">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="5">"Deaf or hard-of-hearing" means having a hearing impairment so that a person cannot hear and understand speech clearly through the ear alone, irrespective of the use of any hearing aid device. </section><section prefix="6">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 67, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 298, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 243, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 23. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 43. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. XI, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40795</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>