<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.080</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of the board. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall administer, coordinate, and enforce the provisions of this chapter, evaluate the qualifications of applicants, supervise the examination of applicants, and may issue subpoenas, examine witnesses, and administer oaths, and shall investigate persons engaging in practices which violate the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall conduct administrative hearings in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. Any person aggrieved by a final order of the board may appeal to Franklin Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall keep records and minutes as necessary and shall promulgate responsible administrative regulations, including but not limited to, administrative regulations which delineate qualifications for licensure and renewal of licensure and which establish ethical standards of practice, and may amend or repeal the same. </section><section prefix="4">Every person who holds a license to practice speech-language pathology or audiology in this state shall be governed and controlled by the rules of professional conduct adopted by the board. </section><section prefix="5">The conferral or enumeration of specific powers elsewhere in this chapter shall not be construed as a limitation of the general powers conferred by this section. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall fix appropriate and reasonable fees for licensing, and shall periodically review and modify these fees as necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 307, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31899</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>