<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.133</section_number><catch_line>Exemption from prosecution for possession of controlled substance or drug paraphernalia if seeking assistance with drug overdose. </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Drug overdose" means an acute condition of physical illness, coma, mania, hysteria, seizure, cardiac arrest, cessation of breathing, or death which reasonably appears to be the result of consumption or use of a controlled substance, or another substance with which a controlled substance was combined, and that a layperson would reasonably believe requires medical assistance; and </section><section prefix="b">"Good faith" does not include seeking medical assistance during the course of the execution of an arrest warrant, or search warrant, or a lawful search. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person shall not be charged with or prosecuted for a criminal offense prohibiting the possession of a controlled substance or the possession of drug paraphernalia if: <section prefix="a">In good faith, medical assistance with a drug overdose is sought from a public safety answering point, emergency medical services, a law enforcement officer, or a health practitioner because the person: <section prefix="1">Requests emergency medical assistance for himself or herself or another person; </section><section prefix="2">Acts in concert with another person who requests emergency medical assistance; or </section><section prefix="3">Appears to be in need of emergency medical assistance and is the individual for whom the request was made; </section></section><section prefix="b">The person remains with, or is, the individual who appears to be experiencing a drug overdose until the requested assistance is provided; and </section><section prefix="c">The evidence for the charge or prosecution is obtained as a result of the drug overdose and the need for medical assistance. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of subsection (2) of this section shall not extend to the investigation and prosecution of any other crimes committed by a person who otherwise qualifies under this section. </section><section prefix="4">When contact information is available for the person who requested emergency medical assistance, it shall be reported to the local health department. Health department personnel shall make contact with the person who requested emergency medical assistance in order to offer referrals regarding substance abuse treatment, if appropriate. </section><section prefix="5">A law enforcement officer who makes an arrest in contravention of this section shall not be criminally or civilly liable for false arrest or false imprisonment if the arrest was based on probable cause. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 11, effective March 25, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44007</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>