<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.48-210</section_number><catch_line>Motor vehicle liability -- Compliance with KRS 304.39-080(7) -- Statement in application for a certificate of filing. </catch_line><order_by>48-210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the liability self-insurance group is formed by governmental entities and coverage is provided for motor vehicle liability, the group is not required to comply with administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (7) of KRS 304.39-080, unless its members elect to become obligated governments for the payment of basic reparation benefits or are required by law to provide basic reparation benefits, in which case the group shall provide the security required by administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (7) of KRS 304.39-080. </section><section prefix="2">If a liability self-insurance group formed by entities other than governmental entities chooses to provide coverage for motor vehicle liability and basic reparation benefits, its application shall be analyzed under both this subsection and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (7) of KRS 304.39-080 and the authority to self-insure motor vehicle liability and basic reparation benefits coverages shall not be granted unless the group complies with this subsection and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (7) of KRS 304.39-080. </section><section prefix="3">All applications for a certificate of filing shall state whether motor vehicle liability or basic reparation benefits coverages are to be covered by the group. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30212</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>