<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152">ENERGY DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>152.715</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 152.710 to 152.720.   </catch_line><order_by>715</order_by><text>As used in KRS 152.710 to 152.720, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Alternative transportation fuels" means: <section prefix="a">Before August 1, 2010, crude oil or transportation fuels produced by processes that: <section prefix="1">Convert coal, waste coal, or biomass resources; or </section><section prefix="2">Extract oil from oil shale or tar sands; </section></section> to produce crude oil or fuels for powering vehicles, aircraft, and machinery; and <section prefix="b">On or after August 1, 2010: <section prefix="1">Crude oil or transportation fuels produced by processes that: <section prefix="a">Convert coal, waste coal, or biomass resources; or </section><section prefix="b">Extract oil from oil shale or tar sands; </section></section> to produce crude oil or fuels for powering vehicles, aircraft, and machinery; <section prefix="2">Liquefied or compressed natural gas produced for use as a transportation fuel; or </section><section prefix="3">Liquefied petroleum gas produced from natural gas, natural gas liquids, or petroleum for use as a transportation fuel. </section></section></section> "Alternative transportation fuels" may include but are not limited to natural gas, petroleum, jet fuel, gasoline, diesel fuel, hydrogen derived from coal, and diesel fuel and ethanol derived from biomass; <section prefix="2">"Synthetic natural gas" means pipeline quality or industrial quality natural gas produced from coal through gasification processes; </section><section prefix="3">"Fossil energy resources" means reserves of coal, oil shale, and natural gas; and </section><section prefix="4">"Biomass resources" means any organic matter that is available on a renewable or recurring basis, including agricultural crops and trees; wood and wood residues; plants, aquatic plants, and plant oils; grasses; animal fats and animal by-products; animal manure; residue materials; and waste products. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 187, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 139, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 100, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 38, effective August 30, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42404</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>