<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-238</section_number><catch_line>Timetables for investments and credit award approval -- Web site reports. </catch_line><order_by>20-238</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No later than the earlier of: <section prefix="a">Sixty (60) days following the date of credit approval, including weekends and holidays; or </section><section prefix="b">December 31 of the calendar year of the approval; </section></section> the qualified investor shall make the qualified investment. Within twenty (20) days of making the qualified investment, including weekends and holidays, the qualified investor shall provide proof of the qualified investment to the authority in the manner required by the authority. <section prefix="2">No later than sixty (60) days following the receipt of proof of the qualified investment, the authority shall notify the department of the credit award, the amount of the credit, and the name and Social Security number of the qualified investor that will receive the credit. </section><section prefix="3">If the qualified investor either fails to make the qualified investment prior to the deadline or fails to provide the required proof of the qualified investment, the award of credit approval shall be null and void, and the authority shall notify the qualified investor of the nullification and readjust the amount of credit available. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The authority shall maintain a publicly available Web site on which it shall report: <section prefix="1">A list of all qualified small businesses and qualified investors it has certified; </section><section prefix="2">The total amount of credit it has awarded; and </section><section prefix="3">The total amount of available credit remaining. </section></section><section prefix="b">This report shall be updated as new small businesses and investors are certified, and as new credits are awarded or the amount of available credit is otherwise adjusted. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 25, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>