<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.247</section_number><catch_line>Victim, witness, and family protection program -- Protective services. </catch_line><order_by>247</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General shall develop and administer a program for the protection of crime victims and witnesses and their immediate families. </section><section prefix="2">Within the limits of the administrative regulations, guidelines, and appropriations for this purpose, the program shall provide funding to the Department of Kentucky State Police or to a sheriff's office or city or county police department agreeing to provide protection to crime victims and witnesses and their families. </section><section prefix="3">Any Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney may apply to the Attorney General for funding for protection of crime victims, witnesses, and their families. </section><section prefix="4">No protective service shall be rendered to the same person for more than six (6) months. </section><section prefix="5">Protective services funded by this program shall be limited to: <section prefix="a">Physical protection of the person; </section><section prefix="b">Physical security measures for the person's residence, vehicle, workplace, or combination thereof; or </section><section prefix="c">Short-term relocation. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Attorney General shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A for the operation of the program. </section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this statute shall be construed to create a cause of action for money damages against the state, a county, a municipality, or any of their agencies, public officials, or employees. </section><section prefix="8">No court shall order a law enforcement agency to protect crime victim witnesses or their immediate families. </section><section prefix="9">No record that may lead to the identity of a person seeking or given protection under this section shall be an open record. This protection shall extend even to the question of whether such a record exists. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 15, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=912</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>