<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.330</section_number><catch_line>Endow Kentucky Commission -- Duties -- Membership -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Endow Kentucky Commission, which shall be responsible for the planning, implementation, and direction of a strategic and collaborative philanthropic partnership to focus on building endowment funds that will address community needs through community foundations. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall be attached to the Department for Local Government for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="3">The duties of the commission shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Explore opportunities for funding for the community endowment fund established by KRS 147A.315; </section><section prefix="b">Consult and advise the Governor and the agencies, departments, boards, and commissions of the Commonwealth, as well as local governments, on matters pertaining to philanthropy; </section><section prefix="c">Provide technical assistance to qualified community foundations and affiliate community foundations; and </section><section prefix="d">Review and certify community foundations pursuant to KRS 147A.325. </section></section><section prefix="4">The membership of the commission shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) citizen member engaged in private rural development philanthropy, or who represents private rural development philanthropic interests, to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative of each community foundation that is organized or operating in the Commonwealth and in compliance with the national standards for community foundations established by the National Council on Foundations, to be appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative from the area development districts appointed by the Governor from a list of names submitted by the executive directors of the area development districts. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Governor shall appoint members for a term of two (2) years, and any member may be reappointed. The members shall designate the chair of the commission from among the membership. </section><section prefix="6">Members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for their actual expenses incurred in the performance of commission duties in accordance with KRS 45.101 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall meet upon the call of the chair, but not less than twice each year. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Governor's Office for Local Development" in subsection (2) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, has been changed in codification to the "Department for Local Government" to reflect the renaming of that agency in Executive Order 2009-540, which was confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 90. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>