<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.470</section_number><catch_line>Preference to be given by governmental bodies and political subdivisions in purchasing commodities or services -- List of commodities and services -- Price range -- Negotiation for identical products and services. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any provision of this chapter to the contrary, all governmental bodies and political subdivisions of this state shall, when purchasing commodities or services, give first preference to the products made by the Department of Corrections, Division of Prison Industries, as required by KRS 197.210. Second preference shall be given to any products produced by Kentucky Industries for the Blind, Incorporated, or any other nonprofit corporation that furthers the purposes of KRS Chapter 163, and agencies of individuals with severe disabilities as described in KRS 45A.465. </section><section prefix="2">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall make a list of commodities and services provided by these agencies and organizations available to all governmental bodies and political subdivisions. The list shall identify in detail the commodity or service the agency or organization may supply and the price. </section><section prefix="3">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall annually determine the current price range for the commodities and services offered from its experience in purchasing these commodities or services on the open market. The prices quoted by these agencies or organizations shall not exceed the current price range. </section><section prefix="4">The Office for the Blind within the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet and qualified agencies for individuals with severe disabilities shall annually cause to be made available to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, lists of the products or services available. </section><section prefix="5">If two (2) or more of the agencies or qualified nonprofit organizations wish to supply identical commodities or services, the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall conduct negotiations with the parties to determine which shall be awarded the contract. The decision of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall be based upon quality of the commodity or service and the ability of the respective agencies to supply the commodity or service within the requested delivery time. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 24, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 209, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 405, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22428</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>