<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.041</section_number><catch_line>Adult education and literacy initiative fund. </catch_line><order_by>041</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created in the Council on Postsecondary Education, a special fund to be known as the adult education and literacy initiative fund, which shall consist of moneys appropriated by the General Assembly, gifts, grants, other sources of funding, public and private, and interest accrued by the fund. This fund shall not lapse at the end of a fiscal year but shall be carried forward to be used only for the purposes specified in this section. Moneys accumulated in this fund on July 14, 2000, shall remain in the fund and be transferred to the Council on Postsecondary Education to be used for purposes stated in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the adult education and literacy initiative fund shall be to support strategies for adult education, to provide statewide initiatives for excellence, and to provide funds for research and development activities. </section><section prefix="3">The council, in collaboration with the Kentucky Adult Education Program, shall establish the guidelines for the use, distribution, and administration of the fund, financial incentives, technical assistance, and other support for strategic planning; and guidelines for fiscal agents to assess county and area needs and to develop strategies to meet those needs. </section><section prefix="4">The fund shall include the following strategies: <section prefix="a">Statewide initiatives. Funds shall be used to encourage collaboration with other organizations, stimulate development of models of adult education programs that may be replicated elsewhere in the state, provide incentives for adults, employers, and providers to encourage adults to establish and accomplish learning contracts, provide incentives to encourage participation in adult education, assist providers of county and area programs in areas of highest need, and for other initiatives of regional or statewide significance as determined by the council. The Collaborative Center for Literacy Development: Early Childhood through Adulthood created under KRS 164.0207 shall evaluate the reading and literacy components of model programs funded under this paragraph. </section><section prefix="b">Research and demonstration. The funds shall be used to develop: <section prefix="1">Standards for the preparation, professional development, and support for adult educators with the advice of the Kentucky Adult Education Program and as compatible with funds provided under Title II of the Federal Workforce Investment Act; </section><section prefix="2">A statewide competency-based certification for transferable skills in the workplace; and </section><section prefix="3">A statewide public information and marketing campaign. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 104, effective July 12, 2006. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 164.041, 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 150, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification>KRS 151B.142</former-codification><lrc-note>(7/7/97).  Although designated to be created as a new section of KRS Chapter 164 by 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 150, this statute has been codified into KRS Chapter 151B under KRS 7.136(1)(a) and (h) because its subject matter clearly belongs within that chapter. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4194</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>