<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.847</section_number><catch_line>Science and mathematics advancement fund -- Purposes -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>847</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The science and mathematics advancement fund is hereby created to provide incentives for public schools to provide or expand student access to rigorous science and mathematics curricula, to make available advanced science and mathematics courses and college credit in these disciplines for high school students, and to increase the quantity and quality of science and mathematics teachers in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="b">Funds may be used in support of public schools to provide: <section prefix="1">Payment of student fees for AP and IB examinations; </section><section prefix="2">Scholarships for high school students to take advanced science and mathematics courses through the Kentucky Virtual High School when those courses are not offered at the school in which they are enrolled; </section><section prefix="3">Two (2) year grants to high schools to support the start-up of advanced science and mathematics courses; </section><section prefix="4">Two (2) year renewable grants to middle schools to support accelerated student learning in science and mathematics; </section><section prefix="5">Grants to school districts for programs to develop and implement an energy technology engineering career track; and </section><section prefix="6">Professional development opportunities, and payment of expenses and stipends for participation, for elementary school teachers to deepen their content knowledge and improve instructional practice in science and mathematics. </section></section><section prefix="c">The fund may receive state appropriations, grants, gifts, federal funds, or any other funds, public or private. </section><section prefix="d">Funds from the science and mathematics advancement fund shall be distributed after all other funds available for these purposes have been obligated, including state funds, federal funds, or any funds available through a scholarship program administered by the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations for the administration of the science and mathematics advancement fund. The Kentucky Department of Education shall administer the fund, approve grant recipients, and distribute the funds to local school districts and other appropriate educational agencies. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered subsection (1) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 3, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3618</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>