<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.6066</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner to publicly announce rules, polling places, and details of assessment before referendum -- Notice to agricultural extension agents. </catch_line><order_by>6066</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With respect to any referendum conducted under KRS 247.6040 to 247.6070, the Commissioner shall publicly announce through the medium of the public press at least thirty (30) days before the date determined for the referendum, the following information: <section prefix="a">The rules and regulations with respect to the holding of the referendum; </section><section prefix="b">The area within which the referendum will be conducted; </section><section prefix="c">The date, hours, and polling places for voting in the referendum; </section><section prefix="d">The effective date of the assessment, if adopted; </section><section prefix="e">The basis of the assessment proposed to be collected; </section><section prefix="f">The means by which the assessment shall be collected if authorized by the growers; </section><section prefix="g">The general purposes to which any amount shall be applied; and </section><section prefix="h">How the proceeds from the assessment shall be administered. </section></section><section prefix="2">Direct written notice shall also be given to each county or area agricultural extension agent in any county covered by the referendum. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 14, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>