<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.072</section_number><catch_line>Economic hardship determinations for regulatory ordinances by a city with population of 3,000 to 7,999 -- Administrative regulations -- Exemption from population requirements.   </catch_line><order_by>072</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section shall apply to any wet city with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) but less than eight thousand (8,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census or county containing a wet city meeting the population requirements of this subsection, notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter relating to the sales of alcoholic beverages by the drink for consumption on the premises. </section><section prefix="2">Upon a determination by the legislative body that an economic hardship exists within the wet city or county and that the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink could aid economic growth, the legislative body may enact a comprehensive, regulatory ordinance covering the licensing and operation of hotels, motels, inns, or restaurants for the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink for consumption on the premises. </section><section prefix="3">Nonquota type 2 (NQ2) retail drink licenses authorizing all types of alcoholic beverage sales shall only be issued to hotels and restaurants having dining facilities for not less than fifty (50) persons. </section><section prefix="4">The city or county legislative body may provide for the issuance of any licenses permitted by KRS 243.060 or 243.070, or the issuance of any other reasonable administrative regulations as may be necessary for the enforcement or administration of this section, except that any administrative regulation adopted shall conform to the requirements of KRS 241.190. </section><section prefix="5">Any city or county enacting a comprehensive regulatory ordinance pursuant to this section prior to January 1, 2014, covering the licensing and operation of hotels, motels, inns, or restaurants for the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink for consumption on the premises is exempt from the application of the population requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 92, sec. 296, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 31, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 22 and 92, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43881</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>