<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-143</section_number><catch_line>Coverage for treatment of autism in the individual and small group market -- Limitation -- Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>17A-143</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All health benefit plans in the individual and small group market shall provide coverage, including pharmacy care, if covered by the plan, psychiatric care, psychological care, therapeutic care, applied behavior analysis, as defined in KRS 304.17A-141(1), habilitative and rehabilitative care, for the treatment of autism spectrum disorders, as defined in KRS 304.17A-141(3), of an individual covered under the policy. </section><section prefix="2">Coverage for autism spectrum disorders shall be subject to a one thousand dollar ($1,000) maximum benefit per month, per covered individual. This limit shall not apply to other health conditions of the individual and services for the individual not related to the treatment of an autism spectrum disorder. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section, "autism spectrum disorder" means a physical, mental, or cognitive illness or disorder which includes any of the pervasive developmental disorders as defined by the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders ("DSM"), published by the American Psychiatric Association, including Autistic disorder, Asperger's disorder, and Pervasive Developmental disorder Not Otherwise Specified. </section><section prefix="4">As used in this section, "individual" means a person one (1) through twenty-one (21) years of age. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 18, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998, as amended by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 585, sec. 2, effective April 14, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was created by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, which was subsequently amended by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 585, sec. 2. These two Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36740</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>