<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.475</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition of airport facilities by counties bordering state boundary. </catch_line><order_by>475</order_by><text>All counties in this state located on the boundary line between this state and any other state, or which are contiguous to such counties, as well as all governmental units which are located in such boundary counties, or contiguous counties, are hereby authorized, separately, jointly with each other or jointly with any other municipality or political subdivision of any such boundary state to acquire, equip, construct, expand, lease, improve, police and operate airports within this state or either within or without the geographical limits of any county, municipality or political subdivision of any such boundary state; and for those purposes to exercise any other powers or functions and be subject to any provisions provided by KRS Chapter 183 as to aviation, without regard to any express or implied limitations thereof to or within this state, including but not limited to those provided by KRS 183.010 through 183.012, "Definitions," KRS 183.132 through 183.138, "Local Air Boards," KRS 183.475 through 183.490, "Acquisition of Airport Facilities," KRS 183.630 through 183.740, "Bonds," KRS 183.762 through 183.772, "Airport Development," and any amendments or supplements thereto which may be provided therein subsequent to this amendment. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 138, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 4. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 20. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 30. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5783</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>