<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.1-750</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network -- Programs and services -- Report to Legislative Research Commission. </catch_line><order_by>1-750</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intention of the General Assembly to generate a substantial increase in the number of new and expanding small businesses in the Kentucky workforce, to foster economic growth in the business sector, and to provide high-quality jobs for Kentuckians. The Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network, part of the National Small Business Development Center Network, is encouraged to extend its wide range of workshops, seminars, and courses for entrepreneurs in cooperation with the public and private sector. Expert instruction shall range from introductory classes designed for start-up businesses to advanced presentations aimed at assisting established companies. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Expanded staff" means consultants to be used exclusively in the small business development centers. All new personnel in the field shall be fully dedicated to consulting and training, with the goal of increasing clients' revenues and job creation capabilities, as well as increasing Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network market penetration by twenty-five percent (25%) over the two (2) year appropriation. </section><section prefix="b">"Expanded equipment" means support for these consultants and includes computers and printers, fax machines, and copiers. </section><section prefix="c">"Expanded operation" means support for new personnel and includes office furniture, phone and fax expenses, and travel costs for consultants. </section><section prefix="d">"Expanded professional development" means the training to ensure that Kentucky small business development center consultants have up-to-date knowledge and information to positively impact new and existing small businesses. </section></section><section prefix="3">Expanded staff, expanded equipment, expanded operation, and expanded professional development shall be used to assist the Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network to increase entrepreneurial training and consulting services, with the goal of increasing the center's impact upon Kentucky's economy. </section><section prefix="4">Entrepreneurial training topics include, but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Starting a business; </section><section prefix="b">Business plan preparation; </section><section prefix="c">Marketing, including advertising and public relations; </section><section prefix="d">Financial analysis; </section><section prefix="e">Tax regulation; </section><section prefix="f">Human resource management; </section><section prefix="g">Capital management; </section><section prefix="h">Global readiness; </section><section prefix="i">Marketing plan preparation; </section><section prefix="j">Young entrepreneurship; </section><section prefix="k">Target market analysis; </section><section prefix="l">Quality management; and </section><section prefix="m">Production management. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network may solicit, accept, receive, invest, and expend moneys from any public or private source for the purpose of implementing this section. </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Small Business Development Center Network's central office shall present a written report to the Legislative Research Commission in November 1998, setting out its progress towards achieving the goals set out in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><former-codification>KRS 154.01-750. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41648</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>