<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="635" order_by="635">PUBLIC OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>635.510</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for classification as juvenile sexual offender -- Juvenile sexual offender assessment. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A child, thirteen (13) years of age or older at the time of the commission of the offense, shall be declared a juvenile sexual offender if the child has been adjudicated guilty of an offense listed in KRS 635.505(2)(a), (b), (c), (d), (e), or (f). </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A child, less than thirteen (13) years of age, may be declared a juvenile sexual offender if the child has been adjudicated guilty of an offense listed in KRS 635.505(2). </section><section prefix="b">Any child, thirteen (13) years of age or older, may be declared a juvenile sexual offender if the child has been adjudicated guilty of an offense listed in KRS 635.505(2)(g). </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon final adjudication by the juvenile court under subsection (2) of this section, the juvenile court judge shall order a juvenile sexual offender assessment to be conducted on the child by the Department of Juvenile Justice treatment program or by a qualified professional approved by the program which shall recommend whether the child be declared a sexual offender and receive sexual offender treatment. Upon receipt of the findings of the assessment, the juvenile court judge shall determine whether the child shall be declared a juvenile sexual offender, and, if so, shall initiate a referral to the Department of Juvenile Justice treatment program for treatment. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 54, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 538, sec. 15, effective April 13, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 62, effective July 15, 1997. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20300</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>