<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.025</section_number><catch_line>Levels of certification or licensure -- Administrative regulations -- Emergency services medical director. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall, subject to the provisions of this chapter, create levels of certification or licensure, as appropriate for individuals providing services under this chapter. These may consist of but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">First responder and first responder instructor; </section><section prefix="b">Emergency medical technician-basic, emergency medical technician-basic instructor, and emergency medical technician-basic instructor trainer; </section><section prefix="c">Paramedic, paramedic course coordinator, paramedic instructor, and paramedic preceptor; </section><section prefix="d">Emergency medical services medical director who supervises a person or organization licensed or certified by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Emergency medical service training institution; </section><section prefix="f">Emergency medical service testing agency; </section><section prefix="g">Ground ambulance service, including categories thereof; </section><section prefix="h">Air ambulance service; </section><section prefix="i">Medical first response provider; </section><section prefix="j">Emergency medical dispatcher, emergency medical dispatch instructor, and emergency medical dispatch instructor trainer; </section><section prefix="k">Emergency medical dispatch center or public safety answering point; and </section><section prefix="l">Any other entity authorized by this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations for any certification or license the board may create. The administrative regulations shall, at a minimum, address: <section prefix="a">Requirements for students, if appropriate; </section><section prefix="b">Requirements for training; </section><section prefix="c">Eligibility for certification or licensure; and </section><section prefix="d">Renewal, recertification, and relicensure requirements. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board may authorize a physician licensed to practice in Kentucky to serve as an emergency medical services medical director if that physician meets the requirements specified by the board by administrative regulation. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>