<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="104" order_by="104">FLOOD CONTROL AND WATER USAGE </unit></structure><section_number>104.490</section_number><catch_line>Contents of petition. </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text>The petition shall contain:  <section prefix="1">The proposed name of the district, which shall be "Flood Control District No. .... of .... County, (or counties), Kentucky."  </section><section prefix="2">The necessity for maintaining and operating any flood control works of the district and that such maintenance and operation will be conducive to the public health, safety, comfort, convenience or welfare.  </section><section prefix="3">A general description of the flood control works to be maintained and operated and of the territory to be included in the proposed district. The description need not be given by metes and bounds or by legal subdivision, but it shall be sufficient if a reasonably accurate description is given of the territory to be organized as a district by showing the boundaries of such district on a map or by other means. The territory may include one or more political subdivisions or portions thereof, and, except as provided in KRS 104.450 to 104.680, shall not be included wholly within the limits of a single municipality. The territory need not be contiguous if it is so situated that the public health, safety, comfort, convenience or welfare will be promoted by its organization as a single district.  </section><section prefix="4">A prayer for the organization of the district.  </section></text><history>Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 5. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27087</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>