<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.515</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall administer and enforce the provisions of KRS 335.500 to 335.599 and shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants for licensure. </section><section prefix="2">The board may issue subpoenas, examine witnesses, pay appropriate witness fees, administer oaths, and investigate allegations of practices violating the provisions of KRS 335.500 to 335.599. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A as necessary to carry out and enforce the provisions of KRS 335.500 to 335.599, including the establishment of fees. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall conduct hearings as necessary pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B and shall keep records and minutes necessary to carry out the function of KRS 335.500 to 335.599. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall issue credentials to qualified candidates. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall renew credentials subject to the provisions of KRS 335.535 and shall require ten (10) continuing education hours as a condition for renewal each year. </section><section prefix="7">The board may suspend or revoke credentials, impose supervisory or probationary conditions upon certificate holders, impose administrative disciplinary fines, issue written reprimands and admonishments, or perform any combination thereof. </section><section prefix="8">The board may seek injunctive relief in Franklin Circuit Court to enjoin violation of KRS 335.505(1). </section><section prefix="9">The board may grant retired status or inactive status to a credential holder under conditions set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="10">The board may employ persons as necessary to carry on its work and shall define those persons' duties and fix their compensation. </section><section prefix="11">The board shall promulgate by administrative regulation a code of ethics for and standards of practice for all credential holders. </section><section prefix="12">The board may enter into reciprocal agreements with certified or licensed professional counseling boards. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31959</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>