<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.100</section_number><catch_line>Small purchases by state governmental bodies. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Procurements may be made in accordance with small purchase administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, as follows: <section prefix="a">Up to ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per project for construction and one thousand dollars ($1,000) for purchases by any state governmental body, except for those state administrative bodies specified in paragraph (b) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="b">Up to forty thousand dollars ($40,000) per project for construction or purchases by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, state institutions of higher education, and the legislative branch of government. </section></section><section prefix="2">Procurement requirements shall not be artificially divided so as to constitute a small purchase under this section. Reverse auctions may be used for small purchase procurements. At least every two (2) years, the secretary shall review the prevailing costs of labor and materials and may make recommendations to the next regular session of the General Assembly for the revision of the then current maximum small purchase amount as justified by intervening changes in the cost of labor and materials. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet may grant to any state agency with a justifiable need a delegation of small purchasing authority which exceeds the agency's small purchase limit provided in subsection (1) of this section. Delegations of small purchasing authority shall be granted or revoked by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the cabinet pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. These administrative regulations shall establish, at a minimum, the criteria for granting and revoking delegations of small purchasing authority, including the requesting agency's past compliance with purchasing regulations, the level of training of the agency's purchasing staff, and the extent to which the agency utilizes the Kentucky Automated Purchasing System. The administrative regulations may permit the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet to delegate small purchase procurements up to the maximum amount specified in subsection (1)(b) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 323, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 250, sec. 19, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 21, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22346</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>