<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0554</section_number><catch_line>Request for exemption -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>0554</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a proposed precinct establishment order has been returned to the county board of elections under KRS 117.0553, and the county board of elections has determined that the noncompliance described by the executive director cannot be corrected by the establishment of a precinct that complies with the provisions of KRS 117.055 to 117.0552, the county board of elections may request the State Board of Elections to grant an exemption. </section><section prefix="2">The State Board of Elections shall conduct a hearing on the exemption request. If the State Board of Elections determines that the noncompliance described by the executive director cannot be corrected by the establishment of a precinct that complies with all provisions of KRS 117.055 to 117.0552, the board shall grant the exemption. </section><section prefix="3">If the State Board of Elections grants the exemption, the county board of elections shall amend the proposed precinct establishment order to establish precinct boundaries: <section prefix="a">In accordance with the exemption granted by the State Board of Elections; </section><section prefix="b">That comply with all other requirements established by KRS 117.055 to 117.0552; and </section><section prefix="c">That are precisely described in the order. </section></section><section prefix="4">The county board of elections shall submit the amended order to the State Board of Elections. If the State Board of Elections finds that the proposed order, as amended, complies with subsection (3) of this section, it shall approve the order. The order shall become effective upon its approval by the State Board of Elections unless the order contains a different effective date. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 5, effective July 14,1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>