<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-052</section_number><catch_line>Office of Occupations and Professions -- Services for boards and commissions -- Charges -- Complaints -- Acceptance of personal checks in payment of license renewal fees. </catch_line><order_by>10-052</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of Occupations and Professions in the Public Protection Cabinet shall provide administrative services, technical assistance, and advice to the following boards and commissions at the request of the individual boards or commissions, all of which maintain their identity and their full authority for making policy decisions in the fields that they regulate: the State Board of Accountancy, the Kentucky Board of Architects, the Kentucky Board of Barbering, the Kentucky Board of Hairdressers and Cosmetologists, the State Board of Podiatry, the Kentucky State Board of Chiropractic Examiners, the Kentucky Board of Dentistry, the State Board of Embalmers and Funeral Directors, the State Board of Registration for Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, the Kentucky Board of Ophthalmic Dispensers, the Kentucky Board of Optometric Examiners, the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy, the State Board of Physical Therapy, the State Board of Examiners of Psychologists, the Kentucky Real Estate Commission, the Kentucky Board of Veterinary Examiners, the Board of Auctioneers, the Kentucky Board of Landscape Architects, the State Board of Medical Licensure, the Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology, the Kentucky Board of Licensure for Nursing Home Administrators, the Kentucky Licensing Board for Specialists in Hearing Instruments, the Kentucky Board of Social Work, and such other boards and commissions as are created to license, certify, register, or otherwise regulate any occupational or professional category. </section><section prefix="2">The office may also provide administrative services to a board or commission that is created to license, certify, register, or otherwise regulate any occupational or professional category if these administrative services are deemed to be preferable or required after the review process conducted under KRS 224.10-053. </section><section prefix="3">To the extent that the office provides administrative services, the respective boards and commissions are relieved of the power and duty to provide the services for themselves. The office shall charge each board or commission a reasonable amount for administrative services provided pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. The office may employ persons previously employed by boards or commissions. </section><section prefix="4">The office may receive complaints against the conduct of licensees granted licensure by the boards and commissions assigned to the office for administrative purposes. The office shall cause such complaints to be reduced to writing and forwarded to the appropriate board or commission for investigation and a determination of the validity of the complaint. The office shall keep a record of all complaints received by it and forwarded to a board or commission. </section><section prefix="5">Any board or commission listed in subsection (1) of this section, shall accept personal checks in payment of license renewal fees. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 24, sec. 351, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, At. II, sec. 8. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. V, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Division of Occupations and Professions" in subsection (2) of this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, has been changed in codification to the "Office of Occupations and Professions" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938.  (6/25/2009). 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 16, proposed to repeal KRS 42.066 and reenact it as a new section of KRS Chapter 42. During codification, the Reviser of Statutes has instead created a new section of Subchapter 10 of KRS Chapter 224 (this statute) to conform with the context of the reorganization effected by 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><former-codification> KRS 42.066. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43369</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>