<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.728</section_number><catch_line>Preconstruction and construction reports -- Long-range planning document -- Execution of funded programs. </catch_line><order_by>728</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Beginning with the 2000-2002 biennium and each biennium thereafter, the authority shall submit to the General Assembly a six (6) year program of preconstruction and construction activities to maintain or increase water available within the Kentucky River. The program shall include a two (2) year construction component that shall be implemented as authorized by the General Assembly in the authority's biennial budget and a four (4) year preconstruction component that shall advise the General Assembly of the consistency of ongoing and long-term planning with the construction activities funded by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall be developed by considering, at a minimum, the following factors: <section prefix="a">The population to be served by the available water; </section><section prefix="b">The social, economic, and environmental impact of program elements; </section><section prefix="c">The condition of existing facilities critical to water availability; </section><section prefix="d">The cost of maintaining, improving, replacing, or removing facilities; and </section><section prefix="e">The dependence of communities within the river basin on specific Kentucky River dam pools or other sources of water. </section></section><section prefix="3">The program shall include a four (4) year planning document setting out preconstruction activities that include planning and design and an environmental analysis of projects to maintain or increase water available within the Kentucky River and geotechnical and stability evaluations of the Kentucky River locks and dams. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall provide to the General Assembly a long-range planning document consisting of twenty (20) years for water supply projects being considered by the authority. </section><section prefix="5">The authority shall be responsible for the execution of each six (6) year program as approved and authorized in the budget by the General Assembly and shall report any anticipated deviations from the authorized construction funding or preconstruction program to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 287, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  This section was created by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 287, which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2166</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>