<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.703</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for living units. </catch_line><order_by>703</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each living unit in an assisted-living community shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least two hundred (200) square feet for single occupancy, or for double occupancy if the room is shared with a spouse or another individual by mutual agreement; </section><section prefix="b">Include at least one (1) unfurnished room with a lockable door, private bathroom with a tub or shower, provisions for emergency response, window to the outdoors, and a telephone jack; </section><section prefix="c">Have an individual thermostat control if the assisted-living community has more than twenty (20) units; and </section><section prefix="d">Have temperatures that are not under a client's direct control at a minimum of seventy-one (71) degrees Fahrenheit in winter conditions and a maximum of eighty-one (81) degrees Fahrenheit in summer conditions if the assisted-living community has twenty (20) or fewer units. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each client shall be provided access to central dining, a laundry facility, and a central living room. </section><section prefix="3">Each assisted-living community shall comply with applicable building and life safety codes as determined by the building code or life safety code enforcement authority with jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>