<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="43" order_by="43">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS </unit></structure><section_number>43.080</section_number><catch_line>Access to books and records -- Power to obtain testimony. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Auditor and his authorized agents shall have access to and may examine all books, accounts, reports, vouchers, correspondence files, records, money and property of any state agency. Every officer or employee of any such agency having such records or property in his possession or under his control shall permit access to and examination of them upon the request of the Auditor or any agent authorized by him to make such request. </section><section prefix="2">The Auditor and his assistants shall have access at all times to the papers, books and records of the asylums, prisons, institutions for the intellectually disabled and eleemosynary institutions, and public works that he is authorized to examine, and of any county officer who receives or disburses county funds. </section><section prefix="3">The Auditor may require information on oath from any person touching any matters relative to any account that the Auditor is required to state, audit or settle. The Auditor may administer the oath himself, or have it done by any officer authorized to administer an oath. </section><section prefix="4">The Auditor and his assistants may issue process and compel the attendance of witnesses before them, and administer oaths and compel witnesses to testify in any of the investigations the Auditor is authorized to make. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 150, 4618-136, 4625, 4636-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22120</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>