<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.070</section_number><catch_line>Registration and title requirements for vehicles, manufactured homes, or trailers. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided, the state resident owner of a vehicle as defined in KRS 186.010(8)(a), manufactured home as defined in KRS 186.650, or trailer which will not be operated upon the highways of this state shall within fifteen (15) days apply for and obtain a certificate of title in his name. He shall not, however, be required to obtain a certificate of registration until the vehicle, manufactured home, or trailer is to be operated upon the highways of this state. </section><section prefix="2">On or after July 1, 2010, any state resident who purchases an all-terrain vehicle as defined in KRS 189.010 shall apply for and obtain a certificate of title in the purchaser's name within fifteen (15) days of purchase. The owner of an all-terrain vehicle shall not be eligible to obtain a certificate of registration pursuant to KRS 186.020. </section><section prefix="3">On or after July 1, 2010, any state resident who owns an all-terrain vehicle and creates a security interest on that vehicle shall be required to obtain a certificate of title within fifteen (15) days of the creation of the security interest. The perfection and discharge of the security interest shall be governed by KRS 186A.190, 186A.193, 186A.195, 186A.200, 186A.205, 186A.210, and 186A.215. The owner of an all-terrain vehicle shall not be eligible to obtain a certificate of registration pursuant to KRS 186.020. </section><section prefix="4">An all-terrain vehicle shall not be operated upon the roadways of this state, except in accordance with KRS 189.515. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective March 31, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6144</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>