<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.18-710</section_number><catch_line>Interstate Water Sanitation Board. </catch_line><order_by>18-710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A three (3) member Interstate Water Sanitation Board is established. The members of the board shall serve as Kentucky's members of interstate water sanitation control commissions created by compacts to which Kentucky is a party, which compacts are composed of states forming a river basin, and which compacts require a three (3) member representation from each state. The Governor shall appoint one (1) of the board members, who shall be a resident and citizen of this state. The member shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years, and shall hold office until his successor is appointed and qualified, subject to removal at the pleasure of the Governor. The Lieutenant Governor and the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall, ex officio, be the second and third members of the board. Except as otherwise provided by the respective compacts, an ex officio member may delegate to any deputy or other subordinate in his cabinet the power to be present and participate, including the right to vote, as his representative or substitute at any meeting, hearing or other proceeding of the commissions. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the first Interstate Water Sanitation Board shall be composed of the membership of the Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission existing on June 19, 1958, and the terms of the appointed members shall be effective from the date of their appointment to the Ohio River Valley Water Sanitation Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 361, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, secs. 1 and 13(2), effective June 21, 1974. -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 47, effective January 1, 1973. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 2, effective June 19, 1958. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4286b-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.205, and also previously codified as KRS 220.560. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>