<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.710</section_number><catch_line>Membership of Kentucky River Authority -- Compensation -- Meetings -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall appoint members to the Kentucky River Authority, created to carry out the essential public purpose of protecting the health and welfare of the people of the Commonwealth as declared in KRS 151.700. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint the secretaries of the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the Energy and Environment Cabinet and ten (10) other persons as the members of the authority. The secretaries may designate alternates. Of the ten (10) persons, one (1) shall be a registered engineer, one (1) an expert in water quality, one (1) a mayor, and one (1) a county judge/executive. The mayor and the county judge/executive shall be officers from counties which obtain the major portion of their water supply from the Kentucky River. Five (5) members shall reside in a county adjacent to the main stem of the Kentucky River, one (1) of the five (5) members residing in counties adjacent to locks and dams one (1) through four (4); and one (1) member shall reside in a county adjacent to either the North Fork, Middle Fork, or South Fork of the Kentucky River. Of the twelve (12) members, only one (1) may be an employee of the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Of the ten (10) members first appointed, two (2) shall continue in office for terms of one (1) year, two (2) for terms of two (2) years, three (3) for terms of three (3) years, and three (3) for terms of four (4) years, as the Governor designates. At the expiration of the original terms and for all succeeding terms, the Governor shall appoint a successor to the authority for a term of four (4) years in each case. Members may be reappointed. A vacancy in an unexpired term shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment to that term. Any member whose term has expired may continue to serve and vote until his or her successor is appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="4">Each member shall receive as compensation one hundred dollars ($100) per day for attending a meeting of the authority. </section><section prefix="5">Any member who misses three (3) consecutive meetings of the authority shall be deemed to have vacated the office. The authority shall declare the office vacant and the office shall be filled as provided by subsections (2) and (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The authority annually shall elect one (1) of its members as chairman. A quorum for the transaction of business shall be seven (7) members, and a majority of the members present at a meeting may take action on any matter legally before the authority. </section><section prefix="7">Members shall be paid their necessary travel expenses incurred in attending meetings and in the performance of their official duties, in addition to the per diem compensation of one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="8">The authority shall meet at least quarterly, and may meet upon the call of the chairman. </section><section prefix="9">The chairman shall be paid necessary travel expenses and a one hundred dollar ($100) per diem compensation for conducting official business of the authority. </section><section prefix="10">The authority shall be attached for administrative purposes to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the cabinet shall provide the necessary personnel to provide administrative services for the authority. </section><section prefix="11">The necessary travel expenses and per diem compensation of the members of the authority in attending meetings and in the performance of their official duties shall be paid by the authority. </section><section prefix="12">The authority shall promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out its duties, and shall report annually to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 180, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 42, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 287, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 500, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. --Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 27, (1) at 622. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>