<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.200</section_number><catch_line>Peer review committee -- Initiation of peer review -- Report of findings -- Licensure of other persons performing peer review of chiropractic claims. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall appoint a peer review committee not to exceed five (5) doctors of chiropractic licensed under this chapter, none of whom are in direct business relationship with the provider, insurer, or patient whose case is being reviewed. Members of the peer review committee shall serve at the pleasure of the board. </section><section prefix="2">Peer review shall occur upon submission by a patient, the patient's representative, insurer, or chiropractor, in accordance with the procedures and fees approved by the board, of an inquiry about a treatment rendered to a patient by a chiropractor. The peer review committee shall examine each inquiry submitted to it and shall report its findings to the board and furnish copies of the findings to the patient, chiropractor, and third-party payor. The findings of the peer review committee on each inquiry reviewed may include a determination of whether or not the chiropractor properly utilized services and rendered or ordered appropriate treatment or services and whether or not the cost of the treatment was unconscionable. </section><section prefix="3">Other persons performing peer review of chiropractic claims shall be licensed by the board and complete annually a board approved utilization review course, in addition to the required annual education in KRS 312.175. Persons performing review services under this subsection shall annually register with the board and pay a registration fee not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100). </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30801</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>