<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="529" order_by="529">PROSTITUTION OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>529.160</section_number><catch_line>Expungement of records relating to violation of chapter when person charged or convicted was a victim of human trafficking at time of offense -- Motion -- Finding -- Presumption. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a person is charged or convicted under this chapter, or with an offense which is not a violent crime as defined in KRS 17.165, and the person's participation in the offense is determined to be the direct result of being a victim of human trafficking, the person may make a motion in the court in which the charges were filed to expunge all records of the offense. </section><section prefix="2">The motion shall be filed no sooner than sixty (60) days following the date the final judgment was entered by the court in which the charges were filed.  </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A motion filed under this section, any hearing conducted on the motion, and any relief granted are governed by KRS 431.076, 431.078, and 431.079 unless otherwise provided in this section. </section><section prefix="b">For the purposes of expungement under KRS 431.076, a finding by the court that the person’s participation in the offense was a direct result of being a victim of human trafficking shall deem the charges as dismissed with prejudice. </section><section prefix="c">No official determination or documentation is required to find that the person’s participation in the offense was a direct result of being a victim of human trafficking, but documentation from a federal, state, local, or tribal governmental agency indicating that the defendant was a victim at the time of the offense shall create a presumption that the defendant's participation in the offense was a direct result of being a victim. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43287</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>