<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="359" order_by="359">WAREHOUSES AND WAREHOUSEMEN </unit></structure><section_number>359.050</section_number><catch_line>Grain warehouseman's license. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No proprietor, lessee or manager of a public grain warehouse shall transact any warehouse business therein until he has obtained for that year a grain warehouseman's license from the county clerk, and no such proprietor, lessee or manager shall continue such business after his license is revoked or has expired, except but by delivering property previously stored in his warehouse. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall issue each grain warehouseman's license upon written application and upon payment of a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012. The application shall state the location and name of the warehouse, the name of each person interested as owner or principal in its management and, if the warehouse is owned or kept by a corporation, the name of the corporation and the names of its president, secretary and treasurer. Each license issued shall be recorded in the bond and power of attorney book in the office of the county clerk. </section><section prefix="3">The license provided for by this section shall not dispense with the requirement of obtaining from year to year such license as the city in which the warehouse is located may require for the purpose of taxation. </section><section prefix="4">A grain warehouseman's license may be revoked by the Circuit Court in summary proceedings, upon written complaint of any person setting forth the particular violation of law and on satisfactory proof taken as directed by the court. The court, in revoking the license, may adjudge that no new license shall be granted to the defendant until at least one (1) year after the revocation. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 27, effective January 1, 2007. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4782, 4784. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34150</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>