<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">A SUPREME COURT OF KENTUCKY </unit></structure><section_number>21A.010</section_number><catch_line>Supreme Court districts. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The Commonwealth is divided into seven (7) Supreme Court districts composed as follows: <section prefix="1">First District:  Allen, Ballard, Butler, Caldwell, Calloway, Carlisle, Christian, Crittenden, Edmonson, Fulton, Graves, Hickman, Hopkins, Livingston, Logan, Lyon, Marshall, McCracken, McLean, Muhlenberg, Simpson, Todd, Trigg, and Webster Counties. </section><section prefix="2">Second District:  Barren, Breckinridge, Bullitt, Daviess, Grayson, Hancock, Hardin, Hart, Henderson, Larue, Meade, Ohio, Union, and Warren Counties. </section><section prefix="3">Third District:  Adair, Bell, Casey, Clay, Clinton, Cumberland, Estill, Garrard, Green, Jackson, Knox, Laurel, Lee, Leslie, Lincoln, Marion, McCreary, Metcalfe, Monroe, Nelson, Pulaski, Rockcastle, Russell, Taylor, Washington, Wayne, and Whitley Counties. </section><section prefix="4">Fourth District:  Jefferson County. </section><section prefix="5">Fifth District:  Anderson, Bourbon, Boyle, Clark, Fayette, Franklin, Jessamine, Madison, Mercer, Scott, and Woodford Counties. </section><section prefix="6">Sixth District:  Bath, Boone, Bracken, Campbell, Carroll, Fleming, Gallatin, Grant, Harrison, Henry, Kenton, Lewis, Mason, Nicholas, Oldham, Owen, Pendleton, Robertson, Shelby, Spencer, and Trimble Counties. </section><section prefix="7">Seventh District:  Boyd, Breathitt, Carter, Elliott, Floyd, Greenup, Harlan, Johnson, Knott, Lawrence, Letcher, Magoffin, Martin, Menifee, Montgomery, Morgan, Owsley, Perry, Pike, Powell, Rowan, and Wolfe Counties. </section></text><history>Amended 1991 2nd Extra. Sess. Acts Ch. 2, Sec. 1, effective December 20, 1991. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 2, effective April 3, 1984. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 2, effective March 23, 1976. </history><metadata><effective> December 20, 1991 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20527</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>