<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.075</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Personnel Board. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text>Subject to the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13A, it shall be the duty of the board to: <section prefix="1">As provided by this chapter, promulgate comprehensive administrative regulations consistent with the provisions of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200, and with federal standards for the administration of a personnel system in the agencies of the state government receiving federal grants for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Make investigations, either on petition of a citizen, taxpayer, interested party, or on its own motion, concerning the enforcement and effect of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200, and to require observance of its provisions and the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13A; and to make such investigation as may be requested by the General Assembly or the Governor and to report thereon; </section><section prefix="3">Hear appeals from applicants for positions for which examinations are being or have been conducted, from eligibles on examination registers, from unclassified employees who have been dismissed, demoted, suspended, or reduced in pay or grade for cause, and from officers or employees serving under the personnel systems created by this chapter, as provided by 1986 Acts Ch. 494; </section><section prefix="4">In cooperation with the secretary, promote public understanding of merit principles in government service; </section><section prefix="5">Present, in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 48, budget requests for the support of the personnel board; </section><section prefix="6">Make annual reports to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet, and the co-chairs of the Interim Joint Committee on State Government prior to October 1. The board shall make biennial reports to the General Assembly, which reports shall be a public record freely available to those persons interested in obtaining a copy. The board may request state agencies to provide information to assist the board in compiling the reports, which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The number of merit state employees at the beginning and the end of the reporting period; </section><section prefix="b">The total number of grievances filed and mediation requests made by merit employees during the reporting period; </section><section prefix="c">A tabulation of the stages in which employee complaints were resolved during the reporting period; and </section><section prefix="d">The average amount of time taken to resolve employee complaints during the reporting period, by stage; </section></section><section prefix="7">Advise the Governor and the secretary with respect to the administration of the personnel system created by this chapter; </section><section prefix="8">Consider and act on such matters as may be referred to the board by the secretary; </section><section prefix="9">Represent the public interest in the improvement of personnel administration in the state service, and advise and assist the secretary in fostering the interest of institutions of learning and of civic, professional, and employee organizations in the improvement of personnel standards in the state service; and </section><section prefix="10">Make a determination, upon receiving notification of proposed classification selection method changes with proper documentation for the necessity for the change from the secretary, on classification selection method changes prior to those changes occurring. Upon receiving a classification selection method change proposal from the secretary, the board shall, at its next regularly scheduled monthly meeting, review and comment on proposed selection method changes. No classification shall have its selection method changed without review and comment from the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 7, effective April 13, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.075, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(2); and ch. 308, sec. 10. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.170. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1355</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>