<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.250</section_number><catch_line>Plans for dams, levees, etc. to be approved and permit issued by cabinet -- Jurisdiction of Department for Natural Resources. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no person and no city, county, or other political subdivision of the state, including levee districts, drainage districts, flood control districts or systems, or similar bodies, shall commence the construction, reconstruction, relocation or improvement of any dam, embankment, levee, dike, bridge, fill or other obstruction (except those constructed by the Department of Highways) across or along any stream, or in the floodway of any stream, unless the plans and specifications for such work have been submitted by the person or political subdivision responsible for the construction, reconstruction or improvement and such plans and specifications have been approved in writing by the cabinet and a permit issued. However, the cabinet by regulation may exempt those dams, embankments or other obstructions which are not of such size or type as to require approval by the cabinet in the interest of safety or retention of water supply. </section><section prefix="2">No person, city, county or other political subdivision of the state shall commence the filling of any area with earth, debris, or any other material, or raise the level of any area in any manner, or place a building, barrier or obstruction of any sort on any area located adjacent to a river or stream or in the floodway of the stream so that such filling, raising or obstruction will in any way affect the flow of water in the channel or in the floodway of the stream unless plans and specifications for such work have been submitted to and approved by the cabinet and a permit issued as required in subsection (1) above. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section is intended to give the cabinet any jurisdiction or control over the construction, reconstruction, improvement, enlargement, maintenance or operation of any drainage district, ditch, or system established for agricultural purposes, or to require approval of the same except where such obstruction of the stream or floodway is determined by the cabinet to be a detriment or hindrance to the beneficial use of water resources in the area, and the person or political subdivision in control thereof so notified. The Department for Natural Resources through KRS Chapter 350 shall have exclusive jurisdiction over KRS Chapter 151 concerning the regulation of dams, levees, embankments, dikes, bridges, fills, or other obstructions across or along any stream or in the floodway of any stream which structures are permitted under KRS Chapter 350 for surface coal mining operations. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 2, effective April 2, 1982. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 29. </history><metadata><effective> April 2, 1982 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2101</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>