<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">G KENTUCKY OFFICE OF HOMELAND SECURITY </unit></structure><section_number>39G.030</section_number><catch_line>Reports by office -- Contents of reports. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>Each year by November 1, the executive director of the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security shall submit a written report to the Governor, the Auditor of Public Accounts, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Interim Joint Committee on Seniors, Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection. The written report shall: <section prefix="1">Assess the Commonwealth's preparedness to respond to acts of war or terrorism, including nuclear, biological, chemical, electromagnetic pulse, agro-, eco-, or cyber-terrorism; </section><section prefix="2">Identify the priority of needs, areas of improvement, and the overall progress made with regard to the Commonwealth's preparedness; and </section><section prefix="3">Provide a record of all federal homeland security funding, including grants, gathered under KRS 39G.020 since the last annual written report, as well as any other relevant homeland security funding information gathered by the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security. The record shall identify, at a minimum, the specific federal source, the amount, the specific recipient, the intended use of the funding, the actual use of the funding, and any unspent amount. </section><section prefix="4">The Auditor of Public Accounts shall conduct an examination of revenues and expenditures provided under the annual written report and under KRS 39G.020(2)(c) and, if examination findings warrant, shall conduct audits. No later than January 30, the Auditor shall submit all examination and audit reports to the Senate Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection Committee and the House Seniors, Military Affairs, and Public Safety Committee. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">In addition to the annual report required under this section, the executive director of the Office of Homeland Security shall provide to the Legislative Research Commission and the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue a quarterly report on the receipt and expenditure of homeland security funds since the previous quarterly report. </section><section prefix="b">The report shall identify, at a minimum, the following: <section prefix="1">Amount and specific source of any homeland security funds received; </section><section prefix="2">Specific expenditures by amount, recipient, and intended or actual use; and </section><section prefix="3">Balance of funds remaining in the account. </section></section><section prefix="c">The initial quarterly report shall be submitted by October 15, 2006, and shall contain the required information on receipts and expenditures since the passage of the federal Homeland Security Act of 2002, Pub. L. No. 107-296. </section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21818</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>