<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.135</section_number><catch_line>Manufacturers to report all shipments of tobacco products into or within state -- Records to be kept by licensed distributors, retail distributors, and retailers of tobacco products.      </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Every manufacturer, whether located in this state or outside this state, that ships tobacco products to a distributor, retailer, retail distributor, or any other person located in this state shall file a report with the department on or before the twentieth day of each month identifying all such shipments made by the manufacturer during the preceding month. The department, within its discretion, may allow a manufacturer to file the report for periods other than monthly. </section><section prefix="b">The reports shall identify: <section prefix="1">The names and addresses of the persons in this state to whom the shipments were made; </section><section prefix="2">The quantities of tobacco products shipped, by type of product and brand; and </section><section prefix="3">Any other information the department may require. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Each licensed distributor and each licensed retail distributor shall keep in each licensed place of business complete and accurate records for that place of business, including: <section prefix="a">Itemized invoices of: <section prefix="1">Tobacco products purchased, manufactured, imported, or caused to be imported into this state from outside this state, or shipped or transported to other distributors or retailers in this state or outside this state, including type of product and brand; </section><section prefix="2">All sales of tobacco products, including sales of tobacco products manufactured or produced in this state, including type of product and brand; and </section><section prefix="3">All tobacco products transferred to retail outlets owned or controlled by the licensed distributor, including type of product and brand; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Any other records required by the department. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each retailer of tobacco products shall keep complete and accurate records of all purchases of tobacco products, including invoices that identify: <section prefix="a">The distributor's name and address; </section><section prefix="b">The name, quantity, and purchase price of the product purchased; </section><section prefix="c">The license number of the distributor licensed under KRS 138.195(7); and </section><section prefix="d">The excise tax as required by KRS 138.140(4)(d)3. </section></section><section prefix="4">All books, records, invoices, and documents required by this section shall be preserved, in a form prescribed by the department, for not less than four (4) years from the making of the records unless the department authorizes, in writing, the destruction of the records. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42615</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>