<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.165</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Grape and Wine Council -- Composition. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Grape and Wine Council is hereby created within the Department of Agriculture. The purpose of the council shall be to promote and facilitate the development of a Kentucky-based grape industry in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall be composed of the Commissioner of Agriculture, or his designee, and nine (9) members appointed by the Governor. Of the nine (9) gubernatorial appointments, the Governor shall appoint one (1) from a list of three (3) candidates submitted by the director of the University of Kentucky Agriculture Experiment Station, one (1) from a list of three (3) candidates submitted by the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, three (3) winery operators from a list of six (6) candidates submitted by the Commissioner of Agriculture, two (2) grape producers from a list of four (4) candidates submitted by the Commissioner of Agriculture, and two (2) citizens at large. </section><section prefix="3">Of the members appointed after January 1, 2007, three (3) members shall serve a term of one (1) year, two (2) shall serve a term of two (2) years, two (2) shall serve a term of three (3) years, and two (2) shall serve a term of four (4) years, as the Governor designates. Thereafter, appointed members shall serve terms of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify. A vacancy in an unexpired term shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment to that term. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall select a chairman and shall meet at least once every three (3) months at the times and places the chairman designates. Six (6) members present at any meeting shall constitute a quorum. Upon the written request of any five (5) members, the chairman shall call a meeting of the council at the time and place requested. </section><section prefix="5">The council may enact bylaws concerning the conduct of the council's business and other administrative procedures as the council deems necessary. </section><section prefix="6">Members shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed, payable from the Kentucky Grape and Wine Council fund, for any actual travel expense incurred while attending meetings of the council. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 67, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 52, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 315, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2002).  This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs.49 and 315, which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch.315, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12555</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>