<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.506</section_number><catch_line>Regional planning councils -- Groups to be invited to join council.   </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The regional community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability established under KRS 210.370 shall institute regional planning councils for the purpose of conducting assessment and strategic planning. The councils shall be attached to the community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">A member of the regional community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability shall serve as chair of the regional planning council. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall issue invitations to join the council to no less than two (2) representatives of each of the following groups: <section prefix="a">Family members of individuals with mental illness, alcohol and other drug abuse disorders, and dual diagnoses; </section><section prefix="b">Consumers of mental health and substance abuse services; </section><section prefix="c">County officials and business leaders; </section><section prefix="d">Health departments and primary care physicians; </section><section prefix="e">Advocates and community organizations; </section><section prefix="f">Educators and school personnel; </section><section prefix="g">Regional interagency councils established under KRS Chapter 200; </section><section prefix="h">Law enforcement and court personnel; </section><section prefix="i">Public and private organizations, agencies, or facilities that provide services for mental health and substance abuse in the region that represent inpatient services, outpatient services, residential services, and community-based supportive housing programs; </section><section prefix="j">Individuals who provide mental health and substance abuse services in the region; and </section><section prefix="k">Public and private hospitals that provide mental health and substance abuse services. </section></section><section prefix="4">The regional planning councils may establish bylaws and procedures to assist in the operation of the councils. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 91, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 4, effective April 21, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>