<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.645</section_number><catch_line>Matters not specified in KRS 16.510 to 16.652.   </catch_line><order_by>645</order_by><text>The following subjects shall be administered in the same manner subject to the same limitations and requirements as provided for the Kentucky Employees Retirement System as follows: <section prefix="1">Cessation of membership, as provided for by KRS 61.535; </section><section prefix="2">Medical examiners and hearing procedures, as provided for by KRS 61.665; </section><section prefix="3">Actuarial bases, as provided for by KRS 61.670; </section><section prefix="4">Duties of the employer, as provided for by KRS 61.675; </section><section prefix="5">Exemption of benefits of the system for taxation and qualified domestic relations orders, as provided for by KRS 61.690; </section><section prefix="6">Retirement allowance increase, as provided for by KRS 61.691; </section><section prefix="7">Calculation of retirement allowance, as provided for by KRS 61.599; </section><section prefix="8">Beneficiaries to be designated by member, change, rights, as provided for by KRS 61.542; </section><section prefix="9">Year of service credit, as provided for by KRS 61.545; </section><section prefix="10">Refund of contributions, death after retirement, as provided by KRS 61.630; </section><section prefix="11">Custodian of fund, payments made, when, as provided for by KRS 61.660; </section><section prefix="12">Credit for service prior to membership date, as provided for by KRS 61.526; </section><section prefix="13">Member's account, confidential, as provided for by KRS 61.661; </section><section prefix="14">Cessation of membership, loss of benefits, as provided for by KRS 61.550; </section><section prefix="15">Correction of errors in records, as provided for by KRS 61.685; </section><section prefix="16">Maximum disability benefit, as provided for by KRS 61.607; </section><section prefix="17">Retirement application procedure, effective retirement date, as provided for by KRS 61.590; </section><section prefix="18">Employer contributions, as provided for by KRS 61.565; </section><section prefix="19">Reinstatement of lost service credit, purchase of service credit, interest paid, and delayed contribution and installment payments, as provided for by KRS 61.552; </section><section prefix="20">Reciprocal arrangement between systems, as provided by KRS 61.680; </section><section prefix="21">Refund of contributions, conditions, as provided by KRS 61.625; </section><section prefix="22">Hospital and medical insurance plan, as provided by KRS 61.702; </section><section prefix="23">Death benefit, as provided by KRS 61.705; </section><section prefix="24">Disability retirement allowance, reduction, and discontinuance, as provided by KRS 61.615; </section><section prefix="25">Service credit, Armed Forces, as provided by KRS 61.555; </section><section prefix="26">Reinstated employee, contributions on creditable compensation, as provided for by KRS 61.569; </section><section prefix="27">Statement to be made under oath, good faith reliance, as provided for in KRS 61.699; </section><section prefix="28">Retirement of persons in hazardous positions, as provided for by KRS 61.592; </section><section prefix="29">Direct deposit of recipient's retirement allowance as provided in KRS 61.623; </section><section prefix="30">Purchase of service credit effective July 1, 2001, as provided in KRS 61.5525; </section><section prefix="31">Payment of small amounts upon death of member, retiree, or recipient without formal administration of the estate as provided in KRS 61.703; </section><section prefix="32">Suspension of retirement payments on reemployment, reinstatement, recomputation of allowance, waiver of provisions in certain instances, reemployment in a different position, as provided for by KRS 61.637; </section><section prefix="33">Medical examination and financial review after disability retirement, staff review, as provided in KRS 61.610; and </section><section prefix="34">Employer payment of increases in creditable compensation during the last five (5) years of employment as provided by KRS 61.598. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 43, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 28, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 3, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 9, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, secs. 10 and 40. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 11. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 17. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 29, effective July 1, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>