<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.500</section_number><catch_line>Mississippi River Parkway Commission of Kentucky -- Members -- Duties -- Reimbursement for expenses. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Mississippi River Parkway Commission of Kentucky is hereby established to serve as the local coordinating agency for the development of the Great River Road along the Mississippi River from Canada to the Gulf of Mexico. The commission shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall consist of the following ten (10) members: Four (4) citizen members, appointed by the Governor, and consisting of one (1) member from each of the four (4) counties that border the Mississippi River, who shall serve a term of four (4) years and may serve until a successor is appointed. Four (4) members shall be the respective county judges/executive of Ballard, Carlisle, Fulton, and Hickman Counties in Kentucky. Other members shall be the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or his designee; and the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, or his designee. The commission shall annually elect a chairman and shall meet quarterly or upon call of the chairman with ten (10) days' written notice. Six (6) members present shall constitute a quorum for the official conduct of business. The commission may enter into contracts with the Purchase Area Development District to provide administrative services. </section><section prefix="3">Members shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed according to state regulations for actual and necessary expenses incurred in conducting commission business. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall assure that the proper direction is taken in developing a corridor of scenic, historical, and archaeological significance through the Kentucky counties of Ballard, Carlisle, Hickman, and Fulton. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 53, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 39, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 57, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>