<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.045</section_number><catch_line>Coordinator and other positions -- Emergency Medical Services for Children Program -- Funds received by program. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may employ or contract with a coordinator and other positions who shall serve at the pleasure of the board for the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program for which funding is provided by the General Assembly or through any other sources, including gifts, grants, or federal funds. </section><section prefix="2">The coordinator shall, subject to the direction of the board: <section prefix="a">Implement and oversee the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program described in this section; and </section><section prefix="b">Serve as liaison for collaboration and coordination between the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program, the board and other public and private organizations, the state traffic safety office, the maternal and child health program, the Medicaid department, the state and local child fatality review and response teams, state and local professional organizations, private sector voluntary organizations, and consumer and community representatives. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Emergency Medical Services for Children Program may include but not be limited to the establishment of the following: <section prefix="a">Guidelines for necessary out-of-hospital medical service equipment; </section><section prefix="b">Guidelines and protocols for out-of-hospital pediatric emergency medical services; </section><section prefix="c">Assistance in the development and provision of professional education programs for emergency medical services personnel for the provision of emergency care of infants and children; </section><section prefix="d">Coordination and cooperation between the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program and other public and private organizations interested or involved in emergency care for children, including those persons and organizations identified in subsection (2)(b) of this section; and </section><section prefix="e">Assistance with the purchase of equipment for the provision of medical services for children only. </section></section> The scope of activities carried out by and the provision of staff for the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program shall be commensurate with the availability of funds. <section prefix="4">Funds received under this section may be distributed based upon a matching grant system to be developed by the board, and distribution shall be need-based. No single grant shall exceed two thousand dollars ($2,000) to the same grantee. </section><section prefix="5">Funds received by the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program shall be placed in a trust and agency account in the state treasury which shall not lapse unless grant provisions specify otherwise. No funds shall be expended from a grant except by vote of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>