<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.127</section_number><catch_line>Regulations -- State retail food code -- Donation of food. </catch_line><order_by>127</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall adopt regulations for the effective administration and enforcement of KRS 217.005 to 217.215. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall adopt a state retail food code which shall include, among other things, provisions for regulating the issuance, suspension, and revocation of permits to operate; submission of plans for construction and equipment layout including plumbing, lighting, ventilation, water supply, sewage disposal, and other facilities; food supply source and protection; health, disease control and cleanliness of personnel; design, construction, installation, and cleanliness of equipment and utensils; toilet and hand-washing facilities; solid waste disposal and vermin control; and any other matters deemed necessary to insure a safe and sanitary operation of a retail food establishment. Standards for construction, plumbing, lighting, and ventilation of fixed retail food establishments shall be effective only if they are approved by the Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction and are included in the Uniform State Building Code, or if they conform to the State Plumbing Code in the case of plumbing fixtures. Any review of plans for construction, plumbing, lighting, and ventilation required before construction of a fixed retail food establishment shall be conducted by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction or authorized local building official pursuant to KRS Chapter 198B. </section><section prefix="3">The donation of safe and apparently wholesome food by a retail food establishment or any other entity regulated under subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall be exempt from any further inspection or regulation if the donated food has been inspected under subsections (1) and (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 321, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1990, Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>