<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0207</section_number><catch_line>Collaborative Center for Literacy Development: Early Childhood through Adulthood -- Duties -- Report. </catch_line><order_by>0207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Collaborative Center for Literacy Development: Early Childhood through Adulthood is created to make available professional development for educators in reliable, replicable research-based reading programs, and to promote literacy development, including cooperating with other entities that provide family literacy services. The center shall be responsible for: <section prefix="a">Developing and implementing a clearinghouse for information about programs addressing reading and literacy from early childhood and the elementary grades (P-5) through adult education; </section><section prefix="b">Providing advice to the Kentucky Board of Education regarding the Reading Diagnostic and Intervention Grant Program established in KRS 158.792 and in other matters relating to reading; </section><section prefix="c">Collaborating with public and private institutions of postsecondary education and adult education providers to provide for teachers and administrators quality preservice and professional development relating to reading diagnostic assessments and intervention and to the essential components of successful reading: phonemic awareness, phonics, fluency, vocabulary, comprehension, and the connections between writing and reading acquisition and motivation to read; </section><section prefix="d">Collaborating with the Kentucky Department of Education to assist districts with students functioning at low levels of reading skills to assess and address identified literacy needs; </section><section prefix="e">Providing professional development and coaching for early childhood educators and classroom teachers, including adult education teachers, implementing selected reliable, replicable research-based reading programs. The professional development shall utilize technology when appropriate; </section><section prefix="f">Developing and implementing a comprehensive research agenda evaluating the early reading models implemented in Kentucky under KRS 158.792; </section><section prefix="g">Maintaining a demonstration and training site for early literacy located at each of the public universities; </section><section prefix="h">Assisting middle and high schools in the development of comprehensive adolescent reading plans and maintaining a repository of instructional materials or summary materials that identify comprehension best practices in the teaching of each subject area and a list of classroom-based diagnostic reading comprehension assessments that measure student progress in developing students' reading comprehension skills; and </section><section prefix="i">Evaluating the reading and literacy components of the model adult education programs funded under the adult education and literacy initiative fund created under KRS 164.041. </section></section><section prefix="2">The center shall review national research and disseminate appropriate research abstracts, when appropriate, as well as conduct ongoing research of reading programs throughout the state. Research activities undertaken by the center shall consist of descriptive as well as empirical studies. <section prefix="a">The center may contract for research studies to be conducted on its behalf. </section><section prefix="b">The research agenda should, at a minimum, consider the impact of various reading and intervention programs: <section prefix="1">In eliminating academic achievement gaps among students with differing characteristics, including subpopulations of students with disabilities, students with low socioeconomic status, students from racial minority groups, students with limited English proficiency, and students of different gender; </section><section prefix="2">In schools with differing characteristics, such as urban versus rural schools, poverty versus nonpoverty schools, schools with strong library media center programs versus schools with weak library media center programs, and schools in different geographic regions of the state; </section><section prefix="3">In terms of their costs and effectiveness; and </section><section prefix="4">In maintaining positive student progress over a sustained period of time. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The center shall submit an annual report of its activities to the Kentucky Department of Education, the Governor, and the Legislative Research Commission no later than September 1 of each year. </section><section prefix="4">With advice from the Department of Education, the Council on Postsecondary Education shall develop a process to solicit, review, and approve a proposal for locating the Collaborative Center for Literacy Development at a public institution of postsecondary education. The Council on Postsecondary Education shall approve the location. The center, in conjunction with the council, shall establish goals and performance objectives related to the functions described in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 5, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 29, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 580, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, which included an amendment to this section, KRS 164.0207, provides that the Act shall be cited as the "Read to Achieve Act of 2005." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4172</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>