<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.221</section_number><catch_line>Administrative powers of cabinet -- Annual directory of alcohol and other drug abuse facilities available. </catch_line><order_by>221</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may: <section prefix="a">Make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the execution of its powers under this chapter, including, but not limited to, contracts with government departments, public and private agencies and facilities, physicians, and other persons rendering services to alcohol and other drug abusers. All rates shall be established in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the cabinet under KRS Chapter 13A. Income and resources of alcohol and other drug abusers to pay for services shall be taken into consideration to the fullest extent possible, and the cabinet shall be subrogated to any public or private third-party payments which may be due; </section><section prefix="b">Establish and operate facilities if adequate public and private resources are not available; </section><section prefix="c">Solicit and accept for use in relation to the purposes of this chapter any gift or bequest of money or property and any grant or loans of money, services, or property from the federal government, the Commonwealth or any political subdivision thereof. Any money received under this paragraph shall be deposited in the State Treasury to be kept in a separate fund which is hereby created, for expenditure by the cabinet in accordance with the conditions of the gift, bequest, loan, or grant without specific appropriations; and </section><section prefix="d">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A setting standards for the admission of patients to its facilities and set fees for treatment. Except as otherwise provided by law, all provisions of KRS Chapter 210 relating to charges and collection for treatment of the mentally ill shall apply to fees and collection of fees for treatment of alcohol and other drug abusers. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall prepare and publish annually a directory of all alcohol and other drug abuse facilities and services available in the Commonwealth. This directory shall be made available upon request. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9922</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>