<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.8-405</section_number><catch_line>Replacement of lost, destroyed, or wrongfully taken security certificate. </catch_line><order_by>8-405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an owner of a certificated security, whether in registered or bearer form, claims that the certificate has been lost, destroyed, or wrongfully taken, the issuer shall issue a new certificate if the owner: <section prefix="a">So requests before the issuer has notice that the certificate has been acquired by a protected purchaser; </section><section prefix="b">Files with the issuer a sufficient indemnity bond; and </section><section prefix="c">Satisfies other reasonable requirements imposed by the issuer. </section></section><section prefix="2">If, after the issue of a new security certificate, a protected purchaser of the original certificate presents it for registration of transfer, the issuer shall register the transfer unless an overissue would result. In that case, the issuer's liability is governed by KRS 355.8-210. In addition to any rights on the indemnity bond, an issuer may recover the new certificate from a person to whom it was issued or any person taking under that person, except a protected purchaser. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 151, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 50, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 8-405, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33713</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>