<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.700</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and policy. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby found: <section prefix="a">That there exists in many cities and in counties containing a city of the first class or consolidated local government in this Commonwealth blighted and deteriorated properties in neighborhoods which cause the deterioration of those and contiguous neighborhoods and constitute a serious and growing menace which is injurious to the public health, safety, morals, and general welfare of the residents of the Commonwealth, and are beyond remedy and control solely by regulatory process in the exercise of the police power; </section><section prefix="b">That the existence of blighted and deteriorated properties within neighborhoods, and the growth and spread of blight and deterioration or the threatened deterioration of other neighborhoods and properties: <section prefix="1">Contribute substantially and increasingly to the spread of disease and crime, and to losses by fire and accident; </section><section prefix="2">Necessitate expensive and disproportionate expenditures of public funds for the preservation of the public health and safety, for crime prevention, correction, prosecution, and punishment, for the treatment of juvenile delinquency, for the maintenance of adequate police, fire and accident protection, and for other public services and facilities; </section><section prefix="3">Constitute an economic and social liability; </section><section prefix="4">Substantially impair or arrest the sound growth of the community; </section><section prefix="5">Retard the provision of decent, safe, and sanitary housing accommodations; </section><section prefix="6">Depreciate assessable values; </section><section prefix="7">Cause an abnormal exodus of families from these neighborhoods; and </section><section prefix="8">Are detrimental to the health, the well-being, and the dignity of many residents of these neighborhoods; </section></section><section prefix="c">That this menace cannot be effectively dealt with by private enterprise without the aids provided herein; and </section><section prefix="d">That the benefits which would result from eliminating the blighted properties that cause the blight and deterioration of neighborhoods will accrue to the inhabitants of the neighborhoods in which these conditions exist and to the inhabitants of this Commonwealth generally. </section></section><section prefix="2">It is hereby declared: <section prefix="a">That it is the policy of this Commonwealth to protect and promote the health, safety, and welfare of the people of the Commonwealth by eliminating the blight and deterioration of neighborhoods through the elimination of blighted and deteriorated properties within these neighborhoods; </section><section prefix="b">That the elimination of such blight and deterioration and the preparation of the properties for sale or lease, for development or redevelopment, constitute a public use and purpose for which public money may be expended and private property acquired and are governmental functions in the interest of the health, safety, and welfare of the people of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="c">That the necessity in the public interest for the provisions enacted herein is hereby declared to be a legislative determination. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 127, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>