<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-590</section_number><catch_line>Licensee to make annual report. </catch_line><order_by>4-590</order_by><text>Each licensee shall annually on or before January 30, file with the commissioner a report for the preceding calendar year. The report shall give information with respect to the financial condition of the licensee and other relevant information as the commissioner may reasonably require. In the event any person or affiliated group of corporations holds more than one (1) license in the state, he, she, or they may file a composite annual report in lieu of separate reports for each licensed office. The report shall be made under oath in the form prescribed by the commissioner, who shall make and publish annually an analysis and recapitulation of the reports. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 666, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 19, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.590. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>