<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.16-060</section_number><catch_line>Approval of merger -- Abandonment.   </catch_line><order_by>16-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsections (2) and (3) of this section, a plan of merger shall be approved by: <section prefix="a">At least two-thirds (2/3) of the voting power of members present at a members meeting called under KRS 272A.16-050; and </section><section prefix="b">If the limited cooperative association has investor members, at least a majority of the votes cast by patron members, unless the organic rules require a greater percentage vote by patron members. </section></section><section prefix="2">The organic rules may provide that the percentage of votes under subsection (1)(a) of this section is: <section prefix="a">A different percentage that is not less than a majority of members voting at the meeting; </section><section prefix="b">Measured against the voting power of all members; or </section><section prefix="c">A combination of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">The vote required to approve a plan of merger shall not be less than the vote required for the members of the limited cooperative association to amend the articles of association. </section><section prefix="4">Consent in a record to a plan of merger by a member shall be delivered to the limited cooperative association before delivery of articles of merger for filing pursuant to KRS 272A.16-070 if, as a result of the merger, the member will have: <section prefix="a">Personal liability for an obligation of the association; or </section><section prefix="b">An obligation or liability for an additional contribution. </section></section><section prefix="5">Subject to subsection (4) of this section and any contractual rights, after a merger is approved, and at any time before the effective date of the merger, a limited cooperative association that is a party to the merger may approve an amendment to the plan of merger or approve abandonment of the planned merger: <section prefix="a">As provided in the plan; and </section><section prefix="b">Except as prohibited by the plan, with the same affirmative vote of the board of directors and of the members as was required to approve the plan. </section></section><section prefix="6">The voting requirements for districts, classes, or voting groups under KRS 272A.4-040 apply to approval of a merger. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 115, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41091</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>