<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.760</section_number><catch_line>Registry may appoint employees, adopt regulations, hold hearings. </catch_line><order_by>760</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Registry of Election Finance shall appoint such employees as are necessary to provide the service to carry out all purposes of KRS 61.710 to 61.780, including an attorney or attorneys on a full or part-time basis. </section><section prefix="2">The registry shall adopt such regulations and official forms and perform such duties as are necessary to implement the provisions of KRS 61.710 to 61.780. The registry is authorized and empowered to: <section prefix="a">Develop prescribed forms for the making of the required reports; </section><section prefix="b">Prepare and publish a manual for the individuals subject to KRS 61.710 to 61.780 describing the requirements of the law, including uniform methods of reporting; </section><section prefix="c">Permit copying or photocopying of any reports as requested by any person; </section><section prefix="d">Ascertain whether any individual subject to the requirements of KRS 61.710 to 61.780 has failed to file a report or has filed a defective report, give notice to delinquents of failure to file the report, as provided in KRS 61.740; </section><section prefix="e">Hold public hearings, investigate any violations in reporting, and issue subpoenas for the production of documents and attendance of witnesses. </section></section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23034</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>