<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.811</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions against certain conduct by legislative agents and their employers -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>811</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A legislative agent or employer shall not knowingly fail to register, as required under KRS 6.807. </section><section prefix="2">A legislative agent or employer shall not knowingly fail to keep a receipt or maintain a record which KRS 6.821 requires the person to keep or maintain. </section><section prefix="3">A person shall not knowingly fail to file a statement that KRS 6.807, 6.821, or 6.824 requires the person to file. </section><section prefix="4">A legislative agent or employer shall not knowingly offer, give, or agree to give anything of value to a legislator, a candidate, or the spouse or child of a legislator or candidate. </section><section prefix="5">A legislative agent shall not serve as a campaign treasurer, and shall not directly solicit, control, or deliver a campaign contribution, for a candidate or legislator. </section><section prefix="6">A legislative agent shall not make a campaign contribution to a legislator, a candidate, or his or her campaign committee. </section><section prefix="7">During a regular session of the General Assembly, an employer of a legislative agent shall not make a campaign contribution to a legislator, candidate, campaign committee for a legislator or candidate, or caucus campaign committee. This subsection shall not apply to candidates for the General Assembly in a special election held during a regular session of the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="8">An employer shall not knowingly employ, appoint, or retain a serving legislator or former legislator as a legislative agent until at least two (2) years have elapsed from the date on which he or she vacated his or her office. </section><section prefix="9">No person shall engage any person to lobby in exchange for compensation that is contingent in any way upon the passage, modification, or defeat of any legislation. No person shall accept any engagement to lobby in exchange for compensation that is contingent in any way upon the passage, modification, or defeat of any legislation. Violation of this provision is a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="10">A legislative agent or other lobbyist shall not go upon the floor of either house of the General Assembly while the house is in session, except upon invitation of that house. Violation of this provision is a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="11">If any legislative agent or employer violates any provision in subsections (4) to (8) of this section, he or she shall for the first violation be guilty of ethical misconduct. For the second and each subsequent violation, he or she shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 26, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43307</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>