<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.305</section_number><catch_line>Elder and vulnerable victims trust fund. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The elder and vulnerable victims trust fund is created as a separate revolving fund in the Office of the State Treasurer. </section><section prefix="2">The moneys in the trust fund shall be expended only as provided in this section and are hereby appropriated for those purposes. </section><section prefix="3">The State Treasurer shall credit to the trust fund all amounts received for this purpose, including appropriations, grants, gifts, and any amounts received under KRS 381.280. </section><section prefix="4">The State Treasurer shall invest trust fund money in the same manner as surplus funds are invested. Earnings shall be credited to the trust fund. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the trust fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="6">Money shall be disbursed from the trust fund only for the purpose of providing funding to one (1) or more public or private nonprofit organizations, including government organizations, in the development or operation of elder or vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation prevention or intervention programs. An organization shall be eligible to receive funding only if: <section prefix="a">The organization agrees to provide at least a twenty-five percent (25%) match of the total project amount requested, which may consist of monetary or in-kind contributions; </section><section prefix="b">The organization demonstrates a willingness and ability to provide program models and consultation to other organizations and communities regarding program development and maintenance; and </section><section prefix="c">The organization funds: <section prefix="1">Programs which provide advocacy, crisis counseling, financial guardianship, or other similar services to victims of elder or vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation; </section><section prefix="2">Law enforcement, prosecution, or court-based programs that enhance case investigations, prosecutions, or victim assistance in criminal cases involving elder or vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation; </section><section prefix="3">Programs which develop and implement public education and awareness campaigns on elder and vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation by making use of electronic and print media to inform the public about the nature of these crimes and available resources such as victims' rights, legal remedies, agency services, and prevention strategies; or </section><section prefix="4">Research initiatives that provide greater insight into the dynamics of elder and vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation and guidance on best practices for intervention or prevention strategies. </section></section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Fiscal, programmatic, and disbursement authority over trust fund money shall be provided by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, which shall develop a review panel system to award grants from the trust fund on an annual basis. Panel members shall be individuals with knowledge and operational experience in elder and vulnerable adult abuse, neglect, or financial exploitation and shall be drawn from the law enforcement, court, prosecution, and victim advocacy communities. </section><section prefix="b">In disbursing money from the trust fund, the panel shall not disburse to any one (1) program more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the total funds available for disbursement and shall seek to distribute meaningful awards to as many programs as possible throughout the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement this section. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.43, sec.4, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39693</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>