<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.600</section_number><catch_line>Licensing requirement -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person requiring a license may obtain an application by calling the Kentucky Department of Agriculture, Division of Regulation and Inspection. A license may be renewed when accompanied by a renewal application and the required fees. A license for the current year shall not be issued if there are past due license fees and penalties pending for previous years. With regard to shell egg dealers, wholesalers, and packers, and specialty egg processors, dealers, and wholesalers, all of the previous year's assessment fees shall be current before licenses shall be renewed. Any person selling eggs without the required license will be subject to having the eggs removed from sale until a license has been acquired. </section><section prefix="2">A license is required of each handler of eggs selling in the Commonwealth subject to the exceptions specified in KRS 260.550. The annual license fees are as follows, varying for dealers, distributors, wholesalers, producers, and packers, according to the average weekly volume of the month in which the licensee handled the most eggs during the preceding year: <section prefix="a">Retailers   ............................................................................................... $20.00 </section><section prefix="b">Shell egg dealers, distributors, wholesalers, producers, and packers within </section> Kentucky or out-of-state:   1-25 cases or 1-750 dozen  ............................................................. $20.00   26-50 cases or 751-1500 dozen  ..................................................... $30.00   Over 50 cases or over 1500 dozen  ................................................. $50.00 <section prefix="c">Specialty egg processors, dealers, and wholesalers within </section> Kentucky or out-of-state  ........................................................................ $50.00. </section><section prefix="3">Any egg handler engaged in more than one (1) type of activity for which a license is provided shall pay that license fee which is the highest of the licenses prescribed for each type of activity in which he is engaged. </section><section prefix="4">All eggs bought or sold within the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall bear a two cent ($0.02) assessment fee for each fifteen (15) dozen shell egg lot or portion thereof. Pasteurized liquid and pasteurized frozen egg products shall be assessed a fee of one-half (1/2) cent ($0.005) per ten (10) pound lot. Dried, dehydrated, hard-cooked, or specialty egg products shall be assessed a fee of one cent ($0.01) per ten (10) pound lot. These assessment fees shall be assessed and paid one (1) time as agreed between responsible parties as the product moves through the distribution network. All reports and fees are due monthly and shall be received by the department prior to the fifteenth of the month following the month of activity, unless there is an agreement with the department to report and pay these fees on a quarterly, semi-annual, or annual basis. In this event, the reports and fees shall be received prior to the fifteenth of the month following the period of activity. </section><section prefix="5">All licenses shall expire on April 1 of each year. Handlers having more than one (1) place of business shall hold a license for each location. Licenses shall not be transferred. </section><section prefix="6">Those that are exempt from licensing under KRS 260.550 are not exempt from inspection, with the exception of consumers. The shell eggs or egg products used by these persons are not exempt from the required assessment fee. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 2. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>