<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0557</section_number><catch_line>Schedule of actions for compliance with KRS 117.055 and 117.0551. </catch_line><order_by>0557</order_by><text>Not later than January 1, 1995, the boundaries of all election precincts in the Commonwealth shall comply with KRS 117.055 and 117.0551, and all county boards of elections shall have filed with the State Board of Elections maps and descriptions of precinct boundaries that provide the information required by KRS 117.055 and 117.0552. For the purpose of implementing this section: <section prefix="1">By July 15, 1993, the State Board of Elections, in consultation with the Legislative Research Commission, shall review the boundaries of all precincts in effect on July 14, 1992, to determine whether or not the boundaries comply with KRS 117.055 and 117.0551. If the State Board of Elections finds that a precinct boundary does not comply with KRS 117.055 and 117.0551, it shall so notify the county board of elections in writing. </section><section prefix="2">By July 15, 1993, the State Board of Elections, in consultation with the Legislative Research Commission, shall review the maps and descriptions of precinct boundaries on file with the State Board of Elections to determine if the boundaries of all precincts in effect on July 14, 1992, are described and mapped in a manner that provides the information required by KRS 117.055 and 117.0552. If the State Board of Elections finds that the information on file does not provide the information required by KRS 117.055 and 117.0552, it shall so notify the county board of elections in writing. </section><section prefix="3">If a county board of elections receives notice under subsection (1) or (2) of this section, it shall prepare a proposed precinct establishment order to establish a precinct boundary in compliance with KRS 117.055 and 117.0551, or provide a map and description of the precinct boundary in compliance with KRS 117.055 and 117.0552, or both, not later than July 15, 1994. The proposed precinct establishment order shall be processed in the manner prescribed by KRS 117.0552 to 117.0555. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27359</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>