<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.280</section_number><catch_line>Criminal Justice Statistical Analysis Center -- Reports -- Purposes. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Criminal Justice Statistical Analysis Center is hereby created as part of the Kentucky Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Criminal Justice Statistical Analysis Center shall provide its reports and recommendations to the Governor and the General Assembly through the Kentucky Criminal Justice Council. </section><section prefix="3">The Criminal Justice Statistical Analysis Center shall: <section prefix="a">Improve the quality and usefulness of criminal justice statistics and research results that are disseminated to citizens, public agencies, and private agencies in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Publish research results and statistical data that are requested by criminal justice agencies; </section><section prefix="c">Improve the relationship between citizens and criminal justice agencies of Kentucky by conducting citizen surveys of the needs, attitudes, and behavior relating to crime and justice; and </section><section prefix="d">Strengthen the relationship between Kentucky criminal justice agencies and the Bureau of Justice Statistics, United States Department of Justice, by: <section prefix="1">Providing justice statistics to the Bureau of Justice Statistics as required; and </section><section prefix="2">Serving as a clearinghouse for Bureau of Justice Statistics materials. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Justice and Public Safety Cabinet may expend any federal grants or federal funds provided for carrying out the functions and authority as assigned in this section. Further, the Kentucky Justice and Public Safety Cabinet may employ such employees as may be necessary to fulfill the duties, responsibilities, and functions assigned by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 16, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>