<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="383" order_by="383">LANDLORD AND TENANT </unit></structure><section_number>383.535</section_number><catch_line>Exclusions from application. </catch_line><order_by>535</order_by><text>The following arrangements are not governed by KRS 383.505 to 383.715: <section prefix="1">Residence at an institution, public or private, if incidental to detention or the provision of medical, geriatric, educational counseling, religious, or similar service. </section><section prefix="2">Occupancy under a contract of sale of a dwelling unit or the property of which it is a part, if the occupant is the purchaser or a person who succeeds to his interest. </section><section prefix="3">Occupancy by a member of a fraternal or social organization in the portion of a structure operated for the benefit of the organization. </section><section prefix="4">Transient occupancy in a hotel, or motel, or lodgings subject to state transient lodgings or room occupancy excise tax act. </section><section prefix="5">Occupancy by an employee of a landlord whose right to occupancy is conditional upon employment in and about the premises. </section><section prefix="6">Occupancy by an owner of a condominium unit or a holder of a proprietary lease in a cooperative. </section><section prefix="7">Occupancy of a dwelling unit located on land devoted to the production of livestock, livestock products, poultry, poultry products or the growing of tobacco or other crops including timber. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted and amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35724</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>