<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.420</section_number><catch_line>Director of health -- Qualifications, salary, term, removal. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text>The director of health shall be a physician, qualified as a public health administrator as provided by standards set up by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of Kentucky and duly qualified and licensed or eligible for license as a medical practitioner in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. He shall receive an annual salary of five thousand dollars ($5,000), payable as other salaries are paid, and shall serve at the pleasure of the board. If said director of health is removed by the board he shall be notified thereof in writing, and before such removal shall become effective said director shall have ten (10) days within which to make a written request for a public hearing in regard thereto. The board shall not be required to hold a hearing unless so requested by said director. If no such request is made said removal shall become effective upon the expiration of said ten (10) day period. If such request is made said public hearing shall be held at the office of the board within ten (10) days after such request is received by the board, and said director shall not be removed until after such hearing has been held, and a decision rendered by the board. The board's decision shall be final. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 409, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 360, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (10). -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>