<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.400</section_number><catch_line>Pension fund in cities -- Coverage provided in County Employees Retirement System after August 1, 1988.   </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city maintaining a pension fund for employees under civil service hired before August 1, 1988, operating pursuant to this section as of January 1, 2015, shall continue to operate the existing pension fund in accordance with this section. The city may assess monthly such amount or percent of the salary of the employees as may be equitably determined on a fair actuarial basis, the assessment to be deducted from the employees' salaries and paid in cash into the pension fund. </section><section prefix="2">The city may make current contributions to the fund on an actuarially funded basis, toward the annuities and benefits herein provided. These contributions shall be equal to the sum of the following: <section prefix="a">An annual amount resulting from the application of a rate percent of salaries of active members, representing the present value of the actuarial reserve requirements for membership service, for service retirement annuity, disability retirement annuity, and annuities to surviving spouses and children, and the one-year term premium for the city's liability for death benefits, after applying the contribution by the active members. Such rate percent shall be fixed by the city legislative body every three (3) years after an actuarial survey of the fund, and shall be in effect for a period of at least three (3) years. </section><section prefix="b">An amount resulting from the application of a rate percent of the salaries of active members which will provide each year regular interest on the remaining liability for prior service. </section></section><section prefix="3">The city may create or continue to operate a board for the pension fund and designate trustees of that board, and may fix the powers of the trustees, determine the eligibility of employees or their dependents to a pension or other benefit, and may provide a monthly allowance for employees eligible for a pension. </section><section prefix="4">Temporary employees appointed without examination shall not be compelled to contribute to any pension fund and shall not be eligible to benefits. </section><section prefix="5">In no year shall the contribution by the city to the pension fund, in the manner provided in this section, be less than the total amount assessed upon and deducted from the salary of the employees. </section><section prefix="6">The trustees of the pension fund shall, at least once every three months, report in writing to the mayor the receipts, expenditures, and financial status of the pension fund, stating the places of deposit of funds, or the character of investments made, and the mayor shall cause copies of the report to be posted in at least three (3) places where city employees frequent and report. </section><section prefix="7">When any city maintaining a pension fund for employees under civil service hired before August 1, 1988, operating pursuant to this section as of January 1, 2015, picks up employee contributions pursuant to KRS 65.155, or accepts from its employees a portion of their wages and contributes city funds therefor, an inviolable contract shall be created between the city as employer and its employees, and the city and its employees shall continue to operate under KRS 90.310 to 90.390 and the adopting ordinance, except that employees, pursuant to subsection (8) of this section, may choose to participate in the County Employees Retirement System. A repeal of that ordinance by the city shall in no wise affect such employees unless by the mutual consent of the city and an employee or employees. </section><section prefix="8">After August 1, 1988, no new pension fund shall be created pursuant to this section, and cities which were covered by this section on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall participate in the County Employees Retirement System effective August 1, 1988. Any city which provided a pension plan for its employees on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall place employees hired after August 1, 1988, in the County Employees Retirement System. The board shall offer employees hired on or prior to August 1, 1988, membership in the County Employees Retirement System under the alternate participation plan as described in KRS 78.530(3), but such employees may elect to retain coverage under this section. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 85, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 192, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 46, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 297, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 13. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3235h-2, 3235h-10. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43670</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>