<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.566</section_number><catch_line>Electronic medical record database. </catch_line><order_by>566</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">To the extent allowable by federal law, any Medicaid-participating health care provider who provides services to any medical assistance recipient may, at the discretion of the health care provider, maintain in an electronic medical record database the medical record for each medical assistance recipient receiving services by the health care provider. </section><section prefix="b">An electronic signature shall be accepted for any medical record maintained under paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any electronic medical record database maintained under subsection (1) of this section shall be capable of printing a complete written medical record of each medical assistance recipient. </section><section prefix="3">Any provider who maintains an electronic medical record database under subsection (1) of this section shall: <section prefix="a">Notify the department of the existence of the electronic medical record database; </section><section prefix="b">Certify that the electronic medical record database will be confidential and that patient privacy will be protected; </section><section prefix="c">Institute best practices to prevent access to the medical record database by any person who would not otherwise be authorized to review or obtain a written version of the medical records; and </section><section prefix="d">Institute the best practices to assure the security of the database. </section></section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7726</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>