<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.050</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for license -- Examinations. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, an applicant seeking to obtain a license to practice architecture in Kentucky shall satisfactorily pass the examination that is prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Every applicant for examination shall: <section prefix="a">Be of good moral character; and </section><section prefix="b">Hold a professional degree in architecture accredited by the National Architectural Accrediting Board (NAAB), or its equivalent as determined by administrative regulations promulgated by the board, with such additional experience as the board may prescribe and approve. </section></section><section prefix="3">Examinations shall be available on a regular basis at a place identified by the testing service and shall be given in accordance with the terms and conditions agreed upon by the board and the testing service. Procedures concerning the examination shall be set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 73-5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>