<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.210</section_number><catch_line>Extension of classified service to other offices and positions. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>The board, without additional compensation, shall perform, under and pursuant to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, the same services and duties provided for herein, for any department, board or agency of such city or any joint board or joint agency of such city and such county, in which said city is located, if and when by statute or by action of the legislative governing body of the city, or the legislative governing bodies of the city and county or by action of the governing body of any independent agency, where appropriate, the personnel or part or parts thereof of such department, board or agency, or joint board or joint agency, is placed under the merit system, and is thereby subjected to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 covering such offices, positions or classes of positions, or places of employment, in such agency, as the governing body of such agency may designate. This section shall also apply to any department of state government, or unit of a department, transferred as a result of a decision or agreement made between the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the city or city and county or independent agency in a city, where appropriate, or a change in funding of a department or unit from state to local. When the provisions hereof shall have been extended in the manner provided for in this section then all of the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 shall be applied to such offices, positions, and places of employment, in such departments, boards, agencies, and joint boards or joint agencies, the same as if originally included herein. The date of any extension of the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 to include additional offices, positions, or classes of positions, or places of employment, shall be considered as the effective date of those sections with respect thereto, and employees then holding such offices, positions, or places of employment, thereby made subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, shall be considered as having satisfied all of the qualifications for obtaining original appointment under those sections, and shall be considered as having been given probationary appointments as defined in KRS 90.110, as of the date they are thus placed in the classified service hereunder. However, the employees of any department, unit, board or agency to which the classified service is extended hereunder shall retain their seniority relative to other employees in the department, unit, board or agency for the purposes of KRS 90.110 to 90.230. </text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25434</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>