<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.023</section_number><catch_line>Evidence to be considered in determining the best interest of a child.   </catch_line><order_by>023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Evidence of the following circumstances if relevant shall be considered by the court in all proceedings conducted pursuant to KRS Chapter 620 in which the court is required to render decisions in the best interest of the child: <section prefix="a">Mental illness as defined in KRS 202A.011 or an intellectual disability as defined in KRS 202B.010 of the parent, as attested to by a qualified mental health professional, which renders the parent unable to care for the immediate and ongoing needs of the child; </section><section prefix="b">Acts of abuse or neglect as defined in KRS 600.020 toward any child; </section><section prefix="c">Alcohol and other drug abuse, as defined in KRS 222.005, that results in an incapacity by the parent or caretaker to provide essential care and protection for the child; </section><section prefix="d">A finding of domestic violence and abuse as defined in KRS 403.720, whether or not committed in the presence of the child; </section><section prefix="e">Any other crime committed by a parent which results in the death or permanent physical or mental disability of a member of that parent's family or household; and </section><section prefix="f">The existence of any guardianship or conservatorship of the parent pursuant to a determination of disability or partial disability as made under KRS 387.500 to 387.770 and 387.990. </section></section><section prefix="2">In determining the best interest of the child, the court may consider the effectiveness of rehabilitative efforts made by the parent or caretaker intended to address circumstances in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 140, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 18, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 7, effective March 17, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40863</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>