<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-300</section_number><catch_line>Examination expense revolving fund. </catch_line><order_by>2-300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created in the State Treasury the "Examination Expense Revolving fund" for the use of the department. The commissioner shall promptly deposit all funds received under a statute requiring examination expenses to be paid by the party examined and deposited with the State Treasurer to the credit of the fund. </section><section prefix="2">Moneys for travel, per diem, compensation and other necessary and authorized expenses incurred by an examiner or other department representative in the examination of any person required to pay, and making payment of, the expense of examination pursuant to KRS 304.2-290 shall be paid out of the examination expense revolving fund, upon approval of the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys for travel and other necessary expenses assessed pursuant to KRS 304.8-190 shall be paid out of the examination expense revolving fund upon approval of the commissioner. </section><section prefix="4">If any amount in the revolving fund remains unexpended at the end of any fiscal year, that amount shall not lapse, but shall remain credited to the account and may be used during the succeeding year or years. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 947, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 4, effective June 21, 1974. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 30. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>