<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.160</section_number><catch_line>Operators of water treatment plant to have certificate of competency -- Limited certificate of competency. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of KRS 223.160 to 223.220 and 223.991 that every operator in responsible charge of a water treatment plant or water distribution system be required to hold a valid and effective certificate of competency issued by the Energy and Environment Cabinet in a class equal to or higher than the class of the particular treatment plant or distribution system where he is currently employed in order to protect the public health. Operators other than those in responsible charge of such facilities shall also be eligible to apply for certification. </section><section prefix="2">An operator of a water treatment facility for a school and for a semipublic water supply shall be entitled to a limited certificate of competency for his particular facility provided he has demonstrated that he has the knowledge and experience required to operate properly the particular water treatment facility for which he is responsible. A limited certificate of competency so issued is not transferable to any other water treatment facility, nor is the period of operation under such a limited certificate eligible for consideration toward the experience requirements for a certificate of competency as provided in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 336, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 44. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (11). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 37. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9966</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>