<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="332" order_by="332">DRIVER TRAINING SCHOOLS AND INSTRUCTORS </unit></structure><section_number>332.210</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for suspension, revocation, or refusal to issue or renew license. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>The commissioner shall, upon receipt of satisfactory evidence, suspend, revoke, refuse to issue, or refuse to renew the license of a driver training school or a driver training instructor if: <section prefix="1">The licensee fails or refuses to comply with the provisions of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">The licensee has made a false material statement or has concealed a material fact in connection with his or her application; </section><section prefix="3">The licensee or any partner, or other person directly interested in the driver training school, held a license issued under this chapter which was revoked or suspended and not reinstated; </section><section prefix="4">The licensee has been guilty of a fraudulent practice in attempting to obtain for himself, herself, or another a license to operate a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="5">Written notice of the cancellation of insurance required by KRS 332.204 is received by the commissioner, and the licensee does not present satisfactory evidence of insurance to the commissioner prior to the effective date of the cancellation. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 6, effective March 31, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>