<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.665</section_number><catch_line>Application for permit. </catch_line><order_by>665</order_by><text>Any transient merchant desiring to transact business in any county in this state shall make application for and obtain a permit in each county in which the merchant desires to transact business at least ten (10) days prior to transacting business in the county. The application for permit shall be designed and distributed by the Department of Revenue, shall be filed by the transient merchant with the county clerk, or the officer of an urban-county government having the responsibility for the issuance of business permits and licenses generally and shall include but not be limited to the following information: <section prefix="1">The name and permanent address of the transient merchant making the application, and if the applicant is a firm or corporation, the name and address of the members of the firm or the officers of the corporation; </section><section prefix="2">If the applicant is a corporation, there shall be stated on the application form the date of incorporation, the state of incorporation, and if the applicant is a corporation formed in a state other than Kentucky, the date on which such corporation qualified to transact business as a foreign corporation in this state; </section><section prefix="3">A statement showing the kind of business proposed to be conducted, the length of time for which the applicant desires to transact such business and the location of the proposed place of business; </section><section prefix="4">An estimate of the aggregate market value of any goods, wares or merchandise to be offered for sale during the permit period; </section><section prefix="5">A statement that the applicant has acquired all other required city, county and state permits and licenses; </section><section prefix="6">The applicant's sales and use tax permit number or temporary vendor's registration number, and the Social Security numbers, of all salesmen employed by the applicant, or representing the applicant, in the transaction of business in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="7">The name and permanent address of the transient merchant's registered agent or office; and </section><section prefix="8">Evidence of security as outlined in KRS 365.680. The absence of any of the above information shall result in the denial of the permit by the county clerk. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 691, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 102, Ky. Acts ch. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>