<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="500" order_by="500">GENERAL PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>500.080</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for Kentucky Penal Code. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>As used in the Kentucky Penal Code, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Actor" means any natural person and, where relevant, a corporation or an unincorporated association; </section><section prefix="2">"Crime" means a misdemeanor or a felony; </section><section prefix="3">"Dangerous instrument" means any instrument, including parts of the human body when a serious physical injury is a direct result of the use of that part of the human body, article, or substance which, under the circumstances in which it is used, attempted to be used, or threatened to be used, is readily capable of causing death or serious physical injury; </section><section prefix="4">"Deadly weapon" means any of the following: <section prefix="a">A weapon of mass destruction; </section><section prefix="b">Any weapon from which a shot, readily capable of producing death or other serious physical injury, may be discharged; </section><section prefix="c">Any knife other than an ordinary pocket knife or hunting knife; </section><section prefix="d">Billy, nightstick, or club; </section><section prefix="e">Blackjack or slapjack; </section><section prefix="f">Nunchaku karate sticks; </section><section prefix="g">Shuriken or death star; or </section><section prefix="h">Artificial knuckles made from metal, plastic, or other similar hard material; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Felony" means an offense for which a sentence to a term of imprisonment of at least one (1) year in the custody of the Department of Corrections may be imposed; </section><section prefix="6">"Government" means the United States, any state, county, municipality, or other political unit, or any department, agency, or subdivision of any of the foregoing, or any corporation or other association carrying out the functions of government; </section><section prefix="7">"He" means any natural person and, where relevant, a corporation or an unincorporated association; </section><section prefix="8">"Law" includes statutes, ordinances, and properly adopted regulatory provisions. Unless the context otherwise clearly requires, "law" also includes the common law; </section><section prefix="9">"Minor" means any person who has not reached the age of majority as defined in KRS 2.015; </section><section prefix="10">"Misdemeanor" means an offense, other than a traffic infraction, for which a sentence to a term of imprisonment of not more than twelve (12) months can be imposed; </section><section prefix="11">"Offense" means conduct for which a sentence to a term of imprisonment or to a fine is provided by any law of this state or by any law, local law, or ordinance of a political subdivision of this state or by any law, order, rule, or regulation of any governmental instrumentality authorized by law to adopt the same; </section><section prefix="12">"Person" means a human being, and where appropriate, a public or private corporation, an unincorporated association, a partnership, a government, or a governmental authority; </section><section prefix="13">"Physical injury" means substantial physical pain or any impairment of physical condition; </section><section prefix="14">"Possession" means to have actual physical possession or otherwise to exercise actual dominion or control over a tangible object; </section><section prefix="15">"Serious physical injury" means physical injury which creates a substantial risk of death, or which causes serious and prolonged disfigurement, prolonged impairment of health, or prolonged loss or impairment of the function of any bodily organ; </section><section prefix="16">"Unlawful" means contrary to law or, where the context so requires, not permitted by law. It does not mean wrongful or immoral; </section><section prefix="17">"Violation" means an offense, other than a traffic infraction, for which a sentence to a fine only can be imposed; and </section><section prefix="18">"Weapon of mass destruction" means: <section prefix="a">Any destructive device as defined in KRS 237.030, but not fireworks as defined in KRS 227.700; </section><section prefix="b">Any weapon that is designed or intended to cause death or serious physical injury through the release, dissemination, or impact of toxic or poisonous chemicals or their precursors; </section><section prefix="c">Any weapon involving a disease organism; or </section><section prefix="d">Any weapon that is designed to release radiation or radioactivity at a level dangerous to human life. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 7, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 130, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1975; and ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>