<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.300</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 90.310 to 90.410 -- Application.   </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In KRS 90.310 to 90.410, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Administrative or directorial position" means the head of a department of municipal government; </section><section prefix="b">"Appointing authority" means the officer, commission, board or body having the power of appointment or removal in any office, department, commission, board or institution; </section><section prefix="c">"Civil service" means the offices and positions of trust or employment in the service of the city not specifically excluded by KRS 90.310 to 90.410 or by ordinance of the city as provided in KRS 90.310; </section><section prefix="d">"Commission" means the board of civil service commissioners as established under KRS 90.310; </section><section prefix="e">"Dismissal" means the discharge of an employee; </section><section prefix="f">"Employee" means any person employed in the conduct of municipal affairs, but the term shall not include the mayor, city manager, city administrative officer, or an administrative or directorial position. The term "employee" shall not include the offices of the board of health, members of the planning and zoning commission, the board of trustees of the public library, members of the housing authority, municipal hospital commission or the trustees, members or corresponding officers of similar boards or commissions, persons employed on temporary and special projects or to persons whose regular employments with the city are seasonal and are less than nine (9) months in any one (1) year, persons in a class of employees designated by ordinance to be non-civil-service positions, and the city clerk or city assessor; and </section><section prefix="g">"Pension fund" means the moneys derived from the employees and the levy of a special tax, either or both, or any other sum derived from any other source, to be used for the retirement of employees after the prescribed years of service and for the benefit of disabled employees, and surviving spouses and dependent children in the case of death of an employee within the scope of his employment according to the terms of KRS 90.310 to 90.410 and the ordinance of the city. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 90.310 to 90.410 are independent of and do not affect the laws governing the police and fire departments, nor their pension funds, as provided in KRS Chapter 95. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 78, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 12. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3235h-1, 3235h-11, 3235h-11a, 3480e-1, 3480e-11. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43663</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>