<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5710Foreign</section_number><catch_line>support agreement.   </catch_line><order_by>5710Foreign</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, a tribunal of this state shall recognize and enforce a foreign support agreement registered in this state. </section><section prefix="2">An application or direct request for recognition and enforcement of a foreign support agreement shall be accompanied by: <section prefix="a">A complete text of the foreign support agreement; and </section><section prefix="b">A record stating that the foreign support agreement is enforceable as an order of support in the issuing country. </section></section><section prefix="3">A tribunal of this state may vacate the registration of a foreign support agreement only if, acting on its own motion, the tribunal finds that recognition and enforcement would be manifestly incompatible with public policy. </section><section prefix="4">In a contest of a foreign support agreement, a tribunal of this state may refuse recognition and enforcement of the agreement if it finds: <section prefix="a">Recognition and enforcement of the agreement is manifestly incompatible with public policy; </section><section prefix="b">The agreement was obtained by fraud or falsification; </section><section prefix="c">The agreement is incompatible with a support order involving the same parties and having the same purpose in this state, another state, or a foreign country if the support order is entitled to recognition and enforcement under KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902 in this state; or </section><section prefix="d">The record submitted under subsection (2) of this section lacks authenticity or integrity. </section></section><section prefix="5">A proceeding for recognition and enforcement of a foreign support agreement shall be suspended during the pendency of a challenge to or appeal of the agreement before a tribunal of another state or a foreign country. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 64, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>