<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.470</section_number><catch_line>Entities organized for charitable purposes related to disasters -- Requirement for filing financial reports when contributions exceed $25,000 -- Filing requirements for other tax exempt organizations which solicited and received contributions exceeding $25,000 before June 25, 2013.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any entity organized for charitable purposes under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, other than a religious organization that is recognized as tax exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, that solicits and receives contributions exceeding twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) for a charitable purpose related to a disaster in Kentucky shall file quarterly financial reports with the Secretary of State until the funds are expended. The quarterly reports shall be in a form and format determined by the Secretary of State and shall contain at a minimum the following: <section prefix="1">The amount of money received as a result of the solicitation at the time that the report is filed; </section><section prefix="2">Where the funds collected as a result of the solicitation are spent; and </section><section prefix="3">The amount of funds collected that are used for administrative costs. </section></section><section prefix="b">The first quarterly report shall be filed no later than the last day of the third month following the commencement of solicitations. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any entity organized for charitable purposes under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, other than a religious organization that is recognized as tax exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, which solicited and received contributions exceeding twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) for a charitable purpose related to a disaster in Kentucky between January 1, 2012, and June 25, 2013, shall file a financial report with the Secretary of State. The financial report shall be in a form and format determined by the Secretary of State and shall contain at a minimum the following: <section prefix="a">The amount of money received as a result of the solicitation; </section><section prefix="b">Where the funds collected as a result of the solicitation were spent; and </section><section prefix="c">The amount of the funds collected that was used for administrative costs. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42397</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>