<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.3101</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations requiring supervision and treatment in accordance with evidence-based practices. </catch_line><order_by>3101</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations that require the supervision and treatment of supervised individuals in accordance with evidence-based practices. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations shall, at a minimum, include: <section prefix="a">The administration of a validated risk and needs assessment on all supervised individuals at regular intervals to determine their criminal risk factors and to identify intervention targets; </section><section prefix="b">Use of assessment scores and other objective criteria throughout the period of community supervision to determine the risk level and program needs of each supervised individual; </section><section prefix="c">Caseload size guidelines that are based on supervised individuals' risk levels and take into account department resources and employee workload and prioritization of supervision and program resources for supervised individuals who are at higher risk to reoffend; </section><section prefix="d">Definitions of various risk levels to apply to supervised individuals during the period of community supervision; </section><section prefix="e">Development of a case plan for each individual who is assessed to be moderate-to-high risk based on the risk and needs assessment, that targets the criminal risk factors identified in the assessment, is responsive to individual characteristics, and provides supervision of offenders according to that case plan; </section><section prefix="f">Implementation of swift, certain, proportionate, and graduated sanctions that a probation and parole officer shall apply in response to a supervised individual’s noncompliant behaviors; and </section><section prefix="g">Establishment of protocols and standards that assess the degree to which policies, procedures, programs, interventions, and practices relating to offender recidivism reduction, whether utilized by the department or contract or referral agencies, are evidence-based. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 51, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39568</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>