<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.400</section_number><catch_line>My Old Kentucky Home Advisory Commission -- My Old Kentucky Home Endowment Fund. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">My Old Kentucky Home Advisory Commission is hereby established to provide continuing attention to the maintenance, furnishings, and repairs of My Old Kentucky Home House Museum, as well as to any other additions made, after July 15, 1986, to the grounds of My Old Kentucky Home State Park. The commission shall be attached to the Department of Parks for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall consist of eleven (11) members. It is recommended that one (1) member shall be the park superintendent of My Old Kentucky Home State Park, one (1) shall be a representative of the Kentucky Heritage Council, one (1) shall be a representative of the Kentucky Historical Society, one (1) shall be a representative of the Division of Historic Properties, one (1) shall be a representative of the commissioner of the Department of Parks, and the remainder of the membership shall be selected from private citizens interested in historic properties with at least two (2) members who are residents of Nelson County. </section><section prefix="3">The public members of the commission shall be appointed by the Governor. Four </section><section prefix="4">members shall serve for terms of four (4) years and two (2) members shall serve </section>for terms of two (2) years. Representatives of state government shall serve terms concurrent with holding their respective offices. (4) The officers of the commission shall consist of a chairman and vice chairman, who shall be elected by the membership and a secretary who shall be responsible for the keeping of minutes and serve as staff to the commission. The park superintendent at My Old Kentucky Home State Park shall serve as secretary to the commission. A simple majority of the membership shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business by the commission. <section prefix="5">There shall be no compensation for serving on the commission, but the members shall be reimbursed for their necessary travel and other expenses actually incurred in the discharge of their duties for the commission. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet at least once a year or when called in to session by the chairman, or at the request of the Governor, or any two (2) members to the chairman. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall examine the house and shall require maintenance of inventory records, approve any major changes to the house, and shall make recommendations to the Department of Parks through the park superintendent. The commissioner of the Department of Parks may review and approve those recommendations based on funds available. </section><section prefix="8">There is established in the State Treasury "My Old Kentucky Home Endowment Fund" which shall be administered by the park superintendent at My Old Kentucky Home State Park under the supervision of the commissioner of the Department of Parks and pursuant to the recommendations of My Old Kentucky Home Advisory Commission. The fund may receive state appropriations, federal funds, and private donations. The fund shall be used for carrying out the functions of the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>