<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="438" order_by="438">OFFENSES AGAINST PUBLIC HEALTH AND SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>438.065</section_number><catch_line>Advertising or soliciting by practitioner of healing arts -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person licensed to practice medicine, dentistry, osteopathy, podiatry, optometry, or chiropractic, or any other healing art in this state shall solicit persons to become patients, or advertise by mail, card, newspaper, pamphlet, radio, television, or any other medium, or permit his services to be advertised; provided, however, that such person may publish a brief announcement of the opening of an office or of any change of office location or change of office hours, and may cause to be listed in the telephone directory and classified advertising sections thereof his name, address, type of practice and office hours. Modest signs on the doors, windows, and walls of the licensee's office or on the building in which he maintains an office setting out his name, professional title in accordance with KRS 311.375, office hours and address shall not be considered as violations of this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">Each violation of subsection (1) of this section shall be punishable by a fine of not less than two hundred and fifty dollars ($250) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or by imprisonment for not less than one (1) month nor more than twelve (12) months or both. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing contained herein prohibits the circulation of educational materials, which are not laudatory of the author or any person with whom he is associated in the practice of his profession, and which contain no solicitation of patients for the author or any such associate of the author, which has been approved as to content by the appropriate licensing agency. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19076</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>