<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.650</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings regarding state's natural history -- Purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>The General Assembly finds that the natural heritage of the Commonwealth is unique and plays a pivotal role in the economy of the state. As the state competes in an expanding global marketplace, this unique heritage must be recognized for its economic importance. In addition, the General Assembly finds that Kentuckians have a deep, personal commitment to a responsible stewardship of the land and water in order that future Kentuckians may benefit from the state's natural heritage. Upon these findings, the General Assembly declares that the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666 are to: <section prefix="1">Establish a natural history museum to showcase the natural heritage of the state; </section><section prefix="2">Provide a focal point for gathering resources to educate Kentuckians about the value and uniqueness of the state's natural heritage and to illustrate the historical human interactions with nature; </section><section prefix="3">Establish a database of information on the state's natural heritage; </section><section prefix="4">Create a repository of historical and contemporary specimens of the state's flora, fauna, fossils, minerals, archeological remains, and other natural features; </section><section prefix="5">Prevent the loss of specimens of Kentucky's natural heritage to other states; and </section><section prefix="6">Complement without duplicating the inventory duties of existing state agencies. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1548</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>