<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.440</section_number><catch_line>County treasurer's duties as treasurer of district -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text>The treasurer of the county in which the district is established shall be treasurer of the district, and the treasurers of the counties other than that in which the proceeding is pending shall pay over to him any funds collected and paid over to them for the benefit of the district, and shall take his receipt therefor in duplicate, the original of which the treasurer paying the money shall keep for his own protection. The duplicate shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the county of which the person receiving the money is treasurer. The treasurer of any district shall pay the money in his hands upon warrants signed by the president and attested by the secretary of the board, when presented for payment. In all cases where a county treasurer becomes treasurer of a district, he shall be liable upon his general bond as county treasurer to the extent of any funds of such district entrusted to him, but he shall give a supplementary bond in such additional sum as the board may require. As compensation for his services the treasurer shall receive an amount fixed by the board, but not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) in any fiscal year.  </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380-48. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>