<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.300</section_number><catch_line>Tobacco Master Settlement Agreement Compliance Advisory Board -- Members -- Organization -- Duties -- Duties of Attorney General. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "consent order" means the consent order of December 21, 1998, agreed to in Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Philip Morris Inc. et al., Docket Number 98-CI-01579, Franklin Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="2">There is created the Tobacco Master Settlement Agreement Compliance Advisory Board in the Department of Law. The board shall be composed of six (6) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The Attorney General, or the Attorney General's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The Commissioner of Agriculture, or the Commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; and </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) citizens at large appointed by the Attorney General. </section></section><section prefix="3">The citizen members of the board shall serve for terms of one (1) year and until their successors are appointed. The citizen members shall be eligible for successive terms on the board. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall annually elect a member to serve as its chair and shall meet at least quarterly on a date set by the board. Board members shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in serving on the board. </section><section prefix="5">The board may adopt rules governing the conduct of its meetings, the creation of meeting agendas, and other procedural matters it deems necessary. The board may adopt reporting forms, which shall be developed in consultation with participating agencies. </section><section prefix="6">The Office of the Attorney General shall: <section prefix="a">Enter into a memorandum of agreement with the Department of Public Health of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control in the Public Protection Cabinet, and the Department of Agriculture to identify and report possible violations of the consent order; </section><section prefix="b">Attempt to secure funding under the master settlement agreement to reimburse the agencies specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection for any compliance activity that they perform; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide necessary funding and staff for administrative expenses related to the operation of the board. The board may request assistance from other state agencies. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Tobacco Master Settlement Agreement Compliance Advisory Board shall: <section prefix="a">Identify activities for which training is required for personnel of the state agencies specified in paragraph (a) of subsection (6) of this section that are responsible for identifying and reporting possible violations of the consent order; </section><section prefix="b">Determine eligible compliance training costs and seek reimbursement for the costs; and </section><section prefix="c">Notify the appropriate tobacco manufacturer, in writing, of any alleged violation of the consent order and request a response and, if applicable, a corrective action plan within thirty (30) days from the date of the notice. If the manufacturer fails to respond or to satisfactorily resolve the matter, the board shall review the matter at its next meeting and may refer the matter to the Office of the Attorney General for enforcement action, if warranted. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 80, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=919</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>