<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="386" order_by="386">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS -- LEGAL INVESTMENTS -- UNIFORM PRINCIPAL AND INCOME ACT </unit></structure><section_number>386.484</section_number><catch_line>Receipts from minerals, water, and other natural resources. </catch_line><order_by>484</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To the extent that a trustee accounts for receipts from an interest in minerals or other natural resources pursuant to this section, the trustee shall allocate them as follows: <section prefix="a">If received as nominal delay rental or nominal annual rent on a lease, a receipt shall be allocated to income; </section><section prefix="b">If received from a production payment, a receipt shall be allocated to income if and to the extent that the agreement creating the production payment provides a factor for interest or its equivalent. The balance shall be allocated to principal; </section><section prefix="c">If an amount received as a royalty, shut-in-well payment, take-or-pay payment, bonus, or delay rental is more than nominal, ninety percent (90%) shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income; or </section><section prefix="d">If an amount is received from a working interest or any other interest not provided for in paragraph (a), (b), or (c) of this subsection, ninety percent (90%) of the net amount received shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income. </section></section><section prefix="2">An amount received on account of an interest in water that is renewable shall be allocated to income. If the water is not renewable, ninety percent (90%) of the amount shall be allocated to principal and the balance to income. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 386.450 to 386.504 apply whether or not a decedent or donor was extracting minerals, water, or other natural resources before the interest became subject to the trust. </section><section prefix="4">If a trust owns an interest in minerals, water, or other natural resources on January 1, 2005, the trustee may allocate receipts from the interest as provided in KRS 386.450 to 386.504 or in the manner used by the trustee before January 1, 2005. If the trust acquires an interest in minerals, water, or other natural resources after January 1, 2005, the trustee shall allocate receipts from the interest as provided in KRS 386.450 to 386.504. </section><section prefix="5">The proceeds from any disposition of an interest specified in this section shall be allocated in the same manner as receipts from the interest. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 18, effective January 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35934</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>