<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.042</section_number><catch_line>Qualified historic site license.   </catch_line><order_by>042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A qualified historic site license may be issued to any establishment meeting the criteria established in KRS 241.010 as long as the establishment is within: <section prefix="a">Any wet territory; or </section><section prefix="b">Any precinct that has authorized the sale of alcoholic beverages under KRS 242.1242. </section></section><section prefix="2">A qualified historic site license shall authorize the licensee to: <section prefix="a">Sell distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages by the drink at one (1) or more permanent or nonpermanent locations on the premises over which the licensee, by lease or ownership, has exclusive control without obtaining additional supplemental bar licenses prescribed by KRS 243.037; </section><section prefix="b">Sell distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages by the drink to patrons at public or private functions held on the premises; and </section><section prefix="c">Purchase and store alcoholic beverages in the manner prescribed in KRS 243.088, 243.250, and 244.310. </section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section exempts the holder of a qualified historic site license from the provisions of KRS Chapters 241, 242, 243, and 244, or from any rules of the board as established by administrative regulations, except as expressly stated in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 52, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43029</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>