<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.0425</section_number><catch_line>Accessible parking registration plate for vehicle used to transport persons with a disability -- Extension of legal parking period. </catch_line><order_by>0425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On the application of any agency or organization which transports persons with a disability described in KRS 186.042 as part of the service provided by that agency or organization to the county clerk for an accessible parking registration plate for a vehicle used in the transportation of persons with a disability, the Transportation Cabinet shall issue the agency or organization an accessible parking registration plate or renewal decal designating the vehicle licensed as being owned or leased by an agency or organization which transports persons with a disability. The license plate or renewal decal may be issued for a passenger car as set forth in KRS 186.050(1) or for a commercial vehicle as set forth in KRS 186.050(3)(a). The registration plates issued shall bear the international symbol of access adopted by Rehabilitation International in 1969, reading from left to right, and shall be followed by the numbers or letters the cabinet finds expedient. The cabinet shall not charge any fee, other than the regular fee for annual registration, for the issuance of the registration plate or renewal decal. </section><section prefix="2">The application for a license plate for an agency or organization which transports persons with a disability shall be made on a form prepared by the Transportation Cabinet. For every agency or organization seeking an accessible parking license plate, the application shall contain at least the following: <section prefix="a">Name of the agency or organization requesting use of an accessible parking placard for a person with a disability; </section><section prefix="b">Number of vehicles being used in the transportation of persons with a disability; and </section><section prefix="c">A statement from the director of the agency or organization verifying the need for the parking placard. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon the sale, transfer, or termination of lease of a vehicle licensed as authorized under this section, the owner or lessee shall remove the license plate and return it and the certificate of registration to the county clerk. The clerk shall issue a regular license plate and certificate of registration upon the payment of an eleven dollar fifty cent ($11.50) state fee and a three dollar ($3) clerk's fee. When the accessible parking plate has been presented to the clerk, he shall reissue the plate free of charge by the Transportation Cabinet and upon payment of a two dollar ($2) clerk's fee, for use on any other vehicle owned or leased by the same agency or organization who purchased the accessible parking plate for the current licensing period. The license plate and decal on the other vehicle shall be turned into the county clerk, who shall forward the license plate to Frankfort. </section><section prefix="4">When a motor vehicle bearing plates issued to an agency or organization which transports persons with a disability as prescribed in this section is being operated for the benefit of a person with a disability who is in the motor vehicle at the time it is being operated, the motor vehicle may be parked for a period of two (2) hours in excess of the legal parking period permitted by local authorities, except where local ordinances or police regulations prohibit parking on a highway for the purpose of creating a fire lane or where the ordinances or police regulations provide for the accommodation of heavy traffic during morning, afternoon, or evening hours or where the motor vehicle is parked in such a manner as to clearly be a traffic hazard. </section><section prefix="5">Registration under this section shall expire July 31. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet may promulgate the administrative regulations necessary to further the purpose of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1994; ch.  416, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 428, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 405, 416, and 428. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between chs. 405 and 416, Acts ch. 416, which was enacted after Acts ch. 405 by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5927</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>