<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">A LICENSING OF NURSING HOME ADMINISTRATORS </unit></structure><section_number>216A.080</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for issuance of license.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall be eligible to practice long-term care administration in this state unless: <section prefix="a">He or she shall make written application to the board on such forms as are provided therefor; </section><section prefix="b">He or she is a citizen of the United States or has declared his or her intent to become a citizen of the United States; </section><section prefix="c">He or she provides proof satisfactory to the board that he or she is of good moral character and is otherwise suitable; </section><section prefix="d">He or she has passed an examination approved by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="e">He or she meets such other requirements as may be established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation, so long as the requirements are uniform and are applied to all other applicants for a license. </section></section><section prefix="2">When an applicant has met the requirements as provided herein, the board shall issue the applicant a license to practice long-term care administration in this state. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 62, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 129 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40590</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>