<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.060</section_number><catch_line>Duty of court upon formal proceeding -- Right to attend proceeding -- Payment for counsel. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the Circuit or District Court determines that a formal proceeding is required in the interest of the child or to determine the truth or falsity of the allegations against the child, a petition shall be required pursuant to KRS 610.020, and the court shall, when the child is brought before the court: <section prefix="a">Explain to the child and his parents, guardian, or person exercising custodial control their respective rights to counsel and, if the child and his parents, guardian, or person exercising custodial control are unable to obtain counsel, shall appoint counsel for the child, as provided in subsection (2) of this section, and, unless specified to the contrary by other provisions of KRS Chapters 600 to 645, may appoint counsel for the parents, guardian, or person exercising custodial control; </section><section prefix="b">Explain the right against self-incrimination by saying that the child, parents, relative, guardian, or custodian may remain silent concerning the charges against the child, and that anything said may be used against the child; </section><section prefix="c">Unless limited by statute, explain the right to confront anyone who has accused the child and to cross-examine that person on the allegations made against the child; </section><section prefix="d">Advise the child and his parents, guardian, or person exercising custodial control of the right to appeal from a determination of the court; and </section><section prefix="e">Advise the child that these rights belong to him and may not be waived by his parents, guardian, or person exercising custodial control. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No court shall accept a plea or admission or conduct an adjudication hearing involving a child accused of committing any felony offense, any offense under KRS Chapter 510, or any offense, including the violation of a valid court order, for which the court intends to impose detention or commitment as a disposition unless that child is represented by counsel. </section><section prefix="b">For a child accused of committing any other offense, before a court permits the child to proceed beyond notification of the right to counsel required by paragraph (a) of subsection (1) of this subsection without representation, the court shall: <section prefix="1">Conduct a hearing about the child's waiver of counsel; and </section><section prefix="2">Make specific findings of fact that the child knowingly, intelligently and voluntarily waived his right to counsel. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Unless otherwise exempted in KRS Chapters 600 to 645, a child and his parents or person exercising custodial control shall have a right to attend the hearing if such attendance will not unnecessarily delay the hearing. </section><section prefix="4">Subject to the provisions of KRS 31.125, the court may order a parent to pay for counsel for the child if the court determines that the parent has the ability to pay for such counsel. The fact that a child is committed to a state agency shall not be cause for the court to order that agency to pay for counsel. </section><section prefix="5">Subject to Rule 43.09 of the Rules of Civil Procedure, the court shall permit the victim, the victim's parents or legal guardian, or, if emancipated, the victim's spouse, or the legal representative of any of these, to attend all proceedings under this section. </section><section prefix="6">An attempt shall be made to notify the persons specified in subsection (5) of this section of the time, date, and place of all proceedings under this section. Each District Court shall, by rule, establish the means of notification and the person or agency responsible for making the notifications. The failure of a victim or other person specified in subsection (5) of this section to receive notice shall not delay the proceedings in the case. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 1, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1997. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 18, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 25, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>