<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.550</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 198B.555 to 198B.630.   </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>As used in KRS 198B.555 to 198B.630, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the department. </section><section prefix="3">A "fire protection sprinkler contractor" is a person engaged in the preparation of technical drawings, installation, repair, alteration, extension, maintenance or inspection of fire protection sprinkler systems and has in his or her employment a certificate holder. </section><section prefix="4">A "fire protection sprinkler contractor's license" is the license issued by the commissioner to a fire protection sprinkler contractor upon application being approved, fee paid and the satisfactory completion of the requirements of KRS 198B.580. The license shall be issued in the name of the fire protection sprinkler contractor with the name or names of the certificate holder noted thereon. </section><section prefix="5">A "certificate holder" is an individual who has satisfactorily met and has received a certificate from the commissioner under the provisions of KRS 198B.570. </section><section prefix="6">A "fire protection sprinkler system" is a system of piping for which technical drawings have been prepared by or preparation supervised by a certificate holder in accordance with fire protection engineering standards. The system is supplied from a reliable, constant, and sufficient water, gas, or chemical supply, such as a gravity tank, fire pump, reservoir, or pressure tank, or connection by underground piping to a city, county, municipal water district, authorized water main, or both. The sprinkler system is considered the fire protection sprinkler system for purposes of KRS 198B.550 to 198B.630, and is a network of specially sized or hydraulically designed piping and includes installations overhead and underground in a building, structure, or area, and to which sprinklers are connected in systematic pattern. The system includes a controlling valve and a device for actuating an alarm when a system is in operation. The system is usually activated by heat from a fire and causes the discharge of water, gas, or chemical over the fire area. Fire protection sprinkler systems shall include the following types: wet-pipe systems, dry-pipe systems, pre-action systems, deluge systems, combined dry-pipe and pre-action systems, antifreeze systems and circulating closed loop systems, systems utilizing gasses or chemicals, and any other fire suppression system approved by the state fire marshal or the chief building code official of the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 273, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 372, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41123</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>