<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.635</section_number><catch_line>Written complaint of violation -- Investigation -- Hearing -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>635</order_by><text>Any person or organization, including the board upon its own volition, may file with the board a written complaint alleging violation of any provision of KRS 335.600 to 335.699. The board shall cause the complaint to be investigated. <section prefix="1">If the investigation reveals evidence supporting the complaint, the board shall set the matter for hearing in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B before refusing to renew, revoking, reprimanding, imposing probation or an administrative fine, or any combination of actions regarding any license holder. </section><section prefix="2">After denying an application for licensure under KRS 335.600 to 335.699, the board may grant a hearing to the denied applicant in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its decision on any disciplinary action. </section><section prefix="4">Any party aggrieved by a disciplinary action of the board may bring an action in Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 525, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43268</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>