<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.308</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of program to detect water loss from distribution lines -- Loans forgiven -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>308</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall establish a program to assist governmental agencies in detecting water loss from distribution lines. The program may include contracting with third parties to conduct water loss audits and leak detection. The program may include giving low interest loans, on a priority basis established by the authority consistent with the findings and purposes set out in KRS 224A.300, for the repair or replacement of distribution facilities, deemed reasonable by the authority, undertaken as a result of the water loss audit. </section><section prefix="2">The authority may forgive any amount of a distribution facility repair or replacement loan from the authority remaining unpaid if: <section prefix="a">Within five (5) years of entering into the loan agreement the governmental agency merges with or consolidates with at least one (1) other public or private water supplier; and </section><section prefix="b">The merger or consolidation is consistent with a 2020 water management planning council plan as reviewed and prioritized under KRS 151.607. </section></section><section prefix="3">The authority may fund the requirements of this section from the 2020 water service account. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10595</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>