<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.021</section_number><catch_line>Guaranteed arrest bond certificate of surety company to be accepted in lieu of cash bail in traffic cases. </catch_line><order_by>021</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A guaranteed arrest bond certificate presented by the person whose signature appears thereon shall be accepted in lieu of cash bail in an amount not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) as a bail bond to guarantee the appearance of such person in any court of this Commonwealth, at the time required by such court, when he is arrested for violation of any law of this Commonwealth or traffic ordinance of any municipality therein relating to the operation of a motor vehicle. A guaranteed arrest bond certificate so presented as a bail bond is subject to the same forfeiture and enforcement provisions as a bail bond or cash bail, but is not subject to Rules 4.30 and 4.34 of the Kentucky Rules of Criminal Procedure. However:  <section prefix="a">The violation must have been committed prior to the expiration date shown on the guaranteed arrest bond certificate, and  </section><section prefix="b">A guaranteed arrest bond certificate may not be accepted when a person is arrested for violation of KRS 189A.010 or KRS Chapter 281.  </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in this section, "guaranteed arrest bond certificate" means a printed card or other certificate issued by an association to any of its members, which is signed by the member and contains a printed statement that such association and a surety company licensed to do business in this Commonwealth:  <section prefix="a">Guarantee the appearance of the person whose signature appears on the card or certificate, and  </section><section prefix="b">Will, in the event of the failure of such person to appear in court at the time set for appearance, pay any fine or forfeiture imposed upon such person in an amount not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200).  </section></section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 24, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 298, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch.152, sec. 167. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 1.  </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18569</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>