<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.155</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet's right of inspection and to carry out statutory provisions and regulations through local health departments -- Requirement that drug inspector be a pharmacist. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet or its duly authorized agent shall have free access at all reasonable times to any factory, warehouse, or establishment in which foods, drugs, devices, or cosmetics are manufactured, processed, packed, or held for sale, or are held after receipt in commerce, or to enter any vehicle being used to transport or hold the foods, drugs, devices, or cosmetics in commerce, for the purpose: <section prefix="a">Of inspecting the factory, warehouse, establishment, or vehicle and all pertinent equipment, finished and unfinished materials, containers, and labeling thereon, to determine if any of the provisions of KRS 217.005 to 217.215 are being violated; </section><section prefix="b">Of securing samples or specimens of any food, drug, device, or cosmetic after paying or offering to pay for the sample. The cabinet shall make or cause to be made examinations of samples secured under the provisions of this section to determine whether or not any provision of KRS 217.005 to 217.215 is being violated; and </section><section prefix="c">Of examining or reproducing books, papers, documents, or other evidence pertaining to the foods, drugs, cosmetics, or devices. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any inspector appointed for the purpose of administering and carrying out the provisions of KRS 217.005 to 217.215 insofar as they relate to drugs in a retail pharmacy shall be a registered pharmacist and a graduate of a school recognized as in good standing by the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may carry out the provisions of KRS 217.005 to 217.215 and regulations relating to food processing establishments, food storage warehouses, salvage distributors, or salvage processing plants or retail food establishments through local health departments. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9302</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>