<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.180</section_number><catch_line>Territory included in district -- Addition of territory -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The territory of a district shall include all lands lying within the boundaries of a district, including incorporated cities, towns, and villages.  </section><section prefix="2">Petitions for including additional territory within an existing district may be filed with the commission, and the proceedings provided for by KRS 262.100 to 262.180 in the case of petitions to organize a district shall be observed as far as may be practicable in the case of petitions for inclusion. The commission shall prescribe the form for such petitions, which shall be as nearly as may be in the form prescribed by KRS 262.100 for petitions to organize a district. The Secretary of State shall receive the application for inclusion of the area within the district and shall attach such application to the original file containing the papers by which such district was organized. Where the total number of landowners in the area proposed for inclusion is less than twenty-five (25), the petition may be filed when signed by a majority of the landowners of the area, and in that case, no referendum need be held. In a referendum upon a petition for inclusion of additional territory, all owners of land lying within the proposed additional area shall be eligible to vote. </section></text><history>Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1972. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 61. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective November 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42i-5. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1972</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>