<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.185</section_number><catch_line>Certified or classified staff member to accompany students on school-sponsored or endorsed trips -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2), boards of education shall require a certified or classified staff member who is at least twenty-one (21) years of age to accompany students on all school-sponsored or school-endorsed trips. Local boards of education may adopt a policy that specifies the job classifications of staff members who may accompany students on trips under this section. </section><section prefix="2">Boards of education may permit a nonfaculty coach or nonfaculty assistant, as defined by administrative regulation promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education under KRS 156.070(2), to accompany students on all school-sponsored or school-endorsed athletic trips. A nonfaculty coach or nonfaculty assistant shall be at least twenty-one (21) years of age, shall not be a violent offender or convicted of a sex crime as defined by KRS 17.165 which is classified as a felony, and shall submit to a criminal record check under KRS 160.380. </section><section prefix="3">Prior to assuming his or her duties, a nonfaculty coach or nonfaculty assistant shall successfully complete training provided by the local school district. The training shall include, but not be limited to, information on the physical and emotional development of students of the age with whom the nonfaculty coach and nonfaculty assistant will be working, the district's and school's discipline policies, procedures for dealing with discipline problems, and safety and first aid training. Follow-up training shall be provided annually. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective March 9, 2011. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 482, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> March 9, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39480</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>