<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.2251</section_number><catch_line>Information required in administrative regulation when incorporating material by reference. </catch_line><order_by>2251</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An administrative body shall incorporate material by reference in the last section of an administrative regulation. This section shall include: <section prefix="a">The title of the material incorporated by reference placed in quotation marks, followed by the edition date of the material; </section><section prefix="b">Information on how the material may be obtained; and </section><section prefix="c">A statement that the material is available for public inspection and copying, subject to copyright law, at the main, regional, or branch offices of the administrative body, and the address and office hours of each. Following the required statement, the administrative body may include optional information that states the administrative body's Web site address or telephone number or that provides contact information for other sources that may have the material available to the public. </section></section><section prefix="2">The section incorporating material by reference shall be titled "Incorporation by Reference". <section prefix="a">If only one (1) item is incorporated by reference, the first subsection of the section incorporating material by reference shall contain the following statement: "(name and edition date of material incorporated) is incorporated by reference." </section><section prefix="b">If more than one (1) item is incorporated by reference, the first subsection of the section incorporating material by reference shall contain the following statement: "The following material is incorporated by reference: (a) (name and edition date of first item incorporated); and (b) (name and edition date of second item incorporated)." </section><section prefix="c">The second subsection of the section incorporating material by reference shall include the following statement: "This material may be inspected, copied, or obtained, subject to applicable copyright law, at (name of administrative body, full address), Monday through Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 4:30 p.m." </section></section><section prefix="3">A summary of the incorporated material, in detail sufficient to identify the subject matter to which it pertains, shall be attached to an administrative regulation that incorporates material by reference. This summary shall include: <section prefix="a">Relevant programs, statutes, funds, rights, duties, and procedures affected by the material and the manner in which they are affected; </section><section prefix="b">A citation of the specific state or federal statutes or regulations authorizing or requiring the procedure or policy found in the material incorporated by reference; and </section><section prefix="c">The total number of pages incorporated by reference. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">One (1) copy of the material incorporated by reference shall be filed with the regulations compiler when the administrative regulation is filed. </section><section prefix="b">Material incorporated by reference shall be placed in a binder, attached to the back of the administrative regulation, or filed on a CD-ROM or DVD. <section prefix="1">If the material is placed in a binder, the administrative body shall indicate, on the front binder cover and on the first page of the material incorporated by reference, the: <section prefix="a">Number of the administrative regulation to which the material incorporated by reference pertains; </section><section prefix="b">Date on which it is filed; and </section><section prefix="c">Citation of each item that is included in the binder. </section></section><section prefix="2">The material incorporated by reference may be attached to the back of the administrative regulation if it is: <section prefix="a">No more than four (4) pages in length; and </section><section prefix="b">Typewritten on white paper, size eight and one-half (8 1/2) by eleven (11) inches, and single-sided. </section></section><section prefix="3">The material incorporated by reference may be filed on a CD-ROM or DVD disc if the material is saved in Adobe Portable Document Format (PDF). The administrative body shall indicate on the disc and the disc's storage case the: <section prefix="a">Number of the administrative regulation to which the material incorporated by reference pertains; </section><section prefix="b">Date on which it is filed; and </section><section prefix="c">Citation of each item that is included on the disc. </section></section></section><section prefix="c">If the same material is incorporated by reference in more than one (1) administrative regulation, an administrative body may file one (1) copy of the material in a binder or on a CD-ROM or DVD disc. The numbers of the administrative regulations in which the material is incorporated by reference shall be indicated with the other information as required by paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>