<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6338</section_number><catch_line>Implementation of pilot projects to provide health care to frail elderly Medicaid-eligible individuals. </catch_line><order_by>6338</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within one (1) year of obtaining necessary waivers from the Federal Health Care Financing Administration, the Secretary of the Cabinet for Health Services shall take all necessary steps to implement from one (1) to three (3) pilot projects to provide health-care services to frail elderly Medicaid-eligible individuals through fully integrated managed-care systems for the elderly similar to the Program of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE) program currently being replicated on a national basis with the approval of Congress. </section><section prefix="2">Within ninety (90) days of July 15, 1994, the Secretary of the Cabinet for Health Services shall request the appropriate waivers from the Federal Health Care Financing Administration to implement a PACE program or a similar program in Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 216, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 116, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/98).  References in this statute to the former Cabinet for Human Resources have been changed to the Cabinet for Health Services under 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 629, and KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7774</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>