<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.402</section_number><catch_line>Application for services from Kentucky Physicians Care Program -- Referral by Department for Community Based Services -- Fee for services prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Individuals may apply for primary care services available from the Kentucky Physicians Care Program in their local Department for Community Based Services office or other enrollment sites approved by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">If an individual is determined to be eligible, the department shall refer the individual to the program. An individual shall be eligible for services available under the program for one (1) year and may reapply. </section><section prefix="3">Services that may be available from the program include but are not limited to visits to health care professionals and prescription drugs donated by pharmaceutical companies and filled by retail and hospital pharmacies. Eligibility for the program does not guarantee an individual access to free services not available under the program. </section><section prefix="4">Individuals shall not be charged a fee for services provided under this program. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish eligibility criteria and implement the provisions of KRS 211.400 and 211.402. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>