<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="519" order_by="519">OBSTRUCTION OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>519.040</section_number><catch_line>Falsely reporting an incident. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of falsely reporting an incident when he:  <section prefix="a">Knowingly causes a false alarm of fire or other emergency to be transmitted to or within any organization, official or volunteer, that deals with emergencies involving danger to life or property; or  </section><section prefix="b">Reports to law enforcement authorities an offense or incident within their official concern knowing that it did not occur; or  </section><section prefix="c">Furnishes law enforcement authorities with information allegedly relating to an offense or incident within their official concern when he knows he has no information relating to such offense or incident; or  </section><section prefix="d">Knowingly gives false information to any law enforcement officer with intent to implicate another; or  </section><section prefix="e">Initiates or circulates a report or warning of an alleged occurrence or impending occurrence of a fire or other emergency under circumstances likely to cause public inconvenience or alarm when he knows the information reported, conveyed or circulated is false or baseless.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Falsely reporting an incident is a Class A misdemeanor.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 166, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>