<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.4-090</section_number><catch_line>Known claims against dissolved series.   </catch_line><order_by>4-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon dissolution pursuant to KRS 386A.4-060(1)(b), (c), (d), or (e), a series of a statutory trust shall dispose of the known claims against the property of or associated with it by following the procedures described in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The series shall notify its known claimants in writing of its dissolution at any time after the effective date of dissolution. The written notice shall: <section prefix="a">Identify the series by such name or names as it used in transacting business and the name of the statutory trust; </section><section prefix="b">Describe information that must be included in a claim; </section><section prefix="c">Provide a mailing address where a claim may be sent; </section><section prefix="d">State the deadline, which may not be fewer than one hundred twenty (120) days after the date of the written notice, by which the series must receive the claim; and </section><section prefix="e">State that the claim will be barred if not received by the deadline. </section></section><section prefix="3">A claim against a series shall be barred: <section prefix="a">If a claimant who is given written notice under subsection (2) of this section does not deliver the claim to the series by the deadline; or </section><section prefix="b">If a claimant whose claim was rejected by the series does not commence a proceeding to enforce the claim within ninety (90) days after the date of the rejection notice. </section></section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this section, "claim" shall not include a contingent liability or a claim based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 30, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40372</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>