<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.370</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for membership in federation -- Powers of federation. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every county farm bureau organized pursuant to KRS 247.250 shall be eligible to membership in any said state federation, but after its admission to membership, said federation shall have power to suspend its membership or expel it for failure to comply with any bylaws or reasonable rule or regulation of the federation.  </section><section prefix="2">Any said state federation shall have authority to:  <section prefix="a">Adopt, amend and repeal bylaws and amendments thereto by two-thirds (2/3) vote of the voting delegates voting at an annual convention;  </section><section prefix="b">Assess annual membership dues against each county farm bureau, and base the amount thereof on the number of paid-in memberships in each county farm bureau;  </section><section prefix="c">Acquire, own and hold property, pursuant to action of its board of directors, or by its executive committee upon authorization or approval of its board of directors;  </section><section prefix="d">Borrow money and mortgage or pledge its property or assets by action of its board of directors, or, by its executive committee, upon authorization or approval of its board of directors;  </section><section prefix="e">Accept gifts, devises and bequests, appropriate and expend its funds, pursuant to action of its board of directors, or its executive committee, upon authorization or approval by its board of directors, for the advancement of agriculture and allied interests and for any purposes deemed advisable to carry on its activities; and  </section><section prefix="f">Do anything necessary to carry out the purpose for which it is organized.  </section></section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 7, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42d-19. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11629</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>