<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.965</section_number><catch_line>Contents of fiscal note -- State mandate determination -- Copies to be furnished to local officials. </catch_line><order_by>965</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A fiscal note shall state whether the bill or order is determined to be a state mandate. Such determination shall be made by the director of the Legislative Research Commission except as provided by subsection (2) of this section. If the bill or order is a state mandate, the note shall contain an estimate of the effect the law will have on expenditures or revenues of local government for the first full fiscal year the law is to be in effect. </section><section prefix="2">The director, at his discretion, may seek a certification from the Attorney General on the question of whether a bill or order constitutes a state mandate. The Attorney General shall, within seven (7) working days from receipt of the request, certify to the director that the bill or order is or is not a state mandate. </section><section prefix="3">If any bill or order is amended after the preparation of the fiscal note, it shall be resubmitted to the person responsible for preparation of the note who shall reevaluate the bill or order as amended and change the fiscal note in accordance therewith. </section><section prefix="4">Copies of the fiscal note shall be furnished by the Legislative Research Commission to any local official upon written request. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=425</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>