<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.290</section_number><catch_line>Meetings, compensation, and expenses of board members. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of trustees shall meet on the third Monday during the months of March, June, September, and December of each year. Special meetings may be called by the chairperson upon giving adequate notice to each member of the board of trustees. The business to be transacted at special meetings shall be specified in the notice of the meeting. </section><section prefix="2">The members of the board of trustees shall serve without compensation, except that elective trustees shall receive ninety dollars ($90) for each day the board is in session and all elected trustees shall be reimbursed from the expense fund for all necessary expenses they incur through service to the board without limitation of the provisions of KRS Chapters 44 and 45. </section><section prefix="3">The board of trustees may authorize a per diem, not to exceed ninety dollars ($90) per day, for trustees representing the system on committees or commissions established by statute or for service as an official representative of the board of trustees. </section><section prefix="4">The school district which employs a teacher trustee who is required to attend regular or special meetings of the board of trustees, represent the system on committees or commissions, or serve as an official representative of the board of trustees shall provide the teacher trustee with special leave with pay and pay the compensation for a substitute for the teacher trustee during periods of absence upon certification by the teacher trustee that the trustee is performing these duties for the system. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1992. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 488, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 395, secs. 3 and 53. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 5. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4506b-8, 4506b-15. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3902</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>