<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.404</section_number><catch_line>Basic training and in-service training for peace officers. </catch_line><order_by>404</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any peace officers employed or appointed after December 1, 1998, who have not successfully completed basic training at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, shall within one (1) year of their appointment or employment, successfully complete at least six hundred forty (640) hours of basic training at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="b">In the event of extenuating circumstances beyond the control of an officer that prevent the officer from completing basic training within one (1) year, the commissioner of the department or his or her designee may grant the officer an extension of time, not to exceed one hundred eighty (180) days, in which to complete the training. </section><section prefix="c">Any peace officer who fails to successfully complete basic training within the specified time periods, including extensions, shall lose his or her law enforcement powers and his or her precertification status shall lapse. Further, the peace officer shall be prohibited from serving as a peace officer for a period of one (1) year from the date that his or her precertification lapses. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">All peace officers with active certification status shall successfully complete forty (40) hours of annual in-service training that has been certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, that is appropriate to the officer's rank and responsibility and the size and location of his department. </section><section prefix="b">In the event of extenuating circumstances beyond the control of an officer that prevent the officer from completing the in-service training within one (1) year, the commissioner of the department or his or her designee may grant the officer an extension of time, not to exceed one hundred eighty (180) days, in which to complete the training. If the officer is unable to complete the in-service training due to injury or illness that prevents him or her from working as a peace officer, the one hundred eighty (180) day extension shall begin on the date that the officer returns to work. </section><section prefix="c">Any peace officer who fails to successfully complete in-service training within the specified time periods, including extensions, shall lose his or her law enforcement powers and his or her certification status shall be changed to training deficiency status. </section><section prefix="d">When a peace officer is deficient in required training, the commissioner of the department or his or her designee shall notify the council, which shall notify the peace officer and his or her agency. </section><section prefix="e">The requirements of this subsection shall be waived for the period of time that a peace officer is serving on active duty in the United States Armed Forces. </section><section prefix="f">This waiver shall be retroactive for peace officers from the date of September 11, 2001. </section></section><section prefix="3">An officer who has lost his or her law enforcement powers due solely to his or her failure to meet the in-service training requirements of this section may regain his or her certification status and law enforcement powers upon successful completion of the training deficiency. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=952</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>