<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="109" order_by="109">LOCAL SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>109.056</section_number><catch_line>Tax levy -- Service charges. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any county or waste management district, if authorized by all the counties that comprise the district, may levy an annual tax, not to exceed ten cents ($0.10) on each one hundred dollars ($100) of assessed valuation of real property within the area subject to taxation for county purposes. The proceeds of such tax shall be used for solid waste management expenses of the area and for redemption of any bonds issued. </section><section prefix="2">The county or waste management district, if authorized by the counties that comprise the district, may in lieu of the tax provided in subsection (1) of this section or in addition thereto finance the maintenance, operation, and capital acquisition costs of the area by fees to be collected from all persons receiving services from the area. The charges shall be fixed in amounts as can be reasonably expected to yield revenues not in excess of the cost of operation and maintenance of the system and for an adequate depreciation fund and amortization of capital acquisition costs. </section><section prefix="3">The service charges authorized by subsections (1) and (2) of this section may be collected by the area directly or the area may enter into an agreement with other utilities either public or private to collect such charges. </section></text><history>Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 32, effective February 26, 1991. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective>February 26, 1991 </effective><former-codification> KRS 109.180 </former-codification><lrc-note>.  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>