<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.2-105</section_number><catch_line>Examination of contents of a decedent's safe deposit box to find will or funeral arrangements. </catch_line><order_by>2-105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If satisfactory proof of the death of the lessee is presented and the interested person possesses a key to the lessee's safe deposit box, a lessor shall permit an interested person to open and examine the contents of a safe deposit box leased by a decedent in the presence of an employee of the lessor for one (1) or both of the following purposes: <section prefix="a">To conduct a will search; and </section><section prefix="b">To obtain any document purporting to be a deed to a burial plot or to give funeral or burial instructions. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the safe deposit box is opened for the purpose of conducting a will search, an employee of the lessor shall remove any document that appears to be a will and make a true and correct machine copy thereof, replace the copy in the box, and then deliver the original thereof to the person requesting the search. </section><section prefix="3">If the safe deposit box is opened for the purpose of obtaining any document purporting to be a deed to a burial plot or to give funeral or burial instructions, the employee of the lessor shall make a true and correct machine copy thereof, replace the copy in the box, and then deliver the original thereof to the person requesting the search. </section><section prefix="4">No contents of a safe deposit box other than a will and a document purporting to be a deed to a burial plot or to give funeral or burial instructions may be removed under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification> KRS 286.105. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14516</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>