<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.460</section_number><catch_line>Registration of elevators and fixed guideway systems -- Time of registration.   </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owner or user of any elevator or fixed guideway system shall register with the department every elevator or fixed guideway system operated by him or her, giving the type, capacity, description, name of manufacturer, and purpose for which each is used. The registration shall be made on a form to be furnished by the department. </section><section prefix="2">If the department has the information required by subsection (1) of this section in its possession, the owner or lessee shall not be required to duplicate the information. Elevators and fixed guideway systems for which construction has begun after July 1, 2011, shall be registered at the time they are completed and placed in service. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 266, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 116, sec. 23, effective July 1, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 80. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><former-codification> KRS 336.590. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 116, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/1/2011).  A reference to the "Office" of Housing, Buildings and Construction in this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 23, has been changed in codification to the "Department" of Housing, Buildings and Construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>