<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.920</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>920</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state board shall do all of the following: <section prefix="a">Meet not less than twice annually at the call of the chairperson; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) year after the original appointment of the state board, and biennially thereafter, develop a state plan for the distribution of funds from the trust fund. In developing the plan, the state board shall review already existing prevention programs. The plan shall assure that an equal opportunity exists for establishment of prevention programs and receipt of trust fund money among all geographic areas in this state. The plan shall be transmitted to the clerk of the House of Representatives, to the clerk of the Senate, and to the Governor; </section><section prefix="c">Provide for the coordination and exchange of information on the establishment and maintenance of prevention programs; </section><section prefix="d">Develop and publicize criteria for the receipt of trust fund money by eligible local task forces and eligible prevention programs; </section><section prefix="e">Review, approve, and monitor the expenditure of trust fund money by local task forces and prevention programs; </section><section prefix="f">Provide statewide educational and public informational seminars for the purpose of developing appropriate public awareness regarding the prevention of child sexual abuse and exploitation; encourage professional persons and groups to recognize and deal with prevention of child sexual abuse and exploitation; encourage and coordinate the development of local task forces; make information about the prevention of child sexual abuse and exploitation available to the public and organizations and agencies which deal with problems of child sexual abuse and exploitation; and encourage the development of community prevention programs; and </section><section prefix="g">Establish a procedure for an annual, internal evaluation of the functions, responsibilities, and performance of the state board. In a year in which the biennial state plan is prepared, the evaluation shall be coordinated with the preparation of the state plan. </section></section><section prefix="2">The state board may enter into contracts with public or private agencies to fulfill the requirements of this section. The state board shall utilize existing state resources and staff of participating departments whenever practicable. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1014</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>