<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">TURNPIKE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175.580</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance of turnpike -- Restoration of private property -- Donation of property by county or city -- Annual report of turnpike activities -- Audits -- Prohibition of interest of department or authority personnel. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in the agreement or lease relating thereto, each turnpike project when constructed and opened to traffic shall be maintained and kept in good condition and repair by the department under the terms and provisions of the agreement or lease, and shall be operated and maintained by such force of tolltakers, and other operating and maintenance employees, as the department may in its discretion employ, and the department shall not be reimbursed for the cost thereof unless expressly otherwise provided in the agreement or lease. </section><section prefix="2">All private property damaged or destroyed in carrying out the powers granted by this chapter shall be restored or repaired and placed in its original condition as nearly as practicable or adequate compensation made therefor out of funds provided under the authority of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">All counties, cities, towns and other political subdivisions and all public agencies and commissions of the Commonwealth, notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, may lease, lend, grant or convey to the authority at its request, upon such terms and conditions as the proper authorities of the counties, cities, towns, political subdivisions, agencies or commissions of the Commonwealth deem reasonable and fair and without the necessity for any advertisement, order of court or other action or formality, other than the regular and formal action of the authorities concerned, any real property which is necessary or convenient to the effectuation of the authorized purposes of the authority, including public roads and other real property already devoted to public use. </section><section prefix="4">On or before January 30 in each year the authority shall make an annual report of its activities for the preceding year to the Governor and to the General Assembly. Each such report shall set forth a complete operating and financial statement covering its operations during the year. The authority shall cause an audit of its books and accounts to be made at least once in each year by certified public accountants and the cost thereof may be treated as a part of the cost of construction or operation of the project. Such audits are public records within meaning of KRS 61.870(2). </section><section prefix="5">No officer or employee of the authority or of the department shall have any interest, direct or indirect, in the sale or purchase of any bonds authorized by this chapter. Violation of this provision shall be punishable by a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or by imprisonment for not more than one (1) year, or both. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 131, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 161. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5090</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>