<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.211</section_number><catch_line>Secretary to correct any underpayment or overpayment of public assistance benefits. </catch_line><order_by>211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided by law, the secretary may, in accordance with the regulations he may prescribe and to the extent permitted by federal law, take all necessary steps to correct any underpayment or overpayment of public assistance benefits under this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">Recovery of overpayments by the secretary may be accomplished through repayment, reduction of future public assistance benefits, or by civil action in the Circuit or District Court depending upon the jurisdictional amount involved. </section><section prefix="3">No reduction in future benefits or civil action shall be instituted except after notice and an opportunity for a fair hearing have been given and the administrative and judicial remedies provided by this chapter have been either exhausted or abandoned. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this section, overpayment shall include payments made to or in behalf of an eligible person in excess of the amount of public assistance benefits to which they are entitled as defined by regulation, payments made to ineligible persons and payments made to persons pending a fair hearing decision or court decision. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit criminal prosecution for fraud under any other statute. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 1, effective March 26, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>March 26, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7658</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>