<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.282</section_number><catch_line>Operation of low-speed vehicle on highway. </catch_line><order_by>282</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "low-speed vehicle" shall have the same meaning as in KRS 186.010. </section><section prefix="2">A person may operate a low-speed vehicle on a highway if: <section prefix="a">The vehicle meets the federal motor vehicle safety standards for low-speed vehicles set forth in 49 C.F.R. sec. 571.500; </section><section prefix="b">The vehicle displays a seventeen (17) character vehicle identification number that meets the requirements set forth in 49 C.F.R. 565; </section><section prefix="c">The posted speed limit of the highway is thirty-five (35) miles per hour or less; </section><section prefix="d">The operator of the low-speed vehicle does not cross a roadway at an at-grade intersection where the roadway being crossed has a posted speed limit of more than thirty-five (35) miles per hour unless the intersection is equipped with an electronic traffic signal; </section><section prefix="e">The operator has a valid operator's license in his or her possession; and </section><section prefix="f">The low-speed vehicle has not been modified to increase its speed above its original standard manufactured limit. </section></section><section prefix="3">A low-speed vehicle operating on a highway shall be insured in compliance with KRS 304.39-080 by the owner or operator, and the proof of insurance shall be inside the vehicle at all times of operation on a highway. </section><section prefix="4">A low-speed vehicle operating on a highway is considered to be a motor vehicle as defined in KRS 186.010 and shall be titled in accordance with KRS Chapter 186A and registered as a motor vehicle in accordance with KRS 186.050(3)(a). </section><section prefix="5">An operator of a low-speed vehicle operating on a highway shall comply with the traffic regulations of KRS Chapter 189 and shall be subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 189A. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6359</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>