<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.11-020</section_number><catch_line>Unauthorized Insurer's Law -- Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>11-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Other than KRS 304.11-050, the provisions of KRS 304.11-020 to 304.11-050, shall not apply to any insurance company or underwriter issuing contracts of insurance to industrial insureds, government entity insureds, and exempt commercial policyholders, nor to any contract of insurance issued to any one (1) or more industrial insureds. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of this section: <section prefix="a">An "industrial insured" is: <section prefix="1">An insured who procures the insurance of any risk or risks other than life and annuity contracts by use of the services of a full-time employee acting as an insurance manager or buyer or the services of a regularly and continuously retained qualified insurance consultant; and </section><section prefix="2">An insured whose aggregate annual premiums for insurance on all risks total at least twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000); and </section><section prefix="3">An insured having at least twenty-five (25) full-time employees; and </section><section prefix="4">All entities that have qualified as industrial insureds as of July 1, 1999; </section></section><section prefix="b">A "government entity insured" is an insured: <section prefix="1">That is a government entity, municipal corporation, or public agency located in a city or county having a population of less than fifty thousand (50,000); and </section><section prefix="2">That procures the insurance of any risk or risks, other than life and annuity contracts, by use of the services of a full-time employee acting as an insurance manager or buyer, or by the use of the services of a regularly and continuously retained qualified insurance consultant; and </section><section prefix="3">Whose aggregate annual premiums for insurance on all risks total at least one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), exclusive of life, health, medical, or annuity premiums; and </section><section prefix="4">That has at least fifty (50) full-time employees; and </section><section prefix="5">That satisfies the criteria the commissioner promulgates by administrative regulation; and </section></section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">An "exempt commercial policyholder" means an insured that employs the services of an insurance agent or broker, procures commercial insurance with the services of a full-time risk manager, or a licensed insurance consultant, pursuant to Subtitle 9 of this chapter and: <section prefix="a">Is a city, county, or urban-county with a population of at least fifty thousand (50,000) persons, or the Commonwealth, or a not-for-profit organization or a public entity with an annual budget of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000) or assets of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000) in the preceding fiscal year; or </section><section prefix="b">Certifies that it meets all four (4) of the following criteria: </section> i. Possesses a net worth of more than twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000) at the time the policy of insurance is issued;  ii. Generated net revenue or sales of more than fifty million dollars ($50,000,000) in the preceding fiscal year;  iii. Employs more than one hundred (100) employees per individual company or two hundred (200) employees per holding company aggregate at the time the policy of insurance is issued; and  iv. Paid annual aggregate insurance premiums of more than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) in the preceding fiscal year. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this subsection, "risk manager" means a person qualified to assess an exempt commercial policyholder's insurance needs and analyze and negotiate a policy of insurance on behalf of an exempt commercial policyholder. A risk manager shall be: <section prefix="a">A full-time employee of an exempt commercial policyholder who holds a professional designation relevant to the type of insurance to be purchased by the exempt commercial policyholder; or </section><section prefix="b">A person retained by an exempt commercial policyholder who holds a professional designation relevant to the type of insurance to be purchased by the exempt commercial policyholder. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Policies issued to industrial insureds, government entity insureds, and exempt commercial policyholders are exempt from the rate and policy form requirements of this chapter. </section><section prefix="b">Policies issued to industrial insureds, government entity insureds, and exempt commercial policyholders shall contain a disclaimer in language similar to the following: "The rate provided for in this policy is exempt from the filing and approval requirements of Subtitle 13 of KRS Chapter 304. The forms which make up this policy contract are exempt from the filing and approval requirements of Subtitle 14 of KRS Chapter 304." </section><section prefix="c">The exemption of commercial policyholders under this section shall not apply to Subtitle 39 of this chapter, KRS Chapter 342, sections in Subtitle 13 of this chapter that pertain to workers' compensation insurance, and KRS 304.12-230. </section></section><section prefix="4">All industrial insureds, government entity insureds, and exempt commercial policyholders shall reapply to the commissioner for their respective insured status every three (3) years, on a form the commissioner shall promulgate by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="5">KRS 304.11-020 to 304.11-050, inclusive, shall not apply to any life insurance company organized and operated, without profit to any private shareholder or individual, exclusively for the purpose of aiding educational or scientific institutions organized and operated without profit to any private shareholder or individual by issuing insurance and annuity contracts directly from the home office of the company and without agents or representatives in this state only to or for the benefit of such institutions and to individuals engaged in the services of such institutions, nor to any policy or contract which it issues; but this exemption shall be conditioned upon any such company complying with the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Payment of an annual registration fee; </section><section prefix="b">Filing a copy of any policy or contract issued to Kentucky residents with the commissioner; </section><section prefix="c">Filing a copy of its annual statement prepared pursuant to the laws of its state of domicile, as well as such other financial material as may be requested, with the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="d">Providing, in such form as may be acceptable for the appointment of the Secretary of State as its true and lawful attorney upon whom may be served all lawful process in any action or proceeding against such company arising out of any policy or contract it has issued to, or which is currently held by, a Kentucky citizen and process so served against such company shall have the same force and validity as if served upon the company. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1101, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 166, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 320, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 11, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 166, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>