<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-430</section_number><catch_line>Twenty percent discount. </catch_line><order_by>20-430</order_by><text>Motor vehicle insurance companies shall give a twenty percent (20%) discount on comprehensive coverage on any motor vehicle equipped with any of the following antitheft devices: <section prefix="1">Passive alarm system which meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Ignition shall be cut off automatically, or starter shall be disabled automatically; </section><section prefix="b">Alarm shall be triggered by entry of doors, hood, or trunk; </section><section prefix="c">Hood shall not open unless unlocked from inside the vehicle by a key or by an electronic keyless device; </section><section prefix="d">Alarm shall sound for no more than eight (8) minutes and shall reset itself; </section><section prefix="e">Alarm shall not emit a pulsating, whooping, or yelping sound which could cause it to be mistaken for the police, fire, or other emergency vehicle siren; </section><section prefix="f">Alarm shall be installed in the engine compartment so as to be inaccessible without opening the hood; and </section><section prefix="g">The system shall be engaged passively by turning the ignition key to the off position. A tubular lock or electronic keyless device shall be used to disarm the system; </section></section><section prefix="2">Passive fuel cutoff device which is engaged by turning the ignition key to the off position and which requires that a trip be switched to start the motor vehicle and which meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The fuel line shall be blocked when the power is off; </section><section prefix="b">The switch to open the fuel line shall be hidden from view but accessible to the driver from the driver's seat or a tubular key or electronic keyless device may be used; </section><section prefix="c">A parking service attendant override switch may be provided which is not accessible from the passenger compartment unless a warning buzzer sounds while the engine is running and the override switch is engaged; and </section><section prefix="d">Any under the dash wiring installed with the device shall blend in color with factory-installed wiring; </section></section><section prefix="3">Armored ignition cutoff switch which is designed to resist tampering and which meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Armored cable shall run from a separate key to the coil, starter, solenoid, or other engine component; </section><section prefix="b">The device shall prevent hot-wiring of the motor vehicle; and </section><section prefix="c">A separate lock shall be of tubular type and installed inside the motor vehicle or an electronic keyless device may be used; </section></section><section prefix="4">Passive multi-component cutoff switch which is activated when the key is turned to the off position and which meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The primary wire to the ignition coil shall be disconnected; </section><section prefix="b">The device shall disconnect the starter; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) or more wires to the electronic ignition system or to the points and condenser shall be disconnected and grounded to the chassis; </section><section prefix="d">The wiring shall blend with factory-installed wiring and the disconnecting/grounding wires shall be routed to random points in the electrical system; </section><section prefix="e">The control module, if separate from the electronic locking mechanism, shall be hidden in the engine compartment or other place where it will not be easily detectable; and </section><section prefix="f">In order to start the car, a lock or electronic device shall be used to deactivate the system. </section></section><section prefix="5">Passive time delay ignition system which requires the operator to wait a prescribed time before moving the ignition key from the on position to the start position; </section><section prefix="6">Armored cable or electrically operated hood lock and ignition cutoff switch which is a supplemental hood lock operated from within the motor vehicle and which also cuts off the ignition when engaged and meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Armored cable hood lock shall have tubing which extends through the firewall. The system shall be engaged by a pushbutton or other device which facilitates use and no portion of the hood lock cable may be accessible from underneath the motor vehicle; and </section><section prefix="b">Electrically operated hood lock shall remain locked even if the wiring operating the hood lock is cut. The system shall be engaged by turning the ignition key to the off position. The lock shall be shielded or armored so that it cannot be operated manually. </section></section><section prefix="7">Passive, delayed ignition cutoff system which disables the ignition circuit at a preset engine speed and meets the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The ignition shall cut off automatically as soon as the engine reaches a speed in the range of fifteen hundred (1,500) to two thousand (2,000) RPM; </section><section prefix="b">The system shall be automatically armed when the ignition key is turned to the off position; </section><section prefix="c">A pushbutton or other type of disarm switch shall be well hidden and the wiring shall blend with factory-installed wiring if placed under the dash; </section><section prefix="d">An alarm or horn shall be actuated at the same time the ignition is disabled; and </section><section prefix="e">If a parking service attendant switch is provided, a buzzer shall sound all the time the engine is running; </section></section><section prefix="8">Passive ignition lock protective system that consists of a protective cap which fits over the ignition to prevent extraction of the ignition lock cylinder; or </section><section prefix="9">High security ignition replacement lock which conforms to federal standards and cannot be removed using a conventional slide hammer or lock puller equipment. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>