<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.060</section_number><catch_line>Duties of probation officers. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>Probation officers appointed pursuant to KRS 605.050 shall: <section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS Chapter 645, make investigations as provided in this chapter, including the administration of a validated risk and needs assessment; </section><section prefix="2">Be present in court to represent the interest of the child when the cases investigated by them are heard, furnish such information as may be required, including the results of a validated risk and needs assessment, advise the court as to the proper disposition of the case and take such charge of the child before and after the hearings as may be ordered; </section><section prefix="3">Visit and supervise children placed on probation and as far as practicable, aid and encourage such children, by friendly advice and admonition, to keep terms of their probation, and provide for their rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="4">Make such reports and records as may be required by the court; </section><section prefix="5">Supervise the transfer of children to and from homes or facilities as directed by the court; and </section><section prefix="6">Work in cooperation with the representatives of the cabinet. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 5, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43503</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>