<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.196</section_number><catch_line>Individual education plan for exceptional children -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>196</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly declares that parents play a critical role in the education of their students. Parents have a major responsibility to assist in the education of their students and deserve respect and meaningful involvement in the decision-making process related to the students' education. </section><section prefix="2">Each exceptional student as defined in KRS 157.200 shall have an individual education plan that shall serve as the centerpiece of the student's educational career and the communication vehicle between the parents and school personnel. The plan shall enable the parents and school personnel to decide the student's educational needs, the services needed to achieve those needs, and the anticipated results. The plan shall be used as a document to monitor the student's progress. School personnel shall provide the parents with reports of the progress toward the student's annual goals at least as often as report cards go to nondisabled students. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing procedures for the development and monitoring of individual education plans that are in compliance with the Federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, as amended. These administrative regulations shall be written in clear, easily understood language that is free of education jargon. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>