<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.448</section_number><catch_line>Liability of officers of business organizations for gasoline and special fuels tax -- Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>448</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, the president, vice president, secretary, treasurer, or any other person holding any equivalent corporate office of any corporation subject to the provisions of KRS 138.210 to 138.446 shall be personally and individually liable, both jointly and severally, for the tax imposed under KRS 138.210 to 138.446. Corporate dissolution, withdrawal of the corporation from the state, or the cessation of holding any corporate office shall not discharge the liability of any person. The personal and individual liability shall apply to each and every person holding a corporate office at the time the tax becomes or became due. No person shall be personally and individually liable under this subsection who had no authority to collect, truthfully account for, or pay over any tax imposed by KRS 138.210 to 138.446 at the time the tax imposed becomes or became due. "Taxes" as used in this section shall include interest accrued at the rate provided by KRS 131.183, all applicable penalties imposed under the provisions of this chapter, and all applicable penalties imposed under the provisions of KRS 131.180, 131.410 to 131.445, and 131.990. <section prefix="a">The provisions of this section shall not apply if a corporation on an annual basis elects to be exempt from the provisions of KRS 138.224 by: <section prefix="1">Filing with the department a financial instrument in an amount not to exceed two (2) months' estimated liability, as calculated by the department, or five thousand dollars ($5,000), whichever is greater; </section><section prefix="2">Certifying by an electronic method acceptable by both the dealer and the department no later than the fifteenth day of each month the amount of gasoline and special fuels tax due the Commonwealth by the twenty-fifth day of that month; and </section><section prefix="3">Agreeing to initiate an Automated Clearing House credit transaction to electronically transfer the amount of tax from the dealer's account to the Kentucky State Treasurer on the twenty-fifth day of that month. </section></section> For the purpose of this paragraph, a "financial instrument" means a bond issued by a corporation authorized to do business in Kentucky, a line of credit, or an account with a financial institution maintaining a compensating balance. <section prefix="b">If a dealer fails to certify the amount of tax collected or does not perform the electronic fund transfer as prescribed by paragraph (a) of this subsection, the department may immediately make demand of the financial instrument and revoke the license of the dealer notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 138.340, and the provisions of this section shall apply. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, KRS 275.150, 362.1-306(3) or predecessor law, or 362.2-404(3) to the contrary, the managers of a limited liability company, the partners of a limited liability partnership, and the general partners of a limited liability limited partnership or any other person holding any equivalent office of a limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership subject to the provisions of KRS 138.210 to 138.446 shall be personally and individually liable, both jointly and severally, for the tax imposed under KRS 138.210 to 138.446. Dissolution, withdrawal of the limited liability company, limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership from the state, or the cessation of holding any office shall not discharge the liability of any person. The personal and individual liability shall apply to each and every manager of a limited liability company, partner of a limited liability partnership and general partner of a limited liability limited partnership at the time the tax becomes or became due. No person shall be personally and individually liable under this subsection who had no authority to collect, truthfully account for, or pay over any tax imposed by KRS 138.210 to 138.446 at the time the tax becomes or became due. "Taxes" as used in this section shall include interest accrued at the rate provided by KRS 131.183, all applicable penalties imposed under the provisions of this chapter, and all applicable penalties imposed under the provisions of KRS 131.180, 131.410 to 131.445, and KRS 131.990. <section prefix="a">The provisions of this section shall not apply if a limited liability company, a limited liability partnership, or limited liability limited partnership on an annual basis elects to be exempt from the provisions of KRS 138.224 by: <section prefix="1">Filing with the department a financial instrument in an amount not to exceed two (2) months' estimated liability, as calculated by the department, or five thousand dollars ($5,000), whichever is greater; </section><section prefix="2">Certifying by an electronic method acceptable by both the dealer and the department no later than the fifteenth day of each month the amount of gasoline and special fuels tax due the Commonwealth by the twenty-fifth day of that month; and </section><section prefix="3">Agreeing to initiate an Automated Clearing House credit transaction to electronically transfer the amount of tax from the dealer's account to the Kentucky State Treasurer on the twenty-fifth day of that month. </section></section> For the purpose of this paragraph, a "financial instrument" means a bond issued by a corporation authorized to do business in Kentucky, a line of credit, or an account with a financial institution maintaining a compensating balance. <section prefix="b">If a dealer fails to certify the amount of tax collected or does not perform the electronic fund transfer prescribed by paragraph (a) of this subsection, the department may immediately make demand of the financial instrument and revoke the license of the dealer notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 138.340, and the provisions of this section shall apply. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 200, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 384, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 15, effective January 1, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2003). The provisions of subsection (2) of this statute created in 2002 Ky. Acts ch.366, sec.15, "apply retroactively to July 15, 1994." 2002 Ky. Acts ch.366, sec.19. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>