<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.130</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for issuance of license. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not be issued a commercial driver's license unless that person: <section prefix="a">Is a resident of this state; </section><section prefix="b">Holds a valid operator's license; </section><section prefix="c">Has complied with the provisions of KRS 281A.300; </section><section prefix="d">Except as provided in KRS 281A.165, has passed the knowledge and skills tests for driving a commercial motor vehicle which comply with minimum federal standards established by federal regulation enumerated in Title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, Part 383, as adopted by the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="e">Has satisfied all other safety requirements including those requirements imposed by state law or federal regulation. The tests shall be prescribed and conducted as set forth in KRS 281A.160. </section></section><section prefix="2">A commercial driver's license, or commercial driver's instruction permit shall not be issued to a person while the person is subject to a disqualification from driving a commercial motor vehicle, or while the person's driver's license or driving privilege is suspended, revoked, or canceled in any state or jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="3">A commercial driver's license shall not be issued to a person who has a commercial driver's license issued by any other state unless the person first surrenders all such licenses, which shall be returned to the issuing jurisdiction for cancellation. </section><section prefix="4">To ensure that an applicant for a commercial driver's license or instruction permit complies with the requirements of subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the circuit clerk shall verify through the commercial driver's license information system and national driver register that the person applying for a Kentucky CDL does not currently have his or her operator's license or driving privilege suspended or revoked in another licensing jurisdiction. If the person's operator's license or driving privilege is currently suspended or revoked in another licensing jurisdiction, the circuit clerk shall not issue the person a Kentucky CDL until the person resolves the matter in the other licensing jurisdiction and complies with the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 186. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 5, effective April 5, 2002. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 13, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39638</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>