<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.070</section_number><catch_line>Specialized rescue squad -- Activities permitted. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A specialized rescue squad shall engage in one or more of the activities listed in the definition of a specialized rescue squad. A specialized rescue squad may engage in any other activity, other than the ones prohibited by law or administrative regulation, if the activity is specified in its mission statement. </section><section prefix="2">A specialized rescue squad shall not engage in a general rescue squad activity as a primary mission unless it meets the requirements of subsection (3) of this section. A specialized rescue squad may engage in a general rescue squad activity as an initial responding unit within its service area, however, upon responding to that activity, the highest officer in command of the response shall cause the immediate notification of the appropriate general rescue squad for assistance, the local director, and the duty officer of the Division of Emergency Management. </section><section prefix="3">A specialized rescue squad may engage in a general rescue squad activity if: <section prefix="a">That activity is specified in its mission statement; </section><section prefix="b">The rescue squad has twelve (12) persons including a commanding officer from within the membership of the specialized rescue squad whose mission statement is to engage in the general rescue squad activity; </section><section prefix="c">The persons assigned to the general rescue squad activity meet the training requirements specified by statute and administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="d">The rescue squad has the equipment required by administrative regulation to engage in general rescue squad activity as listed in its mission statement; and </section><section prefix="e">The rescue squad has a vehicle for transporting the required equipment to the scene. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 89, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21800</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>