<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.446</section_number><catch_line>Annual grants of block grant funds -- Allocation formula -- Use of funds -- Services to be provided -- Matching fund requirements -- Other funds. </catch_line><order_by>446</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state administering agency shall annually grant community services block grant funds under the federal act to community action agencies designated by political subdivisions as provided under KRS 273.435 and 273.437. </section><section prefix="2">An allocation formula for community services block grant funds shall be devised by the state administering agency. The allocation formula shall be based on the 1981 federal fiscal year federal community services administration grantee based allocation and the incidence and severity of poverty throughout the Commonwealth. The formula shall be set forth in administrative regulation by the state administering agency. </section><section prefix="3">Any level of local match to be required by the state administering agency shall not exceed twenty percent (20%) of each community action agency's total annual allocation under the federal act. Community action agencies shall not be prohibited from using noncash resources to meet any match requirement of the state administering agency. </section><section prefix="4">The services to be provided with funds made available under the federal act shall be determined and prioritized by each community action agency in accordance with the allowable services and intended beneficiaries as set forth under KRS 273.443. </section><section prefix="5">Community services block grant funds made available under the federal act shall be used in accordance with the provisions set forth in KRS 273.441 and 273.443, provided that a portion of such funds shall be applied for legislative oversight in accordance with KRS 45.358. </section><section prefix="6">The state administering agency, Governor or his designee may grant to community action agencies such other state and federal funds the purposes of which are in accordance with the provisions set forth in KRS 273.443. </section><section prefix="7">For such other state or federal program funds applicable to the services and activities set forth in KRS 273.443, the Governor shall, upon a determination of community action agencies' capability for utilizing such funds in a manner so as to fulfill the purpose of those funds and to fulfill the policy set forth in KRS 273.405, give special consideration to utilizing community action agencies in implementing such programs. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>