<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.10-225</section_number><catch_line>Verification -- Granting of license -- Renewal. </catch_line><order_by>10-225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Following verification by the department of the information contained in the application, every person having satisfied the provisions of KRS 286.10-200 to 286.10-285 and KRS 286.10-991 and having paid the business taxes and any other taxes required by law shall be granted a license as set forth in this section. The license issued under this section shall state the name of the person to whom issued, the place of business, and street address where the title pledge office is located. The license shall entitle the person to do business at the place designated on the license. The license shall not be transferable from one (1) person to another but, upon approval of the commissioner, may be transferred from one (1) location to another within the county of the location originally licensed. </section><section prefix="2">A title pledge lender license shall be renewed each year upon payment of an annual fee of five hundred dollars ($500) and compliance with the provisions of KRS 286.10-200 to 286.10-285 and KRS 286.10-991. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 826, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.225. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>