<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.550</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against buying, selling, or processing eggs without license -- Exceptions -- Stop orders and withdraw from sale orders imposed for certain violations. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall buy, sell, trade, traffic, or process eggs in Kentucky without a license issued pursuant to the egg marketing law, with the following exceptions: <section prefix="a">Hatcheries purchasing eggs to be used exclusively for hatching purposes; </section><section prefix="b">Hotels, restaurants, and other eating places where all eggs purchased are served in the establishment; </section><section prefix="c">Bakeries, confectioneries, and ice cream manufacturers who use eggs in a manufactured product; </section><section prefix="d">Consumers buying eggs for their own consumption; or </section><section prefix="e">Producers who sell only directly to consumers and do not exceed a sales limit of sixty (60) dozen eggs per calendar week. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person engaged in the act of selling shell eggs or egg products under any of the following circumstances shall have all shell eggs and egg products placed under a stop order: <section prefix="a">Selling or otherwise marketing shell eggs or egg products without a license; </section><section prefix="b">Selling or otherwise marketing shell eggs or egg products without first submitting an emergency recall plan to the department; or </section><section prefix="c">Failing to remit or pay fines owed to the department. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person engaged in the act of selling or otherwise marketing shell eggs under the following conditions shall have those eggs placed under a stop order for: <section prefix="a">Failing to have the proper labels attached, as required by KRS 260.630; or </section><section prefix="b">Failing to meet the tolerances of consumer grades and consumer grade quality standards, as required by KRS 260.620. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person engaged in the act of selling or otherwise marketing shell eggs or egg products shall have these shell eggs or egg products placed under a withdraw from sale order for the following reasons: <section prefix="a">Ambient temperature above forty-five (45) degrees Fahrenheit for a period of four (4) hours or more; or </section><section prefix="b">Contamination or any condition which may render the shell eggs or egg products unfit for human consumption. </section></section> The withdraw from sale order shall remain in effect until such time as the disposition of the shell eggs or egg products has been determined by the department. </text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1957. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12596</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>