<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.045</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Personnel Board -- Membership -- Prohibited Acts. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Personnel Board in which shall be vested the constitutional powers and responsibilities of officers of the Commonwealth. The board shall consist of seven (7) members, five (5) of whom shall be appointed by the Governor as provided in KRS 18A.050. Two (2) members of the board shall be elected by classified employees as provided in KRS 18A.0551. </section><section prefix="2">Personnel Board members shall not accept gifts as provided in KRS 11A.045(1), benefit under any contract or agreement as provided in KRS 11A.040(4), or fail to disclose to other members of the board any direct or indirect conflict of interest as described in KRS 11A.005(2)(c). </section><section prefix="3">Any person retaliating in any manner and any person ordering retaliation against a classified employee or a member of his family because he has participated in an election to the board, either by being a candidate or voting for a candidate, shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 18A.990. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 4, effective April 13, 2010. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1348</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>