<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-100</section_number><catch_line>Statewide network for information transfer and assistance -- Purpose. </catch_line><order_by>10-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall establish a statewide network of information transfer and assistance linkages with appropriate local economic development agencies and entities providing economic development services and financing. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the network shall be to facilitate strategic planning and coordinate service delivery by providing ready access by communities and businesses to all aspects of cabinet operations and to all providers of economic development assistance, and by providing the cabinet with ready access to the most complete and up-to-date information concerning communities, businesses, and economic development service providers. </section><section prefix="3">The network shall employ, to the greatest extent feasible, compatible hardware and software and common databases and library and information services networks in order to ensure a free flow of information and assistance among the components of the network. </section><section prefix="4">In those communities and regions which do not have appropriate existing economic development organizations or agencies, the cabinet shall serve as a catalyst to bring together the elements of private businesses, education, government, and community leaders necessary to form a local or regional economic development operation. Upon the establishment of an appropriate organization, it shall become an element of the statewide economic development network. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>