<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.23-005</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings for KRS 154.23-005 to 154.23-079. </catch_line><order_by>23-005</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds and declares as follows: <section prefix="1">That the general welfare and material well-being of the citizens of the Commonwealth, particularly those residing in qualified zones, depends in large measure upon development and growth of manufacturing and service or technology industries in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">It is in the best interest of the Commonwealth to create new sources of tax revenues for the support of public services, to induce the location and expansion of manufacturing and service or technology industries within qualified zones, and to advance the public purposes of relieving unemployment and providing employment opportunities that would not exist but for the inducements offered by the authority to eligible companies; and </section><section prefix="3">That the authority granted by KRS 154.23-005 to 154.23-079 and purposes to be accomplished under KRS 154.23-005 to 154.23-079 are proper governmental and public purposes for which public moneys may be expended, and the inducements for the location and expansion of manufacturing and service or technology industries within qualified zones is of paramount importance, for which KRS 154.23-005 to 154.23-079 shall be liberally construed and applied to advance public purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 528, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>