<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-614</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for new solid waste disposal facilities and horizontal expansions of existing facilities -- Exemption -- Implementing procedures. </catch_line><order_by>43-614</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All new solid waste disposal facilities and horizontal expansions of existing solid waste disposal facilities, with the exception of construction/demolition or residual landfills, shall meet the design, operating, monitoring, and recordkeeping requirements for contained landfills as defined in accordance with administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet. Special waste, as defined in KRS 224.50-760, except for waste from sanitary wastewater treatment facilities, shall be exempt from this section. </section><section prefix="2">Limited quantity generator hazardous waste as defined by the cabinet and its administrative regulations shall not be disposed in a solid waste disposal facility unless the facility meets the recordkeeping, groundwater monitoring, leachate collection and control systems, and liner system requirements of the administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet for contained landfills. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall implement procedures to assist limited quantity hazardous waste generators to dispose of such waste in compliance with the requirements of this section. Such procedures shall include assistance in the development of limited quantity waste collection and disposal programs, and maintenance of a list of waste sites or facilities which meet the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.), Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 27, effective February 26, 1991. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> February 26, 1991 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.848. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10428</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>