<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.167</section_number><catch_line>Felony-offender record check for employees and members of fire departments, ambulance services, and rescue squads. </catch_line><order_by>167</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "felony offender" means any person who has been convicted of, entered an Alford plea to, or pleaded guilty to the commission of a capital offense or a felony. </section><section prefix="2">Any paid or volunteer fire department certified by the Commission on Fire Protection Personnel Standards and Education, ambulance service licensed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or rescue squad officially affiliated with a local disaster and emergency services organization or with the Division of Emergency Management may apply to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts for a felony offender record check on applicants for employment or membership with the fire department, ambulance service, or rescue squad. </section><section prefix="3">Each application form, provided by a fire department, ambulance service, or rescue squad to an applicant for employment or membership, shall conspicuously state the following: "FOR EMPLOYMENT WITH OR MEMBERSHIP WITH A FIRE DEPARTMENT, AMBULANCE SERVICE, OR RESCUE SQUAD, STATE LAW PERMITS A CRIMINAL RECORD CHECK AS A CONDITION OF EMPLOYMENT OR MEMBERSHIP." </section><section prefix="4">Any request for records under this section shall be on a form approved by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet and the Administrative Office of the Courts shall not charge a fee for making record checks. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 90, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>