<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.210</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 371.210 to 371.330. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>As used in KRS 371.210 to 371.330, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Goods" means all tangible chattels personal when purchased primarily for personal, family or household use and not for commercial, industrial or agricultural use, but not including motor vehicles as herein defined, money, things in action or intangible personal property other than merchandise certificates or coupons as herein described. The term includes such chattels which are furnished or used, at the sale of or subsequently, in the modernization, rehabilitation, repair, alteration, improvement or construction of real property as to become a part thereof whether or not severable therefrom. The term also includes merchandise certificates or coupons, issued by a retail seller, not redeemable in cash and to be used in their face amount in lieu of cash. </section><section prefix="2">"Services" means work, labor or services of any kind when purchased primarily for personal, family or household use and not for commercial or business use, but not including services for which the prices charged are required by law to be determined or approved by or to be filed, subject to approval or disapproval, with the United States or any state, or any department, division, agency, officer or official of either as in the case of transportation services. </section><section prefix="3">"Motor vehicle" means any automobile, mobile home, recreational vehicle, motorcycle, truck trailer, semitrailer, truck tractor and bus designed and used primarily to transport persons or property on a public highway, or any vehicle designed to run only on rails or tracks or in the air, excepting however, any boat trailer and any vehicle propelled or drawn exclusively by muscular power. </section><section prefix="4">"Retail buyer" or "buyer" means a person who buys or agrees to buy goods or obtain services or agrees to have services rendered or furnished, from a retail seller. </section><section prefix="5">"Retail seller" or "seller" means a person regularly and principally engaged in the business of selling goods to retail buyers. </section><section prefix="6">"Retail installment transaction" means any transaction in which a retail buyer purchases goods or services from a retail seller pursuant to a retail installment contract or a retail charge agreement, as defined in this section, which provides for a time price differential, as defined in this section, and under which the buyer agrees to pay the unpaid balance in one (1) or more installments. </section><section prefix="7">"Retail installment contract" means an instrument, other than a retail charge agreement or an instrument reflecting a sale made pursuant thereto, entered into in this state evidencing a retail installment transaction. The term "retail installment contract" may include a chattel mortgage, a security agreement, a conditional sale contract and a contract in the form of a bailment or a lease if the bailee or lessee contracts to pay as compensation for their use a sum substantially equivalent to or in excess of the value of the goods sold and if it is agreed that the bailee or lessee is bound to become, or for no other or a merely nominal consideration, has the option of becoming the owner of the goods upon full compliance with the provisions of the bailment or lease. </section><section prefix="8">"Retail charge agreement" means an instrument prescribing the terms of retail installment transactions which may be made thereunder from time to time and under the terms of which a time price differential, as defined in this section, is to be computed in relation to the buyer's unpaid balance from time to time. </section><section prefix="9">"Time price differential" however denominated or expressed, means the amount which is paid or payable for the privilege of purchasing goods or services to be paid for by the buyer in installments over a period of time. It does not include the amount, if any, charged for insurance premiums, delinquency charges, attorneys fees, court costs, or official fees. </section><section prefix="10">"Cash sale price" means the price stated in a retail installment contract or in a sales slip or other memorandum furnished by a retail seller to a retail buyer under or in connection with a retail charge agreement, for which the seller would have sold or furnished to the buyer and the buyer would have bought or obtained from the seller the goods or services which are the subject matter of a retail installment transaction, if the sale had been a sale for cash. The cash sale price may include any taxes and charges for delivery, installation, servicing, repairs, alterations or improvements. </section><section prefix="11">"Official fees" means the amount of the fees prescribed by law for filing, recording or otherwise perfecting, and releasing or satisfying, a retained title, lien or other security interest created by a retail installment transaction. </section><section prefix="12">"Time sale price" means the total of the cash sale price of the goods or services and the amount, if any, included for insurance, if a separate identified charge is made therefor, and the official fees and the time price differential. </section><section prefix="13">"Principal balance" means the cash sale price of the goods or services which are the subject matter of a retail installment contract plus the amounts, if any, included therein, if a separate identified charge is made therefor and stated in the contract, for insurance and official fees, less the amount of the buyer's down payment in money or goods or both. </section><section prefix="14">"Holder" means the retail seller of the goods or services under the retail installment contract or retail charge agreement or the assignee if the retail installment contract or the retail charge agreement or any indebtedness under either has been sold or otherwise transferred. </section><section prefix="15">"Person" means an individual, partnership, joint venture, corporation, association or any other group, however organized. </section><section prefix="16">Words of the masculine gender include the feminine and the neuter and, when the sense so indicates, words of the neuter gender may refer to any gender. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35239</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>