<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.470</section_number><catch_line>Application of minor -- Renewal of minor's license or permit -- Parental consent to release of academic information to cabinet -- Cancellation. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The application of any minor under the age of eighteen (18) for an operator's license, motorcycle operator's license, intermediate license, or any instruction permit shall not be granted unless the application is signed by a parent or legal guardian of the applicant. Regardless of which parent signs the application, both parents shall be responsible as provided in KRS 186.590. If the minor does not have a father, mother, or guardian, an operator's license, intermediate license, or instruction permit shall not be granted to the minor unless his application is signed by a person willing to assume the obligation imposed by KRS 186.590 upon a person signing the application of a minor. A signature shall not be required in the case of the renewal of a minor's license but the signature on the original application shall continue to make the parent, guardian, or other person liable under the provisions of KRS 186.590 on all renewals of the minor's license until he reaches the age of eighteen (18) unless the license, or any renewal thereof, is canceled as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The application shall include parental consent for the receipt and release of the information as set forth in KRS 159.051 regarding the attendance and academic requirements for a minor to acquire and keep an operator's license, intermediate license, instructional permit, or privilege to operate a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="3">A parent or a guardian of a minor applicant may file with the cabinet a verified written request that the license of the minor be canceled. Thereupon the license of the minor shall be canceled and the person who signed the application shall be relieved as to subsequent acts of the minor from the liability imposed by subsection (1) of KRS 186.590. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet upon receipt of satisfactory evidence of the death of the person who signed the application of a minor for a license shall have the license canceled and no new license shall be issued to the minor until a new application, signed and verified, is made as required by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 7, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 503, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 1; and ch. 386, sec. 33. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 4. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-41. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6065</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>