<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.097</section_number><catch_line>Certification of postsecondary institutions to receive funds for teacher education or model program. </catch_line><order_by>097</order_by><text>No postsecondary education institution shall receive funds from the Council on Postsecondary Education from any trust fund for the purposes of teacher education or model programs of teaching and learning unless the Education Professional Standards Board has certified to the council that the institution has met the following conditions: <section prefix="1">The college or university has developed viable partnerships with local school districts and schools; </section><section prefix="2">There is evidence of ongoing dialogue and collaboration among liberal arts and sciences faculty and administrators with faculty and administrators in the department, school, or college of education; </section><section prefix="3">The college or university has demonstrated a commitment to participate in teacher academies; </section><section prefix="4">The college or university has an active recruitment plan for attracting and retaining minority faculty as well as students, and particularly in the department, school, or college of education; </section><section prefix="5">The college or university has initiated the development of incentives or rewards for faculty across the institution to participate in service activities to local schools; </section><section prefix="6">The department, school, or college of education has developed at least one (1) accelerated alternative plan for teacher education or nontraditional program of teacher preparation, or commits to developing an accelerated alternative or nontraditional program; </section><section prefix="7">The department, school, or college of education provides consistent and quality classroom and field experiences, including early practicums and student teaching experience for all students; </section><section prefix="8">The department, school, or college of education has, as an element of its curriculum, substantial course work and classroom and field experiences directly addressing teacher training in classroom management; </section><section prefix="9">There are no major accreditation deficiencies; and </section><section prefix="10">The institution has demonstrated at least one (1) or more innovations in teacher education. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4202</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>