<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.3-010</section_number><catch_line>Organizers -- Formation of limited cooperative association -- Articles of association.   </catch_line><order_by>3-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited cooperative association shall be organized by one (1) or more organizers. </section><section prefix="2">To form a limited cooperative association, an organizer of the association shall deliver articles of association to the Secretary of State for filing. The limited cooperative association is formed when articles of association that comply with subsection (3) of this section are filed by the Secretary of State, and are effective as determined under KRS 14A.2-070. </section><section prefix="3">The articles of association shall include: <section prefix="a">The name of the association; </section><section prefix="b">The purposes for which the association is formed; </section><section prefix="c">The mailing address of the association’s principal office; </section><section prefix="d">The name and street address of the association’s initial registered office and registered agent that comply with KRS 14A.4-010; </section><section prefix="e">The name and street address and, if different, mailing address of each organizer; and </section><section prefix="f">The term for which the association is to exist if other than perpetual. </section></section><section prefix="4">Subject to KRS 272A.1-110, articles of association may contain any other provisions in addition to those required by subsection (3) of this section not inconsistent with this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>