<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.655</section_number><catch_line>Extension board, powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>655</order_by><text>The extension board of each extension district shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="1">To serve as an agency of the Commonwealth and to manage and transact all of the business and affairs of its district and have authority to acquire property necessary for the conduct of the business of the district for the purposes of KRS 164.605 to 164.675; </section><section prefix="2">To enter into an annual memorandum of agreement with the extension service and the extension district. This memorandum of agreement shall set forth the policy pertaining to (a) appointment of personnel to serve in the district, (b) financing of extension work in the district, and (c) responsibilities of the cooperating parties in planning and executing the program; </section><section prefix="3">To, and shall as soon as possible following the first meeting in which the officers are elected and annually thereafter, file in the office of the county clerk a certificate signed by its chairman and secretary, certifying the names, addresses and terms of office of each member and the names and addresses of the officers of the extension board with the signatures of the officers affixed thereto, and said certificate shall be conclusive as to the organization of the extension district, its extension board and as to its members and its officers; </section><section prefix="4">With the advice of the extension council, to make and adopt such rules and regulations not inconsistent with the law as it may deem necessary for its own government in the transaction of the business of the extension district; </section><section prefix="5">To cooperate with the extension service and the extension council in conducting an extension program in agriculture, home economics, youth work and related subjects in the extension district. Said program shall be planned and executed upon the advice, recommendations and assistance of the extension council with the board to make final decisions; </section><section prefix="6">To cooperate with other extension districts in the employment of personnel, conduct of programs and sponsorship of activities for the mutual benefit of each; </section><section prefix="7">To cooperate with all extension organizations, farm organizations, state and federal agencies, civic clubs and any other organizations who may be interested in and willing to cooperate in conducting the extension programs in the extension district; </section><section prefix="8">To prepare annually not later than April 15 of each year in cooperation with the director of extension an extension district budget for the ensuing year. This budget shall be prepared with consideration being given to the advice and recommendations of the extension council, must be consistent with financing policies of the extension service and shall reflect the agricultural, home economics, youth and related subject matter needs of people in the extension district; </section><section prefix="9">To deposit all district extension education funds in a bank or banks approved by it in the name of the extension district. These receipts shall constitute a fund known as the district cooperative extension education fund which shall be disbursed by the treasurer of the extension board in accordance with the annual budget and the annual memorandum of agreement between the board and the extension service; </section><section prefix="10">To, from time to time when necessary and on approval of the fiscal court, borrow such funds as may be required to meet the financial obligations of the extension district; provided, however, that the extension board cannot in any fiscal year incur indebtedness in an amount which would be in excess of the anticipated revenue of said district for the fiscal year. The amount of the anticipated revenue shall be certified to said board by the fiscal court of the county in which the district is located; </section><section prefix="11">To expand the district cooperative extension education fund for salaries and travel expense of extension personnel, rental, office supplies, equipment, communications, office facilities, services and property acquisition and in payment of such other items as may be necessary to carry out the extension district program; </section><section prefix="12">To carry over unexpended district cooperative extension education funds into the next fiscal year so that funds will be available to carry on the program; provided, however, that such anticipated carry-over funds shall be taken into consideration in the formulation of the extension district budget for the ensuing year; </section><section prefix="13">To comply with the requirements of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090; </section><section prefix="14">To be remunerated from the district cooperative extension education fund for actual expenses incurred in the performance of services for the extension district; provided, however, that payments for expenses must be approved by the extension board; </section><section prefix="15">To accept contributions from fiscal courts and boards of education for use in conducting extension work in the extension district as provided for under KRS 247.080; </section><section prefix="16">To accept private funds for use in conducting extension work in the extension district; provided, however, that the acceptance of all such contributions must be approved by the director of extension; and </section><section prefix="17">To collect reasonable fees for specific services which require special equipment or personnel such as soil testing services, seed testing services or other services in support of the educational program of the extension district. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 58, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41738</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>