<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">HUMAN RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>194.260</section_number><catch_line>Pending business or other matters to be completed by cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text>Any business, litigation, or other matters undertaken or commenced by or against the Kidney Disease Advisory Council, the Family Planning Committee, the Tuberculosis Commission, the Kentucky Manpower Commission, the Kentucky Advisory Committee on Day Care, the Kentucky Children's Advisory Council, the State Advisory Committee for Public Assistance, the Kentucky Commission on Employment of the Handicapped, the Advisory Committee to the Kentucky Commission on Employment of the Handicapped, the Advisory Council on Individuals with an Intellectual Disability, the Developmental Disabilities Act Advisory Council, the Kentucky Commission on Alcoholism and Drug Problems, the Commission on Aging, the Advisory Committee on Aging, the Commission on Handicapped Children, the Commission on Children and Youth, the State Board of Health, the Radiation Operators' Advisory Committee, the Advisory Council for Medical Assistance, the Comprehensive Health Planning Council, and the Kentucky Certificate of Need and Licensure Board and still pending on June 21, 1974, shall be completed and conducted by the cabinet. </text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 399, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 41. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 27. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>