<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.065</section_number><catch_line>Continuing education requirements.   </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Because of the continuous introduction of new therapeutic and diagnostic agents and changing concepts in the practice of pharmacy, it is essential that a pharmacist undertake a program of continuing education to maintain his professional competency to practice in the public interest. </section><section prefix="2">No pharmacist's license shall be renewed until the license holder is able to submit written proof to the board that he has satisfactorily completed, in the previous renewal period, a continuing education program acceptable to the board. Such continuing education requirements shall be determined by regulation of the board, but they shall not require more than an average of one and one-half (1-1/2) continuing education units (CEU) per year. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall adopt rules and regulations to carry out the provisions of this section, to include guidelines and criteria for reviewing and approving continuing education programs. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 18, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 11, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 531, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44621</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>