<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates subsection (2) of KRS 148.051 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned in jail for not less than one (1) day nor more than ten (10) days or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 148.029 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="3">Whoever violates, fails, neglects or refuses to obey any provision of KRS 148.610 to 148.780, or regulation, or order of the commissioner may be compelled to comply with or obey the same by injunction, mandamus, or other appropriate remedy; and provided, further, that whoever violates, fails, neglects, or refuses to obey any provision of KRS 148.610 to 148.780, or regulation, or order of the commissioner shall be punished by a fine of not more than fifty dollars ($50) for each day of such violation. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 148.290 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates KRS 148.290(3), (4), or (5) governing golf cart-type vehicles, all-terrain vehicles, and horse trailers, including administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to that statute, forfeits the rights and privileges, as granted by the commission, of using the vehicle or trailer on State Horse Park property. The executive director of the State Horse Park shall ensure that vehicles or trailers in violation are impounded to the nearest licensed tow company. The owner or operator of such a vehicle or trailer shall pay any and all expenses related to the vehicle's or trailer's towing and impoundment. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1979. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 20. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 2(6). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1828</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>