<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.051</section_number><catch_line>Year-round registration system -- Cabinet may designate separate registration years -- Staggered registration system for commercial motor vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, the cabinet shall by January 1, 1978, establish a year-round system for the registration of vehicles under the provisions of KRS 186.050(1). The system shall be designed so as to distribute the work load as uniformly as practicable within the various offices of the county clerks, as well as the cabinet, on a year-round basis. In implementing a year-round registration system, the cabinet may establish separate and distinct registration years. Each registration year so designated shall begin on the first day of a calendar month and expire on the last day of the last calendar month in a registration period. Registration periods may be designated to include less than twelve (12) consecutive months and registration fees shall be computed at a rate of one-twelfth (1/12) of the appropriate annual registration fee per month in each registration period. The cabinet may establish a registration year of more than twelve (12) months except that registration fees for designated periods of more than twelve (12) months may be paid at the option of the owner. The cabinet may promulgate reasonable administrative regulations to carry out the orderly implementation and administration of the year-round registration system. Any transaction relating to registration or registration renewal which would cause an unexpired Kentucky motor vehicle license plate to be surrendered shall have that unexpired fee prorated or credited against any additional fee required by a subsequent registration. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding the provisions of this chapter, the cabinet shall by April 1, 1980, establish a year-round system for the registration of vehicles under the provisions of KRS 186.050(3)(a). The system shall be designed so as to distribute the work load as uniformly as practicable within the various offices of the county clerks, as well as the cabinet, on a year-round basis. In implementing a year-round registration system, the cabinet may establish separate and distinct registration years. Each registration year so designated shall begin on the first day of a calendar month and expire on the last day of the last calendar month in a registration period. Registration periods may be designated to include less than twelve (12) consecutive months and registration fees shall be computed at a rate of one-twelfth (1/12) of the appropriate annual registration fee per month in each registration period. The cabinet may establish a registration year of more than twelve (12) months except that registration fees for designated periods of more than twelve (12) months may be paid at the option of the owner. The cabinet may promulgate reasonable administrative regulations to carry out the orderly implementation and administration of the year-round registration system. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish a staggered registration system for those commercial motor vehicles registered pursuant to KRS 186.050(13). </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 384, sec. 331, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5934</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>