<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.440</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of information obtained in practice. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A licensee shall not, without the consent of his client, disclose any confidential information pertaining to his client obtained in the course of performing professional services.  </section><section prefix="2">This section does not:  <section prefix="a">Relieve a licensee of any obligations under the rules of professional conduct;  </section><section prefix="b">Affect in any way a licensee's obligation to comply with a validly issued subpoena or summons enforceable by order of a court;  </section><section prefix="c">Prohibit disclosures in the course of a quality review of a licensee's professional services; or  </section><section prefix="d">Preclude a licensee from responding to any inquiry made by the board or any investigative or disciplinary body established by law or formally recognized by the board.  </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the board and professional practice reviewers shall not disclose any confidential client information which comes to their attention from licensees in disciplinary proceedings or otherwise in carrying out their responsibilities, except that they may furnish such information to an investigative or disciplinary body of the kind referred to above.  </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31694</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>