<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.605</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text>As used in KRS 441.610 to 441.695, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Agreement" means a written contract between the authority and any person, firm, corporation, local government, or public entity providing for the construction, reconstruction, improvement or repair and financing of one (1) or more projects of the authority; </section><section prefix="2">"Authority" means the Kentucky Local Correctional Facilities Construction Authority, a body corporate and politic, and an agency and instrumentality of the Commonwealth of Kentucky created by KRS 441.615; </section><section prefix="3">"Bonds" mean revenue bonds, notes or other obligations issued under the provisions of KRS 441.625; </section><section prefix="4">"Cost" means the expenditures for construction, acquisition, financing charges, interest prior to and during construction, principal and interest on any bonds or notes or obligations issued by the authority, engineering and legal expenses, plans, specifications, cost and revenue estimates, other expenses necessary or incidental to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing any project, administrative expenses, and such other expenses necessary or incident to the construction of and placing into operation a project, the financing of such construction and the acquisition of the project; </section><section prefix="5">"Lease" means a written lease executed by the authority as lessor and any local government as lessee; </section><section prefix="6">"Project" means any undertaking to construct, reconstruct, improve, or repair any jail or appurtenant facilities thereof for any county or urban-county government, together with all property, rights, easements and interests which may be acquired by the authority for the construction, reconstruction or repair of any jail or appurtenant facilities; or any undertaking by the authority to finance or refinance, under the provisions of KRS 441.625, the cost of construction or reconstruction of any jail of any county or urban-county government completed and approved by the legislative body thereof since January 1, 1982, provided that such construction or reconstruction is in compliance, at the time such financing or refinancing is approved, with specifications, standards and requirements which are established by the authority to be made applicable to any undertaking by the authority pursuant to KRS 441.625 to 441.695 on or after July 15, 1983; </section><section prefix="7">"Jail" means any county jail and correctional or detention facilities, including correctional facilities defined in KRS 67B.020 and juvenile detention facilities, operated by and under the supervision of any county or urban-county government; </section><section prefix="8">"Local government" means any county or urban-county government. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 5, c, (2) at 651. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19362</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>