<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="72" order_by="72">CORONERS, INQUESTS, AND MEDICAL EXAMINATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>72.405</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>405</order_by><text>As used in KRS 72.410 to 72.470, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Coroner ordered autopsy" means an autopsy ordered by the coroner having jurisdiction and performed by a pathologist pursuant to such authorization in order to ascertain the cause and manner of death in a coroner's case. In the event the pathologist deems it necessary, he may submit the appropriate specimen to a qualified chemist or toxicologist for analysis to assist him in ascertaining the cause of death in a coroner's case; </section><section prefix="2">"Coroner's case" means a case in which the coroner has reasonable cause for believing that the death of a human being within his county was caused by any of the conditions set forth in KRS 72.025; </section><section prefix="3">"Inquest" means an examination ordered by the coroner, or in his absence, ordered by a deputy coroner, into the causes and circumstances of any death which is a coroner's case by a jury of six (6) residents of the county impaneled and selected by the coroner to assist him in ascertaining the cause and manner of death; </section><section prefix="4">"Post-mortem examination" means a physical examination of the body by a medical examiner or by a coroner or deputy coroner who has been certified by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet and may include an autopsy performed by a pathologist or other appropriate scientific tests administered to determine cause of death; and </section><section prefix="5">"Certified coroner" or "certified deputy coroner" means a coroner or deputy coroner who has been certified by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet to have successfully completed both the basic training course and annual inservice training course required by KRS 72.415, except that a deputy coroner shall be certified without completion of training courses required by KRS 72.415 if he is a licensed physician. The secretary of justice and public safety may waive the requirement for basic training and certify a coroner during the eighteen (18) month period after July 15, 1982, if the advisory commission set forth in KRS 72.225 certifies to the secretary after a thorough review that the experience and knowledge of the specific coroner is such that he is qualified to be a certified coroner without taking the basic training. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 151, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>