<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="207" order_by="207">AID TO THE NEEDY BLIND -- EQUAL OPPORTUNITIES </unit></structure><section_number>207.130</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 207.140 to 207.240. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>As used in KRS 207.140 to 207.240 unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Persons" means one (1) or more individuals, partnerships, municipalities, the state, or other political subdivisions within the state, associations, labor organizations, or corporations. </section><section prefix="2">"Physical disability" means the physical condition of a person whether congenital or acquired, which constitutes a substantial disability to that person and is demonstrable by medically accepted clinical or laboratory diagnostic techniques. </section><section prefix="3">"Employer" means a person or governmental unit or officer in this state having in his or its employ eight (8) or more individuals; and any person acting in the interest of an employer, directly or indirectly. </section><section prefix="4">"Labor organization" means a labor organization and an agent of such an organization, and includes an organization of any kind, an agency or employee representation committee, group, association, or plan so engaged in which employees participate and which exists for the purpose, in whole or in part, of dealing with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours, or other terms or conditions of employment, and a conference, general committee, joint system or board, or joint council so engaged which is subordinate to a national or international labor organization. </section><section prefix="5">"Unfair employment practice" means an act that is prohibited under KRS 207.150, 207.160 or 207.170. </section><section prefix="6">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards, under the direction and supervision of the secretary of the Labor Cabinet. </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Workplace Standards in the Labor Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 304, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 62, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 44, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. --Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7915</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>