<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.800</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 45A.800 to 45A.835, 45A.195, 45A.440, and 45A.695. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45A.800 to 45A.835, 45A.195, 45A.440, and 45A.695, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Architect" means an architect licensed under KRS Chapter 323 or a landscape architect licensed under KRS Chapter 323A; </section><section prefix="2">"Engineer" means an engineer licensed under KRS Chapter 322; </section><section prefix="3">"Procuring agency" means either the Finance and Administration Cabinet or the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">"Project" means any undertaking requiring professional architectural, engineering, or engineering-related services, except as provided in KRS 45A.100; </section><section prefix="5">"User agency" means the state agency or any public supported institution of higher education, when it declines to exercise the authority granted under KRS 164A.590, that will occupy or otherwise be the primary beneficiary of a completed Finance and Administration Cabinet project; </section><section prefix="6">"User division" means the division of the Transportation Cabinet that requires the procuring of engineering or engineering-related services for a project; </section><section prefix="7">"Engineering-related services" means specialized professional services performed by individuals, consultants, or other organizations of recognized technical competence, education, or experience that are involved in the planning, design, construction, maintenance, or operation of Kentucky's transportation systems or construction projects in accordance with applicable licensing statutes; and </section><section prefix="8">"Firm" means an individual or other entity that offers professional architectural, engineering, or engineering-related services. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 3, effective April 3, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> April 3, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22480</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>