<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2">CITIZENSHIP, EMBLEMS, HOLIDAYS, AND TIME </unit></structure><section_number>2.255</section_number><catch_line>"Commonwealth Cleanup" week -- Environmental Education Month. </catch_line><order_by>255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fourth week of March each year shall be "Commonwealth Cleanup" week, culminating with a statewide cleanup day on the Saturday of that week. This week shall provide an opportunity for Kentucky communities, in partnership with local, regional, and state entities, to clean and display the natural beauty of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">Local governments and private businesses shall be encouraged to participate in "Commonwealth Cleanup" week through developing, organizing, and implementing activities that highlight the natural beauty of their communities. They are encouraged to work in partnership with civic and volunteer organizations as well as corporate sponsors. Their goal shall be to consider the ways in which Kentucky’s beauty enriches their daily living and underpins their economic vitality. Examples of "Commonwealth Cleanup" week activities include: encouraging local communities to offer prizes for those groups who collect the most litter; asking boat owners to volunteer their services to help remove litter from shorelines not easily reached by land; and setting up locations for recyclables. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky National Guard is encouraged to support this effort by providing logistical support across the Commonwealth to help clean up the sites too large for volunteer groups. </section><section prefix="4">The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall promote "Commonwealth Cleanup" week by continuing to support those agencies and organizations wanting to clean up the environment. The support shall include providing technical assistance in assessing and understanding Kentucky’s natural resources, coordinating contacts with other state and federal agencies that can assist with a project as appropriate, guiding local organizers to possible sources of funding to help implement a project as appropriate, overseeing a statewide campaign to publicize "Commonwealth Cleanup" week, and promoting those communities that have outstanding participation. This includes working in tandem with the Kentucky Department of Education to sponsor a statewide poster contest for children through the eighth grade. </section><section prefix="5">The month of March shall be designated as Environmental Education Month. During this time, state agencies involved in environmental education are encouraged to work with schools and communities to promote the environment and its preservation. Schools shall also be encouraged to sponsor cleanup or beautifying activities on their grounds during this month. </section><section prefix="6">The "Commonwealth Cleanup" week activities shall culminate with the Governor proclaiming the success of those communities, civic organizations, and corporate sponsors that excel in cleaning up where they live. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 346, secs. 1 to 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=71</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>