<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.815</section_number><catch_line>University of Louisville -- Programs. </catch_line><order_by>815</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The University of Louisville shall provide: <section prefix="a">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, associate and baccalaureate degree programs of instruction; </section><section prefix="b">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, master's-degree programs, specialist degrees above the master's-degree level, doctoral degree programs, and joint doctoral programs in cooperation with other public institutions of higher education; </section><section prefix="c">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, professional degree programs including medicine, dentistry, law, engineering, and social professions. </section></section><section prefix="2">The University of Louisville is authorized to provide programs of a community college nature in its own community comparable to those listed for the community college system as provided in this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The University of Louisville shall continue to be a principal university for the conduct of research and service programs without geographical limitation but subject to the implied limitation of KRS 164.125(2). </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 124, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 110, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4466</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>