<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.226</section_number><catch_line>Group Health Insurance Board -- Members -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>226</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To provide quality, affordable health insurance coverage so that the Commonwealth can attract and retain able and dedicated public employees, and to facilitate the need for comprehensive and efficient planning, implementation, and administration of a state employee health insurance program in order to meet this goal, the Kentucky Group Health Insurance Board is created. The board shall be attached to the Personnel Cabinet for administrative purposes only. The board shall consist of thirteen (13) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">The state budget director; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of education; </section><section prefix="e">The chair of the Advisory Committee of State Health Insurance Subscribers; </section><section prefix="f">The commissioner of insurance, ex officio; </section><section prefix="g">The Auditor of Public Accounts, ex officio; </section><section prefix="h">The Director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, or his designee; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) retired state employee appointed by the Kentucky Retirement Systems, who shall serve an initial term of one (1) year; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) retired teacher appointed by the Teachers' Retirement System, who shall serve an initial term of two (2) years; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) active teacher appointed by the organization with the largest number of teacher members on payroll deduction, who shall serve an initial term of one (1) year; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) active state employee appointed by the organization with the largest number of state employee members on payroll deduction, who shall serve an initial term of two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="m">One (1) active classified education support employee appointed by the organization with the largest number of classified education support employee members on payroll deduction, who shall serve an initial term of one (1) year. </section></section> As each appointed member's term expires, the vacancy created shall be filled by the appointing authority for that position for a term of two (2) years. An appointment to fill an unexpired term of an appointed member shall be made by the designated appointing authority for the remainder of the term. Appointed terms shall begin effective October 1. <section prefix="2">The members of the board shall elect from among its members a chair and a vice chair. </section><section prefix="3">Regular meetings of the board shall be held at least once every month at a place, day, and time determined by the board. Special meetings of the board shall be held when needed as determined by the chair. If seven (7) or more members of the board request in writing that the chair call a special meeting, the chair shall call a special meeting. The meetings shall operate in accordance with the provisions of the Open Meetings Law under KRS 61.805 to 61.850. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the board shall receive reimbursement for necessary expenses for attendance at official board meetings or public hearings. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Group Health Insurance Board shall: <section prefix="a">Engage in analyses and research to identify the factors and parameters that affect the state group health insurance program; </section><section prefix="b">Develop and transmit, by October 1 of each year beginning October 1, 2001, to the Governor, the General Assembly, and the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, policy recommendations regarding benefit options and management of the state group health insurance program; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide in the first report, due by October 1, 2001, the following: <section prefix="1">Analysis and discussion of methods used by all other states to provide health insurance benefits to their state group; and </section><section prefix="2">Analysis and discussion of the cost, enrollment, claims, and utilization data for calendar year 2000 on the Kentucky state group; and </section><section prefix="3">Recommendations including but not limited to appropriate structures for the state contribution rate which shall include recommendations on increasing the state contribution to provide support for dependent coverage, possible methods to mitigate adverse selection, competitive plan designs by type and benefit options, the feasibility of a state self-insurance plan, and strategies for evaluating third-party administrators and vendors. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 29, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 1, effective April 21, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1407</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>