<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.595</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for assisted-living communities and long-term care facilities claiming to provide special care for persons with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders -- Waiver on building requirements to address specific needs.   </catch_line><order_by>595</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any assisted-living community as defined by KRS 194A.700, long-term care facility as defined in KRS 216.535, or long-term care facility constructed under KRS 216B.071 that claims to provide special care for persons with a medical diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders shall maintain a written and current manual that contains the information specified in subsection (2) of this section. This manual shall be maintained in the office of the community's or facility's director and shall be made available for inspection upon request of any person. The community or facility shall make a copy of any program or service information contained in the manual for a person who requests information about programs or services, at no cost to the person making the request. </section><section prefix="b">Any advertisement of the community or facility shall contain the following statement: "Written information relating to this community's or facility's services and policies is available upon request." </section><section prefix="c">The community or facility shall post a statement in its entrance or lobby as follows: "Written information relating to this community's or facility's services and policies is available upon request." </section></section><section prefix="2">The community or facility shall maintain and update written information on the following: <section prefix="a">The assisted-living community's or long-term care facility's mission or philosophy statement concerning the needs of residents with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="b">The process and criteria the assisted-living community or long-term care facility uses to determine placement into services for persons with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="c">The process and criteria the assisted-living community or long-term care facility uses to transfer or discharge persons from special services for Alzheimer's or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="d">The supervision provided for residents with a medical diagnosis of Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="e">The family's role in care; </section><section prefix="f">The process for assessing, planning, implementing, and evaluating the plan of care for persons with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="g">A description of any special care services for persons with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; </section><section prefix="h">Any costs associated with specialized services for Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders; and </section><section prefix="i">A description of dementia or other brain disorder-specific staff training that is provided, including but not limited to the content of the training, the number of offered and required hours of training, the schedule for training, and the staff who are required to complete the training. </section></section><section prefix="3">An assisted-living community may request a waiver from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services regarding building requirements to address the specialized needs of individuals with Alzheimer's disease or other brain disorders. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 421, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>