<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.600</section_number><catch_line>Bonds to issue in name of authority -- Identification -- Investment designation. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Bonds of the authority shall be issued in the name of the authority, shall be designated "school building revenue bonds," or, if appropriate, "school building revenue refunding bonds," and shall additionally be identified by the name of the board of education executing the lease. If the authority shall issue more than one (1) series of bonds for the same lessee from time to time, each series, including the first or subsequent to the first, shall additionally be identified distinctly by alphabetical or chronological designation, by date of the bonds, or otherwise as the authority may determine. </section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of determining any limit prescribed by any law for investment of any public funds, or funds of banks, trust companies, insurance companies, building and loan associations, credit unions, pension and retirement funds, and fiduciaries, in obligations of a single obligor, bonds issued by the authority pursuant to KRS 162.520 to 162.620 shall not be deemed to be bonds or obligations of the same obligor except to the aggregate of all series of bonds involving leases of a single board of education. </section><section prefix="3">Bonds issued by the authority under the provisions of KRS 162.520 to 162.620 are hereby made securities in which all public officers and public bodies of the Commonwealth and its political subdivisions, all insurance companies, trust companies, banking associations, investment companies, executors, trustees, and other fiduciaries, and all other persons whatsoever who are now or may hereafter be authorized to invest in bonds or other obligations of a similar nature may properly and legally invest funds, including capital in their control or belonging to them. Such bonds are hereby made securities which may properly and legally be deposited with and received by any state or municipal officer or any agency or political subdivision of the Commonwealth for any purpose for which the deposit of bonds or other obligations of the Commonwealth is now or may hereafter be authorized by law. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 589, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 10, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4094</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>