<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.515</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.510 to 247.595 unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the State Board of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">"Producer" means every person who produces soybeans and thereafter causes the same to be marketed; </section><section prefix="4">"New producer" means a producer who was not engaged in the business of producing soybeans at the time a referendum was conducted in accordance with the provisions of KRS 247.510 to 247.595; </section><section prefix="5">"Person" means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, cooperative, or other business entity; </section><section prefix="6">"Marketing year" means from July 1 to June 30 of the following year; </section><section prefix="7">"Purchaser" means any person, public or private corporation, federal commodity credit corporation, association, or partnership buying, accepting for shipment, or otherwise acquiring the property in or to soybeans from a producer, and shall include a mortgagee, pledgee, lienor, or other person, public or private, having a claim against the producer, when the actual or constructive possession of such soybeans is taken as part payment or in satisfaction of such mortgage, pledge, lien, or claim; </section><section prefix="8">"Net market price" means the sales price or other value received by a producer for soybeans after adjustments have been made for any premium or discount based on grading or quality factors; and </section><section prefix="9">"Promotion board" means the Kentucky Soybean Promotion Board. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>