<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.240</section_number><catch_line>Investigation -- Demand for information or evidence. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the Attorney General has reason to believe that a person has engaged in, is engaging in, or is about to engage in any act or practice declared to be unlawful by KRS 367.110 to 367.300, or when he believes it to be in the public interest that an investigation should be made to ascertain whether a person in fact has engaged in, is engaging in or is about to engage in, any act or practice declared to be unlawful by KRS 367.110 to 367.300, he may execute in writing and cause to be served upon any person who is believed to have information, documentary material or physical evidence relevant to the alleged or suspected violation, an investigative demand requiring such person to furnish, under oath or otherwise, a report in writing setting forth the relevant facts and circumstances of which he has knowledge, or to appear and testify or to produce relevant documentary material or physical evidence for examination, at such reasonable time and place as may be stated in the investigative demand, concerning the advertisement, sale or offering for sale of any goods or services or the conduct of any trade or commerce that is the subject matter of the investigation. Provided however, that no person who has a place of business in Kentucky shall be required to appear or present documentary material or physical evidence outside of the county where he has his principal place of business within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">At any time before the return date specified in an investigative demand, or within twenty (20) days after the demand has been served, whichever period is shorter, a petition to extend the return date, or to modify or set aside the demand, stating good cause, may be filed in the Circuit Court where the person served with the demand resides or has his principal place of business or in the Franklin Circuit Court. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 14. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>