<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.150</section_number><catch_line>Board membership -- Appointment -- Term -- Vacancy -- Oath -- Quorum. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall consist of six (6) members appointed by the Governor. Five (5) members shall be pharmacists licensed in this state. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large, who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice of pharmacy. </section><section prefix="2">In any calendar year scheduled to be the last full calendar year of a member's regular term in office, the association shall select and submit to the Governor a list of five (5) pharmacists, each of whom has had at least five (5) years' experience in the practice of pharmacy, is a resident of the state and in good standing with the board. On or before March 1 of the same year, the society, other state pharmacy organizations, or individuals may submit recommendations to the association for its consideration in selecting the list to be submitted. The Governor shall, before October 1 of the same year, appoint no more than two (2) persons from each list so submitted, to take office on January 1 following. The citizen member shall be appointed by the Governor. No two (2) pharmacist members of the board shall be residents of the same county. </section><section prefix="3">Beginning January 1, 2005, the term of each board member shall be four (4) years. Each member shall serve until his or her successor is appointed and qualified, unless removed for cause. No member shall be appointed to serve for more than two (2) full terms. </section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall fill any vacancy of a pharmacist member from the names last submitted within sixty (60) days after such a vacancy occurs. Any member so appointed shall commence service at the next regularly-scheduled board meeting and shall serve for the remainder of the term vacated. </section><section prefix="5">Each member shall take and subscribe to an oath before a competent officer to perform the duties of the office faithfully and impartially. The oath shall be inscribed upon the member's commission. </section><section prefix="6">Four (4) members of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 8. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 12. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2621, 2622. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31019</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>