<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.620</section_number><catch_line>Relocation assistance authorized. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any department, agency or instrumentality of the state, or any county, municipality, or other political subdivision, or any other public or private entity subject to the provisions of the Federal Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real Property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970, as amended, Public Laws 91-646, and 100-17, Title IV, hereinafter the Federal Uniform Relocation Act, undertakes any project, which results in the acquisition of real property or in any person or persons being displaced from their homes, businesses, or farms, such state department, agency or instrumentality, county, municipality or other political subdivision, or other public or private entity may provide relocation assistance, and make relocation payments to such displaced person and to do such other acts and follow such procedures and practices as may be necessary to comply with the provisions of the Federal Uniform Relocation Act. </section><section prefix="2">Any payment made or to be made under the authority granted herein shall be for compensating or reimbursing the displaced person or owner of real property in accordance with the requirements of the Federal Uniform Relocation Act and such payments shall not for any purpose be deemed or considered compensation for real property acquired or compensation for damages to remaining property. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 541, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22669</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>