<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.635</section_number><catch_line>Vehicle accident reports by operators, law enforcement officers, and agencies -- Availability to parties to accident and news-gathering organizations -- Contracts with outside entities to provide vehicle's accident history and electronic access to reports -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>635</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, Department of Kentucky State Police, shall be responsible for maintaining a reporting system for all vehicle accidents which occur within the Commonwealth. Such accident reports shall be utilized for such purposes as will improve the traffic safety program in the Commonwealth involving the collection, processing, storing, and dissemination of such data and the establishment of procedures by administrative regulations to insure that uniform definitions, classifications, and other federal requirements are in compliance. </section><section prefix="2">Any person operating a vehicle on the highways of this state who is involved in an accident resulting in fatal or nonfatal personal injury to any person or damage to the vehicle rendering the vehicle inoperable shall be required to immediately notify a law enforcement officer having jurisdiction. In the event the operator fails to notify or is incapable of notifying a law enforcement officer having jurisdiction, such responsibility shall rest with the owner of the vehicle or any occupant of the vehicle at the time of the accident. A law enforcement officer having jurisdiction shall investigate the accident and file a written report of the accident with his law enforcement agency. </section><section prefix="3">Every law enforcement agency whose officers investigate a vehicle accident of which a report must be made as required in this chapter shall file a report of the accident with the Department of Kentucky State Police within ten (10) days after investigation of the accident upon forms supplied by the department. </section><section prefix="4">Any person operating a vehicle on the highways of this state who is involved in an accident resulting in any property damage exceeding five hundred dollars ($500) in which an investigation is not conducted by a law enforcement officer shall file a written report of the accident with the Department of Kentucky State Police within ten (10) days of occurrence of the accident upon forms provided by the department. </section><section prefix="5">All accident reports filed with the Department of Kentucky State Police in compliance with subsection (4) above shall not be considered open records under KRS 61.872 to 61.884 and shall remain confidential except that the department may disclose the identity of a person involved in an accident when his or her identity is not otherwise known or when he or she denies his or her presence at an accident. Except as provided in subsection (9) of this section, all other accident reports required by this section, and the information contained in the reports, shall be confidential and exempt from public disclosure except when produced pursuant to a properly executed subpoena or court order, or except pursuant to subsection (8) of this section. These reports shall be made available only to the parties to the accident, the parents or guardians of a minor who is party to the accident, and insurers or their written designee for insurance business purposes of any party who is the subject of the report, or to the attorneys of the parties. </section><section prefix="6">Except as provided for in this subsection, the department shall not release accident reports for a commercial purpose. The department may, as a matter of public safety, contract with an outside entity and release vehicle damage data extracted from accident reports to such an entity if the data is used solely for the purpose of providing the public a means of determining a vehicle's accident history. The department may further contract with a third party to provide electronic access to reports for persons and entities who are entitled to such reports under subsections (5) and (9) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to set out a fee schedule for accident reports made available pursuant to subsections (5), (8), and (9) of this section. These fees shall be in addition to those charged to the public for records produced under KRS Chapter 61. </section><section prefix="8">The report shall be made available to a news-gathering organization, solely for the purpose of publishing or broadcasting the news. The news-gathering organization shall not use or distribute the report, or knowingly allow its use or distribution, for a commercial purpose other than the news-gathering organization's publication or broadcasting of the information in the report. A newspaper, periodical, or radio or television station shall not be held to have used or knowingly allowed the use of the report for a commercial purpose merely because of its publication or broadcast. </section><section prefix="9">The report shall be made available without subpoena to any party to litigation who files with the department a request for the report and includes a copy of the first page of a District or Circuit Court clerk-stamped complaint naming all parties. </section><section prefix="10">The motor vehicle insurers of any train engineer or other train crew member involved in an accident on a railroad while functioning in their professional capacity shall be prohibited from obtaining a copy of any accident report filed on the accident under this section without written consent from the individual the company insures. Insurance companies issuing motor vehicle policies in the Commonwealth shall be prohibited from raising a policyholder's rates solely because the policyholder, in his or her professional capacity, is a train engineer or other train crew member involved in an accident on a railroad. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 211, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 478, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1977. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  The numbering of the subsections in this section has been altered by the Reviser of Statutes from the numbering in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6425</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>