<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.601</section_number><catch_line>Office on Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders -- Purpose, director, and duties. </catch_line><order_by>601</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office on Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders is established within the cabinet. The purpose of the office is to oversee information and resources related to policy and services affecting the sixty thousand (60,000) residents of Kentucky with dementia, and the caregivers and families of the residents. </section><section prefix="2">The director of the office shall be a full-time, permanent employee and shall be responsible for the staffing and operational details of the office. A report on the start-up and implementation of the office shall be made to the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare by September 30, 2000, and on a quarterly basis thereafter. </section><section prefix="3">The office shall: <section prefix="a">Enhance the quality of life for persons affected by dementia and for their caregivers; </section><section prefix="b">Recommend the delivery of services in the most effective and efficient manner possible to facilitate the needs of people with dementia and their caregivers, after consultation with other agencies of state government that work with dementia-related illness; </section><section prefix="c">Determine ways the Commonwealth may secure additional federal and private funding to provide additional services and programs through a coordinated effort; </section><section prefix="d">Apply for any public or private funding relating to dementia that will enhance the office's abilities to perform its duties under this section; </section><section prefix="e">Promote public and professional awareness and education of dementia and access to needed services and programs; </section><section prefix="f">Oversee and receive reports from the Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Advisory Council; and </section><section prefix="g">Coordinate and oversee the implementation of the recommendations of the 1995 Governor's Task Force on Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>