<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.591</section_number><catch_line>Location of Kentucky Community and Technical College System headquarters and community colleges and extension centers -- Approval of General Assembly as requirement for new community colleges. </catch_line><order_by>591</order_by><text>A community college or extension of a community college shall be maintained in each of the following locations: Ashland, Carrollton, Cumberland, Elizabethtown, Glasgow, Henderson, Hopkinsville, Fayette County, Madisonville, Owensboro, Paducah, Prestonsburg, Somerset, Blackey-Hazard, Jefferson County and Mason County. The headquarters of the administration of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall be maintained in Woodford County. Western Kentucky University may continue to operate a community college in Bowling Green. Additional extension centers may be established by the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System with approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education. New community colleges shall require approval of the General Assembly. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 113, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1; and ch. 84, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4338</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>