<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">A OCCUPATIONAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319A.070</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter and shall have the responsibility of evaluating the qualifications of applicants for licensure. </section><section prefix="2">The board may issue subpoenas, examine witnesses, administer oaths, and investigate allegations of practices violating the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The board may: <section prefix="a">Promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, relating to professional conduct to carry out the provisions of this chapter, including but not limited to administrative regulations relating to professional licensure and holding a license to practice occupational therapy or assist in the practice of occupational therapy in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Conduct administrative hearings in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B; </section><section prefix="c">Evaluate the qualifications and authorize the issuance of licenses to qualified occupational therapists and occupational therapy assistants; </section><section prefix="d">Issue and renew licenses based on evidence of initial and continued competence of persons subject to this chapter; </section><section prefix="e">Suspend or revoke licenses; </section><section prefix="f">Require the continuing professional education of persons subject to this chapter; </section><section prefix="g">Keep a record of its proceedings and a register of all persons licensed as occupational therapists or occupational therapy assistants. The register shall show the name of every licensee, the licensee's last known place of business and last known place of residence, and the date and number of the license of each licensed occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant. The board shall, during the month of January of every year, compile and make available a list of licensed occupational therapists and occupational therapy assistants authorized to practice in the Commonwealth. Any citizen of the Commonwealth may obtain a copy of the list upon application to the board and payment of an amount to be fixed by the board, which shall not exceed its cost; </section><section prefix="h">Make an annual report to the Governor and the General Assembly which shall contain an account of duties performed, actions taken, and appropriate recommendations; </section><section prefix="i">Institute and maintain actions to restrain or enjoin any violation of this chapter and administrative regulations notwithstanding the existence or pursuit of other civil or criminal penalties; </section><section prefix="j">Approve an examination for occupational therapists and occupational therapy assistants and establish standards for acceptable performance; </section><section prefix="k">Seek an injunction in Franklin Circuit Court against any individual who practices occupational therapy in the Commonwealth without a license; and </section><section prefix="l">Promulgate administrative regulations to define appropriate supervision of assistants, aides, and unlicensed personnel that are delivering occupational therapy services. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 278, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31260</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>