<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.41-030</section_number><catch_line>Joint Underwriting Association -- Categories covered -- Termination -- Powers of association. </catch_line><order_by>41-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A temporary Joint Underwriting Association is created, consisting of all insurers authorized to write and engage in writing in the Commonwealth on a direct basis the following lines of insurance, as reported in the companies' annual statements: <section prefix="a">Workers' compensation; </section><section prefix="b">Liability other than auto; </section><section prefix="c">Private passenger auto liability; </section><section prefix="d">Commercial auto liability; and </section><section prefix="e">The liability portion of commercial multi-peril policies. </section></section> Every such insurer shall remain a member of the Joint Underwriting Association as a condition of its authority to continue to transact such kinds of insurance in the Commonwealth. <section prefix="2">The implementation of the operation of the Joint Underwriting Association shall become effective upon the order of the commissioner. The commissioner shall not order the association to commence underwriting operations until the commissioner, after due hearing and investigation, has determined that legal professional liability insurance cannot be made available in the voluntary market. The Joint Underwriting Association shall remain in effect for a period of no longer than two and one-half (2 1/2) years from the date that it commences underwriting operations. </section> This subtitle shall not preclude any attorney at law from procuring legal professional liability insurance from the voluntary market.  If the commissioner determines at any time that legal professional liability insurance is readily available in the voluntary market, the association shall thereby cease its underwriting operations. <section prefix="3">The association shall, pursuant to the provisions of this subtitle and the plan of operation with respect to legal professional liability insurance, have the power on behalf of its members: <section prefix="a">To issue, or to cause to be issued, policies of insurance to applicants, including incidental coverages and subject to limitations as specified in the plan of operation, but not to exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) for each claimant under one (1) policy and one million dollars ($1,000,000) for all claimants under one (1) policy in any one (1) year; </section><section prefix="b">To underwrite such insurance and to adjust and pay losses with respect thereto, or to appoint service companies to perform those functions; </section><section prefix="c">To assume reinsurance from its members; </section><section prefix="d">To cede reinsurance; and </section><section prefix="e">To negotiate and obtain in the voluntary market legal professional liability insurance with limits in excess of the foregoing limits for any attorney-at-law to whom the association has issued or caused to be issued a policy of legal professional liability insurance. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1549, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30093</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>