<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.530</section_number><catch_line>Procedure to compel connection with telephone exchange or line. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever any telephone company desires to connect its exchange or lines with the exchange or lines of another telephone company and the latter refuses to permit this to be done upon reasonable terms, rates and conditions, the company desiring the connection may proceed as provided in subsection (2) or as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The company desiring the connection may file a written statement with the Public Service Commission setting out the reasons why the connection is desired and the points at which the connection should be made, and giving the name and address of the owner or chief officer residing in this state of each company with which the connection is desired. The executive director of the commission shall thereupon cause a copy of the written statement to be served upon the companies owning or operating such lines or exchanges, by mailing a copy to the owner or chief officer residing in this state, and shall fix a date, not earlier than ten (10) days from the date of mailing the notice, for the hearing of the application. Upon the day so fixed for the hearing, the companies may respond in writing to the application, and either side may introduce such testimony as it desires and be heard by attorneys. After the hearing is completed the commission shall make its finding and enter it in a book to be kept for that purpose, and shall mail a copy thereof to each side; and if the commission directs the connection to be made it shall indicate the points where the connection is to be made, the number of wires to be connected, the terms and conditions and the rates to be charged, and the division of the rates charged between the companies handling the messages. The cost of making the connection shall be borne equally by the parties. If any company refuses to make a connection for a period of thirty (30) days after the finding of the commission directing the connection to be made, the company desiring the connection may make the connection and may recover one-half (1/2) of the cost thereof from the company so refusing. </section><section prefix="3">In lieu of the procedure provided in subsection (2) of this section, the company desiring the connection may compel the connection upon reasonable terms by suit in equity in the Franklin Circuit Court or in the Circuit Court of the county in which the company making the demand resides or has its chief office in this state, and the court shall, by mandatory injunction, compel the physical connection of the wires and interchange of messages, and enforce the same by contempt proceedings and in the same manner that other mandatory injunctions are enforced. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 49, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 53, effective April 1, 1979. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4679f-2, 4679f-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>