<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="330" order_by="330">AUCTIONEERS AND AUCTION HOUSE OPERATORS </unit></structure><section_number>330.070Apprentice</section_number><catch_line>auctioneer requirements -- Issuance of license -- Fees -- Continuing education requirement -- Pocket license -- Duty of auctioneer upon termination of apprentice employment -- Placement of licenses in escrow -- Notice of change of address.   </catch_line><order_by>070Apprentice</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An apprentice auctioneer applying for an auctioneer license shall, subject to the provisions of KRS 330.060: <section prefix="a">Possess a current Kentucky apprentice auctioneer license; </section><section prefix="b">Serve an apprenticeship for a period of one (1) year as an apprentice auctioneer in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Submit a statement to the board, signed by the principal auctioneer, verifying that the applicant has actively and materially participated in at least ten (10) auctions prior to application; and </section><section prefix="d">Successfully complete at least eighty (80) hours of approved classroom instruction from a board-approved auction education provider. The board may waive the eighty (80) hours of approved classroom instruction requirement if the applicant demonstrates sufficient previous auction experience and competency by affidavit or other evidence as required by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">An apprentice auctioneer with an original license issued prior to June 30, 2010, or after July 1, 2015, shall be required to successfully complete the auctioneer examination. </section><section prefix="3">If an applicant for an auctioneer license resides in a state which does not have a current reciprocity agreement with the board, the board may waive the eighty (80) hour education requirement or the apprenticeship requirement, or both, if the applicant demonstrates sufficient previous auction experience and competency by affidavit or by other evidence as required by the board. </section><section prefix="4">An applicant for an auctioneer license who has previously held an auctioneer license which has been revoked, suspended, or which has expired without renewal may request, and the board may grant, a waiver of the requirement of possession of a current apprentice license. </section><section prefix="5">Every application for a license issued by the board shall be submitted on forms prepared by the board. Each applicant shall furnish pertinent background data as outlined on those forms. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish an initial license fee and annual renewal license fee, neither of which shall exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). <section prefix="a">All licenses shall expire on the thirtieth day of June. </section><section prefix="b">Each license shall be renewed on or before the expiration date. </section><section prefix="c">In addition to the renewal fee, a late fee shall be established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board on each license renewed within six (6) months after the expiration date. </section><section prefix="d">In the absence of any reason or condition which might warrant the refusal of renewing a license, and upon timely receipt of the renewal form and the annual fee, the board shall issue a license for the ensuing year. </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">The board may require as a condition precedent to the renewal of any license, that each licensee complete continuing education up to ten (10) hours per license year. The board may impose different continuing education requirements upon different classifications of licenses under this chapter. The continuing education requirements in this subsection shall not apply to those auctioneers licensed prior to January 1, 1980. </section><section prefix="b">A licensee who has not completed the required continuing education may, within the time period set forth in subsection (6) of this section, remit a fee established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board with the applicable renewal fees, and the continuing education reporting requirement shall be deferred to the next annual renewal. If the licensee fails to meet the continuing education requirement for the next annual renewal, the licensee shall successfully complete the examination before renewal of his or her license. </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The board may require all licensees to complete a six (6) hour board-approved core course once every four (4) years, that includes the core subjects of Kentucky auction statutes and regulations, ethics, and any other subject matter deemed appropriate by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Effective July 1, 2016, each licensee with at least twenty-five (25) years of continuous licensure shall be exempt from the requirements of this paragraph. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">The board shall prepare and deliver to each licensee a pocket license. The pocket license of the apprentice auctioneer shall contain the name and address of his or her principal auctioneer. The board shall also prepare and deliver a license to each auction house operator. <section prefix="a">Auction house operators shall display their licenses conspicuously and at all times in the auction house identified on the license. </section><section prefix="b">All licensees shall carry their pocket licenses, or a digital facsimile thereof, when performing auctioneering tasks, to be shown upon request. </section><section prefix="c">A license or pocket license shall be replaced upon the request of the licensee and payment of a replacement fee established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="9">When an apprentice auctioneer is discharged or voluntarily terminates employment with the auctioneer for any reason: <section prefix="a">It shall be the immediate duty of the principal auctioneer to deliver to the board a written release of the apprentice auctioneer; and </section><section prefix="b">The apprentice auctioneer shall affiliate with a principal auctioneer within thirty (30) days by submitting to the board an affiliation letter signed by the new principal auctioneer and a fee established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section> An apprentice auctioneer shall not perform any of the acts regulated by this chapter until receiving a new license bearing a new principal auctioneer's name and address. <section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">A licensee may place his or her license in escrow with the board if the licensee does not engage in any board-regulated auctioneering activity and continues to pay the annual renewal license fee. </section><section prefix="b">For each year the license is in escrow, a licensee shall be exempt from the contribution to the auctioneer's education, research, and recovery fund and the continuing education requirement. </section><section prefix="c">To reactivate a license in escrow, the licensee shall complete the core course and pay a reactivation fee and the annual renewal recovery fee, both of which shall be established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="11">Notice in writing shall be given to the board by each licensee of any change of principal business location or residence address within ten (10) days of the change, and the board shall issue an updated license for the unexpired period. The board may fine, suspend, or revoke the license of a licensee who does not notify the board of a change of address within ten (10) days. Changing a business or a residence address on its records shall entitle the board to collect a fee established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 407, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 68. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 18. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>