<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.5624</section_number><catch_line>Payment of benefits -- Limitations -- Qualification for coverage. </catch_line><order_by>5624</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Benefits provided under the program shall be limited to the amount of appropriations. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall be the payor of last resort. The program shall cover costs for participants that are not covered by the Medicare Part D program. </section><section prefix="3">Except for dual eligibles during the transition period, during which they are being moved from Medicaid to a Medicare Part D program, applicants who are qualified for coverage of payments for prescription drugs under a public assistance program shall be ineligible for the program for so long as they are so qualified. </section><section prefix="4">Applicants who are qualified for full coverage of payments for prescription drugs under another plan of assistance or insurance shall be ineligible to receive benefits from the program for so long as they are eligible to receive pharmacy benefits from the other plan. </section><section prefix="5">Applicants who are qualified for partial payments for prescription drugs under another insurance plan shall be eligible for the program but may receive reduced assistance from the program. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005; and amended ch. 184, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  This statute was created by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 9. Section 13 of another enactment, 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 184, instructed that the word "who" in subsection (2) should be replaced by the word "that." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>