<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="249" order_by="249">TREES, PLANTS, WEEDS, AND PESTS </unit></structure><section_number>249.060</section_number><catch_line>Nurseries and dealers to be licensed -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every resident nursery or dealer selling nursery stock in this state shall annually file credentials with the state entomologist. If these credentials are satisfactory to the state entomologist, the director, and the Commissioner, the state entomologist shall, upon payment by the nursery or dealer of the fee set out in subsection (2) of this section, issue it a license authorizing it to do business in the state. </section><section prefix="2">Payment of fees shall be made according to the following rates: <section prefix="a">Class A nursery: nurseries that are actively growing nursery stock with the intent of selling shall pay an annual fee of forty dollars ($40), plus one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) per acre. </section><section prefix="b">Class B nursery: nurseries and garden centers that do not grow their nursery stock, but do overwinter a portion of their stock, shall pay an annual fee of forty dollars ($40). </section><section prefix="c">Class A dealer: landscapers and businesses who do not grow or overwinter their nursery stock but whose primary business involves the sale or planting of nursery stock shall pay an annual fee of forty dollars ($40). </section><section prefix="d">Class B dealer: businesses whose primary business is not the sale of nursery stock shall pay an annual fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person soliciting orders for or delivering trees or plants in this state shall carry with him a copy of his license which he shall show to prospective buyers, purchasers, county officials, or agents of the state entomologist, on demand. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1. effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1925a-8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12002</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>