<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.317</section_number><catch_line>Creation of hospital district -- Tax levy and collection. </catch_line><order_by>317</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A hospital district may be created in accordance with the procedures of KRS 65.182 and 216.320. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the creation of a hospital district, as provided in KRS 65.182 and 216.320, the district shall constitute and be a taxing district within the meaning of Section 157 of the Constitution of Kentucky and the county shall be a participating county in the district. In no event shall the special ad valorem tax imposed for the maintenance and operation of the district exceed ten cents ($0.10) on each one hundred dollars ($100) of the assessed valuation of all property in the county. A hospital taxing district may be created with an ad valorem tax rate levy of zero cents ($0.00) on the assessed valuation of the property in the district. </section><section prefix="3">All special ad valorem taxes authorized by KRS 216.310 to 216.360 shall be collected in the same manner as are other county ad valorem taxes in each county affected and shall be turned over to the board as the governing body of the district. The special ad valorem tax shall be in addition to all other ad valorem taxes. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 351, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 4, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>