<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.330</section_number><catch_line>Initial fee for licensure -- Requirements for certification. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text>An applicant for licensure as a marriage and family therapist shall pay the board an initial fee which shall be established by administrative regulation promulgated by the board. The applicant shall show the board that the applicant has: <section prefix="1">Completed a master's or doctoral degree program in marriage and family therapy, from a regionally-accredited educational institution, or a master's, post-master's, or doctoral program approved by the Commission on Accreditation for Marriage and Family Therapy Education or any of its successor organizations, or an equivalent course of study as defined by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. <section prefix="a">The degree or equivalent course of study shall contain specific coursework on psychopathology and the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual; and </section><section prefix="b">In determining equivalency, the board shall use the criteria for marriage and family therapy education and clinical training approved by the United States Department of Education; </section></section><section prefix="2">Completed each of the following: <section prefix="a">At least two (2) years' experience in the practice of marriage and family therapy, acceptable to the board and subsequent to being granted a master's degree; and </section><section prefix="b">A minimum of two hundred (200) hours of clinical supervision acceptable to the board and subsequent to being granted a master's degree; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Passed a written examination prescribed by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>