<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.400</section_number><catch_line>Tax credit for company approved for economic development project under KRS 154.28-010 to 154.28-100. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Approved company" shall have the same meaning as set forth in KRS 154.28-010; </section><section prefix="b">"Economic development project" shall have the same meaning as set forth in KRS 154.28-010; </section><section prefix="c">"Tax credit" means the "tax credit" allowed in KRS 154.28-090; </section><section prefix="d">"Kentucky gross receipts" means Kentucky gross receipts as defined in KRS 141.0401; and </section><section prefix="e">"Kentucky gross profits" means Kentucky gross profits as defined in KRS 141.0401. </section></section><section prefix="2">An approved company shall determine the income tax credit as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="3">An approved company which is an individual sole proprietorship subject to tax under KRS 141.020 or a corporation or pass-through entity treated as a corporation for federal income tax purposes subject to tax under KRS 141.040(1) shall: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Compute the tax due at the applicable tax rates as provided by KRS 141.020 or 141.040 on net income as defined by KRS 141.010(11) or taxable net income as defined by KRS 141.010(14), including income from the economic development project; </section><section prefix="2">Compute the limited liability entity tax imposed under KRS 141.0401, including Kentucky gross profits or Kentucky gross receipts from the economic development project; and </section><section prefix="3">Add the amounts computed under subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph and, if applicable, subtract the credit permitted by KRS 141.0401(3) from that sum. The resulting amount shall be the net tax for purposes of this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Compute the tax due at the applicable tax rates as provided by KRS 141.020 or 141.040 on net income as defined by KRS 141.010(11) or taxable net income as defined by KRS 141.010(14), excluding net income attributable to the economic development project; </section><section prefix="2">Using the same method used under subparagraph 2. of paragraph (a) of this subsection, compute the limited liability entity tax imposed under KRS 141.0401, excluding Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits from the economic development project; and </section><section prefix="3">Add the amounts computed under subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph and, if applicable, subtract the credit permitted by KRS 141.0401(3) from that sum. The resulting amount shall be the net tax for purposes of this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="c">The tax credit shall be the amount by which the net tax computed under paragraph (a)3. of this subsection exceeds the tax computed under paragraph (b)3. of this subsection; however, the credit shall not exceed the limits set forth in KRS 154.28-090. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, an approved company which is a pass-through entity not subject to tax under KRS 141.040, or a trust not subject to tax under KRS 141.040 shall be subject to income tax on the net income attributable to an economic development project at the rates provided in KRS 141.020(2). </section><section prefix="b">The amount of the tax credit shall be determined as provided in subsection (3) of this section. Upon the annual election of the approved company, in lieu of the tax credit, an amount shall be applied as an estimated tax payment equal to the tax computed in this section. Any estimated tax payment made pursuant to this paragraph shall be in satisfaction of the tax liability of the partners, members, shareholders, or beneficiaries of the pass-through entity or trust, and shall be paid on behalf of the partners, members, shareholders, or beneficiaries. </section><section prefix="c">The tax credit or estimated payment shall not exceed the limits set forth in KRS 154.28-090. </section><section prefix="d">If the tax computed in this section exceeds the credit, the excess shall be paid by the pass-through entity or trust at the times provided by KRS 141.0401 or 141.160 for filing the returns. </section><section prefix="e">Any estimated tax payment made by the pass-through entity or trust in satisfaction of the tax liability of partners, members, shareholders, or beneficiaries shall not be treated as taxable income subject to Kentucky income tax by the partner, member, shareholder, or beneficiary. </section></section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the net income subject to tax, the tax credit, and the estimated tax payment determined under subsection (4) of this section shall be excluded in determining each partner's, member's, shareholder's, or beneficiary's distributive share of net income or credit of a pass-through entity or trust. </section><section prefix="6">If the economic development project is a totally separate facility: <section prefix="a">Net income attributable to the project for the purposes of subsections (3), (4), and (5) of this section shall be determined under the separate accounting method reflecting only the gross income, deductions, expenses, gains, and losses allowed under this chapter directly attributable to the facility and overhead expenses apportioned to the facility; and </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits attributable to the project for purposes of subsection (3) of this section shall be determined under the separate accounting method reflecting only the Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits directly attributable to the facility. </section></section><section prefix="7">If the economic development project is an expansion to a previously existing facility: <section prefix="a">Net income attributable to the entire facility shall be determined under the separate accounting method reflecting only the gross income, deductions, expenses, gains, and losses allowed under this chapter directly attributable to the facility and overhead expenses apportioned to the facility, and the net income attributable to the economic development project for the purposes of subsections (3), (4), and (5) of this section shall be determined by apportioning the separate accounting net income of the entire facility to the economic development project by a formula approved by the Department of Revenue; and </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits attributable to the entire facility shall be determined under the separate accounting method reflecting only the Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits directly attributable to the facility, and Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits attributable to the economic development project for the purposes of subsection (3) of this section shall be determined by apportioning the separate accounting Kentucky gross receipts or Kentucky gross profits of the entire facility to the economic development project by a formula approved by the Department of Revenue. </section></section><section prefix="8">If an approved company can show to the satisfaction of the Department of Revenue that the nature of the operations and activities of the approved company are such that it is not practical to use the separate accounting method to determine the net income, Kentucky gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits from the facility at which the economic development project is located, the approved company shall determine net income, Kentucky gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits from the economic development project using an alternative method approved by the Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Revenue may issue administrative regulations and require the filing of forms designed by the Department of Revenue to reflect the intent of KRS 154.22-020 to 154.22-070 and KRS 154.28-010 to 154.28-090 and this section and the allowable tax credit which an approved company may retain under KRS 154.22-020 to 154.22-070 and KRS 154.28-010 to 154.28-090 and this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 23, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XIII, sec. 6, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 505, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 24, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 28, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>(6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007."  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>