<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.612</section_number><catch_line>Membership of individuals providing part-time and substitute services -- Service credit -- Participation in benefits. </catch_line><order_by>612</order_by><text>Effective July 1, 2002, any individual occupying a position on a part-time basis that requires certification or graduation from a four (4) year college or university as a condition of employment and any individual providing part-time or substitute teaching services that are the same or similar to those teaching services provided by certified, full-time teachers shall be a member of the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System, according to the conditions and only to the extent set forth in this section, if the individual is employed by one (1) of the public boards, institutions, or agencies set forth in KRS 161.220, excluding those public boards, institutions, and agencies described in KRS 161.220(4)(b) and (n). Members providing part-time and substitute services shall participate in the retirement system as follows: <section prefix="1">Members providing part-time and substitute services shall accrue service credit as provided under KRS 161.500 and be entitled to a retirement allowance upon meeting the service retirement conditions of KRS 161.600. The board of trustees shall adopt a methodology for accrediting service credit to these members on a pro rata basis. The methodology adopted by the board of trustees may be amended as necessary to ensure its actuarial soundness. The retirement allowance for members providing part-time and substitute services shall be calculated pursuant to KRS 161.620, except that the provisions of KRS 161.620(3) shall not apply. Members providing part-time and substitute services who meet the service retirement conditions of KRS 161.600 may also be eligible to participate as approved by the board of trustees in the medical insurance program provided by the retirement system under KRS 161.675. Members providing part-time and substitute services shall make contributions to the Kentucky Teachers’ Retirement System at the rate provided under KRS 161.540. A member who provides part-time or substitute services, or in the event of the death of the member, the member’s estate or applicably designated beneficiary, will be entitled, within ninety (90) days of the posting of the annual report submitted by the member’s employer, to a refund of contributions as permitted and limited by KRS 161.470; </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees shall adopt eligibility conditions under which members providing part-time and substitute services may participate in the benefits provided under KRS 161.520, 161.655, 161.661, and 161.663. The board of trustees may permit members providing part-time or substitute services to participate in other benefits offered by the retirement system by promulgating administrative regulations that establish eligibility conditions for participation in these benefits. All eligibility conditions adopted by the board of trustees pursuant to this subsection may be amended as necessary to ensure their actuarial soundness; </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the pro rata methodology adopted by the board of trustees under subsection (1) of this section, members providing part-time and substitute services shall be subject to all limitations and conditions regarding the accrual, retention, accreditation, and use of service credit that apply to members providing full-time services. In addition to the eligibility conditions set forth by the board of trustees under subsection (2) of this section, members providing part-time and substitute services shall be subject to all limitations and conditions regarding both the eligibility to participate and the extent of participation in any benefit offered under KRS 161.220 to 161.716 that apply to members providing full-time services; </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section to the contrary, instructional assistants who provide teaching services in the local school districts on a full-time basis in positions covered by the County Employees Retirement System who are used as substitute teachers on an emergency basis for five (5) days or less during any one (1) fiscal year shall not be considered members of the Teachers' Retirement System during that period in which they are serving as substitute teachers for five </section><section prefix="5">days or less; </section>(5) The board of trustees may adopt a pro rata methodology to determine the annual compensation of members providing part-time and substitute services in order to determine benefits provided under KRS 161.661 and 161.663. Members providing part-time and substitute services who had retirement contributions posted to their accounts during the previous fiscal year and who have not had those contributions refunded to them are eligible to vote for the board of trustees; <section prefix="6">The board of trustees of the Teachers’ Retirement System shall be responsible for final determination of membership eligibility and may direct employers to take whatever action that may be necessary to correct any error relating to membership; and </section><section prefix="7">The provisions of this section are not subject to KRS 161.714. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 15, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 17, effective July 1, 2004. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3963</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>