<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.228</section_number><catch_line>"State employee" defined. </catch_line><order_by>228</order_by><text>For purposes of KRS 18A.228 to 18A.2286, the term "state employee" shall mean a person, including an elected public official, who is regularly employed by any department, board, agency, or branch of state, municipal, urban-county, charter county, or county government, and who is a contributing member of any of the retirement systems administered by the state and including any federally-funded time-limited employee. It shall also include a person who must fulfill the requirements established by the State Board of Education for eligibility and a person who is a present or future recipient of a retirement allowance from any of the Kentucky Retirement Systems who either satisfies the requirements of KRS 61.559 or who is board-authorized under KRS 61.702(1), including a beneficiary of a retired employee as defined in KRS 61.542 who is receiving a retirement allowance from any of the Kentucky Retirement Systems and shall include a member of the Legislators' Retirement Plan as provided in KRS 18A.2287. </text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  1990 Ky. Acts ch. 348, secs. 1 and 2 were enacted to be placed within the range of KRS 18A.228 to 18A.2284. However, because of space limitations within this range, these two sections were codified as KRS 18A.2285 and 18A.2286, respectively. Accordingly, the prior reference within this section to the former end section of the range has been changed by the Reviser of Statutes to read KRS 18A.2286, pursuant to his authority under KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1410</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>