<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.042</section_number><catch_line>License to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse -- Application -- Renewal -- Reinstatement -- Use of "APRN" -- Prescriptive authority under CAPA-NS and CAPA-CS -- Exemption from CAPA-NS requirement.   </catch_line><order_by>042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse shall file with the board a written application for licensure and submit evidence, verified by oath, that the applicant has completed an approved organized postbasic program of study and clinical experience; is certified by a nationally established organization or agency recognized by the board to certify registered nurses for advanced practice registered nursing; and is able to understandably speak and write the English language and to read the English language with comprehension. </section><section prefix="2">The board may issue a license to practice advanced practice registered nursing to an applicant who holds a current active registered nurse license issued by the board or holds the privilege to practice as a registered nurse in this state and meets the qualifications of subsection (1) of this section. An advanced practice registered nurse shall be: <section prefix="a">Designated by the board as a certified registered nurse anesthetist, certified nurse midwife, certified nurse practitioner, or clinical nurse specialist; and </section><section prefix="b">Certified in at least one (1) population focus. </section></section><section prefix="3">The applicant for licensure or renewal thereof to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse shall pay a fee to the board as set forth in regulation by the board. </section><section prefix="4">An advanced practice registered nurse shall maintain a current active registered nurse license issued by the board or hold the privilege to practice as a registered nurse in this state and maintain current certification by the appropriate national organization or agency recognized by the board. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who holds a license to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse in this state shall have the right to use the title "advanced practice registered nurse" and the abbreviation "APRN." No other person shall assume the title or use the abbreviation or any other words, letters, signs, or figures to indicate that the person using the same is an advanced practice registered nurse. No person shall practice as an advanced practice registered nurse unless licensed under this section. </section><section prefix="6">Any person heretofore licensed as an advanced practice registered nurse under the provisions of this chapter who has allowed the license to lapse may be reinstated on payment of the current fee and by meeting the provisions of this chapter and regulations promulgated by the board pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="7">The board may authorize a person to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse temporarily and pursuant to applicable regulations promulgated by the board pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A if the person is awaiting the results of the national certifying examination for the first time or is awaiting licensure by endorsement. A person awaiting the results of the national certifying examination shall use the title "APRN Applicant" or "APRN App." </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">Except as authorized by KRS 314.196 and subsection (9) of this section, before an advanced practice registered nurse engages in the prescribing or dispensing of nonscheduled legend drugs as authorized by KRS 314.011(8), the advanced practice registered nurse shall enter into a written "Collaborative Agreement for the Advanced Practice Registered Nurse's Prescriptive Authority for Nonscheduled Legend Drugs" (CAPA-NS) with a physician licensed in Kentucky that defines the scope of the prescriptive authority for nonscheduled legend drugs. </section><section prefix="b">The advanced practice registered nurse shall notify the Kentucky Board of Nursing of the existence of the CAPA-NS and the name of the collaborating physician and shall, upon request, furnish to the board or its staff a copy of the completed CAPA-NS. The Kentucky Board of Nursing shall notify the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure that a CAPA-NS exists and furnish the collaborating physician's name. </section><section prefix="c">The CAPA-NS shall be in writing and signed by both the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician. A copy of the completed collaborative agreement shall be available at each site where the advanced practice registered nurse is providing patient care. </section><section prefix="d">The CAPA-NS shall describe the arrangement for collaboration and communication between the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician regarding the prescribing of nonscheduled legend drugs by the advanced practice registered nurse. </section><section prefix="e">The advanced practice registered nurse who is prescribing nonscheduled legend drugs and the collaborating physician shall be qualified in the same or a similar specialty. </section><section prefix="f">The CAPA-NS is not intended to be a substitute for the exercise of professional judgment by the advanced practice registered nurse or by the collaborating physician. </section><section prefix="g">The CAPA-NS shall be reviewed and signed by both the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician and may be rescinded by either party upon written notice via registered mail to the other party, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, and the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure. </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">Before an advanced practice registered nurse may discontinue or be exempt from a CAPA-NS required under subsection (8) of this section, the advanced practice registered nurse shall have completed four (4) years of prescribing as a nurse practitioner, clinical nurse specialist, nurse midwife, or as a nurse anesthetist. For nurse practitioners and clinical nurse specialists, the four (4) years of prescribing shall be in a population focus of adult-gerontology, pediatrics, neonatal, family, women's health, acute care, or psychiatric-mental health. </section><section prefix="b">After four (4) years of prescribing with a CAPA-NS in collaboration with a physician: <section prefix="1">An advanced practice registered nurse whose license is in good standing at that time with the Kentucky Board of Nursing and who will be prescribing nonscheduled legend drugs without a CAPA-NS shall notify that board that the four (4) year requirement has been met and that he or she will be prescribing nonscheduled legend drugs without a CAPA-NS; </section><section prefix="2">The advanced practice registered nurse will no longer be required to maintain a CAPA-NS and shall not be compelled to maintain a CAPA-NS as a condition to prescribe after the four (4) years have expired, but an advanced practice registered nurse may choose to maintain a CAPA-NS indefinitely after the four (4) years have expired; and </section><section prefix="3">If the advanced practice registered nurse's license is not in good standing, the CAPA-NS requirement shall not be removed until the license is restored to good standing. </section></section><section prefix="c">An advanced practice registered nurse wishing to practice in Kentucky through licensure by endorsement is exempt from the CAPA-NS requirement if the advanced practice registered nurse: <section prefix="1">Has met the prescribing requirements in a state that grants independent prescribing to advanced practice registered nurses; and </section><section prefix="2">Has been prescribing for at least four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="d">An advanced practice registered nurse wishing to practice in Kentucky through licensure by endorsement who had a collaborative prescribing agreement with a physician in another state for at least four (4) years is exempt from the CAPA-NS requirement. </section><section prefix="e">After July 15, 2014: <section prefix="1">An advanced practice registered nurse whose license is in good standing at that time with the Kentucky Board of Nursing and who will be prescribing nonscheduled legend drugs without a CAPA-NS shall notify that board that the four (4) year requirement has been met and that he or she will be prescribing nonscheduled legend drugs without a CAPA-NS; </section><section prefix="2">An advanced practice registered nurse who has maintained a CAPA-NS for four (4) years or more will no longer be required to maintain a CAPA-NS and shall not be compelled to maintain a CAPA-NS as a condition to prescribe after the four (4) years have expired, but an advanced practice registered nurse may choose to maintain a CAPA-NS indefinitely after the four (4) years have expired; and </section><section prefix="3">An advanced practice registered nurse who has maintained a CAPA-NS for less than four (4) years shall be required to continue to maintain a CAPA-NS until the four (4) year period is completed, after which the CAPA-NS will no longer be required. </section></section></section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">Before an advanced practice registered nurse engages in the prescribing of Schedules II through V controlled substances as authorized by KRS 314.011(8), the advanced practice registered nurse shall enter into a written "Collaborative Agreement for the Advanced Practice Registered Nurse's Prescriptive Authority for Controlled Substances" (CAPA-CS) with a physician licensed in Kentucky that defines the scope of the prescriptive authority for controlled substances. </section><section prefix="b">The advanced practice registered nurse shall notify the Kentucky Board of Nursing of the existence of the CAPA-CS and the name of the collaborating physician and shall, upon request, furnish to the board or its staff a copy of the completed CAPA-CS. The Kentucky Board of Nursing shall notify the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure that a CAPA-CS exists and furnish the collaborating physician's name. </section><section prefix="c">The CAPA-CS shall be in writing and signed by both the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician. A copy of the completed collaborative agreement shall be available at each site where the advanced practice registered nurse is providing patient care. </section><section prefix="d">The CAPA-CS shall describe the arrangement for collaboration and communication between the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician regarding the prescribing of controlled substances by the advanced practice registered nurse. </section><section prefix="e">The advanced practice registered nurse who is prescribing controlled substances and the collaborating physician shall be qualified in the same or a similar specialty. </section><section prefix="f">The CAPA-CS is not intended to be a substitute for the exercise of professional judgment by the advanced practice registered nurse or by the collaborating physician. </section><section prefix="g">Before engaging in the prescribing of controlled substances, the advanced practice registered nurse shall: <section prefix="1">Have been licensed to practice as an advanced practice registered nurse for one (1) year with the Kentucky Board of Nursing; or </section><section prefix="2">Be nationally certified as an advanced practice registered nurse and be registered, certified, or licensed in good standing as an advanced practice registered nurse in another state for one (1) year prior to applying for licensure by endorsement in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="h">Prior to prescribing controlled substances, the advanced practice registered nurse shall obtain a Controlled Substance Registration Certificate through the U.S. Drug Enforcement Agency. </section><section prefix="i">The CAPA-CS shall be reviewed and signed by both the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician and may be rescinded by either party upon written notice via registered mail to the other party, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, and the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure. </section><section prefix="j">The CAPA-CS shall state the limits on controlled substances which may be prescribed by the advanced practice registered nurse, as agreed to by the advanced practice registered nurse and the collaborating physician. The limits so imposed may be more stringent than either the schedule limits on controlled substances established in KRS 314.011(8) or the limits imposed in regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Nursing thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="11">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring an advanced practice registered nurse designated by the board as a certified nurse anesthetist to enter into a collaborative agreement with a physician, pursuant to this chapter or any other provision of law, in order to deliver anesthesia care. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 117, sec. 12, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 53, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 86, sec. 5, effective June 1, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 21, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 113 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>