<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.530</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees to operate fund and direct policies -- Membership -- How chosen. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The responsibility for the proper operation of the fund and the direction of its policies shall be vested in a board of trustees of twelve (12) members, consisting of the mayor, the commissioner of public safety, the commissioner of finance, the director of human resources, two (2) retired members of the fund, the chiefs of the police and fire department, and two (2) active members of each department, who shall be elected by ballot by the active members of the respective departments and shall serve for alternating terms of two (2) years under rules adopted by the board. One of the active members representing each department shall be elected on even-numbered years; and the other active member representing the department shall be elected on odd-numbered years. In the event of a vacancy of an elected member, the pension board shall fill the vacancy by appointment until the next regular election. </section><section prefix="2">The retired fund members shall be selected by retired fund members by ballot to serve two (2) year terms. One (1) retired fund member shall be a retired fire department member, and the other shall be a retired police department member. Retired fund members of a department shall submit the names of at least three (3) nominees from their department to the pension board not less than three (3) months before the term of office is due to expire. The retired members of both departments shall have the right to vote for nominees from either department. For the term beginning October 15, 2000, names of nominees from each department shall be submitted to the pension board by no later than August 15, 2000. The pension board shall cause to be prepared an official ballot which shall be distributed to all retired fund members by mail to their last known address. The ballot shall contain the name, address, and former department of each of the candidates. The candidates shall be grouped together by departments for voting purposes and retired fund members shall be instructed to vote for one (1) member from each department. Any ballot marked with more than one (1) vote per department shall be disqualified and not counted. The retiree from either department receiving the most votes shall serve a two (2) year term. The retiree from the other department receiving the most votes shall serve an initial term of one (1) year. Subsequently, retirees elected in alternate years from each department shall serve two (2) years. In the event of vacancy of an elected retired fund member of the board, the retiree receiving the next largest number of votes from the department for which the vacancy exists shall fill the vacancy until the next election for a representative of that retiree's department. Retired fund members shall vote for one (1) candidate from each department by marking a square opposite the name of the candidate of his choice and returning the marked ballot to the secretary of the pension board. Votes shall be tabulated by a committee of three (3) pension board members appointed by the chairman for that purpose. The tabulating committee shall report in writing to the pension board the results of the election and the name of the retired fund member who shall serve on the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 333, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 484, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 18, effective July 1, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 333 and 484. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between a change in ch. 484 that is a revisory amendment to delete superseded text and a change in ch. 333 that is nonrevisory and substantive in nature, ch. 333 has been allowed to prevail. Cf. KRS 7.136(3) </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>