<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.560</section_number><catch_line>Hemophilia Advisory Committee. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Hemophilia Advisory Committee for the purpose of acting in an advisory capacity to the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs regarding the hemophilia treatment program. The committee shall consist of nine (9) members. The executive director of the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs shall be an ex officio member. The other eight (8) members of the committee shall be appointed by the Governor and shall hold office for a term of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify, except that of those members initially appointed the terms shall be as follows: two </section><section prefix="2">members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) for two (2) years, two (2) </section>for three (3) years, and two (2) for four (4) years. Appointments shall be made one (1) from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the following organizations: the Kentuckiana Chapter of the National Hemophilia Foundation, the Kentucky Medical Association, the Kentucky Pharmacists Association, and the Kentucky Hospital Association. The other four (4) appointive members shall be citizens residing within the Commonwealth who are hemophiliacs, parents of hemophiliacs, or health care providers interested in hemophilia. (2) Each appointive member of the committee shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual and necessary expenses in carrying out his duties. <section prefix="3">Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term in the same manner as original appointments, maintaining representations as set out in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall elect a chairman, vice chairman, and secretary from among its members at its first regular meeting in each fiscal year and shall adopt rules governing its proceedings. The committee shall hold a meeting at least once every three (3) months and such other special or regular meetings as may be desired. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted and amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 107, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 211.740. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7313</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>