<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.085</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of registration -- Change of residence -- Name change. </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a voter changes his place of residence to another location within the county, the clerk shall, upon application of the voter in person, by mail, or through a circuit clerk, transfer the voter's registration record to the proper precinct. </section><section prefix="2">When a registered voter changes his place of residence from one (1) precinct to another within the same county before the registration books are closed and fails to transfer his registration with the county clerk prior to the date the registration books are closed, the voter shall be permitted to update the voting records and to vote in the present election at the appropriate precinct for the current address upon affirmation of his current address and signing the precinct list as set forth in KRS 117.225. Before being permitted to vote, the voter shall also confirm his identity as required in KRS 117.227 and complete the affidavit which is required to be completed by a voter whose right to vote has been challenged. The subscribed oaths shall be delivered to the county clerk and investigated in accordance with KRS 117.245. </section><section prefix="3">When a registered voter changes his place of residence from one (1) precinct to another precinct within the same county after the registration books close, the voter shall be permitted to vote in the present election at the appropriate precinct for the current address upon affirmation of his current address and signing the precinct list as set forth in KRS 117.225. Before being permitted to vote, the voter shall confirm his identity as required by KRS 117.227 and complete the affidavit which is required to be completed by a voter whose right to vote is challenged. The subscribed oaths shall be delivered to the county clerk and investigated in accordance with KRS 117.245. </section><section prefix="4">When the boundaries of a precinct are changed by law, placing a registered voter in a new or different precinct, the clerk shall automatically transfer the voter's registration record to the proper precinct and mail the voter a notice of the change. </section><section prefix="5">A voter who has changed his name may indicate the change at the precinct on election day by completing the form provided for this purpose by the State Board of Elections. The form shall be returned by the precinct officer to the county clerk who shall make the necessary change on the voter's registration record. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 6, effective January 1, 1995. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 8, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1995 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  In Attorney General Opinion 94-42, it was concluded that 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, which amended this statute "will take effect on January 1, 1995, the date the National Voter Registration Act will take effect with respect to Kentucky." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27312</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>