<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.150</section_number><catch_line>Information required with application for certificate of eligibility. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No applicant shall be given a certificate of eligibility unless his financial statement and the investigation made by the department show that he possesses net current assets or working capital sufficient in the judgment of the department to render it probable that he can satisfactorily execute his contracts and meet obligations therein incurred. All applications for certificates shall expressly authorize the department to obtain all information which it deems pertinent with respect to the financial status, assets, and liabilities of the applicant from any persons having business transactions with the applicant, and shall expressly authorize all those persons to furnish any information requested from them by the department. </section><section prefix="2">No applicant shall be given a certificate of eligibility until the applicant provides the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet with his sworn statement made under penalty of perjury that he has not knowingly violated any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth and that the award of a contract to the applicant will not violate any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth. "Knowingly" means, with respect to conduct or to a circumstance described by a statute defining an offense, that a person is aware or should have been aware that his conduct is of that nature or that the circumstance exists. </section><section prefix="3">Certificates of eligibility shall be issued without reference to the residence of applicants and the administrative regulations regarding the issuance of certificates shall apply equally to residents and nonresidents. A certificate of eligibility shall not be denied to any applicant upon the sole issue of nationality or residence. </section><section prefix="4">When the applicant is a foreign corporation, limited liability company, or limited partnership, the application shall be accompanied by a certificate from the Secretary of State of the jurisdiction in which it is organized certifying that it is validly existing and in good standing and a certificate from the Kentucky Secretary of State certifying that it is authorized to transact business in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 45, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 45, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 22, effective July 14, 1992. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4356t-20, 4356t-22, 4356t-23. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5185</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>