<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.570</section_number><catch_line>Construction and installation standards and requirements for manufactured homes, mobile homes, and previously owned recreational vehicles -- Certified installer seal -- Inspection -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall enforce such standards and requirements for the installation of plumbing, heating, and electrical systems in manufactured homes and mobile homes and for previously owned recreational vehicles as it determines are reasonably necessary in order to protect the health and safety of the occupants and the public. These standards and requirements shall be those adopted by the Manufactured Home Certification and Licensure Board. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall enforce such standards and requirements for the body and frame design, construction, and installation of manufactured homes and mobile homes as it determines are reasonably necessary in order to protect the health and safety of the occupants and the public. These standards and requirements shall be those adopted by the Manufactured Home Certification and Licensure Board. If any part of 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136 conflicts with Title 6 of the Federal Housing and Community Development Act of 1974, the federal act shall take precedence. </section><section prefix="3">All installations of manufactured homes and mobile homes shall be performed by an installer certified under the provisions of KRS 227.560 in accordance with the manufacturer's instructions, if available, or ANSI A225.1, Manufactured Home Installations. </section><section prefix="4">A certified installer shall apply for a certified installer seal prior to installing a manufactured home or a mobile home. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. The administrative regulations shall provide for the fees, purchase and application of the seal, report procedures, and attachment of the certified installer seal. </section><section prefix="5">The installation of a new manufactured home shall be inspected under subsection (3) of this section. The retailer of the inspected property shall pay a new manufactured home installation inspection fee in an amount not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section><section prefix="6">The board shall specify the new manufactured home installation fee established in subsection (5) of this section through the promulgation of an administrative regulation. The board may increase the fee, but by no more than ten percent (10%) per year, and at no time shall the fee exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section><section prefix="7">All fees received by the department under this section shall be deposited in the trust and agency fund specified in KRS 227.620(5). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 414, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 31, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 4. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "office" of the state fire marshal in subsection (7) of this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, has been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938.  (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 31, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>