<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.37-130</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition of control or merger of domestic insurers. </catch_line><order_by>37-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following definitions shall apply for the purposes of this section only: <section prefix="a">"Acquisition" means any agreement, arrangement, or activity the consummation of which results in a person acquiring directly or indirectly the control of another person, such as the acquisition of voting securities, the acquisition of assets, bulk reinsurance, and mergers; and </section><section prefix="b">An "involved insurer" includes an insurer which either acquires or is acquired, is affiliated with an acquirer or acquired, or is the result of a merger. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">This section applies to any acquisition in which there is a change of control of an insurer authorized to do business in Kentucky, except as set forth in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">This section shall not apply to the following: <section prefix="1">An acquisition subject to approval or disapproval of the commissioner pursuant to KRS 304.37-120; </section><section prefix="2">A purchase of securities solely for the investment purposes so long as the securities are not used by voting or otherwise to cause or attempt to cause the substantial lessening of competition in any insurance market in Kentucky. If a purchase of securities results in a presumption of control under KRS 304.37-010(8), it is not solely for investment purposes unless the insurance regulatory official of the insurer's state of domicile accepts a disclaimer of control, or affirmatively finds that control does not exist, and the disclaimer action or affirmative finding is communicated by the domiciliary insurance regulatory official to the commissioners; </section><section prefix="3">If the acquisition of a person by another person when both persons are neither directly nor through affiliates primarily engaged in the business of insurance, if preacquisition notification is filed with the commissioner in accordance with subsection (3)(a) of this section thirty (30) days prior to the proposed effective date of the acquisition. However, the acquisition notification shall not be required for exclusion from this section if the acquisition would otherwise be excluded from this section by any other subparagraph of this paragraph; </section><section prefix="4">The acquisition of already affiliated persons; </section><section prefix="5">An acquisition if, as an immediate result of the acquisition: <section prefix="a">The combined market share of the involved insurers would not exceed five percent (5%) of the total market; </section><section prefix="b">There would be no increase in any market share; or </section><section prefix="c">The combined market share of the involved insurers would not exceed twelve percent (12%) of the total market; and the market share would not increase by more than two percent (2%) of the total market. </section></section> For the purpose of this subparagraph (b)5., a market means direct written insurance premium in Kentucky for a line of business as contained in the annual statement required to be filed by insurers authorized to do business in Kentucky; <section prefix="6">An acquisition for which a preacquisition notification would be required pursuant to this section due solely to the resulting effect on the ocean marine insurance line of business; and </section><section prefix="7">An acquisition of an insurer whose domiciliary insurance regulatory official affirmatively finds that the insurer is in failing condition, there is lack of feasible alternative to improving the condition, the public benefits of improving the insurer's condition through the acquisition exceed the public benefits that would arise from not lessening competition, and the findings are communicated by the domiciliary insurance regulatory official to the commissioner. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">An acquisition covered by subsection (2) of this section may be subject to an order pursuant to subsection (5) of this section or KRS 304.37-010 unless the acquiring person files a preacquisition notification and the waiting period has expired. The acquired person may file a preacquisition notification. The commissioner shall give confidential treatment to information submitted under this subsection in the same manner as provided in KRS 304.37-050. <section prefix="a">The preacquisition notification shall be in the form and contain the information prescribed by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners relating to those markets which, under subsection (2)(b)5. of this section, cause the acquisition not to be exempted from the provisions of this section. The commissioner may require additional material and information the commissioner deems necessary to determine whether the proposed acquisition, if consummated, would violate the competitive standard of subsection (4) of this section. The required information may include an opinion of an economist as to the competitive impact of the acquisition in Kentucky accompanied by a summary of the education and experience of the economist indicating his or her ability to render an informed opinion. </section><section prefix="b">The waiting period required shall begin on the date of receipt by the commissioner of a preacquisition notification and shall end on the earlier of the thirtieth day after the date of receipt, or termination of the waiting period by the commissioner. Prior to the end of the waiting period, the commissioner may, on a one-time basis, require the submission of additional needed information relevant to the proposed acquisition; if the submission is required, the waiting period shall end on the earlier of the thirtieth day after receipt of the additional information by the commissioner or termination of the waiting period by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The commissioner may enter an order under subsection (5)(a) of this section with respect to an acquisition if there is substantial evidence that the effect of the acquisition may be to lessen substantially competition in any line of insurance in Kentucky or tend to create a monopoly, or if the insurer fails to file adequate information in compliance with subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">In determining whether a proposed acquisition would violate the competitive standard of paragraph (a) of this subsection, the commissioner shall consider the following: <section prefix="1">Any acquisition covered under subsection (2) of this section involving two (2) or more insurers competing in the same market is prima facie evidence of violation of the competitive standards: <section prefix="a">If the market is highly concentrated and the involved insurers possess the following shares of the market: </section><section prefix="b">If the market is not highly concentrated and the involved insurers </section></section><section prefix="2">There is a significant trend toward increased concentration when the <section prefix="a">There is a significant trend toward increased concentration in the </section><section prefix="b">One of the insurers involved is one of the insurers in a grouping of </section><section prefix="c">Another involved insurer's market is two percent (2%) or more; </section></section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of subsection (4)(b) of this section: <section prefix="a">The term "insurer" includes any company or group of companies </section><section prefix="b">The term "market" means the relevant product and geographical </section><section prefix="c">The burden of showing prima facie evidence of violation of the </section></section><section prefix="4">Even though an acquisition is not prima facie violative of the </section></section>    Insurer A Insurer B     4% 4% or more     10% 2% or more     15% 1% or more;  or possess the following shares of the market:     Insurer A Insurer B     5% 5% or more     10% 4% or more     15% 3% or more     19% 1% or more.  A highly concentrated market means one in which the share of the four (4) largest insurers is seventy-five percent (75%) or more of the market. Percentages not shown in the tables are interpolated proportionately to the percentages that are shown. If more than two (2) insurers are involved, exceeding the total of the two (2) columns in the table is prima facie evidence of violation of the competitive standard in paragraph (a) of this subsection. For the purpose of this subparagraph, the insurer with the largest share of the market shall be deemed to be insurer A; aggregate market share of any grouping of the largest insurers in the market, from the two (2) largest to the eight (8) largest, has increased by seven percent (7%) or more of the market over a period of time extending from any base year five (5) to ten (10) years prior to the acquisition up to the time of the acquisition. Any acquisition or merger covered under subsection (2) of this section involving two (2) or more insurers competing in the same market is prima facie evidence of violation of the competitive standard in paragraph (a) of this subsection if: market; the large insurers showing the requisite increase in the market share; and under common management, ownership or control; markets. In determining the relevant product and geographical markets, the commissioner shall give due consideration to factors such as the definitions or guidelines, if any, promulgated by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and to information, if any, submitted by parties to the acquisition. In the absence of sufficient information to the contrary, the relevant product market is assumed to be the direct written insurance premium for a line of business, the line being that used in the annual statement required to be filed by insurers doing business in Kentucky, and the relevant geographical market is assumed to be Kentucky; and competitive standard rests upon the commissioner; and competitive standard under paragraph (b) of this subsection, the commissioner may establish the requisite anticompetitive effect based upon other substantial evidence. Even though an acquisition is prima facie violative of the competitive standard under paragraph (b) of this subsection, a party may establish the absence of the requisite anticompetitive effect based upon other substantial evidence. Relevant factors in making this determination shall be such factors as market shares, volatility of ranking of market leaders, number of competitors, concentration, trend of concentration in the industry, and ease of entry into and exit from the market. <section prefix="c">An order shall not be entered under subsection (5)(a) of this section if: <section prefix="1">The acquisition will yield substantial economies of scale or economies in resource utilization that cannot be feasibly achieved in any other way, and the public benefits which would arise from the economies exceed the public benefits which would arise from not lessening competition; or </section><section prefix="2">The acquisition will substantially increase the availability of insurance, and the public benefits of the increase exceed the public benefits which would arise from not lessening competition. </section></section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">If an acquisition violates the standards of this section, the commissioner may enter an order: <section prefix="1">Requiring an involved insurer to cease and desist from doing business in Kentucky with respect to the line or lines of insurance involved in the violation; or </section><section prefix="2">Denying the application of an acquired or acquiring insurer for a certificate of authority to do business in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="b">The order referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be entered pursuant to a hearing held under Subtitle 2 of this chapter. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1484, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29942</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>