<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-211</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet to prepare and publish maps, surveys, directories, and studies. </catch_line><order_by>12-211</order_by><text>The cabinet shall prepare and publish, or cause to be prepared and published, maps, economic and industrial resources surveys of the state and of individual communities and areas, directories of manufacturers, exporters, and industrial services, surveys as related to natural resources and industrial and commercial needs, studies of agri-business opportunities, surveys of forestry industries potential, studies of industrial site characteristics, and other matters relating to the economic development of the Commonwealth as it shall deem necessary and advisable. </text><history>Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 154.12-211, 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 34, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 3. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 3. -- Created 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. IX. sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1992 </effective><former-codification> KRS 152.070 </former-codification><lrc-note>(10/29/96).  Under KRS 7.136(2), a reference to the Department for Existing Business and Industry in this statute has been changed to the cabinet (i.e., the Cabinet for Economic Development). This department was eliminated by the repeal of KRS 154.12-209 by 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 28, and the duties and functions of the department were reassigned to the cabinet, see 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 499, secs. 13, 14, and 15. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2629</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>