<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties for violation of KRS 353.500 to 353.720. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 353.570 shall be subject to a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisonment for a term not exceeding one hundred and eighty (180) days, or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who continues to violate any provision of KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or any regulation or order promulgated or issued under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 after being notified in writing of the violation by the department shall be subject to a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisonment for a term not exceeding one hundred and eighty (180) days, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who does any of the following for the purpose of evading or violating KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or any regulation or order promulgated or issued under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall be subject to a fine of not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisonment for a term not exceeding one hundred and eighty (180) days, or both: <section prefix="a">Makes or causes to be made a false entry or statement in a report, record, account or memorandum, required by KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or by any regulation or order; </section><section prefix="b">Omits or causes to be omitted from a report, record, account or memorandum full, true, and correct entries and information as required by KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or by any regulation or order; </section><section prefix="c">Removes from this Commonwealth or destroys, mutilates, alters or falsifies a report, record, account or memorandum required by KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or by any regulation or order. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person who knowingly aids or abets any other person in the violation of any provision of KRS 353.500 to 353.720, or any regulation or order promulgated or issued under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall be subject to the same penalty as that prescribed in this section for the violation by the other person. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 353.655 shall be notified by the department that he has twenty (20) days in which to remedy the violation. If after the twenty (20) day time period has elapsed he has failed or refused to comply with the provisions of KRS 353.655, he shall be subject to a fine of twenty dollars ($20) a day until the oil or gas well is brought into compliance. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1985. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 8. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 24, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33165</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>