<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.184</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of KRS 211.182 by cabinet and secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </catch_line><order_by>184</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the cabinet to enforce the provisions of KRS 211.182, and for that purpose the investigators, inspectors, representatives, and agents of the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the cabinet shall have the full power and authority of peace officers in this state, and shall have the power and authority to administer oaths, to enter upon premises at all times for the purpose of making inspections, to seize evidence, to interrogate all persons, and to require the production of books, papers, documents, or other evidence. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services may institute, in his own name, proceedings to enjoin and restrain violations of KRS 211.182, regardless of whether the defendant has been convicted of violation of the penal provisions thereof, and shall not be required to pay any costs or filing fees or furnish any bond in connection therewith. Violation of injunctions and restraining orders shall be punished as a contempt without the intervention of a jury. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 346, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 290, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 204, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(17). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>