<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.110</section_number><catch_line>Display of number on boat -- Specifications -- Certificate of number to be kept available. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owners shall cause to be painted on or attached to each side of the bow of the motorboat the identification number in such manner as may be prescribed by rules and regulations of the department in order that it may be clearly visible. The number shall be maintained in a legible condition. The certificate of number shall be pocket size and shall be available at all times for inspection on the motorboat for which issued, whenever such motorboat is in operation, except as provided in KRS 235.230.  </section><section prefix="2">All numbers placed upon the bow of a motorboat subject to this numbering system shall be:  <section prefix="a">Painted on, or attached to, each side of the bow (i.e. the forward half) of the vessel;  </section><section prefix="b">Read from left to right;  </section><section prefix="c">And in such position as to provide maximum visibility;  </section><section prefix="d">In block letters of good proportion not less than three (3) inches in height;  </section><section prefix="e">Have spaces that are equal to the width of a letter other than "I" or a number other than "1" between the letter and the number groupings (Example: KY 1234 A);  </section><section prefix="f">Of a color which will contrast with the color of the background (i.e. dark numbers on a light background) and so maintained as to be clearly visible and legible.  </section></section><section prefix="3">No number other than the number awarded to a motorboat or granted reciprocity pursuant to this chapter shall be painted, attached, or otherwise displayed on either side of the bow of such motorboat. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 77, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 9. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, secs. 11, 21, and 34, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11055</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>