<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6909</section_number><catch_line>Contents of application -- Certificate from other state. </catch_line><order_by>6909</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for registration shall submit an application for registration to the office in a form prescribed by the office. An application filed under this section is a public record. The application must be in the name of an individual, and except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section, signed or otherwise authenticated by the applicant under penalty of perjury and state or contain: <section prefix="a">The name of the applicant and the address of the applicant's principal place of business; </section><section prefix="b">The name of the applicant's business or employer, if applicable; </section><section prefix="c">Any business or occupation engaged in by the applicant for the five (5) years next preceding the date of submission of this application; </section><section prefix="d">A description of the applicant's: <section prefix="1">Formal training as an athlete; </section><section prefix="2">Practical experience as an athlete agent; and </section><section prefix="3">Educational background relating to the applicant's activities as an athlete agent; </section></section><section prefix="e">The names and addresses of three (3) individuals not related to the applicant who are willing to serve as references; </section><section prefix="f">The name, sport, and last known team for each individual for whom the applicant acted as an athlete agent during the five (5) years next preceding the date of submission of the application; </section><section prefix="g">The names and addresses of all persons who are: <section prefix="1">With respect to the athlete agent's business if it is not a corporation, the partners, members, officers, managers, associates, or profit-sharers of the business; and </section><section prefix="2">With respect to a corporation employing the athlete agent, the officers, directors, and any shareholder of the corporation having an interest of five percent (5%) or greater; </section></section><section prefix="h">Whether the applicant or any person named pursuant to paragraph (g) of this subsection has been convicted of a crime that, if committed in this state, would be a crime involving moral turpitude or a felony, and identify the crime; </section><section prefix="i">Whether there has been any administrative or judicial determination that the applicant or any person named pursuant to paragraph (g) of this subsection has made a false, misleading, deceptive, or fraudulent representation; </section><section prefix="j">Any instance in which the conduct of the applicant or any person named pursuant to paragraph (g) of this subsection resulted in the imposition of a sanction, suspension, or declaration of ineligibility to participate in an interscholastic or intercollegiate athletic event on a student-athlete or educational institution; </section><section prefix="k">Any sanction, suspension, or disciplinary action taken against the applicant or any person named pursuant to paragraph (g) of this subsection arising out of occupational or professional conduct; and </section><section prefix="l">Whether there has been any denial of an application for, suspension or revocation of, or refusal to renew, the registration or licensure of the applicant or any person named pursuant to paragraph (g) of this subsection as an athlete agent in any state. </section></section><section prefix="2">An individual who has submitted an application for, and holds a certificate of, registration or licensure as an athlete agent in another state, may submit a copy of the application and certificate in lieu of submitting an application in the form prescribed pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. The office shall accept the application and the certificate from the other state as an application for registration in this state if the application to the other state: <section prefix="a">Was submitted in the other state within six (6) months next preceding the submission of the application in this state and the applicant certifies that the information contained in the application is current; </section><section prefix="b">Contains information substantially similar to or more comprehensive than that required in an application submitted in this state; and </section><section prefix="c">Was signed by the applicant under penalty of perjury. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 216, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repealed and reenacted 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 164.682. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4391</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>