<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">E IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL HAZARDOUS MATERIALS PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39E.140</section_number><catch_line>Political entities required to participate in local planning process. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">City, county, urban-county governments, and charter county governments, school districts, special purpose district boards, or other municipal corporations or political subdivisions of the state or local government shall participate in the planning process conducted by local emergency planning committees. This participation shall include, as a minimum, providing information concerning government-owned or controlled emergency response assets, reviewing plans developed by the committee, and concurring that the final plan can be executed with existing resources. </section><section prefix="2">In local governments where local emergency management agencies receive state or federal funds, those agencies shall provide administrative and planning support to the committee as specified by the director of the division. </section><section prefix="3">If state or federal funds are appropriated specifically to support emergency response planning or other portions of Pub. L. No. 99-499, these funds may be allocated to local emergency management agencies and may be expended as specified by the director. </section><section prefix="4">Local governments may enact ordinances specifying standards which owners or operators of facilities shall meet to provide warning of releases to workers and to the public which may be affected by a release. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 71, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>