<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.250</section_number><catch_line>Justices of the peace in counties of over 250,000 population not containing a consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for a county containing a consolidated local government, in counties containing a population of over two hundred fifty thousand (250,000), each justice of the peace shall be exclusively compensated for the performance of the duties of his office by a salary to be determined by the fiscal court at a rate no less than nine thousand six hundred dollars ($9,600) per annum but no greater than twelve thousand dollars ($12,000) per annum, which shall be paid, in equal monthly installments, out of the county treasury. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsections (2), (3), and (4) of KRS 64.200 shall apply to justices of the peace in counties containing a population of over two hundred fifty thousand (250,000) except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the same as to constables, and the recorder shall perform the same duties and functions in regard to moneys collected by or for justices of the peace as they are required by KRS 64.200 to perform in regard to moneys collected by or for constables. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2002. --  Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 31, effective January 2. 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 6. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1083a-2, 1083a-3, 1083a-6, 1083a-7, 1083a-11. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>.  A portion of Acts 1972, ch. 311, including this section and a portion of KRS 64.257 (now repealed), was not included in the enrolled bill, due apparently to clerical error. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>