<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">C STATE AID TO LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39C.040</section_number><catch_line>Director's responsibility -- Advisory committee. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Director of the Division of Emergency Management shall have overall responsibility for policy, guidance, administration, and proper utilization of the supplementary fund established in KRS 39C.010 and 39C.020. </section><section prefix="2">The director shall serve as the principal liaison between the division and local officials participating in programs affected by this fund. </section><section prefix="3">The director shall appoint an advisory committee consisting of seven (7) members, including no more than four (4) employees of the staff of the division, to assist in making initial funding allocations each fiscal year and in making quarterly adjustments, based upon program and financial reviews. The members of the committee shall serve at the pleasure of the director, but for no more than four (4) years without reappointment, and shall serve without reimbursement, except when funded through the emergency management assistance programs. The decisions of the committees shall be advisory only and not binding upon the director. </section><section prefix="4">The director, with the advice of the advisory committee, shall make determinations related to fund allocations. </section><section prefix="5">Area managers of the division shall fully explain program opportunities and requirements to local elected officials and local directors, review budget and program submissions, and make recommendations to the director. </section><section prefix="6">Funds pursuant to KRS 39C.010 and 39C.020 shall be made available to not more than one (1) local emergency management agency in any county on a reimbursement basis up to fifty percent (50%) of the total local funds expended in any given year by the local emergency management agency created pursuant to KRS Chapters 39A to 39F. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 43, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>