<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-165Prescription</section_number><catch_line>drug coverage to include exceptions or overridepolicy for refills of covered drugs -- Limitations and exclusions --Program for synchronization of medications.  </catch_line><order_by>17A-165Prescription</order_by><text>(1)Any health benefit plan that provides benefits for prescription drugs shallinclude an exceptions policy or an override policy that provides coverage forthe refill of a covered drug dispensed prior to the expiration of the insured'ssupply of the drug. The insurer shall provide notice in existing written orelectronic communications to pharmacies doing business with the insurer, thepharmacy benefit manager if applicable, and to the insured regarding theexceptions policy or override policy. This subsection shall not apply tocontrolled substances as classified by KRS Chapter 218A.(2)Nothing in this section shall prohibit an insurer from limiting payment to nomore than three (3) refills of a covered drug in a ninety (90) day period.(3)Any individual or group health benefit plan that provides benefits forprescription drugs shall provide a program for synchronization of medicationswhen it is agreed among the insured, a provider, and a pharmacist thatsynchronization of multiple prescriptions for the treatment of a chronic illness isin the best interest of the patient for the management or treatment of a chronicillness provided that the medications:(a)Are covered by the individual or group health benefit plan:(b)Are used for treatment and management of chronic conditions that aresubject to refills;(c)Are not a Schedule II controlled substance or a Schedule III controlledsubstance containing hydrocodone;(d)Meet all prior authorization criteria specific to the medications at the timeof the synchronization request;(e)Are of a formulation that can be effectively split over required short fillperiods to achieve synchronization; and(f)Do not have quantity limits or dose optimization criteria or requirementsthat would be violated in fulfilling synchronization.(4)To permit synchronization, an individual or group health benefit plan shall applya prorated daily cost-sharing rate to any medication dispensed by a networkpharmacy pursuant to this section.(5)Any dispensing fee shall not be prorated and shall be based on an individualprescription filled or refilled.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44745</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>