<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">B ESTHETICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>317B.020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Hairdressers and Cosmetologists to administer KRS Chapter 317B -- Powers and duties.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall administer and enforce this chapter and shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants for licensure and the issuance of licenses. </section><section prefix="2">The board may employ inspectors, staff, and other personnel as reasonably necessary to carry out this chapter. The compensation shall be established by the board. </section><section prefix="3">The board may promulgate administrative regulations, including but not limited to administrative regulations that: <section prefix="a">Protect the health and safety of the public; </section><section prefix="b">Protect the public against incompetent or unethical practice, misrepresentation, deceit, or fraud in the practice of esthetics or teaching of esthetic practices; </section><section prefix="c">Set standards for the operation of the schools and salons; </section><section prefix="d">Protect the students; </section><section prefix="e">Establish the quality of equipment, supplies, materials, records, and furnishings required in esthetic salons or classrooms; </section><section prefix="f">Establish course work and conduct of school owners, instructors, estheticians, esthetic salons, and cosmetology schools conducting classes in esthetic practices; </section><section prefix="g">Set the requirements for the proper education and training of students; </section><section prefix="h">Establish the qualifications of instructors of esthetic practices; </section><section prefix="i">Set standards for the hours and courses of instruction in esthetic practices; </section><section prefix="j">Establish the examinations of applicants for licenses; </section><section prefix="k">Establish a code of ethics for persons licensed by the board; and </section><section prefix="l">Establish fees required pursuant to this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="4">Administrative regulations pertaining to health and sanitation shall be approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services before becoming effective. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 675, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the establishment of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40896</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>