<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.746</section_number><catch_line>Statewide planning and mapping system for public buildings. </catch_line><order_by>746</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To the extent funds are made available, the Commonwealth Office of Technology shall establish a statewide planning and mapping system for public buildings in this state for use by response agencies who are called to respond to an act of terrorism or an emergency. </section><section prefix="2">The statewide planning and mapping system for public buildings shall include: <section prefix="a">Floor plans, fire protection information, building evacuation plans, utility information, known hazards, and information on how to contact emergency personnel; </section><section prefix="b">The manner by which the information required by paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be transferred to the system from state agencies and the local political subdivisions who participate in the system; </section><section prefix="c">Standards for the software that shall be used by state agencies and local political subdivisions that participate in the system; </section><section prefix="d">Conditions for use of the system by response agencies; </section><section prefix="e">Guidelines for: <section prefix="1">The accessibility and confidentiality of information contained within the system; and </section><section prefix="2">The incorporation, in connection with the use of the system, of the items described in subsection (3)(b) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="f">In accordance with information obtained by the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security, a priority for the distribution of any money that may be available for state agencies and political subdivisions to participate in the system; and </section><section prefix="g">Guidelines recommended by the Division of Emergency Management for the training of persons employed by the response agencies concerning the use of the system. </section></section><section prefix="3">To the extent money is available, state agencies and political subdivisions shall: <section prefix="a">Participate in the statewide planning and mapping system; and </section><section prefix="b">Incorporate into their use of the system, without limitation: <section prefix="1">Evacuation routes and strategies for evacuation; </section><section prefix="2">Alarms and other signals or means of notification; </section><section prefix="3">Plans for remaining inside a building, room, structure, or other location during an emergency when egress may be impossible or when egress may present a more substantial risk than remaining inside; and </section><section prefix="4">Training and strategies for prevention in connection with attacks involving violence. </section></section></section> If a state agency or political subdivision uses its own planning and mapping system before the Commonwealth Office of Technology establishes a statewide planning and mapping system, the state agency or political subdivision may continue to use its system unless money is made available for the state agency or political subdivision to update or modify its system as necessary for inclusion in the statewide system. <section prefix="4">The Commonwealth Office of Technology: <section prefix="a">Shall pursue any money that may be available from the federal government for the development and operation of a statewide planning and mapping system for public buildings, and for the distribution of grants to state agencies and political subdivisions that participate in the system; and </section><section prefix="b">May accept gifts, grants, and contributions for the development and operation of a statewide planning and mapping system, and for the distribution of grants to the state agencies and political subdivisions that participate in the system. </section></section><section prefix="5">Each state agency and political subdivision that participates in the system shall, on or before July 1, 2007, and on or before July 1 of each year thereafter, submit to the Commonwealth Office of Technology a progress report setting forth, in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Commonwealth Office of Technology, the experience of the agency or political subdivision with respect to its participation in the system. The Commonwealth Office of Technology shall receive and process the progress reports, and provide a summarized overview of the system to the Legislative Research Commission on or before October 1, 2007, and on or before October 1 of each year thereafter. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 14, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms reorganization within the executive branch and establishes the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><former-codification> KRS 11.520. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22102</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>