<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="181" order_by="181">COUNTY AND CITY BRIDGES, TUNNELS, AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>181.580</section_number><catch_line>Commission is a corporation -- Officers -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall constitute a corporation under the name of (insert name of city) Bridge Commission with the usual corporate powers. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall elect a chairman and a vice chairman from its members, and a secretary-treasurer who need not be a member of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">The members of the commission, other than the chief executive, shall receive compensation fixed by the city legislative body, either as a salary or as payment for meetings attended, but the compensation of the chairman shall not exceed one thousand dollars ($1000) per annum and the compensation of each other member shall not exceed five hundred dollars ($500) per annum. The commission shall fix the compensation of the secretary-treasurer in its discretion. </section><section prefix="4">All compensation of members and employees shall be paid solely from funds provided under the provisions of KRS 181.560 to 181.840, and the commission shall not exercise any powers given it to bind the commission beyond the extent to which money is provided under KRS 181.560 to 181.840. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3235g-10. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5632</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>