<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">STATE AND AREA PLANNING -- REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147.070</section_number><catch_line>State planning functions of Governor's Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor's Cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Prepare and adopt plans for complete systems of state or regional highways, expressways, parkways, parks, water supply and forest reservations, airways and air terminals, and other things of significance in furthering a well balanced development of the state. </section><section prefix="b">Advise with state agencies, local authorities and individuals with a view to the coordination of all physical development plans that are related to state activities. </section><section prefix="c">Make surveys of rural land utilization with a view to the determination of the areas suitable for field crops, reforestation, watershed protection, recreation and urban expansion. </section><section prefix="d">Draft for submission to the General Assembly such regulations affecting the use and development of property as are deemed reasonable and necessary for orderly and coordinated developments preserving the integrity of officially approved plans or conserving the natural resources of the state. </section><section prefix="e">Collect and publish information relating to welfare problems affecting the people of the state and make such recommendations on those problems to the General Assembly as may seem advisable and proper. </section><section prefix="f">Cooperate with planning boards of other states and the national planning board. </section><section prefix="g">Act as a research broker in assisting state government to meet its research needs and to perform such functions also upon request from local governments. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall have such powers as are necessary to promote state planning and to enable it to carry out the purposes of KRS 147.070 to 147.100. </section><section prefix="3">All public officials shall upon request furnish to the Governor's Cabinet, within a reasonable time, such available information as it may require for its work. The members and employees of the cabinet may, in the performance of their functions, enter upon any land, make examinations and surveys and place and maintain necessary monuments and marks thereon. </section><section prefix="4">Every state officer or agency, before requesting legislative or executive approval of a plan or authorization of an appropriation for a major public improvement related to or affected by any general plan prepared under authority of KRS 147.070 to 147.100, or before requesting a change of use or disposition of real property that is owned by the state or in which the state has an interest, shall make a written request to the Governor's Cabinet for its recommendations, and shall give the cabinet a reasonable opportunity to study and make its recommendations thereon. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1992c-2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1564</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>