<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4011</section_number><catch_line>Application for licensure as elevator contractor -- Contents -- Eligibility requirements.  </catch_line><order_by>4011</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An application for licensure as an elevator contractor shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">For an applicant who is a person or sole proprietor: <section prefix="1">Name; </section><section prefix="2">Residence; and </section><section prefix="3">Business address of the applicant; </section></section><section prefix="b">For an applicant that is a partnership: <section prefix="1">Names of the partners; </section><section prefix="2">Residential addresses of the partners; and </section><section prefix="3">Business address of the partnership; </section></section><section prefix="c">For an applicant that is a domestic corporation: <section prefix="1">Name of the principal corporate officer; </section><section prefix="2">Residential address of the principal corporate officer; and </section><section prefix="3">Business address of the corporation; </section></section><section prefix="d">For an applicant that is a corporation other than a domestic corporation: <section prefix="1">Name of the corporation's agent who is authorized to accept service of process and official notices on behalf of the corporation in the state; and </section><section prefix="2">Physical address of the corporation's authorized agent; </section></section><section prefix="e">The number of years the applicant has engaged in the business of installing, maintaining, or servicing elevators or fixed guideway systems; </section><section prefix="f">The approximate number of persons, if any, to be employed by the elevator contractor applicant; </section><section prefix="g">Proof that he or she has complied with workers' compensation and unemployment insurance laws; </section><section prefix="h">Evidence that the applicant is covered by general liability, personal injury, and property damage insurance; </section><section prefix="i">Criminal record of convictions, if any, as verified through a criminal background check conducted by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The cost of the background check shall be paid by the applicant; and </section><section prefix="j">Upon request by the department, supplemental documentation of information required by this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant for an elevator contractor license shall: <section prefix="a">Employ at least one (1) licensed elevator mechanic who performs the work described in KRS 198B.4003; and </section><section prefix="b">Have proof of compliance with insurance requirements of KRS 198B.4027. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  A reference to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5, has been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>