<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.400</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and conclusions. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the finding of the General Assembly that cultural opportunities and the arts have a direct and positive impact on the hotel industry through promotion of tourism and convention trade. The Kentucky Center for the Arts will serve as catalyst in the development of Louisville and Jefferson County as a major convention and entertainment center. The Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation will have as management priority the stimulation of the Jefferson County hotel industry and promotion of tourism through: <section prefix="a">The presentation of Kentucky and Louisville-area and nationally and internationally prominent arts activities which will attract regional audiences; </section><section prefix="b">Regional and national promotion of events occurring within the Commonwealth, along with ancillary services and activities; </section><section prefix="c">The development, in conjunction with local hotels and the arts and entertainment industry, of tourist packages including performance and group plans; </section><section prefix="d">The active solicitation of arts related conferences and conventions; </section><section prefix="e">The active participation with local hotels and convention bureaus in attracting non-arts related conferences and conventions, with the center serving as an important amenity; </section><section prefix="f">The development of a Kentucky folklore program which will attract participants and an audience from throughout the state; </section><section prefix="g">The contribution to cultural diversity and the attractiveness of Louisville and Jefferson County as a year-round tourist and entertainment attraction. </section></section><section prefix="2">For these reasons, the General Assembly concludes that the dedication of additional revenues from the increased transient room tax authorized in counties containing first class cities to the Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation will directly benefit the Jefferson County hotel industry, and that this dedication symbolizes the integral relationship between the Kentucky center and promotion of the Jefferson County hotel industry, created by KRS 153.400 to 153.460. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2480</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>