<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.981</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 164.981 to 164.9819. </catch_line><order_by>981</order_by><text>As used in KRS 164.981 to 164.9819: <section prefix="1">"Autism" means a developmental disability significantly affecting verbal and nonverbal communication and social interaction, generally evident before age three (3), that adversely affects educational performance. Characteristics of autism include: <section prefix="a">Irregularity and impairment in communication; </section><section prefix="b">Engagement in repetitive activity and stereotyped movement; </section><section prefix="c">Resistance to environmental change or change in daily routine; and </section><section prefix="d">Unusual responses to sensory experience. </section></section> The term does not include children with characteristics of an emotional-behavioral disability as defined in KRS 157.200; <section prefix="2">"Council" means the Council on Postsecondary Education in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">"Center" means the autism training center; </section><section prefix="4">"Client" means a person with the primary diagnosis of autism or autistic-like behavior; and </section><section prefix="5">"Expenses" means those reasonable and customary expenditures related to training and treatment of eligible clients as defined in administrative regulations promulgated by the council pursuant to KRS 13A. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 133, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4519</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>