<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.872</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure of information from financial information repository -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>872</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person may obtain or attempt to obtain, or cause to be disclosed or attempt to cause to be disclosed to any person, financial information from a financial information repository by knowingly: <section prefix="a">Making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to an officer, employee, or agent of a financial information repository with the intent to deceive the officer, employee, or agent into relying on that statement or representation for the purpose of releasing financial information; </section><section prefix="b">Making a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation to a customer of a financial information repository with the intent to deceive the customer into releasing financial information or authorizing the release of such information; or </section><section prefix="c">Providing any document to an officer, employee, or agent of a financial information repository, knowing that the document is forged, counterfeit, lost, or stolen, or that the document was fraudulently obtained, or that the document contains a false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation, if such a document is provided with the intent to deceive the officer, employee, or agent into releasing the financial information. </section></section><section prefix="2">Violation of this section is a Class D felony. If the person violating this section is a business that has violated this section on more than one (1) occasion, then that person also violates the Consumer Protection Act, KRS 367.110 to 367.300. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18925</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>