<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.6225</section_number><catch_line>Medical order for scope of treatment (MOST) form -- Eligible persons -- Scope -- Effect.   </catch_line><order_by>6225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An adult with decisional capacity, an adult's legal surrogate, or a responsible party may complete a medical order for scope of treatment directing medical interventions. The form shall have the title "MOST, Medical Orders for Scope of Treatment" and an introductory section containing the patient’s name and date of birth, the effective date of the form, including the statement "Form must be reviewed at least annually" and the statements "HIPAA permits disclosure of MOST to other health care professionals as necessary" and "This document is based on this person’s medical condition and wishes. Any section not completed indicates a preference for full treatment for that section." The form shall be in substantially the following order and format and shall have the following contents: <section prefix="a">Section A of the form shall direct cardiopulmonary resuscitation when a person has no pulse and is not breathing by selection of one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">"Attempt Resuscitation (CPR)"; or </section><section prefix="2">"Do Not Attempt Resuscitation"; and </section></section> include the statement "When not in cardiopulmonary arrest, follow orders in B, C, and D."; <section prefix="b">Section B of the form shall direct the scope of treatment when a person has a pulse or is breathing by selection of one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">Full scope of treatment, including the use of intubation, advanced airway interventions, mechanical ventilation, defibrillation or cardioversion as indicated, medical treatment, intravenous fluids, and comfort measures. This option shall include the statement "Transfer to a hospital if indicated. Includes intensive care. Treatment Plan: Full treatment, including life support measures."; </section><section prefix="2">Limited additional intervention, including the use of medical treatment, oral and intravenous medications, intravenous fluids, cardiac monitoring as indicated, noninvasive bi-level positive airway pressure, a bag valve mask, and comfort measures. This option excludes the use of intubation or mechanical ventilation. This option shall include the statement "Transfer to a hospital if indicated. Avoid intensive care. Treatment Plan: Provide basic medical treatments."; or </section><section prefix="3">Comfort measures, including keeping the patient clean, warm, and dry; use of medication by any route; positioning, wound care, and other measures to relieve pain and suffering; and the use of oxygen, suction, and manual treatment of airway obstruction as needed for comfort. This option shall include the statement "Do not transfer to a hospital unless comfort needs cannot be met in the patient's current location (e.g. hip fracture).". </section></section> These options shall be followed by a space for other instructions; <section prefix="c">Section C of the form shall direct the use of oral and intravenous antibiotics by selection of one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">Antibiotics if indicated for the purpose of maintaining life; </section><section prefix="2">Determine use or limitation of antibiotics when infection occurs; </section><section prefix="3">Use of antibiotics to relieve pain and discomfort; or </section><section prefix="4">No antibiotics, use other measures to relieve symptoms. </section></section> This option shall include a space for other instructions; <section prefix="d">Section D of the form shall: <section prefix="1">Have the heading "Medically Administered Fluids and Nutrition: The provision of nutrition and fluids, even if medically administered, is a basic human right and authorization to deny or withdraw shall be limited to the patient, the surrogate in accordance with KRS 311.629, or the responsible party in accordance with KRS 311.631."; </section><section prefix="2">Direct the administration of fluids if physically possible as determined by the patient's physician in accordance with reasonable medical judgment and in consultation with the patient, surrogate, or responsible party by selecting one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">Long-term intravenous fluids if indicated; </section><section prefix="b">Intravenous fluids for a defined trial period. This option shall be followed by "Goal:................."; or </section><section prefix="c">No intravenous fluids, provide other measures to ensure comfort; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Direct the administration of nutrition if physically possible as determined by the patient's physician in accordance with reasonable medical judgment and in consultation with the patient, surrogate, or responsible party by selecting one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">Long-term feeding tube if indicated; </section><section prefix="b">Feeding tube for a defined trial period. This option shall be followed by "Goal:................."; or </section><section prefix="c">No feeding tube. This option shall be followed by a space for special instructions; </section></section></section><section prefix="e">Section E of the form shall: <section prefix="1">Have the heading "Patient Preferences as a Basis for this MOST Form" and shall include the language "Basis for order must be documented in medical record"; </section><section prefix="2">Provide direction to indicate whether or not the patient has an advance medical directive such as a health care power of attorney or living will and, if so, a place for the printed name, position, and signature of the individual certifying that the MOST is in accordance with the advance directive; and </section><section prefix="3">Indicate whether oral or written directions were given and, if so, by which one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">Patient; </section><section prefix="b">Parent or guardian if patient is a minor; </section><section prefix="c">Surrogate appointed by the patient's advance directive; </section><section prefix="d">The judicially appointed guardian of the patient, if the guardian has been appointed and if medical decisions are within the scope of the guardianship; </section><section prefix="e">The attorney-in-fact named in a durable power of attorney, if the </section>durable power of attorney specifically includes authority for health care decisions; <section prefix="f">The spouse of the patient; </section><section prefix="g">An adult child of the patient or, if the patient has more than one (1) child, the majority of the adult children who are reasonably available for consultation; </section><section prefix="h">The parents of the patient; and </section><section prefix="i">The nearest living relative of the patient or, if more than one (1) relative of the same relation is reasonably available for consultation, a majority of the nearest living relatives; </section></section></section><section prefix="f">A signature portion of the form shall include spaces for the printed name, signature, and date of signing for: <section prefix="1">The patient’s physician; </section><section prefix="2">The patient, parent of minor, guardian, health care agent, surrogate, spouse, or other responsible party, with a description of the relationship to the patient and contact information, unless based solely on advance directive; and </section><section prefix="3">The health care professional preparing the form, with contact information; </section></section><section prefix="g">A section of the form shall be titled "Information for patient, surrogate, or responsible party named on this form" with the following language: "The MOST form is always voluntary and is usually for persons with advanced illness. MOST records your wishes for medical treatment in your current state of health. The provision of nutrition and fluids, even if medically administered, is a basic human right and authorization to deny or withdraw shall be limited to the patient, the surrogate in accordance with KRS 311.629, or the responsible party in accordance with KRS 311.631. Once initial medical treatment is begun and the risks and benefits of further therapy are clear, your treatment wishes may change. Your medical care and this form can be changed to reflect your new wishes at any time. However, no form can address all the medical treatment decisions that may need to be made. An advance directive, such as the Kentucky Health Care Power of Attorney, is recommended for all capable adults, regardless of their health status. An advance directive allows you to document in detail your future health care instructions or name a surrogate to speak for you if you are unable to speak for yourself, or both. If there are conflicting directions between an enforceable living will and a MOST form, the provisions of the living will shall prevail."; </section><section prefix="h">A section of the form shall be titled "Directions for Completing and Implementing Form" with these four (4) subdivisions: <section prefix="1">The first subdivision shall be titled "Completing MOST" and shall have the following language: </section> "MOST must be reviewed, prepared, and signed by the patient's physician in personal communication with the patient, the patient's surrogate, or responsible party.  MOST must be reviewed and contain the original signature of the patient's physician to be valid. Be sure to document the basis in the progress notes of the medical record. Mode of communication (e.g., in person, by telephone, etc.) should also be documented.  The signature of the patient, surrogate, or a responsible party is required; however, if the patient’s surrogate or a responsible party is not reasonably available to sign the original form, a copy of the completed form with the signature of the patient’s surrogate or a responsible party must be signed by the patient's physician and placed in the medical record.  Use of original form is required. Be sure to send the original form with the patient.  There is no requirement that a patient have a MOST.";<section prefix="2">The second subdivision shall be titled "Implementing MOST" and shall have the following language: "If a health care provider or facility cannot comply with the orders due to policy or personal ethics, the provider or facility must arrange for transfer of the patient to another provider or facility."; </section><section prefix="3">The third subdivision shall be titled "Reviewing MOST" and shall have the following language: </section> "This MOST must be reviewed at least annually or earlier if:  The patient is admitted and/or discharged from a health care facility;  There is a substantial change in the patient’s health status; or  The patient’s treatment preferences change.  If MOST is revised or becomes invalid, draw a line through Sections A-E and write "VOID" in large letters."; and <section prefix="4">The fourth subdivision shall be titled "Revocation of MOST" and shall have the following language: "This MOST may be revoked by the patient, the surrogate, or the responsible party."; and </section></section><section prefix="i">A section of the form shall be titled "Review of MOST" and shall have the following columns and a number of rows as determined by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure: <section prefix="1">"Review Date"; </section><section prefix="2">"Reviewer and Location of Review"; </section><section prefix="3">"MD/DO Signature (Required)"; </section><section prefix="4">"Signature of Patient, Surrogate, or Responsible Party (Required)"; and </section><section prefix="5">"Outcome of Review, describing the outcome in each row by selecting one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">No Change; </section><section prefix="b">FORM VOIDED, new form completed; or </section><section prefix="c">FORM VOIDED, no new form". </section></section></section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to develop the format for a standardized medical order for scope of treatment form to be approved by the board, including spacing, size, borders, fill and location of boxes, type of fonts used and their size, and placement of boxes on the front or back of the form so as to fit on a single sheet. The board may not alter the wording or order of wording provided in subsection (1) of this section, except to add identifying data such as form number and date of promulgation or revision and instructions for completing, reviewing, and revoking the election of the form. The board shall consult with appropriate professional organizations to develop the format for the medical order for scope of treatment form, including: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Association of Hospice and Palliative Care; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Hospital Association; </section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities; </section><section prefix="e">LeadingAge Kentucky; </section><section prefix="f">The Kentucky Right to Life Association; and </section><section prefix="g">Other groups interested in end-of-life care. </section></section><section prefix="3">The medical order for scope of treatment form developed under subsection (2) of this section shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">An advisory that completing the medical order for scope of treatment form is voluntary and not required for treatment; </section><section prefix="b">Identification of the person who discussed and agreed to the options for medical intervention that are selected; </section><section prefix="c">All necessary information necessary to comply with subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="d">The effective date of the form; </section><section prefix="e">The expiration or review date of the form, which shall be no more than one (1) calendar year from the effective date of the form; </section><section prefix="f">Indication of whether the patient has a living will directive or health care power of attorney, a copy of which shall be attached to the form if available; </section><section prefix="g">An advisory that the medical order for scope of treatment may be revoked by the patient, the surrogate, or a responsible party at any time; and </section><section prefix="h">A statement written in boldface type directly above the signature line for the patient that states "You are not required to sign this form to receive treatment." </section></section><section prefix="4">A physician shall document the medical basis for completing a medical order for scope of treatment in the patient's medical record. </section><section prefix="5">The patient, the surrogate, or a responsible party shall sign the medical order for scope of treatment form; however, if it is not practicable for the patient's surrogate or a responsible party to sign the original form, the surrogate or a responsible party shall sign a copy of the completed form and return it to the health care provider completing the form. The copy of the form with the signature of the surrogate or a responsible party, whether in electronic or paper form, shall be signed by the physician and shall be placed in the patient's medical record. When the signature of the surrogate or a responsible party is on a separate copy of the form, the original form shall indicate in the appropriate signature field that the signature is attached. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). During codification, the Reviser of Statutes has changed the numbering of subparagraphs within paragraphs (d) and (e) of subsection (1) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44035</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>