<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.853</section_number><catch_line>Prequalification of underwriters and bond counsels -- Request for proposals -- Response -- First meeting of selection committee -- Second meeting. </catch_line><order_by>853</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A firm shall not be considered for providing underwriting or bond counsel services unless the office has prequalified the firm prior to the date of issuance of the request for proposals. </section><section prefix="b">A firm's prequalification shall remain in effect for twenty-four (24) months from the date of prequalification. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The office shall consult with the bond issuing agency before arriving at a request for proposals. The request for proposals shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">The deadline for posing written questions about the request for proposals to the selection committee chairman elected pursuant to subsection (7)(b) of this section. This deadline shall occur before the deadline for filing a written response to a request for proposals; </section><section prefix="2">The deadline for filing a written response; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the services sought; </section><section prefix="4">A description of the skills required to perform the services; </section><section prefix="5">A description of evaluation factors and their relative weight, including the reciprocal preference for resident bidders required by KRS 45A.494; and </section><section prefix="6">In the case of a request for proposals from bond counsel firms, a requirement to submit proposed fees and expenses. </section></section><section prefix="b">The office shall provide materials to the firms which have prequalified pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. The materials shall include, but not be limited to, the request for proposals and the evaluation sheet to be used by the relevant selection committee. </section></section><section prefix="3">Prior to the deadline for posing questions established in the request for proposals, a firm may pose written questions about the request for proposals to the selection committee chairman. The chairman shall respond in writing. If, in the discretion of the chairman, an answer could have a material effect on other respondents' proposals, then both the question and the answer shall be distributed to all firms at the same time prior to the deadline for the filing of responses to the request for proposals. </section><section prefix="4">A firm shall file a written response to the request for proposals prior to the deadline for filing a written response established in the request for proposals. A firm which fails to meet the deadline shall be barred from the procurement process. </section><section prefix="5">The employees of the office and the members of the selection committee shall keep all responses to a request for proposals confidential until the contract to the winning firm has been awarded. </section><section prefix="6">The executive director of the office shall designate an office employee to identify which firms prequalified pursuant to subsection (1) of this section and filed, in a timely fashion, a written response to a request for proposals. He shall create a list of firms which have done so and certify the list. </section><section prefix="7">The office shall organize the selection committee's first meeting. At that meeting, each selection committee member shall sign a statement of confidentiality. Also, at that meeting, the selection committee shall: <section prefix="a">Determine whether a majority of the voting members are merit employees of the Commonwealth. If a majority are not merit employees, the selection committee shall disband, and another selection committee shall be selected pursuant to KRS 45A.843. A majority of its voting members shall be merit employees of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Elect from among the voting members of the committee a chairman and vice chairman who shall hold their positions for the duration of the selection committee's involvement in the bond issuance; </section><section prefix="c">Be provided with: <section prefix="1">The certified list created pursuant to subsection (6) of this section; </section><section prefix="2">If applicable, an out-of-state firm's preference handicap created pursuant to KRS 45A.873(1); </section><section prefix="3">The request for proposals; </section><section prefix="4">Forms for keeping a log of all contacts with firms which have responded to the request for proposals as well as contacts with persons acting on behalf of those firms. Each committee member shall keep a log which shall summarize the subject of any contact and state the date and place of the contact; and </section><section prefix="5">The selection evaluation sheets; and </section></section><section prefix="d">Discuss the future conduct of its affairs. </section></section><section prefix="8">At the second meeting of a selection committee, the committee shall: <section prefix="a">Be provided with the following: <section prefix="1">Written questions and answers produced pursuant to subsection (3) of this section; and </section><section prefix="2">The firms' responses to the request for proposals; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Discuss the future conduct of its affairs. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22498</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>