<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-143</section_number><catch_line>Bases for carbon dioxide emission reduction performance standards for existing natural gas-fired electric generating units. </catch_line><order_by>20-143</order_by><text>Except for adjustments of the performance standard on a case-by-case basis under KRS 224.20-144, the performance standard that shall be established for existing gas-fired electric generating units shall be based on the following: <section prefix="1">The best system of emission reduction which has been adequately demonstrated for gas-fired electric generating units subject to the performance standard. Best system of emission reduction shall take into account the cost of: <section prefix="a">Achieving the emission reduction; </section><section prefix="b">Impacting non-air-quality health and the environment; and  </section><section prefix="c">Maintaining energy requirements needed to serve the load of the electric generating unit; </section></section><section prefix="2">Reductions in emissions of carbon dioxide that can reasonably be achieved through measures undertaken at each gas-fired electric generating unit; and </section><section prefix="3">Efficiency and other measures that can be undertaken at the unit to reduce carbon dioxide emissions from the unit without switching from natural gas to other fuels that emit less carbon dioxide than natural gas or by limiting the utilization of the electric generating unit. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>