<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.866</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 158.865 to 158.867.   </catch_line><order_by>866</order_by><text>For purposes of KRS 158.865 to 158.867: <section prefix="1">"Attendance area" means the physical boundaries that determine the school that a student is to attend; </section><section prefix="2">"Core academic area" means reading or mathematics; </section><section prefix="3">"Economically disadvantaged student" or "disadvantaged" means a student who meets a school district's definition for purposes of the federal Elementary and Secondary Education Act, No Child Left Behind, Title I, Part A; </section><section prefix="4">"Enrichment instructor" means an individual considered appropriately qualified by the administrator of the summer learning program with approval by the local superintendent to instruct or facilitate a specific enrichment program, who has completed at least two (2) years of study at an accredited postsecondary education institution, who has complied with KRS 160.380, who is paid by the local district from funds other than federal Title I funds, and who is supervised by the director or principal of the summer program. A highly qualified teacher may be employed to teach enrichment classes; </section><section prefix="5">"Highly qualified teacher" means a person who holds a Kentucky certificate under KRS 161.030 or 161.048 for the subject or level of instruction he or she is teaching and who demonstrates competency in the core academic subjects taught; and </section><section prefix="6">"Low-achieving Title I student" means a student who performs academically below expected potential as measured by assessments used for Title I identification. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40599</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>