<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.390</section_number><catch_line>Adulterated food found in food establishment to be tagged -- Disposition. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any duly authorized officer mentioned in KRS 217.380 finds any article of food that is adulterated, or any other article or substance that is detrimental to public health, the article shall be tagged or otherwise properly marked, giving notice that the product is suspected of being adulterated or detrimental to public health and has been quarantined, and warning all persons not to remove it until given permission by the officer or the courts. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall remove or otherwise dispose of such article in violation of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The officer shall then petition the judge of the District Court in the judicial circuit in which the article is found, for the condemnation and destruction of the article. The owner or defender of the article shall be given the right to a hearing, first before the officer, if desired, and before the court. The notice of a hearing before the officer shall state the length of time within which the hearing may be had. </section><section prefix="4">If the finding of the court is with the officer, the article shall be destroyed at the expense of the owner, or by the owner under the supervision of the officer. The costs shall be taxed against the owner or defender of the property, if he appears. If no one appears, the costs shall be collected against the owner or agent properly ascertained. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 207, effective January 2, 1978 -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 102. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2060b-12. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>