<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.353</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Medal for Freedom -- Eligibility -- Administrative regulations -- Funds to defray costs.   </catch_line><order_by>353</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Medal for Freedom is hereby created to be awarded by the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs to an individual who has been killed in action on or after January 1, 1991, while: <section prefix="a">Engaged in an action against an enemy of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Engaged in military operations involving conflict with an opposing foreign force; </section><section prefix="c">Serving with friendly foreign forces engaged in an armed conflict against an opposing armed force in which the United States is not a belligerent party; or </section><section prefix="d">Serving in a combat zone as designated by presidential order. </section></section><section prefix="2">Individuals eligible to receive the Kentucky Medal for Freedom include: <section prefix="a">Members of the Kentucky National Guard or a Reserve Component stationed in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Members of a state National Guard or a Reserve Component who named Kentucky as a home of record; </section><section prefix="c">Members of the regular United States Armed Forces who named Kentucky as a home of record; and </section><section prefix="d">Members of the regular United States Armed Forces, a state National Guard, or a Reserve component who were buried in Kentucky on or after July 15, 2008, and have a surviving spouse, parent, or next available family member who is a Kentucky resident. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department shall enter the name of a recipient of the Kentucky Medal for Freedom on the Kentucky Medal for Freedom roll. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The department may receive funds from the veterans' program trust fund to defray the cost of the Kentucky Medal for Freedom. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42400</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>