<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.110</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations relating to classification, work, and pay of prisoners. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>The Department of Corrections shall promulgate administrative regulations it deems necessary and proper in relation to: <section prefix="1">The classification of prisoners; </section><section prefix="2">The terms and conditions under which prisoners may be assigned to work under the direction of any other state agency; </section><section prefix="3">The adequate care, supervision, guarding, discipline, maintenance, transportation, and housing of prisoners when assigned to work outside of the prison. The department shall ascertain from the jailer of the county in which the work is being carried on if accommodations are available, and shall place as many prisoners as possible under the care of the jailer; </section><section prefix="4">The payment of money to prisoners and their dependents for work performed, including the amount to be paid and the manner of the payment and distribution thereof; </section><section prefix="5">Any other purposes as the department deems necessary and proper for carrying out the intent of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 232, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 51, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 26. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3828b-11. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6879</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>