<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.120</section_number><catch_line>Division of Workers' Compensation Funds -- Fund's liability for claims occurring after December 12, 1996 -- Payment of settlements for income benefits. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Division of Workers' Compensation Funds in the Department of Workplace Standards which shall be responsible for the administration of the special fund and the coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund and the maintenance of records regarding the payment of claims by these funds. The Division of Workers' Compensation Funds shall be headed by a director appointed by the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, with the prior written approval of the Governor pursuant to KRS 12.050. The director shall be responsible for overseeing the administration of the funds and the maintenance of records regarding the payment of claims by the funds. </section><section prefix="2">The special fund shall have no liability upon any claim in which the injury occurred, or for cumulative trauma, the disability became manifest, or, for occupational disease, if the date of injury or last exposure occurred, after December 12, 1996. </section><section prefix="3">Where the employer has settled its liability for income benefits and thereafter a determination has been made of the special fund's liability, the special fund portion of the benefit rate shall be paid over the maximum period provided for by statute for that disability, with the period of payment beginning on the date settlement was approved by an administrative law judge. This provision is remedial and shall apply to all pending and future claims. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1786, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 3, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 9, sec. 31, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 390, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 9, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 34, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 17. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 11. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 9. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 12. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4901. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32400</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>