<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.145</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocal arrangements -- Recovery of benefit overpayments. </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet may enter into arrangements with the appropriate agencies of other states or of the federal government, or both, for the purpose of assisting the secretary and such agencies in the payment of benefits and the furnishing of services to unemployed or underemployed workers. Such arrangements may provide that the respective agencies shall, for and on behalf of each other, act as agents in effecting registrations for work, notices of unemployment, and any other certifications or statements relating to a worker's claim for benefits; in making investigations, taking depositions, holding hearings, or otherwise securing information relating to benefit eligibility and payments; and in such other matters as the secretary considers suitable in effectuating the purpose of these administrative arrangements. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary may enter into arrangements with the appropriate agencies of other states or the federal government whereby workers performing services in this and other states for a single employing unit under circumstances not specifically provided in KRS 341.050, or under similar provisions in the unemployment compensation laws of such other states, shall be deemed to be engaged in employment performed entirely within this state or within one of such other states. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The secretary shall participate in any arrangements for the payment of benefits on the basis of combining an individual's wages and employment covered under this chapter with his wages and employment covered under the unemployment compensation laws of other states or the federal government which are approved by the United States Secretary of Labor in consultation with the state unemployment compensation agencies as reasonably calculated to assure the prompt and full payment of benefits in such situations and which include provisions for applying the base period of a single state law to a claim involving the combining of an individual's wages and employment covered under two (2) or more state unemployment compensation laws, and avoiding the duplicate use of wages and employment by reason of such combining. Reimbursements to another state or the federal government, paid from the fund pursuant to this subsection, shall be deemed to be benefits for the purposes of this chapter and charged to contributory employers' reserve accounts and reimbursing employers' accounts in accordance with the provisions of KRS 341.530(2) and (3) to the extent of calculations made on wages paid during the base period established by KRS 341.090 and wages paid after such base period; provided, however, benefits based on a period previous to the base-wage period established by KRS 341.090 shall be charged to the pooled account for contributing employers only. Provided, that if the Secretary of Labor determines that the charging of reimbursements provided above is inconsistent with the requirements of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act, charges of such reimbursements shall then be made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="b">In order that such reciprocal arrangements, when entered into, may be effectuated, wages for insured work under an employment security law of another state or of the federal government shall be deemed to be wages earned in covered employment from a subject employer for the purpose of determining his benefits under this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, benefits shall not be denied or reduced to an individual solely because he files a claim in another state (or a contiguous country with which the United States has an agreement with respect to unemployment compensation) or because he resides in another state (or such a contiguous country) at the time he files a claim for benefits. </section><section prefix="5">To the extent permissible under the laws and Constitution of the United States, the secretary is authorized to enter into or cooperate in arrangements or reciprocal agreements with appropriate and duly authorized agencies of other states or the United States Secretary of Labor or both, whereby: <section prefix="a">Overpayments of unemployment benefits, as determined under this chapter, shall be recoverable (after due notice and opportunity for appeal has been provided to the claimant) by offset from unemployment benefits otherwise payable under the unemployment compensation law of another state, in either the current or any subsequent benefit year, in an amount equivalent to the amount of overpayment determined under this chapter, provided the Office of Employment and Training, Department of Workforce Investment, certifies to the other state the facts involved and that the claimant is liable to repay the benefits and the office requests the other state to recover the benefits; and </section><section prefix="b">Overpayments of unemployment benefits, as determined under the unemployment compensation law of another state, shall be recoverable (after such state has provided due notice and opportunity for appeal to the claimant) by offset from unemployment benefits otherwise payable under this chapter, in either the current or subsequent benefit year, in an amount equivalent to the amount of overpayment determined by such other state, provided such state certifies to the office the facts involved and that the individual is liable to repay the benefits and the state requests the office to recover the benefits; and </section><section prefix="c">Provided there is in effect a reciprocal agreement between this state and the United States Secretary of Labor, as authorized by Section 303(g)(2) of the Social Security Act, the overpayment of unemployment benefits or allowances for unemployment provided under a federal program administered by this state shall be recoverable by offset from benefits otherwise payable under this chapter or any such federal program. Such agreement shall also suffice to permit the offset from unemployment benefits, otherwise payable under a federal program administered by this state, the overpayment of unemployment benefits paid under this chapter. </section></section> If another state also has in effect a like agreement with the United States Secretary of Labor, then these provisions for cross-offset of state and federal unemployment benefits shall apply to benefits otherwise payable under this chapter, the laws of the other state or any federal unemployment program administered by either state. </text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 73, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 136, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 11. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 2. --Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 5. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32256</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>