<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">TURNPIKE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175.525</section_number><catch_line>Toll-road identification card -- Exemptions from tolls. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority or the cabinet shall establish by administrative regulation promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A a toll-road identification card to be provided to paying and nonpaying users of toll facilities. The toll-road identification cards shall be issued through an application process. A fee that shall not exceed five dollars ($5) may be established for the issuance of each card. </section><section prefix="2">Upon application, nonpaying accounts shall be established for: <section prefix="a">State police, local police, and fire department vehicles while the vehicles are being operated in an official capacity on a turnpike project; </section><section prefix="b">Emergency vehicles operated by an ambulance service while the vehicles are being operated in an official capacity, in both emergency and nonemergency situations on a turnpike project; </section><section prefix="c">Funeral processions on turnpike projects; and </section><section prefix="d">School district vehicles while the vehicles are being operated in an official capacity on turnpike projects. </section></section><section prefix="3">To receive the exemption contained in subsection (2) of this section, an ambulance service shall be licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 143, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 130, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 122, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 99 and 130, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5084</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>