<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="143" order_by="143">COAL TAX </unit></structure><section_number>143.021</section_number><catch_line>Tax credit for thin seam coal. </catch_line><order_by>021</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A nonrefundable severance tax credit against the severance tax imposed by KRS 143.020 shall be allowed for new permitted production after July 1, 2000, as follows. <section prefix="a">For coal mined from above-drainage seams using deep mining or underground mining methods, the credit shall be equal to: <section prefix="1">Two and one-quarter percent (2.25%) of the gross value of coal with a coal thickness of between twenty-seven (27) and thirty (30) inches; or </section><section prefix="2">Three percent (3%) of the gross value of coal with a coal thickness of less than twenty-seven (27) inches. </section></section><section prefix="b">For coal mined from below-drainage seams using deep mining or underground mining methods, the credit shall be equal to: <section prefix="1">Two and one-quarter percent (2.25%) of the gross value of coal with a coal thickness of between thirty-two (32) and thirty-six (36) inches; </section><section prefix="2">Three percent (3%) of the gross value of coal with a coal thickness of between twenty-seven (27) and thirty-two (32) inches; or </section><section prefix="3">Three and three-quarters percent (3.75%) of the gross value of coal with a coal thickness of less than twenty-seven (27) inches. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Coal thickness under subsection (1) of this section shall be based on the weighted average isopach mapping of actual coal thickness by mine as certified by a professional engineer for each reporting period. The taxpayer shall attach a copy of the certified isopach mapping for each reporting period to the return filed for that period. </section><section prefix="3">The taxpayer shall take the tax credit under this section in conjunction with the taxpayer's monthly return. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 478, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29234</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>