<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.015</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of 1952 Act amending game and fish laws -- Policy of state as to wildlife -- Liberal construction -- Promotion of hunger relief through wildlife management and conservation. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The declared purpose of Acts 1952, ch. 200, and the policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, is to protect and conserve the wildlife of this Commonwealth so as to insure a permanent and continued supply of the wildlife resources of this state for the purpose of furnishing sport and recreation for the present and for the future residents of this state; to promote the general welfare of the Commonwealth; to provide for the prudent taking and disposition of wildlife within reasonable limits, based upon the adequacy of the supply thereof; to protect the food supply of this state, and to insure the continuation of an important part of the commerce of this state which depends upon the existence of its wildlife resources. It is further the declared purpose of Acts 1952, ch. 200, and the policy of this Commonwealth, that an adequate and flexible system be installed to accomplish the aforesaid purposes. All of the provisions of Acts 1952, ch. 200, shall be liberally construed in such manner as most effectually to carry out its purposes and intent. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall establish a program to promote hunger relief through specific wildlife management and conservation efforts and shall utilize the funds derived from the sources outlined in KRS 150.150(3). </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 2, effective June 19, 1952. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1927</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>