<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.130</section_number><catch_line>License renewal -- Fees -- Waiver. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each certified social worker, licensed social worker and licensed clinical social worker shall renew his license every three (3) years, and shall pay the board a renewal fee as established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">Licensees whose licenses are renewed by the board shall be issued a renewal license. </section><section prefix="3">Renewal fees shall be waived for any licensee actually serving in the Armed Forces of the United States. The waiver shall be effective for six (6) months following honorable discharge, separation, or release from the Armed Forces, after which period a license shall be considered lapsed. </section><section prefix="4">The board may, at its discretion, require continuing education as a condition of license renewal. </section><section prefix="5">If the board requires continuing education as authorized in subsection (4), the continuing education requirements for each licensed social worker and each licensed clinical social worker shall include one and one-half (1.5) hours of continuing education approved by the board and covering the recognition and prevention of pediatric abusive head trauma, as defined in KRS 620.020, at least one (1) time every six (6) years. The one and one-half (1.5) hours of continuing education required under this section shall be included in the current number of required continuing education hours. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31931</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>