<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.15-315</section_number><catch_line>Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Individual Deferred Annuities. </catch_line><order_by>15-315</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section shall be known as the "Standard Nonforfeiture Law for Individual Deferred Annuities." </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not apply to any reinsurance group annuity purchased under a retirement plan or plan of deferred compensation established or maintained by an employer (including a partnership or sole proprietorship) or by an employee organization, or by both, other than a plan providing individual retirement accounts or individual retirement annuities under Section 408 of the Internal Revenue Code, as now or hereafter amended, premium deposit fund, variable annuity, investment annuity, immediate annuity, any deferred annuity contract after annuity payments have commenced, or reversionary annuity, nor to any contract which shall be delivered outside this state through an agent or other representative of the insurer issuing the contract. However, to the extent that a variable annuity contract provides benefits that do not, before the maturity date, vary in accordance with the investment performance of any separate account or accounts maintained by the insurer as to such contract, as provided for in KRS 304.15-390, the contract shall contain provisions that satisfy the requirements of this section and shall not otherwise be subject to this section. </section><section prefix="3">In the case of contracts issued on or after the operative date of this section as defined in subsection (12) of this section, no contract of annuity, except as stated in subsection (2) of this section, shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this state unless it contains in substance the following provisions, or corresponding provisions which in the opinion of the commissioner are at least as favorable to the contract holder, upon cessation of payment of considerations under the contract. <section prefix="a">That upon cessation of payment of considerations under a contract, the insurer will grant a paid-up annuity benefit on a plan stipulated in the contract of such value as is specified in subsections (5), (6), (7), (8), and (10) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">If a contract provides for a lump sum settlement at maturity, or at any other time, that upon surrender of the contract at or prior to the commencement of any annuity payments, the insurer will pay in lieu of any paid-up annuity benefit a cash surrender benefit of such amount as is specified in subsections (5), (6), (8), and (10) of this section. The insurer shall reserve the right to defer the payment of such cash surrender benefit for a period of six (6) months after demand therefor with surrender of the contract. </section><section prefix="c">A statement of the mortality table, if any, and interest rates used in calculating any minimum paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits that are guaranteed under the contract, together with sufficient information to determine the amounts of such benefits. </section><section prefix="d">A statement that any paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits that may be available under the contract are not less than the minimum benefits required by any statute of the state in which the contract is delivered and an explanation of the manner in which such benefits are altered by the existence of any additional amounts credited by the insurer to the contract, any indebtedness to the insurer on the contract or any prior withdrawals from or partial surrenders of the contract. </section></section> Notwithstanding the requirements of this subsection, any deferred annuity contract may provide that if no considerations have been received under a contract for a period of two (2) full years and the portion of the paid-up annuity benefit at maturity on the plan stipulated in the contract arising from considerations paid prior to such period would be less than twenty dollars ($20) monthly, the insurer may at its option terminate such contract by payment in cash of the then present value of such portion of the paid-up annuity benefit, calculated on the basis of the mortality table, if any, and interest rate specified in the contract for determining the paid-up annuity benefit, and by such payment shall be relieved of any further obligation under such contract. <section prefix="4">The minimum values as specified in subsections (5), (6), (7), (8), and (10) of this section of any paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits available under an annuity contract shall be based upon minimum nonforfeiture amounts as defined in this section. <section prefix="a">With respect to contracts providing for flexible considerations, the minimum nonforfeiture amount at any time at or prior to the commencement of any annuity payments shall be equal to an accumulation up to such time at a rate of interest of three percent (3%) per annum of percentages of the net considerations (as hereinafter defined) paid prior to such time, decreased by the sum of: <section prefix="1">Any prior withdrawals from or partial surrenders of the contract accumulated at a rate of interest of three percent (3%) per annum; and </section><section prefix="2">The amount of any indebtedness to the insurer on the contract, including interest due and accrued; </section></section> and increased by any existing additional amounts credited by the insurer to the contract. The net considerations for a given contract year used to define the minimum nonforfeiture amount shall be an amount not less than zero and shall be equal to the corresponding gross consideration credited to the contract during that contract year less an annual contract charge of thirty dollars ($30) and less a collection charge of one dollar and twenty-five cents ($1.25) per consideration credited to the contract during that contract year. The percentages of net considerations shall be sixty-five percent (65%) of the net consideration for the first contract year and eighty-seven and one-half percent (87.5%) of the net considerations for the second and later contract years. Notwithstanding the provisions of the preceding sentence, the percentage shall be sixty-five percent (65%) of the portion of the total net consideration for any renewal contract year which exceeds by not more than two (2) times the sum of those portions of the net considerations in all prior contract years for which the percentage was sixty-five percent (65%). <section prefix="b">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, for any contract issued on or after July 1, 2003, and before July 1, 2006, the interest rate at which net considerations, prior withdrawals, and partial surrenders shall be accumulated for the purpose of determining nonforfeiture amounts shall be no less than one and one-half percent (1.5%) per annum. </section><section prefix="c">With respect to contracts providing for fixed scheduled considerations, minimum nonforfeiture amounts shall be calculated on the assumption that considerations are paid annually in advance and shall be defined as for contracts with flexible considerations which are paid annually with two (2) exceptions: <section prefix="1">The portion of the net consideration for the first contract year to be accumulated shall be the sum of sixty-five percent (65%) of the net consideration for the first contract year plus twenty-two and one-half percent (22.5%) of the excess of the net consideration for the first contract year over the lesser of the net considerations for the second and third contract years; and </section><section prefix="2">The annual contract charge shall be the lesser of, <section prefix="a">Thirty dollars ($30), or </section><section prefix="b">Ten percent (10%) of the gross annual consideration. </section></section></section><section prefix="d">With respect to contracts providing for a single consideration, minimum nonforfeiture amounts shall be defined as for contracts with flexible considerations except that the percentage of net consideration used to determine the minimum nonforfeiture amount shall be equal to ninety percent (90%) and the net consideration shall be the gross consideration less a contract charge of seventy-five dollars ($75). </section></section><section prefix="5">Any paid-up annuity benefit available under a contract shall be such that its present value on the date annuity payments are to commence is at least equal to the minimum nonforfeiture amount on that date. Such present value shall be computed using the mortality table, if any, and the interest rate specified in the contract for determining the minimum paid-up annuity benefits guaranteed in the contract. </section><section prefix="6">For contracts which provide cash surrender benefits, such cash surrender benefits available prior to maturity shall not be less than the present value as of the date of surrender of that portion of the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit which would be provided under the contract at maturity arising from considerations paid prior to the time of cash surrender reduced by the amount appropriate to reflect any prior withdrawals from or partial surrenders of the contract, such present value being calculated on the basis of an interest rate not more than one percent (1%) higher than the interest rate specified in the contract for accumulating the net considerations to determine such maturity value, decreased by the amount of any indebtedness to the insurer on the contract, including interest due and accrued, and increased by any existing additional amounts credited by the insurer to the contract. In no event shall any cash surrender benefit be less than the minimum nonforfeiture amount at that time. The death benefit under such contracts shall be at least equal to the cash surrender benefit. </section><section prefix="7">For contracts which do not provide cash surrender benefits, the present value of any paid-up annuity benefit available as a nonforfeiture option at any time prior to maturity shall not be less than the present value of that portion of the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit provided under the contract arising from considerations paid prior to the time the contract is surrendered in exchange for, or changed to, a deferred paid-up annuity, such present value being calculated for the period prior to the maturity date on the basis of the interest rate specified in the contract for accumulating the net considerations to determine such maturity value, and increased by any existing additional amounts credited by the insurer to the contract. For contracts which do not provide any death benefits prior to the commencement of any annuity payments, such present values shall be calculated on the basis of such interest rate and the mortality table specified in the contract for determining the maturity value of the paid-up annuity benefit. However, in no event shall the present value of a paid-up annuity benefit be less than the minimum nonforfeiture amount at that time. </section><section prefix="8">For the purpose of determining the benefits calculated under subsections (6) and (7) of this section, in the case of annuity contracts under which an election may be made to have annuity payments commence at optional maturity dates, the maturity date shall be deemed to be the latest date for which election shall be permitted by the contract, but shall not be deemed to be later than the anniversary of the contract next following the annuitant's seventieth birthday or the tenth anniversary of the contract, whichever is later. </section><section prefix="9">Any contract which does not provide cash surrender benefits or does not provide death benefits at least equal to the minimum nonforfeiture amount prior to the commencement of any annuity payments shall include a statement in a prominent place in the contract that such benefits are not provided. </section><section prefix="10">Any paid-up annuity, cash surrender or death benefits available at any time, other than on the contract anniversary under any contract with fixed scheduled considerations, shall be calculated with allowance for the lapse of time and the payment of any scheduled considerations beyond the beginning of the contract year in which cessation of payment of considerations under the contract occurs. </section><section prefix="11">For any contract which provides, within the same contract by rider or supplemental contract provision, both annuity benefits and life insurance benefits that are in excess of the greater of cash surrender benefits or a return of the gross considerations with interest, the minimum nonforfeiture benefits shall be equal to the sum of the minimum nonforfeiture benefits for the annuity portion and the minimum nonforfeiture benefits, if any, for the life insurance portion computed as if each portion were a separate contract. Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (5), (6), (7), (8), and (10) of this section, additional benefits payable: <section prefix="a">In the event of total and permanent disability; </section><section prefix="b">As reversionary annuity or deferred reversionary annuity benefits; or </section><section prefix="c">As other policy benefits additional to life insurance, endowment and annuity benefits, and considerations for all such additional benefits; </section></section> shall be disregarded in ascertaining the minimum nonforfeiture amounts, paid-up annuity, cash surrender and death benefits that may be required by this section. The inclusion of such additional benefits shall not be required in any paid-up benefits, unless such additional benefits separately would require minimum nonforfeiture amounts, paid-up annuity, cash surrender and death benefits. <section prefix="12"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">After August 1, 2005, any insurer may file with the commissioner a written notice of its election to apply the provisions of KRS 304.15-365 on a contract-form by contract-form basis to annuity contracts issued by the insurer during the period from the date of the election through June 30, 2006; </section><section prefix="2">In all other instances, insurers shall apply the provisions of KRS 304.15-315 to annuity contracts issued through June 30, 2006; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Insurers shall apply the provisions of KRS 304.15-365 to all annuity contracts issued on or after July 1, 2006. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1183, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17231</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>