<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.180Individuals</section_number><catch_line>required to make return -- Verification.   </catch_line><order_by>180Individuals</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2005: <section prefix="a">Every individual, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, having for the taxable year an adjusted gross income which exceeds five thousand dollars ($5,000), if single, or if married and not living with husband or wife and every married individual living with husband or wife whose adjusted gross income combined with the adjusted gross income of his or her spouse exceeds five thousand dollars ($5,000) shall make to the department a return stating specifically the items which he claims as deductions and tax credits allowed by this chapter. </section><section prefix="b">Any individual who is blind or who has attained the age of sixty-five (65) before the close of the taxable year shall be required to make a return only if the taxpayer has for the taxable year an adjusted gross income which exceeds five thousand dollars ($5,000). Every married individual living with husband or wife shall, if both spouses have attained the age of sixty-five (65), be required to make a return if the combined adjusted gross income of both spouses exceeds five thousand four hundred dollars ($5,400). If the individual is unable to make his or her own return, the return shall be made by a duly authorized agent. </section><section prefix="c">Any individual, who is both sixty-five (65) or over and blind before the close of the taxable year, shall make a return if the taxpayer has for the taxable year an adjusted gross income which exceeds five thousand dollars ($5,000). </section><section prefix="d">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, an individual, having for the taxable year gross income from self-employment of five thousand dollars ($5,000) or more, shall make a return. </section><section prefix="e">Any nonresident individual with gross income from Kentucky sources and a total gross income of five thousand dollars ($5,000) or over shall make a return. </section></section><section prefix="2">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004: <section prefix="a">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, every individual having for the taxable year a modified gross income exceeding the threshold amount determined under KRS 141.066, and every married couple living together with a combined modified gross income exceeding the threshold amount determined under KRS 141.066, shall file a return with the department stating specifically the items claimed as deductions and tax credits allowed by this chapter. If the individual is unable to file a return, the return shall be made by a duly authorized agent. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, an individual having, for the taxable year, gross income from self-employment exceeding the threshold amount determined under KRS 141.066 shall file a return. </section><section prefix="c">Any nonresident individual with gross income from Kentucky sources and a total gross income exceeding the threshold amount determined under KRS 141.066 shall file a return. </section></section><section prefix="3">A husband and wife not living together shall make separate returns. A husband and wife living together may make a joint return, or may make separate returns. However, if separate returns are made, neither spouse shall report income nor claim deductions properly attributable to the other. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provisions of KRS Chapters 131 and 141, a husband or a wife who is jointly and severally liable for taxes levied under KRS 141.020, applicable penalties, and interest shall be relieved of liability for tax, interest, penalties, and other amounts if: <section prefix="a">The spouse has been relieved of liability for federal income tax, interest, penalties, and other amounts for the same taxable year by the Internal Revenue Service under Section 6015 of the Internal Revenue Code, to be effective as of the date that the Internal Revenue Service approved the relief; or </section><section prefix="b">It is shown that the spouse would have qualified for relief under the provisions of Section 6015 of the Internal Revenue Code for the same taxable year if there had been a federal income tax liability, to be effective as of the date that the department approved the relief. </section></section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding KRS 134.580, any relief granted pursuant to paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (4) of this section shall not result in a tax overpayment to the spouse requesting relief for payments made before the relief was approved. </section><section prefix="6">Each individual return shall be verified by a declaration that it is made under the penalties of perjury. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 12, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 485, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 14, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. VII D, sec. 634, effective April 11, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 77, Pt. I, sec. 4. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. III, sec. 5, effective February 5, 1960. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 3. -- Amended 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 9. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 4. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4281b-13, 4281b-17. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (7/14/2000).  The change in the Internal Revenue Code cites in subsection (7)(a) and (b) from Section 6013e to Section 6015 "apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1999." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44485</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>