<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.3975</section_number><catch_line>Training requirements for employment -- Biennial in-service training -- Extension -- Loss of status upon failure to complete training -- Regaining certification. </catch_line><order_by>3975</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A court security officer employed or appointed after June 26, 2007, shall satisfy the basic training requirements for employment if he or she successfully completes law enforcement training developed and approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council and the Administrative Office of the Courts of at least eighty (80) hours. </section><section prefix="2">A court security officer employed or appointed after June 26, 2007, shall successfully complete forty (40) hours of biennial in-service training that has been certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, and that is appropriate to the officer's responsibilities. </section><section prefix="3">In the event of extenuating circumstances beyond the control of a certified court security officer that prevent the officer from completing the basic or in-service training within the time specified in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, the commissioner of the department or his or her designee may grant the officer an extension of time, not to exceed one hundred eighty (180) days in which to complete the training. </section><section prefix="4">Any court security officer who fails to successfully complete basic training within the specified time periods, including extensions, shall lose his or her court security powers and his or her precertification status shall lapse. Any court security officer who fails to successfully complete in-service training within the specified time periods, including extensions, shall lose his or her court security powers and his or her certification status shall be changed to training deficiency status. When a court security officer is deficient in required training, the commissioner of the department or his or her designee shall notify the council, which shall notify the court security officer and his or her agency. </section><section prefix="5">A certified court security officer who has lost his or her court security powers due solely to his or her failure to meet the in-service training requirements of this section may regain his or her certification status and court security powers upon successful completion of the training deficiency. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=946</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>