<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.437</section_number><catch_line>Administering boards. </catch_line><order_by>437</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a private nonprofit corporation is designated as a community action agency, the board of directors of the private nonprofit corporation, if constituted in compliance with subsection (3) of this section, shall be the governing board.  </section><section prefix="2">When a political subdivision is designated as the community action agency the board of directors of the community action agency shall be a community action board constituted as required by subsection (3) of this section.  </section><section prefix="3">Governing boards and community action boards shall be so established and organized that the poor and residents of the area concerned will be able to influence the character of programs affecting their interests and regularly participate in the planning and implementation of those programs. The articles of incorporation shall be deemed to meet these requirements if they provide that:  <section prefix="a">One-third (1/3) of the members of the administering board shall be public officers, including elected public officials or their representatives, unless the number of public officers reasonably available or willing to serve is less than one-third (1/3) of the membership of the board;  </section><section prefix="b">At least one-third (1/3) of the members of the administering board shall be persons chosen in accordance with democratic selection procedures adequate to assure that they are representative of the poor in the area to be served by the agency;  </section><section prefix="c">The remaining members of the administering board shall be officials or members of business, industry, labor, religious, welfare, education, or other major groups and shall be interested in the community;  </section><section prefix="d">Each member of the board who is to represent a specific geographic area within a community shall reside in the area he represents; and  </section><section prefix="e">Total membership of the board is not less than fifteen (15) and not more than fifty-one (51).  </section></section><section prefix="4">Neighborhood based organizations composed of residents of the area or individual members of the groups served by the community action agency shall be consulted by each community action agency to assist the agency in the planning, conduct, and evaluation of components of the community action program.  </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13740</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>