<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.160</section_number><catch_line>Furnishing potential employer with person's record of convictions, guilty pleas, and Alford pleas involving specified crimes. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an employer may request from the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts, or both, records of all available convictions involving any felony offense, any misdemeanor offense in KRS Chapter 531 or KRS Chapter 510, any misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 218A committed within the five (5) years immediately preceding the application, or any conviction for violating KRS Chapter 189A committed within the five (5) years immediately preceding the application of a person who applies for employment or volunteers for a position in which he or she would have supervisory or disciplinary power over a minor. The cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts, as appropriate, shall furnish the information to the requesting employer and shall also send a copy of the information to the applicant. </section><section prefix="2">Any request for records under subsection (1) of this section shall be on a form approved by the cabinet and the Administrative Office of the Courts. No fee shall be charged to the employer or to the person whose records were requested if funding for the record checks provided for in this section is provided through some other mechanism; otherwise the cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts may charge a fee to be paid by the organization making the request, not to exceed the actual cost of processing the request. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet and the Administrative Office of the Courts shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. No administrative regulation shall be adopted requiring or authorizing the fingerprinting of applicants. </section><section prefix="4">As used in this section, "employer" means any organization chartered by the Congress of the United States or specified by the Attorney General which employs or uses the services of volunteers or paid employees in positions in which the volunteer or employee has supervisory or disciplinary power over a child or children. An organization which has an administrative office with paid personnel which has jurisdiction over suborganizations in one (1) or more counties shall make application for record checks through the administrative office of the organization and not through each individual suborganization. </section><section prefix="5">Offenses which may be searched for under this section are ones involving any conviction, plea of guilty, or Alford plea, to any offense specified in subsection (1) of this section or the attempted violation of any offense specified in subsection (1) of this section. Conviction for a violation or attempted violation of an offense committed outside the Commonwealth of Kentucky is a crime if such offense would have been a crime in Kentucky under subsection (1) of this section if committed in Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 88, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>