<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.11-007</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>11-007</order_by><text>This subtitle does not apply to: <section prefix="1">The United States or any department, agency, or instrumentality thereof; </section><section prefix="2">The United States Post Office or a contractor acting on behalf of the United States Post Office; </section><section prefix="3">A state or any agency, department, or political subdivision of a state; </section><section prefix="4">A financial institution or its subsidiaries, affiliates, and service corporations, or any office of an international banking corporation, branch of a foreign bank, or corporation organized pursuant to the Bank Service Corporation Act, 12 U.S.C. secs. 181 to 1867, or a corporation organized under the Edge Act, 12 U.S.C. secs. 611 to 633; or </section><section prefix="5">The provision of electronic transfer of government benefits for any federal, state, or county governmental agency as defined in Federal Reserve Board Regulation E, by a contractor for and on behalf of the United States or any department, agency, or instrumentality thereof, or any state or any political subdivisions thereof. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 4, effective April 24, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> April 24, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was created in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 as a new section of KRS Chapter 366A. Sec. 38 of that same bill also required that all sections of KRS Chapters 287, 288, 290, 291, 294, 366, 366A, and 368 be renumbered as sections of a single KRS chapter entitled the "Kentucky Financial Services Code." Therefore, the Statute Reviser, acting under KRS 7.136(1), has codified this section as a new section of KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14947</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>