<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.830</section_number><catch_line>Coercion of employees prohibited -- Lay-off priorities.   </catch_line><order_by>830</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful to coerce certified and equivalent employees who may be or who are subject to lay-off to resign or retire in lieu of lay-off. Dismissals shall comply with applicable statutes and lay-offs shall not be utilized as a method of dismissal. </section><section prefix="2">In the same office, county, and job classification, temporary, emergency, limited status, and probationary employees shall be laid-off before permanent full-time or permanent part-time employees with continuing status. The Office of Career and Technical Education shall not transfer positions, including vacant positions, in order to circumvent the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="3">If two (2) or more employees subject to lay-off in a lay-off plan submitted to the commissioner of education have the same qualifications and similar performance evaluations, the employee with the lesser seniority shall be laid-off first. </section><section prefix="4">An employee who is laid-off shall be placed on a reemployment list for the class of position from which laid-off and for any class for which such employee is qualified. </section><section prefix="5">For a period of three (3) years, laid-off employees shall be considered before any applicant from outside the Office of Career and Technical Education, except another laid-off employee with more seniority who is already on the list. </section><section prefix="6">For a period of three (3) years, a laid-off employee shall not be removed from the list unless: <section prefix="a">The laid-off employee notifies the office in writing that he or she no longer wishes to be considered for a position on the list; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) written offers of appointment are declined, the offers to be for a position of the same classification and salary, and located in the same county or contiguous counties, as the position from which laid-off; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) written offers to schedule an interview are made and the laid-off employee fails to respond to a certified letter requesting the laid-off employee to schedule an interview within ten (10) working days; </section><section prefix="d">The laid-off employee fails to report for an interview after notification in writing at least ten (10) calendar days prior to the date of the interview; </section><section prefix="e">The laid-off employee cannot be located by postal authorities at the last address provided; or </section><section prefix="f">The laid-off employee has willfully violated the provisions of KRS 156.800 to 156.860. </section></section><section prefix="7">When a laid-off employee has accepted a bona fide offer of appointment to any position, effective on a specified date, the employee's name may be removed from the list for all classes for which the maximum salary is the same as or less than that of the class of appointment. </section><section prefix="8">When a laid-off employee is removed from the reemployment list, the employee shall be notified in writing and shall be notified of the right to appeal to the board under provisions of KRS 156.820. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 31, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 24, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 14, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 151B.080. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42181</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>