<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9113</section_number><catch_line>Eminent domain.   </catch_line><order_by>9113</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a unit is acquired by eminent domain, or if part of a unit is acquired by eminent domain leaving the unit owner with a remnant which may not practically or lawfully be used for any purpose permitted by the declaration, the award shall compensate the unit owner for his or her unit and its interest in the common elements, whether or not any common elements are acquired. Upon acquisition, unless the decree otherwise provides, that unit's allocated interests are automatically reallocated to the remaining units in proportion to the respective allocated interests of those units before the taking, and the association shall promptly prepare, execute, and record an amendment to the declaration reflecting the reallocations. Any remnant of a unit remaining after part of a unit is taken under this subsection is thereafter a common element. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (1) of this section, if part of a unit is acquired by eminent domain, the award shall compensate the unit owner for the reduction in value of the unit and its interest in the common elements, whether or not any common elements are acquired. Upon acquisition, unless the decree otherwise provides: <section prefix="a">The unit's allocated interests are reduced in proportion to the reduction in the size of the unit; and </section><section prefix="b">The portion of the allocated interests divested from the partially acquired unit are automatically reallocated to that unit and the remaining units in proportion to the respective allocated interests of those units before the taking, with the partially acquired unit participating in the reallocation on the basis of its reduced allocated interests. </section></section><section prefix="3">If part of the common elements is acquired by eminent domain, the portion of the award attributable to the common elements taken shall be paid to the association and, unless the declaration provides otherwise, the award attributable to the acquisition of a limited common element shall be equally divided among the owners of the units to which that limited common element was allocated at the time of acquisition. </section><section prefix="4">The court decree shall be recorded in every county in which any portion of the condominium is located. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36824</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>