<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.247</section_number><catch_line>Highway construction contingency account. </catch_line><order_by>247</order_by><text>There is created within the road fund the highway construction contingency account. The account shall consist of moneys appropriated to the account by the General Assembly. The Transportation Cabinet may transfer money from the highway construction contingency account to a highway construction project, for expenditure thereon. These moneys may be authorized by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet for: <section prefix="1">Projects of an emergency nature; </section><section prefix="2">Promotion of economic or industrial development; </section><section prefix="3">Relief of a hazardous condition; </section><section prefix="4">Other purposes that the secretary determines to be a priority; </section><section prefix="5">Provision of required state match for any unanticipated federal funds made available by the Federal Highway Administration to the Commonwealth as a result of other states not utilizing their total federal obligation; </section><section prefix="6">The funding of any nonfederal share of a project in a previous or the current biennial highway construction programs that exceeds its cost estimate; </section><section prefix="7">The nonfederal share of federal emergency highway projects, federal discretionary projects, and federal demonstration projects; and </section><section prefix="8">The nonfederal share of projects due to an increase in the federal apportionment or federal obligation limits. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 532, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 433, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 502, sec. 4, effective April 11, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>