<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.544</section_number><catch_line>Colon Cancer Screening Advisory Committee -- Membership -- Duties -- Annual report -- Colon cancer screening, education, and outreach programs. </catch_line><order_by>544</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Colon Cancer Screening Advisory Committee shall be established within the Kentucky Cancer Consortium. The advisory committee shall include: <section prefix="a">One (1) appointee appointed by the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) appointee appointed by the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="c">The deputy commissioner of the Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) at-large members appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="e">The director of health initiatives for the mid-south division of the American Cancer Society; </section><section prefix="f">The director of the Kentucky Cancer Program at the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="g">The director of the Kentucky Cancer Program at the University of Louisville; </section><section prefix="h">The director of the Kentucky Cancer Registry; </section><section prefix="i">The director of the Colon Cancer Prevention Project; </section><section prefix="j">The chair of Kentucky African Americans Against Cancer; and </section><section prefix="k">The director of the Kentucky Cancer Consortium. </section></section> Members of the advisory committee shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. <section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Members appointed under subsection (1)(a) to (d) of this section shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="1">Members shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years, except as provided in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph; </section><section prefix="2">The initial appointments shall be for a period of two (2) years; thereafter, the appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years; and </section><section prefix="3">Members shall not serve more than two (2) terms of four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="b">Members serving under subsection (1)(e) to (k) of this section shall serve by virtue of their positions and shall not be subject to term limits. </section></section><section prefix="3">The chair of the advisory committee shall be elected from the membership of the advisory committee to serve for a two (2) year term. A member of the advisory committee may designate an alternate to attend meetings in his or her place. </section><section prefix="4">The advisory committee may add members from other organizations as deemed appropriate. </section><section prefix="5">The advisory committee shall provide recommendations for the overall implementation and conduct of the Colon Cancer Screening Program. </section><section prefix="6">The advisory committee shall establish and provide oversight for a colon cancer screening public awareness campaign. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall contract with the Kentucky Cancer Consortium at the University of Kentucky to provide the required support. The amount of the contract shall not be included in the base budget of the university as used by the Council on Postsecondary Education in determining the funding formula for the university. </section><section prefix="7">The Colon Cancer Screening Advisory Committee shall provide an annual report on implementation and outcomes from the Colon Cancer Screening Program and recommendations to the Legislative Research Commission, the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare, the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, the Governor, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the commissioner of the Department for Public Health. </section><section prefix="8">The Kentucky Cancer Program, jointly administered by the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville, shall establish a colon cancer screening, education, and outreach program in each of the state area development districts. The colon cancer screening, education, and outreach program shall focus on individuals who lack access to colon cancer screening. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall contract with the University of Louisville and the University of Kentucky to provide the required support. The amount of the contract shall not be included in the base budgets of the universities as used by the Council on Postsecondary Education in determining the funding formula for the universities. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  There are two incorrect internal references in subsection (2) of this statute that have not been corrected in codification because they are drafting errors, not manifest clerical or typographical errors correctable by the Reviser of Statutes under KRS 7.136(1)(h). However, the reference in subsection (2)(a) to "subsection (1) of this section" should have been drafted as "subsection (1)(a), (c), and (d) of this section" since the deputy commissioner of the Department for Public Health referenced in subsection (1)(c) of this statute serves as an ex officio, not appointed, member of the advisory committee. Likewise, the reference in subsection (2)(b) of this statute to "subsection (1)(e) to (k) of this section" should have been drafted as "subsection (1)(c) and (e) to (k) of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8838</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>