<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.625</section_number><catch_line>Procurement strategy for greater use of alternative fuel motor vehicles -- Reports.   </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall develop a strategy to: <section prefix="a">Replace at least fifty percent (50%) of the state-owned passenger vehicles and light-duty trucks managed by the Division of Fleet Management as of January 1, 2014, with: <section prefix="1">New qualified hybrid motor vehicles as defined in 26 U.S.C. sec. 30B; </section><section prefix="2">New advanced lean burn technology motor vehicles as defined in 26 U.S.C. sec. 30B; </section><section prefix="3">New qualified fuel cell motor vehicles as defined in 26 U.S.C. sec. 30B; or </section><section prefix="4">New qualified alternative fuel motor vehicles as defined in 26 U.S.C. sec. 30B; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Increase the use of ethanol, cellulosic ethanol, biodiesel, and other alternative transportation fuels as defined in KRS 152.715 to reduce state government's dependence on petroleum-based transportation fuels, where possible. </section></section><section prefix="2">On or before December 1, 2013, and every December 1 thereafter, the cabinet shall report to the Legislative Research Commission: <section prefix="a">The strategy for transitioning to motor vehicles outlined in subsection (1) of this section, including a life-cycle cost comparison, and a projected timetable to replace motor vehicles in the state motor pool as provided in subsection (1) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">The strategy for increased use of ethanol, cellulosic ethanol, biodiesel, and alternative transportation fuels, including the targeted amount and the dates by which these targets shall be achieved. </section></section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 34, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42409</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>