<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.181</section_number><catch_line>Determination of death by registered nurses -- Protocol for registered nurses employed by ambulance services -- Procedures not deemed artificial maintenance of respiration and circulation. </catch_line><order_by>181</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service shall complete training in determination of death and preservation of evidence as required by the board through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">A registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service shall determine whether or not a patient served by the ambulance service is dead. The registered nurse shall utilize the protocol specified by the board by administrative regulations. The registered nurse shall, when responding to a patient, first attempt resuscitation, unless the protocol indicates that the patient is not capable of being resuscitated. </section><section prefix="3">If it is determined that death has occurred in accordance with the procedures of KRS 446.400(1) concerning patients whose circulation and respiration are not being artificially maintained, the registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service may make the actual determination and pronouncement of death. </section><section prefix="4">When the determination and pronouncement of death of a patient whose circulation and respiration are not being artificially maintained, as required under KRS 446.400(1), occurs in a hospital or nursing facility, that declaration may be made by a registered nurse, in addition to any other person permitted by law to determine and pronounce death. The nurse shall notify the patient's attending physician of the death in accordance with the hospital's or facility's policy. </section><section prefix="5">In the event that a registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service determines that a person is dead, the registered nurse shall make the notifications required by KRS 72.020 and take the protective actions required by that statute. </section><section prefix="6">The administration of cardiopulmonary resuscitation or other basic life support measures to the apparently dead person, prior to the arrival of the registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service, by any person shall not be considered as artificial maintenance of respiration and circulation for the purposes of this section and KRS 446.400. The administration of advanced cardiac life support procedures by any person, other than a paramedic rendering care pursuant to KRS 311A.180, prior to the arrival of the registered nurse shall preclude the determination of death by the registered nurse, and the provisions of KRS 446.400 shall apply. Nothing in this section shall preclude the supervising physician from directing the registered nurse who is employed by an ambulance service to cease resuscitative efforts under approved agency medical protocols. </section><section prefix="7">The resuscitative efforts of a nurse under protocols authorized by this section shall not invoke the provisions of KRS 446.400. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 41, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 391, sec. 20, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>