<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.560</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45.570 to 45.640, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Contract" means any binding legal relationship between the Commonwealth of Kentucky and a contractor for supplies and services, including construction, or for the use of Commonwealth property, in which the parties, respectively, do not stand in the relationship of employer and employee; </section><section prefix="2">"Contractor" means any prime contractor holding a contract with the Commonwealth of Kentucky government, and shall include subcontractors when the context so indicates; </section><section prefix="3">"Contracting agency" means the person or persons, board, commission, court, council, governing body, employee, or official which is authorized by law to purchase or contract for supplies, materials, services, or equipment for the state; </section><section prefix="4">"Subcontractor" means any person, including a corporation, partnership, or business association of any kind, who holds an agreement or purchase order to perform all or any part of the work or to make or furnish any article or service required for the performance of a negotiated contract or of a subcontract entered thereunder; </section><section prefix="5">"Cabinet" means the Finance and Administration Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="6">"Equal employment opportunity job categories" means the major employment classifications described by the United States Equal Employment Opportunity Commission. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 171, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 171, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22282</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>