<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.813</section_number><catch_line>Manager -- Qualifications -- Powers and duties -- Bond. </catch_line><order_by>813</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Following a nationwide search, the board shall hire a manager, subject to Senate confirmation in accordance with KRS 11.160 who shall serve at the pleasure of the board. The manager shall be compensated at a level determined by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The manager shall have proven successful experience for a period of at least five (5) years as an executive at the general management level in insurance operations or in the management of a state fund for workers' compensation. </section><section prefix="3">The manager shall conduct the day-to-day operations of the authority for the purpose of carrying out the policies and procedures of the board. The duties of the manager include, but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Administering all operations of the authority in accordance with the direction of the board; </section><section prefix="b">Recommending to the board an annual administrative budget covering the operations of the authority and, upon approval, submitting the administrative budget, financial status, and actuarial condition of the authority to the Governor and the General Assembly for their examination; </section><section prefix="c">Directing and controlling all expenditures of the approved budget; </section><section prefix="d">From time to time, upon the recommendation of an actuary, recommending to the board actuarially-sound rating plans, and the amount of dividends, if any, to be returned to policyholders; </section><section prefix="e">Investing the assets of the authority under the guidance of the board and in accordance with the provisions of Subtitle 7 of KRS Chapter 304; </section><section prefix="f">Recommending to the board and administering a system of personnel administration; </section><section prefix="g">Preparing and administering fiscal, payroll, accounting, data processing, and procurement procedures for the operation of the authority; </section><section prefix="h">Recommending to the board bylaws and uniform procedures for the management of the authority; </section><section prefix="i">Within the limitations of the budget, employing necessary staff personnel in accordance with the personnel policies of the board; </section><section prefix="j">Maintaining appropriate levels of property, casualty, and liability insurance as approved by the board to protect directors, officers, employees, and assets of the authority; and </section><section prefix="k">Contracting in accordance with KRS 342.811 for claims administration, safety services, legal defense, actuaries, medical providers, financial services, and other services which the manager elects to obtain outside employed staff. </section></section><section prefix="4">The manager may: <section prefix="a">Reinsure any risk or part of any risk; </section><section prefix="b">Cause to be inspected and audited the payrolls of policyholders or employers applying to the authority for insurance; </section><section prefix="c">Establish procedures for adjusting claims in accordance with this chapter; and </section><section prefix="d">Require policyholders to maintain an adequate deposit to provide security for periods of coverage for which premiums have not been paid. </section></section><section prefix="5">The manager shall give an official bond in an amount and with sureties approved by the board. The premium for the bond shall be paid by the authority. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of KRS Chapters 18A and 64 shall not apply to the board, the manager, or the staff of the authority; however, the board shall adopt a system of personnel administration that includes benefits, grievance procedures, training and compensation. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 12,  sec. 45, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32566</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>