<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.120</section_number><catch_line>Assessment of civil penalties, suspension, revocation, delay, or modification of license or registration -- Causes. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text>The department may assess civil penalties as provided by KRS 217B.193, or may suspend, revoke, delay issuing, or modify the provision of any license or registration issued under this chapter, if it finds that the applicant or holder has committed any of the following acts, each of which is declared to be a violation of this chapter: <section prefix="1">Made false or fraudulent claims through any media, misrepresenting the effect of materials or methods to be utilized; </section><section prefix="2">Made a pesticide recommendation or application not in accordance with the label registered by the department under KRS 217.541 to 217.640; </section><section prefix="3">Applied known ineffective or improper materials; </section><section prefix="4">Operated faulty or unsafe equipment; </section><section prefix="5">Operated application equipment in a careless or negligent manner; </section><section prefix="6">Refused or, after notice, neglected to comply with the provisions of this chapter, the administrative regulations promulgated under this chapter, or of any lawful order of the department; </section><section prefix="7">Refused or neglected to keep and maintain the records required by this chapter, or to make reports when and as required; </section><section prefix="8">Made false or fraudulent records, invoices, or reports; </section><section prefix="9">Engaged in the business of the application of a pesticide without having a licensed applicator or operator in direct "on-the-job" supervision; </section><section prefix="10">Operated unregistered equipment; </section><section prefix="11">Used fraud or misrepresentation in making an application for a license or registration or renewal of a license or registration; </section><section prefix="12">Refused or neglected to comply with any limitations or restrictions on or in a duly issued license or registration; </section><section prefix="13">Aided or abetted a licensed or an unlicensed person to evade the provisions of this chapter, combined or conspired with a licensed or an unlicensed person to evade the provisions of this chapter, or allowed one's license to be used by an unlicensed person; </section><section prefix="14">Made false or misleading statements during or after an inspection concerning any infestation or infection of pests found on land; </section><section prefix="15">Impersonated any state, county, or city inspector or official; </section><section prefix="16">Made a sale to, or distributed a restricted use pesticide to, an uncertified applicator; </section><section prefix="17">Failed to obtain any license or registration required by this chapter; </section><section prefix="18">Failed to obtain or maintain financial responsibility required by this chapter; </section><section prefix="19">Failed to comply with the provisions of KRS 217B.190; </section><section prefix="20">Failed to provide direct on-the-job supervision of a trainee by a licensed operator or applicator in the application of a pesticide; </section><section prefix="21">Failed to follow notification and information requirements in accordance with KRS 217B.300, including: <section prefix="a">Failure to provide customer written information prior to application; </section><section prefix="b">Failure to place lawn marker; </section><section prefix="c">Failure to meet minimum requirements for lawn marker; </section><section prefix="d">Failure to furnish customer proper information at application; or </section><section prefix="e">Failure to furnish prior notification of application when requested; or </section></section><section prefix="22">Failed to follow notification and information requirements in accordance with KRS 217B.320, including: <section prefix="a">Failure to place golf course marker immediately after application; </section><section prefix="b">Failure to meet minimum requirements for golf course marker; or </section><section prefix="c">Failure to furnish prior notification of application when requested. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 73, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 11. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9538</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>