<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.840</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of receipt for payment of fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee -- County government's payment acceptance options. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for taxes collected on behalf of the state for which standard receipt forms had been supplied by the state prior to 1974, all county officials shall, upon the receipt of any fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee, prepare a receipt that meets the specifications of the state local finance officer, if the fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee is paid: <section prefix="a">In cash; </section><section prefix="b">By a party appearing in person to pay; or </section><section prefix="c">By check, credit card, or debit card account received through the mail, if the party includes an addressed, postage-paid return envelope and a request for receipt. </section></section><section prefix="2">One (1) copy of the receipt shall be given to the person paying the fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee and one (1) copy shall be retained by the official for his own records. One (1) copy of the receipt shall be retained by the official to be placed with the daily bank deposit. </section><section prefix="3">A county government may, but shall not be required to, accept payment of any fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee by check, draft, electronic funds transfer, debit or credit card account, or other similar means of payment. If an individual chooses to pay a fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee by any means other than cash, the county government may recover any transaction fee that would otherwise be incurred by the county for submitting or processing the transaction as part of and in addition to the original amount of the fine, forfeiture, tax, or fee. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 1, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 323, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and ch. 254, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>