<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7891</section_number><catch_line>Osteopathic Medicine Scholarship Program. </catch_line><order_by>7891</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly to establish a scholarship program to provide eligible Kentucky students the opportunity to attend an accredited osteopathic school of medicine located in the Commonwealth and become certified practitioners rendering medical service in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority may award scholarships, to the extent funds are available for that purpose, to persons who declare an intent to become osteopaths and practice in the Commonwealth and who are eligible under subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The authority may award scholarships to students who meet the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Kentucky residents who are United States citizens as determined by the institution in accordance with criteria established by the Council on Postsecondary Education for the purposes of admission and tuition assessment; </section><section prefix="b">Students who are enrolled or accepted for enrollment in an eligible program of study accredited by the Bureau of Professional Education of the American Osteopathy Association or its successor, on a full-time basis, or eligible students who have a disability defined by Title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 12131 et seq., certified by a licensed physician to be unable to attend the eligible program of study full-time because of the disability; </section><section prefix="c">Students who agree to render one (1) year of qualified service in the Commonwealth for each year the scholarship was awarded. "Qualified service" means a full-time practice in the Commonwealth of Kentucky as a licensed doctor of osteopathy for a majority of the calendar year in the fields of family practice, general practice, general internal medicine, general pediatrics, general obstetrics, or gynecology, except that an individual having a disability defined by Title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 12131 et seq., whose disability, certified by another licensed physician, prevents him or her from practicing full-time, shall be deemed to perform qualified service by practicing the maximum time permitted by the attending physician; and </section><section prefix="d">Students who sign a promissory note as evidence of the scholarship awarded and the obligation to repay the scholarship amount or render medical service as agreed in lieu of payment. </section></section><section prefix="4">The amount of the scholarship awarded to an eligible student by the authority shall be equal to the difference between: <section prefix="a">The average of the prevailing amount charged for in-state tuition at the University of Kentucky School of Medicine and the University of Louisville School of Medicine; and </section><section prefix="b">The prevailing amount charged for tuition at the osteopathic school of medicine in which the student is enrolled. </section></section><section prefix="5">The authority shall require a promissory note to be executed by the student as evidence of the obligation. The recipient shall render one (1) year of qualified service for each year the scholarship was awarded. Upon completion of each year of qualified service, the authority shall cancel the appropriate number of promissory notes. Promissory notes shall be canceled by qualified service in the order in which the promissory notes were executed. Service credit shall not include residency service. In the event a recipient fails to complete an eligible program of study, or fails to render qualified medical service as a primary care physician as agreed in subsection (3) of this section, the recipient shall be liable for the total repayment of the sum of all outstanding promissory notes and accrued interest. </section><section prefix="6">A scholarship shall not be awarded or a promissory note cancellation shall not be granted to any person who is in default on any obligation to the authority under any program administered by the authority under KRS 164.740 to 164.785 until financial obligations to the authority are satisfied, except that ineligibility for this reason may be waived by the authority for cause. </section><section prefix="7">A repayment obligation imposed by this section shall not be voidable by reason of the age of the recipient at the time of executing the promissory note. </section><section prefix="8">Failure to meet repayment obligations imposed by this section shall be cause for the revocation of the scholarship recipient's license to practice medicine, subject to the procedures set forth in KRS Chapter 311. </section><section prefix="9">Notwithstanding KRS 164.753(3), the authority shall establish by administrative regulation procedures or the terms of promissory notes for the administration of this program, including the execution of appropriate contracts and promissory notes, cancellation of the obligation, the rate of repayment and deferment of repayment of outstanding debt, and the priority of awarding scholarships if funds are insufficient to honor all requests. </section><section prefix="10">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, the maximum interest rate applicable to repayment of a promissory note under this section shall be twelve percent (12%) per annum, except that if a judgment is rendered to recover payment, the judgment shall bear interest at the rate of five percent (5%) greater than the rate actually charged on the promissory note. </section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">The "Osteopathic Medicine Scholarship Program" is hereby created as a special trust fund in the State Treasury administered by the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority for the purpose of providing funds for scholarships to eligible students studying osteopathic medicine in schools in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="b">Funding shall be transferred to the special trust fund from the coal severance tax revenues levied under KRS 143.020 in an amount that permits each Kentucky resident eligible under subsection (3) of this section to be awarded a scholarship in the amount established under subsection (4) of this section. No more than four percent (4%) of the coal severance tax revenues levied under KRS 143.020 and collected annually shall be transferred to the trust fund. To the extent this appropriation and other funds are available, the authority shall award scholarships to all renewal applicants and eligible students in accordance with the formula for determining the amount of the scholarship award established in this section. </section><section prefix="c">The trust fund may also receive state appropriations, gifts, and grants from public and private sources, and federal funds. Any unallotted or unencumbered balances in the trust fund shall be invested as provided in KRS 42.500(9). Income earned from the investments shall be credited to the trust fund. Any fund balance at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year and continuously appropriated only for the purposes specified in this section. A general statement that all continuing appropriations are repealed, discontinued, or suspended shall not operate to repeal, discontinue, or suspend this fund or to repeal this section. </section><section prefix="d">All moneys repaid to the authority under this section shall be added to the appropriations made for purposes of this section, and the funds and unobligated appropriations shall not lapse. </section></section><section prefix="12">On or before August 1 of each year, sixty-five percent (65%) of the amount of funding provided in subsection (11)(b) of this section shall be transferred to the special trust fund and the remaining thirty-five percent (35%) shall be transferred on or before December 1 of each year. The revenue transfers shall be based upon the revenue estimates prevailing at the time each transfer is due. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 15, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40060</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>