<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.370</section_number><catch_line>Bylaws -- Adoption and contents. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The incorporators of each corporation organized under KRS 279.310 to 279.600 shall adopt for its management bylaws not inconsistent with the powers granted by KRS 279.310 to 279.600. The written consent of a majority of the incorporators, evidenced by their signatures to the bylaws adopted, shall be necessary to the adoption of bylaws. The bylaws may be amended by a majority vote of the board of trustees.  </section><section prefix="2">The bylaws may provide for any or all of the following matters:  <section prefix="a">The time, place and manner of calling and conducting meetings of the members.  </section><section prefix="b">The number of members constituting a quorum.  </section><section prefix="c">The right of members to vote by mail, and the conditions, manner, form and effect of such votes.  </section><section prefix="d">The number of trustees constituting a quorum.  </section><section prefix="e">The qualifications, compensation, powers, duties and terms of office of trustees and officers, the time of their election and the manner of giving notice thereof.  </section><section prefix="f">An executive committee and the allotment to that committee of any or all of the functions and powers of the board of trustees, subject to the general direction and control of the board.  </section><section prefix="g">The amount of entrance, organization and membership fees, if any, the manner of collecting them and the purposes for which they may be used.  </section><section prefix="h">The qualifications of members of the corporation and the conditions precedent to membership; the time and manner of permitting members to withdraw; the manner of assignment or transfer of the interest of a member; the conditions upon which and the time when membership of any member shall cease; the suspension of the rights of a member when he ceases to be eligible to membership in the corporation; the manner and effect of the expulsion of a member; the manner of determining the value of a member's interest and provision for its purchase by the corporation upon the death or withdrawal of a member or upon his expulsion or forfeiture of membership, or, at the option of the corporation, the purchase of the member's interest at a price fixed by appraisal by the board. The bylaws may provide that in case of the forced withdrawal or expulsion of a member the board shall equitably appraise his property interest in the corporation and shall at its option fix the amount thereof in money or other property, which shall be paid to him within one (1) year after his expulsion or withdrawal.  </section><section prefix="i">Penalties for violation of the bylaws.  </section><section prefix="j">Any other matter relating to the operation or management of the corporation and not inconsistent with law or with the articles of incorporation.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 7, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1950</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14213</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>