<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.10-220</section_number><catch_line>Application for title pledge lending license. </catch_line><order_by>10-220</order_by><text>Each application for a title pledge lending license shall be filed with the department, and the application shall provide the following: <section prefix="1">The name of the beneficial owner if a sole proprietorship; or in the case of a corporation, all individuals serving as officers or directors; or in the case of a partnership or limited liability company, the members thereof; </section><section prefix="2">The street address where the title pledge office is to be operated; </section><section prefix="3">Proof of the capital and surety bond requirements set forth in KRS 286.10-215, accompanied by an unaudited financial statement from a certified public accountant; </section><section prefix="4">An affidavit from each individual set forth in subsection (1) of this section stating that each individual has not been convicted of a felony within the ten (10) year period preceding the date of application; </section><section prefix="5">Certified funds in the amount of five hundred dollars ($500) payable to the department; and </section><section prefix="6">Other information as required by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 825, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.220. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14929</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>