<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.978</section_number><catch_line>Transporting vehicle to carry license -- Application -- Issuance. </catch_line><order_by>978</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All trucks or other vehicles used to transport or carry wastes from sewage pretreatment units, grease traps, or holding tanks shall be licensed by the cabinet. The application for this vehicle license shall be made prior to March 1 of each year on forms provided by the cabinet, and shall state any information that the cabinet shall deem necessary. The secretary may establish a fee schedule according to authorization in the state budget document. </section><section prefix="2">If the cabinet, after any investigation it deems necessary, finds that the truck or vehicle and equipment is acceptable for the purposes of this chapter, it shall issue or cause to be issued a license for the use of the vehicle for the purpose of this chapter. This license is not transferable from one vehicle to another, and shall be carried on the vehicle at all times. There shall be painted on both sides and the rear of the vehicle in letters not less than two inches high the letters "K.Y.", followed by the assigned vehicle license number. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(8). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 17, effective January 1, 1973. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.230. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8555</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>