<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.153</section_number><catch_line>School bus standards -- "School bus" defined -- Use of clean transportation fuels.   </catch_line><order_by>153</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All school buses for which bids are made or bid contracts awarded shall meet the standards and specifications of the Kentucky Department of Education. </section> The term "school bus," as used in this section, shall mean any motor vehicle which meets the standards and specifications for school buses as provided by law or by the standards or specifications of the Kentucky Department of Education authorized by law and used solely in transporting school children and school employees to and from school under the supervision and control and at the direction of school authorities, and shall further include school bus accessory equipment and supplies and replacement equipment considered to be reasonably adaptable for purchase from price contract agreements. <section prefix="2">Except in cases of emergencies or for the transportation of students with disabilities, only school buses as defined in subsection (1) of this section shall be used for transporting students to and from school along regular bus routes. Districts may use district-owned vehicles that were designed and built by the manufacturer for passenger transportation when transporting nine (9) or fewer passengers, including the driver, for approved school activities. Vehicles used under this subsection shall be clearly marked as transporting students and shall be safety inspected no less than once every thirty (30) days. </section><section prefix="3">As part of its regular procedure for establishing and updating school bus standards and specifications, the Kentucky Department of Education shall consider allowing school buses to operate using clean transportation fuels, as defined in KRS 186.750. If the department determines that school buses may operate using clean transportation fuels while maintaining the same or a higher degree of safety as fuels currently allowed, it shall update its standards and specifications to allow for such use. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 367, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. XVI, sec. 21. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42410</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>