<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.011</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>011</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Dead body" means a human body or parts of the human body from the condition of which it reasonably may be concluded that death recently occurred; </section><section prefix="3">"Fetal death" means death prior to the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of human conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy; the death is indicated by the fact that after such expulsion or extraction the fetus does not breathe or show any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscles. This definition shall exclude induced termination of pregnancy; </section><section prefix="4">"File" means the presentation of a vital record provided for in this chapter for registration by the Vital Statistics Branch; </section><section prefix="5">"Final disposition" means the burial, interment, cremation, removal from the Commonwealth, or other authorized disposition of a dead body or fetus; </section><section prefix="6">"Induced termination of pregnancy" means the purposeful interruption of pregnancy with the intention other than to produce a live-born infant or to remove a dead fetus and which does not result in a live birth. This definition shall exclude management of prolonged retention of product of conception following fetal death; </section><section prefix="7">"Institution" means any establishment, public or private, which provides inpatient medical, surgical, or diagnostic care or treatment or nursing, custodial, or domicilary care, or to which persons are committed by law; </section><section prefix="8">"Live birth" means the complete expulsion or extraction from its mother of a product of human conception, irrespective of the duration of pregnancy which, after the expulsion or extraction, breathes, or shows any other evidence of life such as beating of the heart, pulsation of the umbilical cord, or definite movement of voluntary muscles, whether or not the umbilical cord has been cut or the placenta is attached; </section><section prefix="9">"Provisional death certificate" means an interim certificate identifying the deceased and authorizing a funeral director, or person acting as such, to take custody of the body and, except for cremation, to make final disposition; </section><section prefix="10">"Registration" means the acceptance by the Vital Statistics Branch and the incorporation of vital records provided for in this chapter into its official records; </section><section prefix="11">"System of vital statistics" means the registration, collection, preservation, amendment, and certification of vital records and the collection of other reports required by this chapter; </section><section prefix="12">"Secretary" means the secretary for health and family services; </section><section prefix="13">"Sudden infant death syndrome" means the death of an ostensibly healthy child who is two (2) weeks of age or older but less than three (3) years of age, which occurs suddenly and unexpectedly, with no known or apparent cause, and which remains unexplained after the performance of an autopsy; </section><section prefix="14">"Vital records" means certificates or reports of birth, death, fetal death, marriage, dissolution of marriage, or annulment, and data related thereto; </section><section prefix="15">"Vital statistics" means the data derived from certificates and reports of birth, death, fetal death, induced termination of pregnancy, marriage, dissolution of marriage, and related reports; </section><section prefix="16">"Certificate" means the certificate of birth, death, fetal death, marriage, dissolution of marriage, or annulment as required by this chapter; </section><section prefix="17">"Commission" means the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs; </section><section prefix="18">"Hard of hearing infant" means a child at birth with a significant hearing loss which prevents the acquisition of speech and language through normal channels; and </section><section prefix="19">"Hearing risk certificate" means the certificate that includes questions which identify newborn babies with a higher risk than normal for hearing loss. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 427, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 378, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 80, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8701</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>