<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.235</section_number><catch_line>Temporary amusement rides and attractions -- License required -- Sanctions. </catch_line><order_by>235</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Every person that operates a for-profit business that provides temporary amusement rides or amusement attractions that are within the same county as, or are within a five (5) mile radius of, a public fair or exposition that is sanctioned by the Department of Agriculture and is operated by a public fair association shall, before beginning operation, pay a license fee of two thousand dollars ($2,000) per day of operation to the fiscal court of the county in which the temporary amusement rides or amusement attractions are located. </section><section prefix="b">The provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection shall not apply to temporary amusement rides or amusement attractions that: <section prefix="1">Operate in connection with the sanctioned public fair or exposition; </section><section prefix="2">Operate at a public fair or exposition that is in a contiguous county, is sanctioned by the Department of Agriculture, and is under the authority of a public fair association; </section><section prefix="3">Operate under the authority of a religious or educational organization; </section><section prefix="4">Operate more than thirty (30) days before or seven (7) days after the sanctioned public fair or exposition; </section><section prefix="5">Are clown acts, local festivals, or amusement or entertainment shows with six (6) or fewer kiddie rides; or </section><section prefix="6">Operated as a nonprofit or charitable organization in this state before March 10, 2003. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Collection and enforcement for payment of the license fee shall be the sole responsibility of the law enforcement entity acting on behalf of and at the direction of the fiscal court in which the temporary amusement rides or amusement attractions are located. </section><section prefix="3">Failure to pay the license fee upon request of the law enforcement entity shall result in the cessation of operation of the amusement rides or amusement attractions by the operator. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 2, effective March 10, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> March 10, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>