<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.171</section_number><catch_line>Corrections personnel to take educational course on AIDS. </catch_line><order_by>171</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Corrections shall develop an educational course on the human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of not more than four (4) hours for the instruction of corrections personnel who have day-to-day contact with incarcerated persons and personnel who may be expected to respond to crisis situations. The literature and training curriculum shall include information of known modes of transmission and methods of controlling and preventing these diseases with an emphasis on appropriate behavior and attitude change. The training may be part of any continuing education program. </section><section prefix="2">All persons referred to in subsection (1) of this section shall successfully complete the training required. Any person holding the position referred to in subsection (1) of this section shall not fill that position for more than one (1) year without successful completion of the required training. If a person does not successfully complete the required training within the time specified, he shall be suspended from further service until he successfully completes the required training. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 170, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 130, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 33, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 33, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6809</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>