<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.125</section_number><catch_line>Cruelty to animals in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following persons are guilty of cruelty to animals in the first degree whenever a four-legged animal is caused to fight for pleasure or profit: <section prefix="a">The owner of the animal; </section><section prefix="b">The owner of the property on which the fight is conducted if the owner knows of the fight; </section><section prefix="c">Anyone who participates in the organization of the fight. </section></section><section prefix="2">Activities of animals engaged in hunting, field trials, dog training, and other activities authorized either by a hunting license or by the Department of Fish and Wildlife shall not constitute a violation of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Cruelty to animals in the first degree is a Class D felony. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 65, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><lrc-note> (3/30/90)   The definition of "animal" contained in KRS 446.010(2) does not reflect the amendatory language contained in Senate Bill 263 of the 1980 Regular Session of the Kentucky General Assembly because the 1980 Senate Journal indicates that Senate Bill 263 was vetoed by Governor John Y. Brown, Jr., on April 9, 1980, and recommitted by action of the Senate to its Committee on Appropriations and Revenue on April 14, 1980. Senate Bill 263 proposed to change KRS 446.010(2) to read as follows: " 'Animal' includes every warmblooded living creature except birds and human beings;". By a letter dated March 16, 1990, the Attorney General has informally opined that Governor Brown's veto of Senate Bill 263 was not timely; that letter has exhibits showing that the bill was received by the Governor on March 28, 1980, and that his veto was received by the Senate Clerk on April 10, 1980. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19935</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>