<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.286</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner to supervise referendum -- Expenses -- Conducting referendum -- Voter to certify volume of propane represented by vote -- Mechanism for notification of eligible voters. </catch_line><order_by>286</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The manner, conduct, and management of any referendum held under the provisions of KRS 234.270 to 234.302 shall be under the supervision and direction of the commissioner. Any and all expenses in connection with the initial referendum shall be borne by the association conducting the referendum. Any and all expenses in connection with subsequent referenda shall be borne by the council. </section><section prefix="2">With respect to any referendum conducted under the provisions of KRS 234.270 to 234.302, the association or council responsible for the referendum shall select an independent auditing firm, subject to the approval of the commissioner, to conduct the referendum. </section><section prefix="3">All persons voting in the referendum shall certify to the independent auditing firm the volume of propane represented by their vote. The information provided under this subsection shall be considered proprietary and shall remain confidential. </section><section prefix="4">The association or council responsible for the referendum shall develop a mechanism for notifying those persons eligible to vote in the referendum. Notice of the referendum, at a minimum, shall be given to all retail marketers in Kentucky holding a "Class A" license from the department and notice shall be published in existing industry publications with significant circulation within the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 507, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>