<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.211</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of license -- Fees -- Expiration and termination of license -- Reinstatement -- Continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each person licensed as a veterinarian shall, on or before September 30 of each even-numbered year, pay to the board a renewal fee to be promulgated by administrative regulation of the board for the renewal of his license. All licenses not renewed by September 30 of each even-numbered year shall expire based on the failure of the individual to renew in a timely manner. </section><section prefix="2">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed after September 30, as required for renewal in subsection (1) of this section, during which time individuals may renew their licenses upon payment of the renewal fee plus a late renewal fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. All licenses not renewed by November 30 shall terminate based on the failure of the individual to renew in a timely manner. Upon termination, the licensee is no longer eligible to practice in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">After the sixty (60) day grace period, individuals with a terminated license may have their licenses reinstated upon payment of the renewal fee plus a reinstatement fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. No person who applies for reinstatement after termination of his license shall be required to submit to any examination as a condition for reinstatement, if reinstatement application is made within five (5) years from the date of termination. </section><section prefix="4">A suspended license is subject to expiration and termination and shall be renewed as provided in this chapter. Renewal shall not entitle the licensee to engage in the practice until the suspension has ended, or is otherwise removed by the board and the right to practice is restored by the board. </section><section prefix="5">A revoked license is subject to expiration or termination but may not be renewed. If it is reinstated, the licensee shall pay the reinstatement fee as set forth in subsection (3) of this section and the renewal fee as set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">A person who fails to reinstate his license within five (5) years after its termination may not have it renewed, restored, reissued, or reinstated. A person may apply for and obtain a new license by meeting the current requirements of this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">The board may require that a person applying for renewal or reinstatement of licensure show evidence of completion of continuing education as prescribed by the board by administrative regulation. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 33, effective July 13, 2004; and ch. 96, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><lrc-note>(7/13/2004).  This section was amended by 2004 Ky. Acts chs. 96 and 189, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31385</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>