<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.265</section_number><catch_line>Motor buses -- Height, length and weight limits on designated highways. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Motor bus" shall mean any motor vehicle designed primarily for the transportation of passengers and having a seating capacity in excess of nine (9) passengers including the driver, provided, however, that transit authorities created pursuant to KRS Chapter 96A are exempt from the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall operate on any highway, except such highways as may be designated by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet pursuant to subsection (3) of this section, any motor bus which exceeds, including any part of the body or load, eleven (11) feet six (6) inches in height, forty (40) feet in length, twenty (20) tons in gross weight, or ninety-six (96) inches in width, exclusive of any required safety equipment. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, in respect to highways which are a part of the state-maintained system, by official order may increase the maximum height of a motor bus to twelve (12) feet six (6) inches and the maximum width of a motor bus to 102 inches, exclusive of any required safety equipment and tire bulge due to loads, if in the opinion of the secretary the increased height and width designated by him is justified by the width of such highways, provided, however, that any such increase in the width of motor buses or designation of highways to be used by them shall not, in any way, exceed the federal law or regulations thereunder or jeopardize the allotment or qualification for federal aid funds of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6347</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>