<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">CITY CLASSIFICATION, BOUNDARIES, AND ALTERNATIVE METHOD OF CONSOLIDATING GOVERNMENTAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>81.050</section_number><catch_line>Proceedings to incorporate -- Exception upon adoption of consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 67C.111(2), proceedings to incorporate a city shall be commenced by a petition being filed with the circuit clerk of the county in which the area to be incorporated is located. The petition shall contain: <section prefix="a">The signatures and addresses of: <section prefix="1">A number of registered voters equal to two-thirds (2/3) of the voters of the proposed territory; or </section><section prefix="2">A number of real property owners, the sum total of whose assessed value of real property is equal to at least two-thirds (2/3) of the assessed value of the real property in the proposed territory; </section></section><section prefix="b">A statement of the boundaries proposed and the number of residents; </section><section prefix="c">An accurate map of the proposed territory; </section><section prefix="d">A detailed statement of the reasons for incorporation including the services sought from the proposed city; </section><section prefix="e">A description of the existing facilities and services within the proposed territory; and </section><section prefix="f">A statement of the form of government under which the city will operate if incorporated. </section></section><section prefix="2">The petition shall be docketed for hearing not less than twenty (20) days from the date of filing the petition. Notice of the filing of the petition and of its object shall be given by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 90, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 71, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 36. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3714. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>