<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any officer to whom KRS 64.050 applies, or his personal representative, trustee, or committee, as the case may be, collects any fees, accounts, or demands due him in his official capacity after the expiration of his term, or after he has resigned or died or vacated the office, or fails to deliver to his successor all the fees, claims, and accounts due to him in his official capacity, he, or his personal representative, committee, or trustee, as the case may be, shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="2">If any successor or collector mentioned in KRS 64.050(1) fails to make any report or pay the money collected to the Department for Local Government, as required by KRS 64.050(1), he shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. If he knowingly omits or fails to report a correct statement of all money received or collected or knowingly makes or subscribes any false statement concerning the same, he shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">If any deputy or personal representative issuing a fee bill in accordance with KRS 64.420 knowingly makes a wrong charge, or in any respect issues an illegal fee bill, he shall be subject to the same penalties as an officer issuing such a fee bill. </section><section prefix="4">Every fee bill containing one (1) illegal charge, or which, in any respect, is not according to what is required by law, shall be void for the whole amount. </section><section prefix="5">Any officer who splits up and divides his services so as to make two (2) charges, when the law intends but one (1) charge or fee for the whole service, or who knowingly makes an illegal charge, or issues an illegal fee bill, or collects or attempts to collect his fees twice for the same services, or by any indirection collects or attempts to collect more for his services than is allowed by law, shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor and his conviction shall be prima facie evidence of his guilt in a proceeding to remove him from office. </section><section prefix="6">Any official who violates the provisions of KRS 64.820 to 64.850 shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 45, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 39, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 44, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and ch. 254, sec. 16. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 14. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1750, 1754, 1755, 1756, 1761, 1761-1, 1765, 1766, 1770, 1771, 1773, 1778. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23313</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>