<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.470</section_number><catch_line>Total and permanent disability not occasioned by duties of member -- Benefits. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Upon total and permanent disability of a member as the result of any cause other than occupational disability, if a member shall have rendered at least five (5) years of total service, he shall be entitled to a disability retirement annuity determined under this section. </section><section prefix="b">For a member whose participation date in the fund is prior to March 14, 2013, the amount of the disability retirement annuity shall be equal to two and one-half percent (2.5%) of the average salary, as defined in KRS 67A.360(13), for each full year of total service, subject to a minimum payment of twenty-five percent (25%) of such average salary and a maximum payment of seventy-five percent (75%) of average salary. </section><section prefix="c">For a member whose participation date in the fund is on or after March 14, 2013, the amount of the disability retirement annuity shall be equal to two and one-quarter percent (2.25%) of the average salary, as defined in KRS 67A.360(13), for each full year of total service, subject to a minimum payment of twenty-two and one-half percent (22.5%) of such average salary and a maximum payment of sixty-seven and one-half percent (67.5%) of average salary. </section><section prefix="d">Payment of the disability annuity as provided by this section shall be made during disability of the member. After the member's death, his eligible widow, if any, shall receive the benefits as provided in KRS 67A.492, and his minor children, if any, shall receive benefits as provided under KRS 67A.450. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any annuity for nonoccupational disability shall begin to accrue upon the expiration of ninety (90) days following the commencement of disability provided that if the member is receiving salary for sick leave for a period of more than ninety (90) days, payment shall accrue from the date such salary ceases. If written application for such annuity shall not have been filed with the board prior to the expiration of ninety (90) days from date of disability, the annuity shall begin to accrue from the date the application shall be filed but not prior to the expiration of ninety (90) days from the date of disability, nor in any event prior to the time when salary payments to the employee shall have ceased. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 10, effective March 14, 2013. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>March 14, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41664</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>