<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="180" order_by="180">STATE BRIDGES, TUNNELS, AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>180.105</section_number><catch_line>Interstate bridges may be united in one project for construction, enlargement, repair or reconstruction -- Issuance of bonds and collection of tolls for projects. </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the commissioner of highways shall deem it necessary to construct a new bridge, or to enlarge an existing bridge by the addition of new lanes of traffic, or, by reason of a major catastrophe, to repair or reconstruct an existing bridge, he may, by order, unite into a single bridge project all interstate bridges owned by the Department of Highways which are situated not more than ten (10) miles distant from each other. </section><section prefix="2">When, pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, any bridges are united into a single bridge project, bonds may be issued for the purpose of paying the cost of the building and construction of any such new bridge, or the performing of any of the other functions authorized under subsection (1) of this section, which may include the cost of reconstruction, maintenance and operation of said bridge or bridges united into a single bridge project only for and during the time the said bonds are being paid and only up until the time same are retired and paid, and in order to pay and retire any and all bonds so issued, the Department of Highways may charge and collect tolls for vehicular traffic over the bridge or bridges constituting such single bridge project; provided, however, that the charging and collection of tolls shall not begin until the completion of any new bridge built or constructed or upon the completion of any of the other functions authorized under subsection (1) of this section, and shall terminate and be at an end after the completion of the payment of the bonds issued for said purpose or purposes; and further provided that nothing in this section, or elsewhere contained, shall be construed to authorize the imposition, charge or collecting of tolls at any time for the maintenance or operation of said bridge or bridges after the bonds have been retired and paid. </section></text><history>Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1954 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>