<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.035</section_number><catch_line>Functions of chapter to be carried out by board. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text>The board may carry out the functions of this chapter, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Establishing minimum data reporting requirements, including requirements specifically related to emergency medical services and trauma care of children, for ambulance providers and collection and analysis of data related to the provision of emergency medical services; </section><section prefix="2">Maintaining the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program with federal funds so designated plus any additional funds that may be appropriated by the General Assembly, or any other funds that may become available to the board, including gifts, grants, or other sources; </section><section prefix="3">Developing a statewide plan for the implementation of emergency medical services systems and trauma care systems within the Commonwealth of Kentucky that specifically addresses the unique needs of rural areas; </section><section prefix="4">Applying for, receiving, and disposing of federal, state, or private funds by grant, appropriation, donation, or otherwise for emergency medical services programs, personnel, and equipment; and </section><section prefix="5">Developing, monitoring, and encouraging other projects and programs that may be of benefit to emergency medical services in the Commonwealth. </section>Nothing in this section shall be construed to change or alter the issuance of certificates of need for emergency medical services providers. </text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30723</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>