<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.675</section_number><catch_line>Employer's administrative duties -- Audit -- Filing of contributions and reports. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The employer shall prepare the records and, from time to time, shall furnish the information the system may require in the discharge of its duties. Upon employment of an employee, the employer shall inform him of his duties and obligations in connection with the system as a condition of employment. </section><section prefix="2">The system may at any time conduct an audit of the employer in order to determine if the employer is complying with the provisions of KRS 16.505 to 16.652, 61.610 to 61.705, or 78.510 to 78.852. The system shall have access to and may examine all books, accounts, reports, correspondence files, and records of any employer. Every employer, employee, or agency reporting official of a department or county, as defined in KRS 78.510(3), having records in his possession or under his control, shall permit access to and examination of the records upon the request of the system. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Any agency participating in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System which is not an integral part of the executive branch of state government shall file the following at the retirement office on or before the tenth day of the month following the period being reported: <section prefix="1">The employer and employee contributions required under KRS 61.560, 61.565, and 61.702; </section><section prefix="2">The employer contributions and reimbursements for retiree health insurance premiums required under KRS 61.637; and </section><section prefix="3">A record of all contributions to the system on the forms prescribed by the board. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the agency fails to file all contributions and reports on or before the tenth day of the month following the period being reported, interest on the delinquent contributions at the actuarial rate adopted by the board compounded annually, but not less than one thousand dollars ($1,000), shall be added to the amount due the system. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 20, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 27, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 45, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 55. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 34. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>