<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIX" order_by="39">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES, ENFORCEMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="425" order_by="425">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES </unit></structure><section_number>425.600</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of receiver -- Appeal from order appointing or refusing to appoint -- Powers of receiver. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On the motion of any party to an action who shows that he has, or probably has, a right to, a lien upon, or an interest in, any property or fund, the right to which is involved in the action, and that the property or fund is in danger of being lost, removed or materially injured, the court may appoint a receiver, or order the master commissioner to take charge of the property or fund during the pendency of the action, and may order and coerce the delivery of it to him.  The order of a court appointing or refusing to appoint a receiver, shall be deemed a final order for the purpose of an appeal; Provided, that such order shall not be superseded.  </section><section prefix="2">The receiver or master commissioner has, under the control of the court, power to bring and defend actions, respecting the property, to take and keep possession of the property, to receive rents, collect debts and generally to do such acts respecting the property as the court may authorize.  </section><section prefix="3">Any income accruing during the pendency of proceedings under this section shall follow the property upon final disposition of the case.  </section></text><history>Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 54, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>