<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.652</section_number><catch_line>Distribution -- Administrative costs -- Monthly hold harmless amounts. </catch_line><order_by>652</order_by><text>Money in the gross revenues and excise tax fund shall be distributed monthly as follows: <section prefix="1">One percent (1%) shall be deposited in a trust and agency account created in the State Treasury to be used by the department for administration costs associated with the implementation, collection, and distribution of the tax imposed by KRS 136.604 and 136.616. </section><section prefix="2">After the distribution required under subsection (1) of this section, the department shall distribute to each political subdivision, school district and special district the applicable monthly hold-harmless amount as calculated under KRS 136.650. In addition, the department shall distribute one-twelfth (1/12) of the sheriff department's fixed hold-harmless amount as defined in KRS 136.650(2)(b). For tax collections received in January and February of 2006, the department shall make the distribution by April 25, 2006. For all other periods, the department shall make distribution by the twenty-fifth day of the next calendar month following the tax receipts. </section><section prefix="3">After the distribution required by subsection (2) of this section, the department shall deposit one million two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($1,250,000) in the state general fund. This amount shall be adjusted on a prospective basis after the collection of the first twelve (12) months of tax receipts from the taxes imposed by KRS 136.604 and 136.616 to equal the average monthly tax receipts attributable to the taxation of satellite broadcast and wireless cable services under KRS 136.604 and 136.616. The amount shall then become the fixed amount distributed to the general fund. </section><section prefix="4">Money remaining in the gross revenues and excise tax fund after the distribution required by subsection (3) of this section shall be transferred to the state baseline and local growth fund established in KRS 136.648. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 114, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (1/01/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, F, 7, (1) at 641. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>