<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.140</section_number><catch_line>Personnel director -- Appointment -- Qualifications -- Removal -- Duties -- Employment of chief examiner -- Certification of payroll changes. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall employ a personnel director who shall be the administrative officer of the board. The personnel director shall be, at the time of appointment, a person familiar, and in sympathy, with the principles, and experienced in the methods and technique, of personnel administration on the merit basis and a person of recognized character and ability. </section><section prefix="2">Beginning January 1, 1973, the personnel director shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year and shall serve thereafter on a year to year basis unless notified in writing thirty (30) days before the year expires that he will not be reappointed; provided however that the personnel director may be removed at any time only for cause and after public hearing by the board and after at least ten (10) days' notice shall have been given to the said director, which notice shall contain a copy of the charges preferred against him, and the decision of the board thereon shall be final. At such hearing the personnel director may be represented by counsel. </section><section prefix="3">The personnel director shall be the secretary-treasurer of the board and shall attend all the meetings thereof; shall set up and direct the actual work of the board; supervise and direct the work of the employees thereof; make such investigations as may be deemed desirable and report thereon to the board. The personnel director shall submit to the board not later than the first day of November of each year an annual report on the operations of the board for the preceding fiscal year, and shall discharge all such other duties as the board may require. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall employ a chief examiner who shall be professionally qualified and experienced in the art of testing, and who shall formulate, give, grade, and retain control of, all written tests as required by the board, and said chief examiner shall report to the board the results of all tests given and he shall be solely responsible to the board. The job of personnel director may not be combined with the job of chief examiner. The chief examiner shall be responsible only to the civil service board and shall perform such other duties as the board may require. </section><section prefix="5">The director of finance of the city shall immediately certify to the personnel director the name of any person in the classified service added to or removed from the payroll. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1. --Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>