<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.42-080</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of association. </catch_line><order_by>42-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a member insurer is an impaired insurer, the association may, in its discretion, and subject to any conditions imposed by the association that do not impair the contractual obligations of the impaired insurer and that are approved by the commissioner: <section prefix="a">Guarantee, assume, or reinsure, or cause to be guaranteed, assumed, or reinsured, any or all of the policies or contracts of the impaired insurer; or </section><section prefix="b">Provide such monies, pledges, loans, notes, guarantees, or other means as are proper to effectuate paragraph (a) of this subsection and assure payment of the contractual obligations of the impaired insurer pending action under paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a member insurer is an insolvent insurer, the association shall, in its discretion, either: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Guarantee, assume, or reinsure, or cause to be guaranteed, assumed, or reinsured, the policies or contracts of the insolvent insurer; or </section><section prefix="2">Assure payment of the contractual obligations of the insolvent insurer; and </section><section prefix="3">Provide such monies, pledges, loans, notes, guarantees, or other means as are reasonably necessary to discharge such duties; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Provide benefits and coverages in accordance the following provisions: <section prefix="1">With respect to life and health insurance policies and annuities, assure payment of benefits for premiums identical to the premiums and benefits (except for terms of conversion and renewability) that would have been payable under policies or contracts of the insolvent insurer, for claims incurred: <section prefix="a">With respect to group policies and contracts, not later than the earlier of the next renewal date under such policies or contracts or forty-five (45) days, but in no event less than thirty (30) days, after the date on which the association becomes obligated with respect to such policies or contracts; </section><section prefix="b">With respect to nongroup policies, contracts, and annuities not later than the earlier of the next renewal date (if any) under such policies or contracts or one (1) year, but in no event less than thirty (30) days, from the date on which the association becomes obligated with respect to such policies or contracts; </section></section><section prefix="2">Make diligent efforts to provide all known insureds or annuitants for nongroup policies and contracts, or group policy owners with respect to group policies and contracts thirty (30) days' notice of the termination under subparagraph 1. of this paragraph of the benefits provided; </section><section prefix="3">With respect to individual health and life insurance policies, and annuities covered by the association, make available to each known insured or annuitant, or owner if other than the insured or annuitant, and with respect to an individual formerly insured or formerly and annuitant under a group policy who is not eligible for replacement group coverage, make available substitute coverage on an individual basis in accordance with the provisions of subparagraph 4. of this paragraph, if the insureds or annuitants had a right under law or the terminated policy to convert coverage to individual coverage or to continue an individual policy or annuity in force until a specified age or for a specified time, during which the insurer had no right unilaterally to make changes in any provision of the policy or had a right only to make changes in premium by class; </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">In providing substitute coverage required under subparagraph 3. of this paragraph the association may offer either to reissue the terminated coverage or to issue an alternative policy. </section><section prefix="b">Alternative or reissued policies shall be offered without requiring evidence of insurability, and shall not provide for any waiting period or exclusion that would not have applied under the terminated policy. </section><section prefix="c">The association may reinsure any alternative or reissued policy; </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Alternative policies adopted by the association shall be subject to approval by the domiciliary insurance commissioner or receivership court. The association may adopt alternative policies of various types for future issuance without regard to any particular impairment or insolvency. </section><section prefix="b">Alternative policies shall contain at least the minimum statutory provisions required in this state and provide benefits that shall not be unreasonable in relation to the premium charged. The association shall set the premium in accordance with a table of rates which it shall adopt. The premium shall reflect the amount of insurance to be provided and the age and class of risk of each insured, but shall not reflect any changes in the health of the insured after the original policy was last underwritten. </section><section prefix="c">Any alternative policy issued by the association shall provide coverage of a type similar to that of the policy issued by the impaired or insolvent insurer, as determined by the association; </section></section><section prefix="6">If the association elects to reissue terminated coverage at a premium rate different from that charged under the terminated policy, the premium shall be set by the association in accordance with the amount of insurance provided and the age and class of risk, subject to approval by the domiciliary insurance commissioner or by the receivership court; and </section><section prefix="7">The association's obligations with respect to coverage under any policy of the impaired or insolvent insurer or under any reissued or alternative policy shall cease on the date such coverage or policy is replaced by another similar policy by the policy owner, the insured, or the association. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">When proceeding under subsection (2)(b) of this section with respect to any policy or contract carrying guaranteed minimum interest rates, the association shall assure the payment or crediting of a rate of interest consistent with KRS 304.42-030(2)(b)3. </section><section prefix="4">Nonpayment of premiums within thirty-one (31) days after the date required under the terms of any guaranteed, assumed, alternative, or reissued policy or contract for substitute coverage shall terminate the association's obligations under such policy or coverage under this subtitle with respect to such policy or coverage, except with respect to any claims incurred or any net cash surrender value which may be due in accordance with the provisions of this subtitle. </section><section prefix="5">Premiums due for coverage after entry of an order of liquidation of an insolvent insurer shall belong to and be payable at the direction of the association, and the association shall be liable for unearned premiums due to policy or contract owners arising after the entry of such order. </section><section prefix="6">The protection provided by this subtitle shall not apply where any guaranteed protection is provided to residents of this state by the laws of the domiciliary state or jurisdiction of the impaired or insolvent insurer other than this state. </section><section prefix="7">In carrying out its duties under subsection (2) of this section, the association may: <section prefix="a">Subject to approval by a court in this state, impose permanent policy or contract liens in connection with any guarantee, assumption, or reinsurance agreement, if the association finds that the amounts which can be assessed under this subtitle are less than the amounts needed to assure full and prompt performance of the association's duties under this subtitle, or that the economic or financial conditions as they affect member insurers are sufficiently adverse to render the imposition of such permanent policy or contract liens to be in the public interest; and </section><section prefix="b">Subject to approval by a court in this state, impose temporary moratoriums or liens on payments of cash values and policy loans, or any other right to withdraw funds held in conjunction with policies or contracts, in addition to any contractual provisions for deferral of cash or policy loan value. In addition, in the event of a temporary moratorium or moratorium charge imposed by the receivership court on payment of cash values or policy loans, or on any other right to withdraw funds held in conjunction with policies or contracts, out of the assets of the impaired or insolvent insurer, the association may defer the payment of cash values, policy loans, or other rights by the association for the period of the moratorium or moratorium charge imposed by the receivership court, except for claims covered by the association to be paid in accordance with a hardship procedure established by the liquidator or rehabilitator and approved by the receivership court. </section></section><section prefix="8">A deposit in this state, held under law or required by the commissioner for the benefit of creditors, including policy owners, not turned over to the domiciliary liquidator upon the entry of a final order of liquidation or order approving a rehabilitation plan of an insurer domiciled in this state or in a reciprocal state, shall be promptly paid to the association. The association: <section prefix="a">Shall be entitled to retain a portion of any amount so paid to it equal to the percentage determined by dividing the aggregate amount of policy owners' claims related to that insolvency for which the association has provided statutory benefits by the aggregate amount of all policy owners' claims in this state related to that insolvency; and </section><section prefix="b">Shall remit to the domiciliary receiver the amount so paid to the association and retained in accordance with paragraph (a) of this subsection. Any amount so paid to the association less the amount retained by it in accordance with paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be treated as a distribution of estate assets under KRS 304.33-440 or similar provision of the state of domicile of the impaired or insolvent insurer. </section></section><section prefix="9">If the association fails to act within a reasonable period of time with respect to an insolvent insurer as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the commissioner shall have the powers and duties of the association under this subtitle with respect to the insolvent insurer. </section><section prefix="10">The association may render assistance and advice to the commissioner, upon his or her request, concerning rehabilitation, payment of claims, continuance of coverage, or the performance of other contractual obligations of any impaired or insolvent insurer. </section><section prefix="11">The association shall have standing to appear or intervene before any court or agency in this state with jurisdiction over an impaired or insolvent insurer concerning which the association is or may become obligated under this subtitle or with jurisdiction over any person or property against whom the association may have rights through subrogation or otherwise. Such standing shall extend to all matters germane to the powers and duties of the association, including, but not limited to, proposals for reinsuring, modifying, or guaranteeing the policies or contracts of the impaired or insolvent insurer and the determination of the policies or contracts and contractual obligations. The association shall also have the right to appear or intervene before a court or agency in another state with jurisdiction over an impaired or insolvent insurer for which the association is or may become obligated or with jurisdiction over any person or property against whom the association may have rights through subrogation or otherwise. </section><section prefix="12"><section prefix="a">Any person receiving benefits under this subtitle shall be deemed to have assigned the rights under, and any causes of action against any person for losses arising under, resulting from, or otherwise relating to, the covered policy or contract to the association to the extent the benefits received because of this subtitle, whether benefits are payments of or on account of contractual obligations, continuation of coverage, or provision of substitute or alternative coverages. The association may require an assignment to it of such rights and cause of action by any payee, policy or contract owner, beneficiary, insured, or annuitant as a condition precedent to the receipt of any right or benefits conferred by this subtitle upon such person. </section><section prefix="b">The subrogation rights of the association under this subsection shall have the same priority against the assets of the impaired or insolvent insurer as that possessed by the person entitled to receive benefits under this subtitle. </section><section prefix="c">In addition to paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection, the association shall have all common law rights of subrogation and any other equitable or legal remedy that would have been available to the impaired or insolvent insurer or owner, beneficiary, or payee of a policy or contract with respect to such policy or contract, including without limitation, in the case of a structured settlement annuity, any rights of the owner, beneficiary, or payee of the annuity, to the extent of benefits received under this subtitle against a person originally or by succession responsible for the losses arising from the personal injury relating to the annuity or payment therefor. </section><section prefix="d">If the preceding provisions of this subsection are invalid or ineffective with respect to any person or claim for any reason, the amount payable by the association with respect to the related covered obligations shall be reduced by the amount realized by any other person with respect to the person or claim that is attributable to the policies or portion thereof covered by the association. </section><section prefix="e">If the association has provided benefits with respect to a covered obligation and a person recovers amounts as to which the association has rights as described in the preceding paragraphs of this subsection, the person shall pay to the association the portion of the recovery attributable to the policies or portion thereof covered by the association. </section></section><section prefix="13">In addition to the rights and powers elsewhere in this subtitle, the association may: <section prefix="a">Enter into such contracts as are necessary or proper to carry out the provisions and purposes of this subtitle; </section><section prefix="b">Sue or be sued, including taking any legal actions necessary or proper to recover any unpaid assessments under KRS 304.42-090 and to settle claims or potential claims against it; </section><section prefix="c">Borrow money to effect the purposes of this subtitle; any notes or other evidence of indebtedness of the association not in default shall be legal investments for domestic insurers and may be carried as admitted assets; </section><section prefix="d">Employ or retain such persons as are necessary or appropriate to handle the financial transactions of the association, and to perform such other functions as may become necessary or proper under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="e">Take such legal action as may be necessary or appropriate to avoid or recover payment of improper claims; </section><section prefix="f">Exercise, for the purposes of this subtitle and to the extent approved by the commissioner, the powers of a domestic life or health insurer, but in no case may the association issue insurance policies or annuity contracts other than those issued to perform its obligations under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="g">Organize itself as a corporation or in other legal form permitted by the laws of the state; </section><section prefix="h">Request information from a person seeking coverage from the association in order to aid the association in determining its obligations under this subtitle with respect to the person, and the person shall promptly comply with the request; and </section><section prefix="i">Take other necessary or appropriate action to discharge its duties and obligations under this subtitle or to exercise its powers under this subtitle. </section></section><section prefix="14">The association may join an organization of one (1) or more other state associations of similar purposes, to further the purposes and administer the powers and duties of the association. </section><section prefix="15"><section prefix="a">At any time within one (1) year after the date on which the association becomes responsible for the obligations of a member insurer, the association may elect to succeed to the rights and obligations of the member insurer that accrue on or after that date and that relate to contracts covered in whole or in part by the association, under any one (1) or more indemnity reinsurance agreements entered into by the member insurer as a ceding insurer and selected by the association. The association may not exercise any such election with respect to a reinsurance agreement if the receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator of the member insurer has previously and expressly disaffirmed the reinsurance agreement. The election shall be effected by a notice to the receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator and to the affected reinsurer. If the association makes an election, subparagraphs 1. to 4. of this paragraph shall apply with respect to the agreements selected by the association: <section prefix="1">The association shall be responsible for all unpaid premiums due under the agreements for periods both before and after the date, and shall be responsible for the performance of all other obligations to be performed after the coverage date, in each case which relate to contracts covered, in whole or in part, by the association. The association may charge contracts covered in part by the association, through reasonable allocation methods, the costs for reinsurance in excess of the obligations of the association; </section><section prefix="2">The association shall be entitled to any amounts payable by the reinsurer under the agreements with respect to losses or events that occur in periods after the coverage date and that relate to contracts covered by the association, in whole or in part. Upon receipt of any such amounts the association shall be obliged to pay to the beneficiary under the policy or contract on account of which the amounts were paid a portion of the amount equal to the excess of: <section prefix="a">The amount received by the association, over </section><section prefix="b">The benefits paid by the association on account of the policy or contract less the retention of the impaired or insolvent member insurer applicable to the loss or event; </section></section><section prefix="3">Within thirty (30) days following the association's election, the association and each indemnity reinsurer shall calculate the net balance due to or from the association under each such reinsurance agreement as of the date of the association's election, which calculation shall give full credit to all items paid by either the member insurer or its receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator, or the indemnity reinsurer during the period between the coverage date and the date of the association's election. Either the association or indemnity reinsurer shall pay the net balance due the other within five (5) days of the completion of the calculation. If the receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator has received any amounts due the association under subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, the receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator shall remit those amounts to the association as promptly as practicable; and </section><section prefix="4">If the association, within sixty (60) days of the election, pays the premiums due for periods both before and after the coverage date that relate to contracts covered by the association in whole or in part, the insurer shall not be entitled to terminate the reinsurance agreements insofar as the agreements relate to contracts covered by the association in whole or in part and shall not be entitled to set off any unpaid premium due for periods prior to the coverage date against amounts due the association. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the association transfers its obligations to another insurer, and if the association and the other insurer agree, the other insurer shall succeed to the rights and obligations of the association under paragraph (a) of this subsection effective as of the date agreed upon by the association and the other insurer and regardless of whether the association has made the election referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection if: <section prefix="1">The indemnity reinsurance agreements automatically terminate for new reinsurance unless the indemnity reinsurer and the other insurer agree to the contrary; </section><section prefix="2">The obligations described in subparagraph 2. of paragraph (a) of this subsection no longer apply on and after the date the indemnity reinsurance agreement is transferred to the third party insurer; and </section><section prefix="3">The association has not previously expressly determined in writing that it will not exercise the election referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="c">The provisions of this subsection shall supersede the provisions of any law of this state or of any affected reinsurance agreements that provide for or require any payment of reinsurance proceeds, on account of losses or events that occur in periods after the coverage date, to the receiver, liquidator, or rehabilitator of the insolvent member insurer. The receiver, rehabilitator, or liquidator shall remain entitled to any amounts payable by the reinsurer under the reinsurance agreements with respect to losses or events that occur in periods prior to the coverage date, subject to applicable setoff provisions. </section><section prefix="d">Except as otherwise expressly provided in this subsection, nothing in this subsection shall alter or modify the terms and conditions of the indemnity reinsurance agreements of the insolvent member insurer. Nothing in this subsection shall abrogate or limit any rights of any reinsurer to claim that it is entitled to rescind a reinsurance agreement. Nothing in this subsection shall give a policy owner or beneficiary an independent cause of action against an indemnity reinsurer that is not otherwise set forth in the indemnity reinsurance agreement. </section></section><section prefix="16">The board of directors of the association shall have discretion and may exercise reasonable business judgment to determine the means by which the association is to provide the benefits of this subtitle in an economical and efficient manner. </section><section prefix="17">If the association has arranged or offered to provide the benefits of this subtitle to a covered person under a plan or arrangement that fulfills the association's obligations under this subtitle, the person shall not be entitled to benefits from the association in addition to or other than those provided under the plan or arrangement. </section><section prefix="18">Venue in a suit against the association under this subtitle shall be in Franklin County. The association shall not be required to give an appeal bond in an appeal that relates to a cause of action arising under this subtitle. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1562, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 537, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30112</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>