<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.7-530</section_number><catch_line>Authority of department -- Regulations. </catch_line><order_by>7-530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every corporation organized under the provisions of KRS 286.7-410 to 286.7-600 shall report to and be subject to examination, supervision, and control by the Department of Financial Institutions. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 286.7-410 to 286.7-600 shall be enforced by the commissioner, who may, after notice to holders of certificates and a hearing, promulgate regulations, referenced to the section or sections which set forth the legislative standards they interpret or apply, for the proper conduct of the business authorized under KRS 286.7-410 to 286.7-600. </section><section prefix="3">On or before January 30 of each year, every industrial loan company shall file with the commissioner a report for the preceding calendar year. The report shall give information with respect to the financial condition of the industrial loan company, and other relevant information as the commissioner may reasonably require. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 755, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 291.530. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14842</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>