<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.895</section_number><catch_line>Evacuation plan required for child-care centers and family child-care homes -- Annual updating of plan -- Provision of plan to local emergency management officials and parents.   </catch_line><order_by>895</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A child-care center licensed under KRS 199.896 and a family child-care home certified under KRS 199.8982 shall have a written plan for evacuation in the event of fire, natural disaster, or other threatening situation that may pose a health or safety hazard to the children in the center or home. The plan shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">A designated relocation site and evacuation route; </section><section prefix="b">Procedures for notifying parents of the relocation and ensuring family reunification; </section><section prefix="c">Procedures to address the needs of individual children including children with special needs; </section><section prefix="d">Instructions relating to the training of staff or the reassignment of staff duties, as appropriate; </section><section prefix="e">Coordination with local emergency management officials; and </section><section prefix="f">A program to ensure that appropriate staff are familiar with the plan's components. </section></section><section prefix="2">A child-care center and a family child-care home shall update the evacuation plan by December 31 each year. </section><section prefix="3">A child-care center and a family child-care home shall retain an updated copy of the plan for evacuation, provide an updated copy to appropriate local emergency management officials, and provide a copy to each parent, custodian, or guardian of the child at the time of the child's enrollment in the program and whenever the plan is updated. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 3, effective December 31, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40523</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>