<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">C APPLIED BEHAVIOR ANALYSTS </unit></structure><section_number>319C.080</section_number><catch_line>Application for license as licensed behavior analyst or licensed assistant behavior analyst -- Temporary license -- Duties of certification board. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person applying for a license as a licensed behavior analyst shall apply to the board upon such form and in such manner as the board shall prescribe and shall furnish evidence to the board that such person: <section prefix="a">Has met the education requirements of the Board Certified Behavior Analyst (BCBA)® standards, has passed the Board Certified Behavior Analyst (BCBA)® examination, and is credentialed as a behavior analyst by the certification board; </section><section prefix="b">Maintains active status and fulfills all requirements for renewal and recertification with the certification board as a Board Certified Behavior Analyst (BCBA)®; </section><section prefix="c">Conducts his or her professional activities in accordance with accepted standards as required by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS 319C.050(1); and </section><section prefix="d">Complies with all applicable administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person applying for a license as a licensed assistant behavior analyst shall make application to the board upon such form and in such manner as the board shall prescribe by administrative regulation and shall furnish evidence to the board that such person: <section prefix="a">Has met the education requirements of the Board Certified Assistant Behavior Analyst (BCaBA)® standards, has passed the BCaBA® examination, and is credentialed as an assistant behavior analyst by the certification board; </section><section prefix="b">Maintains active status and fulfills all requirements for renewal and recertification with the certification board as a Board Certified Assistant Behavior Analyst®; </section><section prefix="c">Conducts his or her professional activities in accordance with accepted standards as required by administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS 319C.050(1); </section><section prefix="d">Complies with all applicable administrative regulations promulgated by the board; and </section><section prefix="e">Is supervised by a certified behavior analyst in a manner consistent with the certification board requirements for supervision of Board Certified Assistant Behavior Analysts®. </section></section><section prefix="3">A person applying for a temporary license to complete his or her experience requirement shall make application to the board upon such form and in such manner as the board shall prescribe by administrative regulation and shall furnish evidence to the board that he or she: <section prefix="a">Has met the coursework requirements for a Board Certified Behavior Analyst® or Board Certified Assistant Behavior Analyst® and will begin accumulating experience as required by the certification board; and </section><section prefix="b">Will comply with the provisions of this chapter and the requirements of the certification board during the period of temporary licensure. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the certification board ceases certification of practitioners of applied behavior analysis, the board shall: <section prefix="a">Approve a successor entity to the certification board; or </section><section prefix="b">Establish a certification process by administrative regulation and approve an examination for behavior analysts and assistant behavior analysts and establish standards for acceptable performance. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31299</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>