<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.160</section_number><catch_line>Denial, revocation, or suspension of license -- Grounds.   </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text>The board may deny, revoke, or suspend the license of an individual who: <section prefix="1">Has engaged in conduct relating to his or her profession that is likely to deceive, defraud, or harm the public; </section><section prefix="2">Has engaged in alcohol and other drug abuse as defined in KRS 222.005; </section><section prefix="3">Develops a physical or mental disability or other condition that makes continued practice or performance of his or her duties potentially dangerous to patients or the public; </section><section prefix="4">Performs procedures under or represents as valid to any person a license: <section prefix="a">Not issued by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Containing unauthorized alterations; or </section><section prefix="c">Containing changes that are inconsistent with board records regarding its issuance; </section></section><section prefix="5">Has been convicted of a crime that is a felony under the laws of this state or convicted of a felony in a federal court, unless the individual has had all civil rights restored; </section><section prefix="6">Exhibits significant or repeated failure in the performance of professional duties; or </section><section prefix="7">Fails to comply with any administrative regulation of the board. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 16, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>