<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.1121</section_number><catch_line>Broadband deployment account -- Purpose -- Incentive program -- Funding criteria and prioritization schedules -- Administrative regulations -- Project completion deadline. </catch_line><order_by>1121</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of the broadband deployment account set forth in KRS 224A.112 shall be to assist governments and private sector entities to construct infrastructure for the deployment of broadband service to unserved areas of the Commonwealth. The authority shall manage the account and may accept and receive appropriations from the General Assembly or other funds or gifts from both public and private sources, including but not limited to local governments and federal agencies. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall establish an incentive program that allocates funds from the broadband deployment account in accordance with this section. Incentives may be used by government or private sector entities for broadband deployment projects. </section><section prefix="3">The incentive program shall be developed to give highest funding priority to those projects which most effectively provide broadband service to the greatest number of unserved Kentucky citizens and at the lowest cost. Funding shall not be used for projects with an intent to deploy broadband service to areas where broadband service already exists; however, the authority may consider funding for projects that, in providing broadband service for an unserved area, create an overlap in existing broadband coverage for less than twenty percent (20%) of households in the proposed coverage area. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall develop funding criteria and prioritization schedules for broadband deployment projects in accordance with this section and with consideration given to recommendations submitted by area development districts, telecommunications businesses, information services, technology industries, governmental entities, and by Kentucky-based nonprofit organizations, including ConnectKentucky. </section><section prefix="5">To carry out the purposes of this section, the authority shall promulgate administration regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="6">Projects receiving funding as provided by this section shall be completed within twelve (12) months of receiving the funds. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>