<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.1241</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations on Kentucky coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund. </catch_line><order_by>1241</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds and declares that the awards of workers' compensation benefits for coal workers' pneumoconiosis (black lung) have placed a substantial financial burden on all employers of the Commonwealth through the special fund assessments imposed on all employers to cover the liabilities of the special fund. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly finds and declares that the purpose of creating the Kentucky Coal Workers' Pneumoconiosis Fund in KRS 342.1242 is to assure that liabilities incurred as a result of workers' compensation awards for coal workers' pneumoconiosis with dates of last exposure after December 12, 1996, shall be the financial responsibility of employers engaged in severance and processing of coal. </section><section prefix="3">Therefore, it is the intent of the General Assembly in imposing the assessments required in KRS 342.1242(3)(a) and (b) to assure that liabilities incurred as a result of workers' compensation awards for coal workers' pneumoconiosis with dates of last exposure after December 12, 1996, shall be the financial responsibility of employers engaged in the severance and processing of coal. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 75, effective December 12, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>