<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.730</section_number><catch_line>Immediate review of petition -- Summons to evidentiary hearing -- Exparte emergency protective order.  (Effective January 1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text>(1)(a)The court shall review a petition for an order of protection immediatelyupon its filing. If the review indicates that domestic violence and abuseexists, the court shall summons the parties to an evidentiary hearing notmore than fourteen (14) days in the future. If the review indicates thatsuch a basis does not exist, the court may consider an amended petitionor dismiss the petition without prejudice.(b)Service of the summons and hearing order under this subsection shall bemade upon the adverse party personally and may be made in the mannerand by the persons authorized to serve subpoenas under Rule 45.03 ofthe Rules of Civil Procedure. A summons may be reissued if service hasnot been made on the adverse party by the fixed court date and time.(2)(a)If the review under this section also indicates the presence of animmediate and present danger of domestic violence and abuse, the courtshall, upon proper motion, issue ex parte an emergency protective orderthat:1.Authorizes relief appropriate to the situation utilizing the alternativesset out in KRS 403.740, other than awarding temporary support orcounseling;2.Expires upon the conclusion of the evidentiary hearing required bythis section unless extended or withdrawn by subsequent order ofthe court; and3.Does not order or refer the parties to mediation unless requested bythe petitioner, and the court finds that:a.The petitioner's request is voluntary and not the result ofcoercion; andb.Mediation is a realistic and viable alternative to or adjunct tothe issuance of an order sought by the petitioner.(b)If an order is not issued under this subsection, the court shall note on thepetition, for the record, any action taken or denied and the reason for it.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 4, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. --Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44752</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>