<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.050</section_number><catch_line>Schedule I controlled substances. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>Unless otherwise rescheduled by administrative regulation of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the controlled substances listed in this section are included in Schedule I: <section prefix="1">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following opiates, including their isomers, esters, ethers, salts, and salts of isomers, esters, and ethers, unless specifically excepted, whenever the existence of these isomers, esters, ethers, or salts is possible within the specific chemical designation: Acetylfentanyl; Acetylmethadol; Allylprodine; Alphacetylmethadol; Alphameprodine; Alphamethadol; Benzethidine; Betacetylmethadol; Betameprodine; Betamethadol; Betaprodine; Clonitazene; Dextromoramide; Dextrorphan; Diampromide; Diethylthiambutene; Dimenoxadol; Dimepheptanol; Dimethylthiambutene; Dioxaphetyl butyrate; Dipipanone; Ethylmethylthiambutene; Etonitazene; Etoxeridine; Furethidine; Hydroxypethidine; Ketobemidone; Levomoramide; Levophenacylmorphan; Morpheridine; Noracymethadol; Norlevorphanol; Normethadone; Norpipanone; Phenadoxone; Phenampromide; Phenomorphan; Phenoperidine; Piritramide; Proheptazine; Properidine; Propiram; Racemoramide; Trimeperidine; </section><section prefix="2">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following opium derivatives, including their salts, isomers, and salts of isomers, unless specifically excepted, whenever the existence of these salts, isomers, or salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation: Acetorphine; Acetyldihydrocodeine; Benzylmorphine; Codeine methylbromide; Codeine-N-Oxide; Cyprenorphine; Desomorphine; Dihydromorphine; Etorphine; Heroin; Hydromorphinol; Methyldesorphine; Methyldihydromorphine; Morphine methylbromide; Morphine methylsulfonate; Morphine-N-Oxide; Myrophine; Nicocodeine; Nicomorphine; Normorphine; Pholcodine; Thebacon; </section><section prefix="3">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following hallucinogenic substances, their salts, isomers, or salts of isomers, unless specifically excepted, whenever the existence of these salts, isomers, and salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation: 3, 4-methylenedioxyamphetamine; 5-methoxy-3, 4-methylenedioxy amphetamine; 3, 4, 5-trimethoxyamphetamine; Bufotenine; Diethyltryptamine; Dimethyltryptamine; 4-methyl-2, 5-dimethoxyamphetamine; Ibogaine; Lysergic acid diethylamide; Marijuana; Mescaline; Peyote; N-ethyl-3-piperidyl benzilate; N-methyl-3-piperidyl benzilate; Psilocybin; Psilocyn; Tetrahydrocannabinols; Hashish; Phencyclidine, 2 Methylamino-1-phenylpropan-1-one (including but not limited to Methcathinone, Cat, and Ephedrone); synthetic drugs; or salvia; </section><section prefix="4">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substance having a depressant effect on the central nervous system, including its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers, unless specifically excepted, whenever the existence of these salts, isomers, or salts of isomers is possible within the specific chemical designation: gamma hydroxybutyric acid; and </section><section prefix="5">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances: <section prefix="a">2-(2,5-dimethoxyphenyl)-N-[(2-methoxyphenyl)methyl]ethanamine (2,5H-NBOMe); </section><section prefix="b">2-(4-iodo-2,5-dimethoxyphenyl)-N-[(2-methoxyphenyl)methyl]ethanamine (2,5I-NBOMe); </section><section prefix="c">2-(4-bromo-2,5-dimethoxyphenyl)-N-[(2-methoxyphenyl)methyl]ethanamine (2,5B-NBOMe); or </section><section prefix="d">2-(4-chloro-2,5-dimethoxyphenyl)-N-[(2-methoxyphenyl)methyl]ethanamine (2,5C-NBOMe). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 10, effective March 25, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective March 19, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 5, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.45, sec.4, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 5, effective April 13, 2010; and ch. 160, sec. 5, effective April 26, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 530, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 473, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 412, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44006</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>