<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.530</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text>For the purposes of KRS 15.530 to 15.590: <section prefix="1">"CJIS" means the Criminal Justice Information System; </section><section prefix="2">"CJIS-full access course" means a training program of at least forty (40) hours approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council; </section><section prefix="3">"CJIS telecommunicator" means any full-time public employee, sworn or civilian, whose primary responsibility is to dispatch law enforcement units by means of radio communications for an agency that utilizes the Criminal Justice Information System, and is part of or administered by the state or any political subdivision; </section><section prefix="4">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Criminal Justice Training; </section><section prefix="5">"Non-CJIS telecommunicator" means any full-time public employee, sworn or civilian, whose primary responsibility is to dispatch law enforcement units by means of radio communications for an agency that does not utilize the Criminal Justice Information System and is part of or administered by the state or any political subdivision; </section><section prefix="6">"Non-CJIS telecommunicator academy" means a training course of at least one hundred twenty (120) hours approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council; and </section><section prefix="7">"Telecommunications academy" means a training course of at least one hundred sixty (160) hours approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=968</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>