<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.576</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 186.576 to 186.579. </catch_line><order_by>576</order_by><text>As used in KRS 186.576 to 186.579: <section prefix="1">"Applicant" means any person applying for an instruction permit or an operator's license who must use a bioptic telescopic device in order to operate a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">"Binocular vision" means visual acuity that is 20/200 or better in both eyes, with or without corrective lenses; </section><section prefix="3">"Bioptic telescopic device" means a two (2) focus optical system used to magnify distant objects by including a small telescope that is mounted in a spectacle lens in a manner to allow an unobstructed view of the horizontal visual field through a person's normal distance corrective lens; </section><section prefix="4">"Certified driver training program" means a program that provides and coordinates comprehensive assessment and training of driving skills and responses that emphasizes the vision, hearing, psychological, perceptual, orientation, and mobility skills of an applicant and that is certified by the department; </section><section prefix="5">"Combined visual acuity" means visual acuity attained by using both eyes together where a person has binocular vision; </section><section prefix="6">"Corrective lenses" means eyeglasses, contact lenses, and intraocular lenses, but does not mean a bioptic telescopic device; </section><section prefix="7">"Daytime driving restriction" means operation of a motor vehicle is restricted to the period of time from between thirty (30) minutes after sunrise and thirty (30) minutes before sunset. Under this restriction, driving during adverse weather conditions that significantly reduce the visibility of the roadway, other traffic, and traffic control devices shall be prohibited; </section><section prefix="8">"Office" means the Office for the Blind; </section><section prefix="9">"Monocular vision" means visual acuity that is 20/200 or better in only one (1) eye, with or without corrective lenses; </section><section prefix="10">"Restricted out-of-state driver" means a person who has been issued, by another state, a valid operator's license with a restriction requiring the use of a bioptic telescopic device; </section><section prefix="11">"Vision specialist" means a licensed ophthalmologist or optometrist; </section><section prefix="12">"Visual acuity" means the measure of a person's visual acuity based on the Snellen visual acuity scale; and </section><section prefix="13">"Visual field" means the area of physical space visible to the eye in a given fixed position. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 116, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6084</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>