<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.640</section_number><catch_line>Medical Assistance Revolving Trust Fund (MART) -- Distribution of disproportionate share funds -- Authority for administrative regulations -- Duties of hospitals receiving funds from MART. </catch_line><order_by>640</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of Medicaid services shall adopt a disproportionate share program consistent with the requirements of Title XIX of the Social Security Act which shall include to the extent possible, but not limited to, the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The Medical Assistance Revolving Trust Fund (MART) shall be established in the State Treasury and all provider tax revenues collected pursuant to KRS 142.301 to 142.363 shall be deposited in the State Treasury and transferred on a quarterly basis to the Department for Medicaid Services for use as specified in this section. All investment earnings of the fund shall be credited to the fund. Provider tax revenues collected in accordance with KRS 142.301 to 142.363 may be used to fund the provisions of KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929 and to supplement the medical assistance-related general fund appropriations for fiscal year 1994 and subsequent fiscal years. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 48.500 and 48.600, the MART fund shall be exempt from any state budget reduction acts. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Beginning in state fiscal year 2000-2001 and continuing annually thereafter, provider tax revenues and state and federal matching funds shall be used to fund the disproportionate share program established by administrative regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Disproportionate share funds shall be divided into three (3) pools for distribution as follows: <section prefix="1">Forty-three and ninety-two hundredths percent (43.92%) of the total disproportionate share funds shall be allocated to acute care hospitals; </section><section prefix="2">Thirty-seven percent (37%) of the total disproportionate share funds shall be allocated to university hospitals; </section><section prefix="3">The percentage allowable by federal law pursuant to 42 U.S.C. sec. 1396r-4(h), up to nineteen and eight hundredths percent (19.08%) of the total disproportionate share funds shall be allocated to private psychiatric hospitals and state mental hospitals, with the allocation to each respective group of hospitals established by the biennial budget; </section><section prefix="4">If there are any remaining disproportionate share funds from private psychiatric hospitals and state mental hospitals, fifty-four percent (54%) of those funds shall be distributed to the acute care hospitals and forty-six percent (46%) shall be distributed to the university hospitals; and </section><section prefix="5">If, in any year, one (1) or both university hospitals fail to provide state matching funds necessary to secure federal financial participation for the funds allocated to university hospitals under this subsection, the portion of the funding allocation applicable to the hospital or hospitals that fail to provide state matching funds shall be made available to acute care hospitals. </section></section><section prefix="b">The MART fund shall be used to compensate acute care hospitals, private psychiatric hospitals, state mental hospitals, and university hospitals participating in the disproportionate share program for uncompensated service provided by the hospitals to individuals and families with total annual incomes and resources up to one hundred percent (100%) of the federal poverty level, as determined by the hospital pursuant to administrative regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in accordance with this section. </section><section prefix="c">An individual hospital shall receive distributions for indigent care provided by that hospital if the hospital meets the requirements of the disproportionate share program. </section><section prefix="d">Distributions to acute care and private psychiatric hospitals shall be made as follows: <section prefix="1">The department shall calculate an indigent care factor for each hospital annually. The indigent care factor shall be determined by calculating the percentage of each hospital's annual indigent care costs toward the sum of the total annual indigent care costs for all hospitals within each respective pool. For purposes of this paragraph, "indigent care costs" means the hospital's inpatient and outpatient care as reported to the department multiplied by the hospital's Medicaid rate, or at a rate determined by the department in administrative regulation that, when multiplied by the hospital's reported indigent care, is equivalent to the amount that would be payable by the department under the fee-for-service Medicaid program for the hospital's total reported indigent care. </section><section prefix="2">Each hospital's annual distribution shall be calculated by multiplying the hospital's indigent care factor by the total fund allocated to all hospitals within the respective pool under paragraph (a) of this subsection. <section prefix="a">Hospitals shall report uncompensated care provided to qualified individuals and families with total annual incomes and resources up to one hundred percent (100%) of the federal poverty level, including care rendered to indigent persons age twenty-two (22) to sixty-four (64) in a psychiatric hospital to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services on a quarterly basis. However, all data for care provided during the state fiscal year shall be submitted no later than August 15 of each year. </section><section prefix="b">For state fiscal year 2001-2002 and each year thereafter, the department shall use data reported by the hospitals for indigent care services rendered for the twelve (12) month period ending June 30 of each year as reported by the hospital to the department by August 15 in calculating each hospital's indigent care factor. The hospital shall, upon request by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, submit any supporting documentation to verify the indigent care data submitted for the calculation of an indigent care factor and annual payment. </section><section prefix="c">By September 1 of each year, the department shall calculate a preliminary indigent care factor and preliminary annual payment amount for each hospital, and shall notify each hospital of their calculation. The notice shall contain a listing of each hospital's indigent care costs, their indigent care factor, and the estimated annual payment amount. Hospitals shall notify the department by September 15 of any adjustments in the department's preliminary calculations. The department shall make adjustments identified by hospitals and shall make a final determination of each hospital's indigent care factor and annual payment amount by October 1. The department shall make a final determination of each hospital's annual payment amount upon notification through the Federal Register of the annual federal disproportionate share hospital allotment for the Commonwealth. </section></section></section><section prefix="e">The department shall issue to each hospital one (1) lump-sum payment on October 15, or later as soon as federal financial participation becomes available through notification by publication of the Federal Register, for the disproportionate share funds available during the corresponding federal fiscal year. The department may pay a portion of the expected annual payment prior to the publication of the annual federal allotment. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provision to contrary, total annual disproportionate share payments made to state mental hospitals, university hospitals, acute care hospitals, and private psychiatric hospitals in each state fiscal year shall be equal to the maximum amount of disproportionate share payments established under the Federal Balanced Budget Act of 1997 and any amendments thereto. Disproportionate share payments shall be subject to the availability of adequate state matching funds and shall not exceed total uncompensated costs. </section><section prefix="5">Hospitals receiving reimbursement shall not bill patients for services submitted for reimbursement under this section and KRS 205.641. Services provided to individuals who are eligible for medical assistance or the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program do not qualify for reimbursement under this section and KRS 205.641. Hospitals shall make a reasonable determination that an individual does not qualify for these programs and shall request the individual to apply, if appropriate, for medical assistance or Kentucky Children's Health Insurance on forms supplied by and in accordance with procedures established by the Department for Medicaid Services. The hospital shall document any refusal to apply and shall inform the patient that the refusal may result in the patient being billed for any services performed. The hospital shall not be eligible for reimbursement if the patient was eligible for medical assistance or Kentucky Children's Health Insurance and did not apply. Hospitals receiving reimbursement under this section and KRS 205.641 shall not bill patients for services provided to patients not eligible for medical assistance with family incomes up to one hundred percent (100%) of the federal poverty level. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, for the administration and implementation of this section. </section><section prefix="7">All hospitals receiving reimbursement under this section and KRS 205.641 shall display prominently a sign which reads as follows: "This hospital will accept patients regardless of race, creed, ethnic background, or ability to pay." </section><section prefix="8">The hospital shall, upon request by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, submit any supporting documentation to substantiate compliance with the audit requirements established by 42 C.F.R. sec. 455. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 258, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 120, sec. 14, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 9, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 2, effective April 4, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 426, sec. 217, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 545, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 85, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1993 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 20, effective June 8, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2006).  The amendments to this statute made in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1, have not taken effect. Section 2 of 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 107 states: "This Act shall become effective upon certification to the Reviser of Statutes from the secretary of the Cabinet for Health Services that necessary federal approval of the proposed distribution of disproportionate share funds outlined in subsection (3) of Section 1 has been obtained. This Act shall not become effective if certification is not received prior to July 1, 2006." The Reviser of Statutes did not receive certification by that date.  (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 82, 426, and 545. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between ch. 426 and ch. 545, Acts ch. 545, which was a nonrevisory Act, prevails under KRS 7.136(3). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>