<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.062</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal incentive program for local efforts to enhance public safety and reduce juvenile justice system costs. </catch_line><order_by>062</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the Commonwealth to maintain public safety and achieve savings through the use of evidence-based treatment programs and practices at the local level and to reinvest a portion of the savings achieved into community-based programs and services. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall, as funds become available, develop a fiscal incentive program to fund local efforts that enhance public safety while reducing juvenile justice system costs. </section><section prefix="3">Funds appropriated to the cabinet for the fiscal incentive program shall be distributed as follows: <section prefix="a">Ninety percent (90%) shall be utilized for renewable, competitive grants to be awarded to judicial districts, or groups of judicial districts, for the purpose of establishing community-based sanction and treatment programs that provide alternatives to out-of-home placement; and </section><section prefix="b">Ten percent (10%) shall be made available to judicial districts, or groups of judicial districts, not receiving funds under paragraph (a) of this subsection, to fund individualized interventions on an occasional basis to avoid commitment to the Department of Juvenile Justice for a limited number of youth. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall establish the incentive grant application and award process for funds allocated under subsection (3)(a) of this section that includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">The requirements for the grant application, including: <section prefix="1">The identification of the local committee that will be responsible for the grant application and implementation. The committee shall consist of local individuals or organizations, which may include judges, county attorneys, defense attorneys, educators, treatment providers, mental health or behavioral health service providers, local officials, law enforcement, and other interested persons. The local committee may utilize an existing committee or may be formed for the purpose of the grant application and implementation; </section><section prefix="2">A requirement that the application be signed as "Have Reviewed and Agree" by all juvenile court judges in the applicant's judicial district or group of judicial districts; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the proposed program region and the juvenile justice need the program is intended to meet; </section><section prefix="4">A description of how the proposed program collaborates with: <section prefix="a">Schools; </section><section prefix="b">The Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="c">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="d">Private entities serving children and families; and </section><section prefix="e">The department; and </section></section><section prefix="5">A description of performance measures to be utilized to measure the outcome and overall impact of the program;  </section></section><section prefix="b">The procedure for review of the grant applications and the award of the grants including: <section prefix="1">A committee that includes subject matter experts to review the applications; </section><section prefix="2">Criteria to be utilized in awarding of the grants, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">The use of evidence-based practices in program design; </section><section prefix="b">How the program reduces the use of commitments; </section><section prefix="c">How the program reduces the use of out-of-home placements; </section><section prefix="d">How the program reduces recidivism; </section><section prefix="e">How the program establishes or utilizes educational, vocational, substance abuse, behavioral health, mental health, or family intervention services, and local alternatives to detention; </section><section prefix="f">Whether grant funds will be used to leverage existing funding resources or increase access to existing resources; </section><section prefix="g">Geographical distribution; </section><section prefix="h">The number of youth potentially served by the program or service; </section><section prefix="i">The cost of the program or service; and </section><section prefix="j">The existence of similar services in the judicial district; and </section></section><section prefix="3">A process for awarding the grants that may include objective scoring criteria; </section></section><section prefix="c">A baseline for calculating reductions for the competitive grant program utilizing 2013 data that combines commitment and detention admissions, and overrides of decisions to allow eligible cases to proceed to diversion; and </section><section prefix="d">Criteria for renewal of a grant awarded under subsection (3)(a) of this section, including: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A twenty percent (20%) reduction in detention admissions, public offense commitment, or combination thereof, as compared to the applicant's baseline; or </section><section prefix="b">A ten percent (10%) reduction in detention admissions, public offense commitments, or combination thereof and a thirty percent (30%) reduction in the use of prosecutorial override of diversion recommendations as compared to the applicant's baseline; </section></section><section prefix="2">If the judicial district meets the reductions required in this subsection, the judicial district may be considered for grant renewal. The grants are not guaranteed to be renewed, and an application shall be submitted for consideration of renewal; </section><section prefix="3">If a judicial district has substantially complied with the requirements of the program, but has not attained the reductions required in this subsection, the judicial district may apply for a grant renewal if there is a fifteen percent (15%) reduction in detention admissions, public offense commitments, or a combination thereof during year one (1) as compared to the applicant’s baseline; and </section><section prefix="4">Detention and public offense commitments for violent offenses as specified in KRS 439.3401 shall not be counted in the calculation of reductions for a judicial district. </section></section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A judicial district may apply for the competitive grant program under subsection (3)(a) of this section until: <section prefix="1">The population of detention admissions and public offense commitments is reduced by sixty percent (60%) as compared to the applicant's baseline; or </section><section prefix="2">The population of detention admissions, public offense commitments, or a combination thereof is reduced by thirty percent (30%) as compared to the applicant's baseline, and the use of prosecutorial override of diversion recommendations is reduced by ninety percent (90%) as compared to the applicant's baseline. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the judicial district meets the reductions described in paragraph (a) of this subsection, the district may continue to apply for funding so long as the reductions required are maintained.  </section></section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall establish an expedited application and approval process for awarding the one (1) time only funds under subsection (3)(b) of this section, that includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">A requirement that the application be signed as "Have Reviewed and Agree" by a juvenile court judge in the applicant's judicial district or group of judicial districts; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the proposed purpose of the grant and the applicant’s need; and </section><section prefix="c">Other requirements as determined appropriate by the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall: <section prefix="a">Act as the fiscal agent to receive funds awarded to a judicial district; </section><section prefix="b">Provide technical assistance to the judicial district in developing and writing its grant application; and </section><section prefix="c">Collect and report data the judicial districts are required to report under the fiscal incentive program. </section></section><section prefix="8">The cabinet shall report annually to the oversight council created in KRS 15A.063 on the fiscal incentive program, outcomes achieved, and cost savings realized through reductions in the use of detention and commitments. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43480</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>