<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.239</section_number><catch_line>Debts owed Court of Justice -- Identification and collection of debts and liquidated debts -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>239</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Court of Justice shall initiate, by October 1, 2004, fully implement by October 1, 2005, and thereafter maintain a system for tracking and identifying debts. </section><section prefix="2">The Court of Justice shall establish and operate a system for collecting debt. </section><section prefix="3">In establishing the systems required by this section, the Court of Justice shall consider technology that could assist in the accurate, timely, and efficient delivery of payments of debts. </section><section prefix="4">The Court of Justice, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and the Department of Revenue shall collaborate to implement a system, if feasible, to identify and collect debts in existence prior to the implementation date of the system required by subsection (1) of this section. Confidential information shared among these entities to identify and collect debts shall not be divulged to any unauthorized person. Debts collected under this subsection shall be reported annually and designated separately as part of the report required pursuant to KRS 45.238 beginning on October 1, 2005, and ending with the report filed on or before October 1, 2009. </section><section prefix="5">The Court of Justice, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and Department of Revenue shall collaborate to implement a system, if feasible, to identify and collect liquidated debts in existence prior to the implementation date of the system required by subsection (1) of this section. Confidential information shared among these entities to identify and collect debts shall not be divulged to any unauthorized person. Debts collected under this subsection shall be reported annually to the Legislative Research Commission beginning on October 1, 2005, and ending with the report filed on or before October 1, 2009. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 125, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 63, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004; and ch. 192, sec. 3, effective April 21, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(4/21/2004).  This section was created by 2004 Ky. Acts chs. 118, sec. 7, and 192, sec. 3, which have been codified together. Subsection (1) of this statute was enacted identically in subsection (1) of ch. 118, sec. 7, and subsection (1) of ch. 192, sec. 3. Subsections (4) and (5) were enacted by the same two Acts with substantially similar, but nonidentical, text. Subsection (4) was created by ch. 192, sec. 3, subsec. (4), and subsection (5) was created by ch. 118, sec. 7, subsec. (2). Because the two subsections differ slightly in the texts, both have been codified in their entirety. Subsections (2) and (3) were enacted by subsections (2) and (3) of ch. 192, sec. 3. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>