<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.100</section_number><catch_line>Deputy attorney general, assistant deputy attorneys general, assistants, special attorneys and contract attorneys. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General shall appoint a deputy attorney general, who shall have the same qualifications required of a Circuit Judge except for residence in a district and who shall receive the same salary as a Circuit Judge, to serve at the pleasure of the Attorney General and to perform the duties he may designate. The Attorney General may appoint two (2) assistant deputy attorneys general, who shall have the same qualifications required of a District Judge except for residence in a district and who shall receive the same salary as a District Judge, to serve at the pleasure of the Attorney General and to perform the duties he may designate. In addition thereto, he may appoint another assistant deputy attorney general to function as administrator and shall set his salary. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to the deputy attorney general, the Attorney General shall appoint such assistants and special attorneys as he deems necessary to transact the business of the Department of Law, and to perform the duties he may designate. The deputy attorney general, assistant deputy attorneys general, assistants, and special attorneys shall have full power, as authorized and under the direction of the Attorney General, to perform such duties as may be performed by the Attorney General. The Attorney General shall be responsible for the official acts of his deputy, assistant deputy attorneys general, assistants, and special attorneys. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the appointment and designation of a deputy, assistant deputy attorneys general, assistants and special attorneys pursuant to subsections (1) and (2) of this section, the Attorney General may enter into such contracts for legal services as he deems necessary and advisable. </section><section prefix="4">Each assistant or special attorney so appointed or designated shall be a person admitted to the practice of law by the Supreme Court of this Commonwealth and shall qualify by taking the oath of office. </section></text><history>Amended 1988Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 9. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. II, sec. 5. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 29. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 112-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=884</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>