<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="248" order_by="248">TOBACCO </unit></structure><section_number>248.520</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text>The Kentucky Tobacco Research Board shall: <section prefix="1">Formulate policies and procedures as necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="2">Promulgate rules and regulations as necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 248.510 to 248.570 and to ensure proper expenditure of state funds appropriated for the purposes of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="3">Review and authorize research projects and programs to be undertaken and financed under the provisions of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. <section prefix="a">The facilities designated the Tobacco and Health Research Institute before July 15, 2002, shall be retained and operated by the University of Kentucky exclusively for the program and activities described in KRS 248.580. </section><section prefix="b">In addition to the research and development funded by authority of the Kentucky Tobacco Research Board, the board is authorized to allow other research operations having related or complementary interests to share this physical facility with the Kentucky Tobacco Research and Development Center, subject to approval of the board. </section></section><section prefix="4">Review and approve all progress and final research reports on projects authorized under the provisions of KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="5">Ensure that state funds, appropriated by KRS 248.510 to 248.570 or any other act for tobacco research, are not diverted to any other use and that all authorized research projects are directed toward: <section prefix="a">Preserving and strengthening tobacco agriculture in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Facilitating the progress of commercial endeavors in crop agriculture which have potential to provide entirely new market opportunities for tobacco growers; and </section><section prefix="c">Applying, when appropriate, previously authorized research initially conducted with tobacco to other plants which might be grown commercially in Kentucky, thus obtaining the fullest possible practical benefit from the research progress. </section></section><section prefix="6">Provide the Governor, the General Assembly, and the Legislative Research Commission an annual report by January 30 of each year showing the status of funds appropriated under KRS 248.510 to 248.570 for tobacco research and the progress of the board in terms of the results of its tobacco research efforts. </section><section prefix="7">Advise the General Assembly by January 30 during each even-numbered-year regular session of the need for continuation of the Kentucky Tobacco Research Board and the tax levied by Chapter 255 of the Acts of 1970 for the purpose of financing tobacco and related new crops research programs as provided by KRS 248.510 to 248.570. </section><section prefix="8">Approve and release public statements relating to the progress and results of research projects. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 19, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 2. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>