<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14">DEPARTMENT OF STATE </unit></structure><section_number>14.306</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for cancellation of a program participant's certification -- Notice of cancellation -- Appeal -- Voluntary withdrawal from program -- Procedure to ensure that request for withdrawal is legitimate -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>306</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State may cancel certification of a program participant if within fourteen (14) days: <section prefix="a">From the date of the program participant changing his or her name, the program participant fails to notify the Secretary of State that he or she has obtained a name change; however, the program participant may reapply under his or her new name; or </section><section prefix="b">From the date of changing his or her address, the program participant fails to notify the Secretary of State of the change of address. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State shall cancel certification of a program participant who applies using false information. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State shall send notice of certification cancellation to the program participant. The notice of certification cancellation shall set out the reasons for cancellation. The program participant has the right to appeal the decision within thirty (30) days under procedures established by the Office of the Secretary of State by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="4">The Secretary of State shall cancel certification of a program participant who is required to register as a sex offender. </section><section prefix="5">A program participant may withdraw from the program by providing the Secretary of State with notice of his or her intention to withdraw from the program. The Secretary of State shall promulgate by administrative regulations a secure procedure by which to ensure that the program participant's request for withdrawal is legitimate. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42326</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>