<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.091</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of court records -- Expungement. </catch_line><order_by>091</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The court records of a respondent made in all proceedings pursuant to KRS Chapter 202A are hereby declared to be confidential and shall not be open to the general public for inspection except when such disclosure is provided in KRS 202A.016. </section><section prefix="2">Following the discharge of a respondent from a treatment facility or the issuance of a court order denying a petition for a commitment, a respondent may at any time move to have all court records pertaining to the proceedings expunged from the files of the court. The county attorney shall be given notice of any such motion and shall have five (5) days in which to respond to same or request a hearing thereon. </section><section prefix="3">Any person seeking information contained in the court files or the court records of proceedings involving persons under this chapter may file a written motion in the cause setting out why the information is needed. A District Judge may issue an order to disclose the information sought if he finds such order is appropriate under the circumstances and if he finds it is in the best interest of the person or of the public to have such information disclosed. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 17, effective July 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was enacted in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7463</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>