<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.630</section_number><catch_line>Public records to be kept on equipment and infrastructure -- Accounts. </catch_line><order_by>630</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each soil and water conservation district which receives or uses the equipment referred to in KRS 262.610 shall maintain its public records to show for each piece of equipment: <section prefix="a">The hours same has worked on each job in each district; </section><section prefix="b">The amounts collected from each job in each district; </section><section prefix="c">The expense of repairing, moving, manning and other usual costs of operation; and </section><section prefix="d">The amount paid by each district for the purpose of amortizing the commission's investment in the equipment. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each soil and water conservation district which leases or otherwise obtains a right of use of the infrastructure with the support of the Division of Conservation pursuant to KRS 262.610 shall maintain in public records a copy of the lease or other contract which provides the district a right of use of the infrastructure; and <section prefix="a">In the case of a purchase, the amount paid by each district for the purpose of amortizing the commission's investment in the infrastructure; or </section><section prefix="b">In the case of lease without right of purchase or some other contractual arrangement or agreement, the payments made to the Division of Conservation for the right of use of the infrastructure. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each of the soil and water conservation districts shall send a duplicate copy of the records to the commission, who shall retain same in its files for public inspection. </section><section prefix="4">In addition thereto, the commission shall at all times maintain an account showing each piece of equipment, the title to which is vested in it, and any infrastructure, the title of which may be vested solely in the commission or jointly with the district, and the amount paid thereon by any soil and water conservation district, and the amount remaining to be amortized. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 65. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal numbering system in this statute, inserting paragraph designations [(a), (b), (c), and (d)] in place of subsection numbers [(1), (2), (3), and (4)] within subsection (1) of this section. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12773</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>