<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.5093</section_number><catch_line>Procedures to terminate assessment. </catch_line><order_by>5093</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The question of the levy of the assessment on small grains may be referred to a vote of the small grains producers of the state by filing petitions with the certified association containing signatures of Kentucky small grains producers equal in number to ten percent (10%) of all small grains producers in the state as recorded in the latest United States Census of Agriculture. If after the petitions are filed and at the referendum election a majority of Kentucky small grains producers voting on the question vote against the levy on small grains, the assessment shall be terminated at the end of the marketing year in which the referendum was conducted; otherwise, the assessment program shall continue. </section><section prefix="2">If the duly certified association of small grains producers expresses in writing its desire to the Commissioner to discontinue the assessment program and terminate the program, the Commissioner shall within fifteen (15) days following receipt of the request convene the board to review and act on the request. The board, after reviewing the request and conducting whatever proceedings are deemed appropriate and necessary in connection with the request, may terminate the program effective at the end of the marketing year in which the board action is taken; and, in this event, the Commissioner shall notify, by certified mail, the purchasers of small grains affected thereby of the termination of the program. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>