<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2">CITIZENSHIP, EMBLEMS, HOLIDAYS, AND TIME </unit></structure><section_number>2.240</section_number><catch_line>Organ Donor Awareness Week. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fourth week of April of each year is designated as Organ Donor Awareness Week, and the Governor shall annually issue a proclamation inviting and urging the people of the Commonwealth to be involved with appropriate activities. This observance is created to educate the citizens of the Commonwealth about the importance of organ donation. </section><section prefix="2">As part of Organ Donor Awareness Week, the Governor and the House of Representatives and the Senate of the General Assembly shall honor those persons who have donated organs and surviving family members with a ceremony in the Capitol rotunda. Each person who has donated an organ shall be recognized collectively by citation and, upon request, the person or the person's family shall be given a copy of the citation. The Governor may establish an organ donor honor board to collect the name of each person, subject to the person's consent, who donates an organ in the Commonwealth during the year, and to recognize medical professionals, educators, volunteers, public employees, and private organizations that are involved with the organ donation process. Nothing in this section shall be construed to require reporting of the name of any person involved with the organ donation process or to supersede patient confidentiality protections established by statute, the Board of Medical Licensure or other state entity, or the Federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. </section><section prefix="3">Education efforts are encouraged to focus on the importance of organ donation and its significance with saving the lives of Kentuckians. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services is encouraged to develop and circulate materials relating to organ donation. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 72, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=68</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>