<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.076</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 177.076 to 177.079. </catch_line><order_by>076</order_by><text>As used in KRS 177.076 to 177.079, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Historical site" means a cultural or educational site that is officially listed in the National Register of Historical Places; </section><section prefix="2">"Fully controlled access highway" means a limited access highway, an interstate highway, and a parkway; </section><section prefix="3">"Limited supplemental guide sign" means an official highway guide sign that is erected by the Department of Highways to give directions, furnish advance notice, show mileage or exit indicators, and indicate access to historical sites or to scenic, cultural, and recreational tourist areas or attractions and that conforms to the design standards and requirements set forth in the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD); </section><section prefix="4">"Post-interchange guide sign" means an official highway sign that may be used in conjunction with a limited supplemental guide sign and lists the name of a tourist area or attraction or an historical site and the distance from an interstate to a tourist area or attraction or an historical site. A post-interchange guide sign shall conform to the design standards and requirements set forth in the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD); </section><section prefix="5">"Rural area" means an area that does not have sufficient population to be designated as an urban area; </section><section prefix="6">"Tourist area or attraction" means a cultural, recreational, or entertainment facility, family entertainment center, or an area of natural phenomenon or scenic beauty that is suited for outdoor recreation that receives a major portion of its income or visitors during the normal business season from motorists not residing in the immediate area of the tourist area or attraction. "Tourist area or attraction" does not include any of the following: <section prefix="a">Lodging facilities; or </section><section prefix="b">Facilities that are primarily devoted to the retail sale of goods, unless the facilities are a family entertainment center or the goods are created by individuals at the tourist area or attraction or if the sale of goods is incidental to the tourist area or attraction; or </section><section prefix="c">Recreational facilities that do not serve as a likely destination where individuals who are not residents of the state would remain overnight in commercial lodging at or near the tourism area or attraction; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Family entertainment center" means a facility, other than a stand alone shopping center, that meets all of the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Contains a minimum of fifty thousand (50,000) square feet of building space; </section><section prefix="b">Is located on property encompassing at least five (5) acres adjacent or complementary to a cultural, recreational, or entertainment facility, or natural recreational area; </section><section prefix="c">Provides a variety of entertainment and leisure options; </section><section prefix="d">Contains at least one (1) restaurant and at least two (2) additional venues, including, but not limited to, live entertainment, concert halls, museums, zoos, or other cultural, recreational or leisure activities; and </section><section prefix="e">Is at a location where sixty percent (60%) of the developed property is devoted to entertainment and food options. </section></section><section prefix="8">"City" means an area with a population of one hundred thousand (100,000) or more designated by the United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5263</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>