<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.050</section_number><catch_line>Personnel Board -- Grandfather clause -- Composition -- Terms -- Automatic termination. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person serving on the board on July 15, 1982, shall serve until the expiration of his current term of office. Subsequent appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years from the date of expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, except that a person appointed to fill a vacancy prior to the expiration of such term shall be appointed in the same manner as provided in KRS 18A.045 and for the remainder of such term. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the expiration of the terms of office of the two (2) board members whose terms expire January 1, 1984, the Governor shall appoint two (2) members from a list of four (4) names submitted by the Legislative Research Commission. Thereafter, upon the expiration of these terms, such terms shall be filled in the same manner as provided in this subsection. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the expiration of the terms of office, of the members whose terms expire December 31, 1982, January 1, 1985, and January 1, 1986, the Governor shall appoint citizens at large who are not associated with state government in any manner. Thereafter upon the expiration of these terms, such terms shall be filled in the same manner as provided in this subsection. </section><section prefix="4">These five (5) appointments to the board shall be subject to confirmation by the Senate. If the Senate is not in session, these five (5) appointments shall be subject to review by the Interim Joint Committee on State Government which shall hold a public hearing and shall transmit its recommendations to the Senate. </section><section prefix="5">The initial election of classified employees to the board shall be held as provided in KRS 18A.0551. The two (2) classified employees initially elected to the board shall serve until July 1, 1986. Subsequent elections shall be for a term of four (4) years from the date of expiration of the term for which his predecessor was elected. If a vacancy occurs prior to the expiration of such term, the board shall fill the vacancy as provided in KRS 18A.060. </section><section prefix="6">If an elected board member accepts an unclassified position with state government, his membership on the board shall be terminated immediately and the vacancy shall be filled as provided in KRS 18A.060. </section><section prefix="7">If an elected board member accepts a classified position in a cabinet employing another board member or if, through no fault of his own, he is placed in that cabinet, his membership on the board shall not be terminated for the remainder of his term. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 5, effective April 13, 2010. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1349</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>