<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.134</section_number><catch_line>Investigation and prosecution of reports made pursuant to KRS 237.130 or 237.132 -- Annual report to Legislative Research Commission. </catch_line><order_by>134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a report is made to the Department of Kentucky State Police pursuant to KRS 237.130 or 237.132, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall notify the Commonwealth's attorney and the county attorney for the county in which the training was conducted of the report and shall cooperate with them in the investigation and prosecution of the case. </section><section prefix="2">When a report is made to a Commonwealth's or county attorney pursuant to KRS 237.130 or 237.132, the Commonwealth's or county attorney shall notify the Department of Kentucky State Police of the report and shall cooperate with them in the investigation and prosecution of the case. </section><section prefix="3">When a report is made to the Department of Criminal Justice Training alleging a violation of KRS 237.130 or 237.132, the department shall notify the Commonwealth's attorney and county attorney of the county in which the training took place and shall make a notification of the report to the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall make an annual report to the Legislative Research Commission, not later than December 31 of each year, detailing each notice received pursuant to this section detailing: <section prefix="a">The name of the firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor if that instructor trainer or instructor has been arrested or indicted as a result of the notification, otherwise the name shall be omitted; </section><section prefix="b">The precise allegation; </section><section prefix="c">Whether the allegation resulted in arrest or indictment; </section><section prefix="d">Whether the allegation resulted in a trial, and the results of that trial; and </section><section prefix="e">If the defendant was found guilty, the punishment imposed. </section></section><section prefix="5">In or appended to the report specified in subsection (4) of this section the Department of Kentucky State Police shall report the number of arrests, indictments, trials, convictions, cases which were dismissed, and cases in which the defendant was found not guilty for failure to report nonreceipt of training and failure to report insufficient training. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 269, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11141</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>