<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.027</section_number><catch_line>Meetings of commission -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>027</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall meet at least every six (6) months and when called into session by the chairman at the request of the Governor, of any two (2) or more members of the commission, or on his own motion. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall examine the Executive Mansion, the Old Governor's Mansion, the Vest Lindsey House, and the New State Capitol at least once each year, and the commission shall have authority over any construction, repairs, structural restoration, or renovation of these properties. The commission shall supervise the maintenance of a current inventory of all furnishings in the properties and the inventory shall be maintained by the Division of Historic Properties in the Department for Facilities and Support Services in the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The Division of Historic Properties shall maintain inventory records relating to all such property of the state and no such property shall be disposed of except upon recommendation of the director of the Division of Historic Properties with advice of the Historic Properties Advisory Commission. The proceeds realized from the sale of any items shall be deposited in the historic properties endowment fund, established by KRS 11.026, except that the proceeds realized from the sale of any items derived from, or related to, the Vest Lindsey House shall be deposited in the separate and distinct Ida Lee Willis-Vest Lindsey House endowment trust fund, established by KRS 11.026(8). </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall recommend, from time to time, on the needs for furnishings, maintenance, repair, or renovation of the Executive Mansion, the Old Governor's Mansion, the Vest Lindsey House, and the New State Capitol; and the Department for Facilities and Support Services in the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall, from funds available, take the action recommended. The commission shall have final authority over articles placed in the properties and moneys spent on these buildings, except that the Kentucky Heritage Council shall have final authority over any moneys spent from the Ida Lee Willis-Vest Lindsey House endowment trust fund. The commission shall develop criteria for this display of objects on and for the use of the public areas of the basement and first and second floors of the New State Capitol and shall be consulted by the director of the Division of Historic Properties before objects are accepted for or removed from permanent display in the Capitol. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall provide coordination and make arrangements for an orderly transition between outgoing and incoming chief executives. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 27, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=527</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>