<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.465</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 45A.470. </catch_line><order_by>465</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45A.470, the words: <section prefix="1">"Other individuals with severe disabilities" means an individual or class of individuals with a disability, other than blindness, that constitutes an obstacle to new or continued normal employment. </section><section prefix="2">"Products" means programs, books, tapes, records, processes, packaging, modification, supplies, food, clothing, materials, commodities, equipment of all kinds, and any other article of commerce originally manufactured or assembled or purchased for resale by a qualified nonprofit agency. </section><section prefix="3">"Qualified nonprofit agency for individuals with severe disabilities" means an organization that: <section prefix="a">Is organized and operated in the interest of individuals with severe disabilities; and </section><section prefix="b">Complies with any applicable occupational health and safety law of the United States and the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="c">In the manufacture or provision of products or services listed or purchased under KRS 45A.470, during the fiscal year employs individuals with severe disabilities for not less than seventy-five percent (75%) of the man hours of direct labor required for the manufacture or provision of the products or services; and </section><section prefix="d">Is registered and in good standing as a nonprofit organization with the Secretary of State. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Services" means contractual services; rental services of all kinds; professional, technical, or artistic services; and other personal performance of work by officers, employees, or beneficiaries of a nonprofit agency. </section><section prefix="5">"State agency" means those spending agencies subject to the state purchasing requirements of this code and any regulations promulgated pursuant thereto. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 30, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>