<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.30-050</section_number><catch_line>Revocation and suspension of licenses. </catch_line><order_by>30-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may revoke or suspend the license of any premium finance company when and if, after investigation, it appears to the commissioner that: <section prefix="a">Any license issued to the company was obtained by fraud; </section><section prefix="b">There was any misrepresentation in the application for the license; </section><section prefix="c">The holder of the license has otherwise shown himself or herself untrustworthy or incompetent to act as a premium finance company; </section><section prefix="d">The company has violated any of the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="e">The company has been rebating part of the service charge as allowed and permitted by KRS 304.30-090 to any insurance agent or any employee of an insurance agent or to any other person as an inducement to the financing of any insurance policy with the premium finance company. </section></section><section prefix="2">Before the commissioner shall revoke, suspend, or refuse to renew the license of any premium finance company, he or she shall give to the person an opportunity for a hearing to be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. In lieu of or in addition to revoking or suspending the license for any of the causes enumerated in the section, after hearing as provided in this subsection, the commissioner may subject the company to a penalty specified in Subtitle 99 of this chapter when the commissioner determines that the public interest would not be harmed by the continued operation of the company. The amount of any penalty shall be paid by the company through the department of the commissioner to the State Treasurer. </section><section prefix="3">If any applicant or licensee is aggrieved by any final order of the commissioner, the applicant or licensee shall have the right to appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1410, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 241, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 30, sec. 5, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29749</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>