<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.1-705</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Peace Corps Governing Board. </catch_line><order_by>1-705</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be created by KRS 154.1-700 to 154.1-745 the Kentucky Peace Corps Governing Board consisting of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor to staggered terms not to exceed four (4) years. Three (3) of these appointees shall be from 501c charitable corporations; one (1) shall represent local government; one (1) shall represent labor; one (1) shall represent the business community; and three (3) shall be employed by state agencies performing work related to the corps' purposes. </section><section prefix="2">At least one (1) member of the board appointed pursuant to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be from each congressional district. No more than two (2) members shall be from the same congressional district. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall annually elect one (1) of its members chairman and one (1) of its members vice chairman. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall meet at such time and place as shall be specified by the call of its chairman. At least one (1) meeting shall be held each month. </section><section prefix="5">All meetings of the board shall be open to the public as provided in KRS 61.810 to 61.850. </section><section prefix="6">At least seven (7) days in advance of each regular meeting of the board, notice shall be given in writing to each member by the director, which shall include, at the least, a tentative agenda. Five (5) members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The board shall keep records and minutes of its business and official actions. </section><section prefix="7">All records of the board shall be public records and open to public inspection as provided in KRS 61.872 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="8">Board members shall not receive any compensation for their services, but may be reimbursed in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 44 and 45 and KRS 18A.200 for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties as prescribed by KRS 154.1-710 and 154.1-715. </section></text><history> Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification>KRS 154.01-705. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>