<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.170</section_number><catch_line>Release of prisoner -- Parties to be notified -- Means of providing notice -- Posting of notice received by law enforcement officers. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The wardens of the state penitentiaries upon the release of any prisoner or inmate from confinement shall immediately notify: <section prefix="1">The Circuit Court, the Commonwealth's attorney of the district, and the sheriff of the county where the inmate was sentenced; </section><section prefix="2">The Circuit Court, the Commonwealth's attorney of the district, the county attorney and sheriff of the county, and the chief of police of the city and county, to which the inmate is released; and </section><section prefix="3">Any victim, as defined in KRS 421.500, who has requested that he or she be notified on release of a particular inmate who victimized him or her and who has forwarded a current address and telephone number to the Department of Corrections. </section></section><section prefix="b">The notice shall give the residence of the person released and the name of the person to whom he or she was released. The provisions of KRS Chapter 202A notwithstanding, the Department of Corrections may release to the public the information that a petition to involuntarily hospitalize a prisoner has been filed concerning any inmate who is scheduled to be released from custody. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notice under subsection (1) of this section shall be given by mail, fax, or electronic means at the discretion of the Department of Corrections in a manner to insure receipt. </section><section prefix="3">Notices received by sheriffs and chiefs of police shall be posted in a conspicuous location where personnel employed by the department may see it. Notices posted under this subsection shall remain posted for not less than seven (7) days. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, secs. 96 and 121, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3827-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6885</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>