<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.632</section_number><catch_line>Department to require audit. </catch_line><order_by>632</order_by><text>It shall be the duty of the department, upon written request of the commission: <section prefix="1">To cause the certified public accountant auditing the district to audit the financial records relating to any identified and described bond issue of the commission, as an incident to the certified public accountant's next ensuing annual audit of such board of education, and each subsequent annual audit; and to provide a statement or report to the commission. </section><section prefix="2">Upon receiving a notification and request from the commission to ascertain whether the lease of the board of education has been renewed and is in force in accordance with its terms, and if the same is ascertained to be in force; to withhold from the board of education a sufficient portion of any undisbursed funds then held or set aside or allocated by the department for the board of education, and to comply with the terms of the notification and request of the commission for the account of said board of education. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 388, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 34, effective October 18, 1985. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 28, (3) at 623. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>