<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="5" order_by="5">LEGISLATIVE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>5.010</section_number><catch_line>Explanation of sources -- Official maps. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>For the purpose of this chapter: <section prefix="1">The boundaries of the legislative districts created by this chapter shall be those shown on the maps generated by the Legislative Research Commission's geographic information system to accompany a redistricting plan enacted into law. The official copies of these maps shall be on file with the State Board of Elections. A duplicate set of maps and associated population information shall be retained by the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Designated precincts are those precincts in existence on July 15, 2010. Precinct boundaries shown in the maps referred to in subsection (1) of this section are taken from county precinct maps and verified and corrected by the Legislative Research Commission staff in consultation with county election officials. </section><section prefix="b">Census tracts and blocks shown in the maps referred to in subsection (1) of this section are those utilized for the making of the 2010 United States Census. </section><section prefix="c">Population data utilized for redistricting is the 2010 United States Census Pub. L. 94-171 population data that was deemed to be official by the United States Secretary of Commerce on or before July 15, 2011, and election precinct population data prepared by the Legislative Research Commission staff from the official Pub. L. 94-171 population data. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 139, effective August 23, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 146, effective January 31, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 101, effective January 11, 1996; and ch. 2, sec. 39, effective January 11, 1996. -- Amended 1995 (3d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 39, effective November 3, 1995. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1993. -- Created 1991 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 40, effective January 8, 1992; and ch. 5, sec. 102, effective January 8, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> August 23, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42891</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>