<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.755Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission.   </catch_line><order_by>755Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Commonwealth of Kentucky War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission, which shall be attached to the Kentucky Historical Society for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The Commonwealth of Kentucky War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission shall be composed of eighteen (18) members, as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members of the Kentucky House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members of the Kentucky Senate, appointed by the President of the Kentucky Senate; </section><section prefix="c">The adjutant general or the adjutant general's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="e">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) members from the Kentucky Historical Society, appointed by the executive director of that agency; </section><section prefix="g">Three (3) members from the Kentucky Heritage Council, appointed by the executive director of that agency, including at least one (1) member each from the Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission and the Kentucky Native American Heritage Commission; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) member from the Kentucky Humanities Council, appointed by the executive director of that agency; and </section><section prefix="i">Five (5) citizen members from the state at large with a demonstrated interest in history and substantial knowledge and appreciation of the War of 1812, appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="3">The chair of the commission shall be elected by the members of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">The first meeting of the commission shall be held no later than July 31, 2010. </section><section prefix="5">The commission may create an advisory board of persons with a demonstrated interest in various aspects of the War of 1812. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the commission shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="7">The Commonwealth of Kentucky War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission shall expire on January 31, 2015. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44496</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>