<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.220</section_number><catch_line>Nature of partner's liability. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, all partners shall be liable: <section prefix="a">Jointly and severally for everything chargeable to the partnership under KRS 362.210 and 362.215; and </section><section prefix="b">Jointly for all other debts and obligations of the partnership; but any partner may enter into a separate obligation to perform a partnership contract. </section></section><section prefix="2">Subject to subsection (3) of this section and subject to any agreement among the partners, a partner in a registered limited liability partnership shall not be liable directly or indirectly, including by way of indemnification, contribution, assessment or otherwise, for debts, obligations, and liabilities of or chargeable to the partnership, whether arising in tort, contract, or otherwise, arising from negligence, malpractice, wrongful acts, or misconduct committed while the partnership is a registered limited liability partnership and in the course of the partnership business by another partner or an employee, agent, or representative of the partnership. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (2) of this section shall not affect the liability of a partner in a registered limited liability partnership for his own negligence, wrongful acts, or misconduct. </section></text><history> Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 97, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 15, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34303</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>