<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.210</section_number><catch_line>Viewers' final report -- Notice -- Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>When the final report of the viewers is completed and filed, it shall be examined by the county judge/executive, and if it is found to be legal and in due form it shall be accepted, and if not it may be referred back to the viewers with instructions to secure further information, to be reported at a subsequent date fixed by the county judge/executive. The chief engineer shall examine the report, and may recommend any changes in the plan of drainage for final adoption by the board. Such changes, when adopted, shall become a part of the plan. When the report is completed and accepted by the county judge/executive, with any changes in the plan adopted by the board, a date not less than twenty (20) days thereafter shall be fixed by the county judge/executive for the final hearing upon the report, and notice shall be given by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, and by posting a notice on the door of the courthouse in each county in which land affected is assessed, and at five (5) conspicuous places throughout the district. During this time a copy of the report shall be on file in the office of the county clerk in which the proceeding is pending, and shall be open to the inspection of any landowner or person interested within the district. </text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 406, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 182. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380-15. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12885</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>