<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.5279</section_number><catch_line>Repeal of training incentive program for city officers -- Designation of incentive payments relative to retirement and compensation -- Alternate incentives for continuing education and training. </catch_line><order_by>5279</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A city may, by ordinance, elect to repeal the training incentive program. </section><section prefix="2">The training incentive payments provided under KRS 64.5278 shall not be included in the calculation for a retirement allowance for any city officer participating in the County Employees Retirement System set out in KRS 78.510 to 78.852. </section><section prefix="3">Training incentive payments provided under KRS 64.5278 shall not be considered compensation and shall not be required to be included in the ordinance establishing the compensation of elected city officers under KRS 67C.129, 67C.131, 83A.070, or when applicable, KRS 64.610. </section><section prefix="4">Training incentive payments provided under KRS 64.5278 shall not be a factor in setting elected city officers' maximum compensation under KRS 83A.075(2). </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 64.5277 to 64.5279 shall be construed to prohibit a city from enacting or establishing alternative incentives for the continuing education and training of its elected officers or employees. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.44, sec.3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>