<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.8941Monetary</section_number><catch_line>incentives for child-care facilities -- Professional development.   </catch_line><order_by>8941Monetary</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Early Childhood Advisory Council shall, by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A, establish a program of monetary incentives including but not limited to an increased child-care subsidy and a one-time merit achievement award for child-care centers and certified family child-care homes that are tied to a quality rating system for child care as established under KRS 199.8943. </section><section prefix="2">The monetary incentive program shall be reviewed annually by the council for the purpose of determining future opportunities to provide incentives. </section><section prefix="3">Participation in the program of monetary incentives and in the quality rating system by public-funded child-care centers and certified family child-care homes is mandatory. </section><section prefix="4">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall encourage the professional development of persons who are employed or provide training in a child-care or early childhood setting by facilitating their participation in the scholarship program for obtaining a child development associate credential, postsecondary certificate, diploma, degree, or specialty credential as established under KRS 164.518. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 194, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44070</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>