<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.870</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations and records. </catch_line><order_by>870</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board, with any committee assistance requested by the board, may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of KRS 311.864 to 311.890 as follows: <section prefix="a">Establish qualifications for a surgical assistant to practice in this state; </section><section prefix="b">Establish requirements for an examination and develop an application to certify a surgical assistant to practice; </section><section prefix="c">Establish minimum education and training requirements necessary for a certificate to practice as a surgical assistant; </section><section prefix="d">Develop an approved program of mandatory continuing education and the manner in which attendance at all approved courses, clinics, forums, lectures, programs, or seminars is monitored and recorded; </section><section prefix="e">Accept the continuing education rules and guidelines of the Association of Surgical Technologists or other national association of surgical assisting that develops continuing education guidelines; </section><section prefix="f">Establish reasonable and necessary fees for the application, examination, initial certificate, renewal certificate, and other fees necessary to implement KRS 311.864 to 311.890; and </section><section prefix="g">Identify the surgical assistant's scope of practice citing appropriate medical tasks, and define the delegating physician's oversight responsibilities. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall maintain a record for each certificate holder that contains information determined by the board. Any certificate holder who, after notifying the board of his or her official address or addresses, moves his or her practice location to a new address shall immediately notify the board of the change. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30663</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>