<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="62" order_by="62">OATHS AND BONDS </unit></structure><section_number>62.055</section_number><catch_line>Bonds of county clerks -- Minimum -- Record.   </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every county clerk, before entering on the duties of his office, shall execute bond to the Commonwealth, with corporate surety authorized and qualified to become surety on bonds in this state. Any county clerk holding office as of January 1, 1978, who has not executed bond as provided herein shall do so within thirty (30) days from February 9, 1978. </section><section prefix="2">In counties containing a consolidated local government or a city of the first class, the amount of the county clerk's bond shall be at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). In counties containing an urban-county form of government, the amount of county clerk's bond shall be at least four hundred thousand dollars ($400,000). In counties containing a city of the home rule class but not a city of the first class, a consolidated local government, or an urban-county form of government, the amount of the county clerk's bond shall be at least one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000). </section><section prefix="3">The bond of the county clerk shall be examined and approved by the fiscal court, which shall record the approval in its minutes. The fiscal court shall record the bond in the county clerk's records and a copy of the bond shall be transmitted within one (1) month to the Department of Revenue, where it shall be recorded and preserved. Except in those counties where the fees of the county clerk are paid into the State Treasury, the premium on the county clerk's bond shall be paid by the county. </section><section prefix="4">Where circumstances in a particular county indicate that the amount of the bond may not be sufficient, the Department of Revenue may request the fiscal court to increase the bond as provided in KRS 62.060. The fiscal court shall then require a bond of sufficient amount to safeguard the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 27, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 88, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective February 9, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>