<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.430</section_number><catch_line>Percentage reduction in allotments in case of insufficient appropriation by General Assembly. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text>If, when the apportionments are being determined under the provisions of KRS 157.310 to 157.440, funds appropriated by the General Assembly to the public school fund are insufficient to provide the amount of money required under KRS 157.390, the chief state school officer, unless otherwise provided by the General Assembly in a budget bill, shall make a percentage reduction in the allotments to reduce the total of these allotments to funds available. </text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. III, sec. 101, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 32, effective July 1, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 18, effective June 30, 1976 -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 9. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 106, secs. 7 and 8. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 13.</former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 157.430.</former-history-former-name><lrc-note>.  By reason of the amendment of KRS 157.390 by Acts 1985 (Ex. Sess.), ch. 10, รยง 6, a technical correction has been made in the reference to that section by the Reviser of Statutes, pursuant to KRS 7.136. Former KRS 157.430 (Enact. Acts 1954, ch. 214, sec. 13; 1956, ch. 106, secs. 7, 8; 1960, ch. 145, sec. 9; 1964, ch. 171, sec. 1) was repealed by Acts 1974, ch. 363, sec. 18, effective June 30, 1976. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3328</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>