<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.10-160</section_number><catch_line>Records of broker. </catch_line><order_by>10-160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each broker shall keep in his or her office a full and true record of each surplus lines coverage procured by him or her, including a copy of each daily report, if any, a copy of each certificate of insurance issued by him or her, and of the following items as may be applicable: <section prefix="a">Amount of the insurance; </section><section prefix="b">Gross premium charged; </section><section prefix="c">Return premium paid, if any; </section><section prefix="d">Rate of premium charged upon the several items of property; </section><section prefix="e">Effective date of the contract, and the terms thereof; </section><section prefix="f">Name and address of each insurer on the direct risk and the proportion of the entire risk assumed by the insurer if less than the entire risk; </section><section prefix="g">Name and address of the insured; </section><section prefix="h">Brief general description of the property or risk insured and where located or to be performed; and </section><section prefix="i">Other information as may be required by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">The record shall be open to examination by the commissioner at all times within five (5) years after issuance of the coverage to which it relates. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1097, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 44, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 10, sec. 16, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>