<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.5278</section_number><catch_line>Ordinance establishing incentive program for city officers to obtain educational training -- Training incentive payments -- Continuing education hours required -- Proof of attendance and evaluation of courses. </catch_line><order_by>5278</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city may elect, by adopting an ordinance meeting the requirements of this section, to establish an incentive program for city officers to obtain educational training related to their duties and responsibilities as city officers and the functions of city governments. </section><section prefix="2">The ordinance shall apply to all elected city officers within the city, and the city may allow any nonelected city officer holding an office existing or created under KRS 83A.080 to participate in the incentive program. </section><section prefix="3">The ordinance shall designate a base training incentive payment amount that shall be awarded to the city officer for the completion of a training unit during service as a city officer within the city. This base incentive payment amount shall be no less than one hundred dollars ($100) and no more than five hundred dollars ($500). The training incentive payment amount established in the ordinance shall not be adjusted by any index reporting changes to consumer prices or any other method to account for inflation. </section><section prefix="4">The ordinance shall require city officers to complete a number of continuing education hours equal to at least one (1) training unit during each calendar year in order to receive a training incentive payment. </section><section prefix="5">The ordinance shall state that the city shall award the training incentive payment to the city officer for the completion of a training unit during the calendar year. The training incentive payment awarded shall be the base training incentive payment multiplied by the training incentive multiplier earned by the city officer. The city officer shall accumulate no more than one (1) training incentive multiplier per calendar year of continuous service, for a maximum of four (4) training incentive multipliers. </section><section prefix="6">The ordinance shall provide that a city officer who fails to earn at least one (1) training unit in any calendar year shall receive no training incentive payment for that calendar year and shall have his or her training incentive multiplier reset to one (1) for the following year. </section><section prefix="7">The ordinance may permit the city officer to carry forward no more than fifteen (15) hours of excess credit hours earned in one (1) calendar year to apply to the minimum fifteen (15) hours training unit required in the next calendar year. "Excess hours" means credit hours earned beyond fifteen (15) during a single calendar year. </section><section prefix="8">The ordinance shall require the city officer to present proof of his or her completion of the annual training unit and shall establish the time that the city officers shall receive their training incentive payments. </section><section prefix="9">Each city shall, in the ordinance establishing the city officers training program, establish a policy regarding the reimbursement to the city officer, or payment to the provider for the city officer's attendance of an event hosting a course where the officer seeks to earn credit. </section><section prefix="10">The ordinance shall specify criteria for the presentation of proof of attendance by city officers and the criteria for the evaluation of a course's relevance to the duties and functions of city officers and the functions of city governments. In addition to other courses that may be deemed relevant by the city, courses that provide instruction on statutory powers and duties of cities and city officers, intergovernmental relationships, municipal finance and budgeting, municipal taxation, ethics, open records, open meetings, economic development, or municipal police powers shall satisfy the criteria established in the ordinance. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.44, sec.2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>