<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.881</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of safety and security officers. </catch_line><order_by>881</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Safety and security officers so appointed shall be peace officers and conservators of the peace. They shall have general police powers to arrest, without process, all persons who within their view commit any crime or misdemeanor. They shall possess all of the common law and statutory powers, privileges, and immunities of sheriffs, except that they shall be empowered to serve civil process to the extent authorized by the employing airport board. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, such safety and security officers are hereby specifically authorized and empowered, and it shall be their duty: <section prefix="a">To preserve the peace, maintain order and prevent unlawful use of force or violence or other unlawful conduct on the airport facility of their respective airport board, and to protect all persons and property located thereon from injury, harm and damage; </section><section prefix="b">To enforce, and to assist officials of their respective airport boards in the enforcement of the lawful rules and regulations of said airport board, and to assist and cooperate with the law enforcement agencies and officers. </section></section> Provided, however, that such safety and security officers shall exercise the powers herein granted upon any real property owned or occupied by their respective airport boards including the streets passing through and adjacent thereto. Said powers may be exercised in any county of the Commonwealth where the airport board owns, uses, or occupies property. Additional jurisdiction may be established by agreement with the chief of police of the municipality or sheriff of the county or the appropriate law enforcement agency in which such property is located, dependent upon the jurisdiction involved. <section prefix="2">Safety and security officers may exercise their powers away from the locations described in subsection (1) of this section only upon the following conditions: <section prefix="a">When in hot pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law; </section><section prefix="b">When authorized to do so pursuant to the agreement authorized by subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">When requested to act by the chief of police of the city or county in which the airport board's property is located; </section><section prefix="d">When requested to act by the sheriff of the county in which the airport board's property is located; </section><section prefix="e">When requested to act by the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="f">When requested to act by the authorized delegates of those persons or agencies listed in paragraph (c), (d) or (e) above; </section><section prefix="g">When requested to assist a state, county, or municipal police officer, sheriff, or other peace officer in the performance of his or her lawful duties; or </section><section prefix="h">When operating under an interlocal cooperation agreement pursuant to KRS Chapter 65. </section></section><section prefix="3">Safety and security officers appointed pursuant to KRS 183.110 and 183.880 to 183.886 shall have, in addition to the other powers enumerated herein, the power to conduct investigations anywhere in this Commonwealth, provided such investigation relates to criminal offenses which occurred on property owned, leased, or controlled by the airport board. Where desirable and at the discretion of the airport board's police officials, the airport board's safety and security department may coordinate said investigations with any law enforcement agency of this Commonwealth or with agencies of the federal government. </section><section prefix="4">Safety and security departments created and operated by the airport boards shall, for all purposes, be deemed public police departments and the sworn safety and security officers thereof are, for all purposes, deemed public police officers. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 183.110 and 183.880 to 183.886 shall be construed as a diminution or modification of the authority or responsibility of any city or county police department, the Department of Kentucky State Police, sheriff, constable, or other peace officer either on the property of an airport board or otherwise. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 187, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>