<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.610</section_number><catch_line>Legislative intent -- Additional and alternative nature. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 441.625 to 441.695 is intended solely to provide an additional and alternative method of constructing, reconstructing, improving, or repairing and financing jails and appurtenant facilities for any local government in this state to the end that such projects expedite the provision of safe and proper facilities by a local government for the incarceration of prisoners as defined by KRS 441.005. Nothing in KRS 441.625 to 441.695 shall be construed as prohibiting a local government from providing for the construction, reconstruction, improvement, or repair and financing of a jail and appurtenant facilities as may be otherwise provided by law. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 441.625 to 441.695 shall be construed as prohibiting two (2) or more local governments from entering into a cooperative agreement for the purpose of participating with the authority in providing for the construction, reconstruction, improvement, or repair and financing of a jail and appurtenant facilities for the use and benefit of all local governments agreeing to the cooperative undertaking, but the authority shall determine the number and location of regional jails and regional detention centers, as authorized by KRS 441.625. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (2) of this section is intended solely as an alternative method to KRS 65.210 to 65.300. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 5, c, (2) at 651. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>