<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="68" order_by="68">COUNTY FINANCE AND COUNTY TREASURER </unit></structure><section_number>68.530</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal court resolution and order designating submission of proposals to voters -- Election -- Framing of questions. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event the fiscal court of any county determines that the public interest requires the establishment of one or more public service programs and that existing county revenues are inadequate to reasonably provide for such programs, the fiscal court may by resolution and order determine that one or more questions for the establishment of any such public service program shall be submitted to the electorate of such county. Such resolution and order shall designate with specificity each public service program to be submitted, together with the proposed source of funding therefor, which shall be either an ad valorem tax levy of a certain maximum number of cents per each one hundred dollars ($100) of assessed valuation subject to constitutional limits, or an occupational license tax subject to the limitations of KRS 68.520 to 68.550. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall, following adoption of the resolution and order identified in subsection (1) of this section, cause to be prepared a question for submission to the voters of the county at an election held pursuant to notice as prescribed in KRS 424.130. Said election shall be held in conjunction with a regularly scheduled November election, as provided by law. The question as it will appear on the ballot shall be filed with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the regular election. The question shall be so framed that any voter who wishes to vote for the public service program or any individual public service program if there be more than one, may signify his approval by voting "Yes," and any voter who wishes to vote against the public service program or any individual public service program so submitted may do so by voting "No." </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24111</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>