<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.108</section_number><catch_line>Membership of Transportation and Tourism Interagency Committee -- Compensation -- Officers -- Meetings -- Proxy voting. </catch_line><order_by>108</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation and Tourism Interagency Committee shall be composed of thirteen (13) members or their official appointed designees, as follows: <section prefix="a">Six (6) members appointed by the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Six (6) members appointed by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member appointed by the executive director of the Kentucky Heritage Council. </section></section><section prefix="2">Committee members shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for all reasonable expenses necessarily incurred in connection with the performance of their duties and functions as committee members. </section><section prefix="3">The committee shall elect its chair and vice chair from representatives of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage and Transportation Cabinets for a term of one (1) year. The vice chair shall succeed the chair. The chair shall alternately be a representative of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage and Transportation Cabinets. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall meet upon the call of the chair and upon the request of the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="5">A committee member may appoint a proxy for an individual meeting, delegating to the proxy the privilege of voting on any issue. The proxy appointment shall be in writing. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 55, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 41, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5282</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>