<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.410</section_number><catch_line>Units for personal or farm use excluded -- Exclusions for parks, festivals, and publicly announced events lasting less than 30 days -- Standards for installation.   </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in KRS 219.310 to 219.410 shall be construed to include manufactured homes, mobile homes, or recreational vehicles maintained by any persons on their own premises and used exclusively to house their own farm labor. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Nothing in KRS 219.310 to 219.410 shall be construed to apply to manufactured home parks, mobile home parks, or recreational vehicle parks owned and operated on a temporary or seasonal basis by a city, county, charter county, urban-county, or consolidated local government or its agencies. </section><section prefix="b">Nothing in KRS 219.310 to 219.410 shall be construed to apply to festivals lasting not more than thirty (30) days that are organized and operated by a city, county, charter county, urban-county, or consolidated local government or its agencies. </section><section prefix="c">Nothing in KRS 219.310 to 219.410 shall be construed to apply to the temporary parking of recreational vehicles on public or private property, for not more than thirty (30) days, associated with festivals, fairs, sporting events, yard sales, or other publicly announced events. </section></section><section prefix="3">All installations of manufactured homes and mobile homes shall be performed by an installer certified under the provisions of KRS 227.560 in accordance with the manufacturer's instructions, if available, or ANSI 225.1 Manufactured Home Installations. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(22). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012).The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered subsection (2)(d) of this statute as subsection (3) of this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40223</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>