<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">A RESPIRATORY CARE PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>314A.200</section_number><catch_line>Board of Respiratory Care. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Board of Respiratory Care which shall consist of seven (7) voting members appointed by the Governor. <section prefix="a">Four (4) members shall be respiratory care practitioners holding a valid mandatory certificate and practicing in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members shall be pulmonologists who are licensed and practicing physicians in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in respiratory care. </section></section><section prefix="2">Members shall be appointed to the board for terms of three (3) years, expiring on October 30 of the third year. No person shall be appointed to serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="3">By May 30 of years in which respiratory care practitioner terms expire, the Kentucky Society for Respiratory Care shall submit to the Governor a list of names of candidates qualified for the appointment of respiratory care practitioner, in numbers not less than twice the numbers of appointments to be made, from which the Governor shall make each appointment or appointments by October 31 of that year. The Governor shall also appoint the pulmonologist and citizen at-large members by October 31 of any year in which a term expires. </section><section prefix="4">A vacancy on the board shall be filled by the Governor as provided under subsection (1) of this section. The appointment shall be for the remaining portion of the member's term. </section><section prefix="5">The Governor or board may remove a member from the board for cause or as provided under administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall reorganize annually and select a chairperson. Four (4) voting members of the board shall constitute a quorum to do business. The board shall hold at least one (1) regular meeting each year. Additional meetings may be held upon the call of the chairperson or at the written request of any two (2) members of the board. All meetings of the board shall be open and public to the extent permitted by law. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30979</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>