<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.170</section_number><catch_line>Reports of licensee -- Alcohol and substance abuse reports.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All reports of any facility licensed pursuant to this chapter shall be made to the director. The licensee of each commercial coal mine shall give at the end of each calendar year accurate information, on blank forms furnished by the commissioner, as to the number of accidents that have occurred, the number of persons employed, the tons of coal mined, and any other related information that the commissioner requests. </section><section prefix="2">The operator or superintendent of each licensed facility shall report, by the close of the next business day, any certified persons who: <section prefix="a">Have been discharged for violation of a company's substance or alcohol abuse policies; </section><section prefix="b">Refused to submit to a test required by the company's substance or alcohol abuse policies or KRS 351.182, 351.183, 351.184, 351.185, and 352.180; or </section><section prefix="c">Tested positive and failed to complete an employee assistance program. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 19, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 15, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 14. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 12, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739-12, 2739-13. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44536</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>