<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.270</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against local regulation of fertilizer and pesticides for agriculture and silviculture. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby determines that the citizens of the state benefit from a system of safe, effective, and scientifically sound fertilizer and pesticide regulation on agricultural and silvicultural land. The Commonwealth further finds that a system of fertilizer and pesticide regulation which is consistent, coordinated, and comports with both federal and state technical expertise is essential to the public health, safety, and welfare, and that local regulation of fertilizer and pesticides does not materially assist in achieving these benefits. </section><section prefix="2">No city, town, county, or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth shall adopt or continue in effect any ordinance, resolution, rule, or regulation regarding agriculture and silviculture fertilizer regulated pursuant to KRS 250.371 and pesticide sale or use, including without limitation: registration, notification of use, advertising and marketing distribution, applicator training and certification, storage, transportation, disposal, disclosure of confidential information, or product composition. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed to: <section prefix="a">Abrogate any authority afforded by the state statutes to any program cabinet established under KRS Chapter 12 or any state or federal mandated hazardous materials regulations or fire safety codes and comprehensive hazardous materials management program; </section><section prefix="b">Abrogate the planning and zoning authority granted local government pursuant to KRS Chapter 100; or </section><section prefix="c">Waive any reporting requirement established by state or federal law or regulation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9558</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>