<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.562</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors -- Appointment -- Terms -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>562</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall be governed by a board of directors consisting of thirteen (13) members as follows: <section prefix="a">Secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">Secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">Secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="d">Secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) members appointed by the Governor, one (1) to be a representative of the Kentucky Arts Council, and two (2) to be at-large members; and </section><section prefix="f">Six (6) members appointed by the mayor of the city of Berea to include two </section></section><section prefix="2">representatives of Berea city government, two (2) representatives of Berea <section prefix="a">One (1) appointment by the Governor and two (2) appointments by the mayor </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) appointments by the mayor of the city of Berea and one (1) </section><section prefix="c">One (1) appointment by the Governor and one (1) appointment by the mayor </section><section prefix="d">One (1) appointment by the mayor of the city of Berea shall serve a term of </section></section>College recommended by the president of Berea College, one (1) representative of Eastern Kentucky University recommended by the president of Eastern Kentucky University, and one (1) at-large member. (2) Members shall serve for staggered terms of four (4) years beginning August 1, 2000, except that of the initial appointments: of the city of Berea shall each serve a term of four (4) years; appointment by the Governor shall each serve a term of three (3) years; of the city of Berea shall each serve a term of two (2) years; and one (1) year. <section prefix="3">The Governor shall appoint a chair from among the members of the board. </section><section prefix="4">A quorum of the board shall consist of seven (7) members, with a majority of members present authorized to act upon any matter legally before the authority. </section><section prefix="5">A member may be removed by the appointing authority only for neglect of duty, misfeasance, or malfeasance, and after being afforded an opportunity for a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, relating to administrative hearings. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 21, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 20, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  This section was amended by 2009 Ky. Acts chs. 11 and 16, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>