<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.556</section_number><catch_line>Membership of board -- Chair -- Terms -- Committees.   </catch_line><order_by>556</order_by><text>The board shall consist of the members named in subsections (1) and (2) of this section: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The program administrator of the Sex Offender Treatment Program created pursuant to KRS 197.400; and </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, or the commissioner's designee. </section></section><section prefix="2">The following members, appointed by the Governor: <section prefix="a">One (1) probation and parole officer; </section><section prefix="b">Four (4) mental health professionals licensed or certified pursuant to KRS Chapter 309, 311, 314, 319, or 335 who demonstrated expertise in working with sex offenders; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) professional working in an agency which provides services to adult or child victims of sex offenses; and </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative of an advocacy group with a demonstrated interest in the welfare of victims of sex offenses. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Governor shall appoint the first chair of the board who shall serve for a term of two (2) years after which the chair shall be elected by the members of the board. </section><section prefix="4">The probation and parole officer and the members identified in subsection (2) of this section shall serve for the remainder of the term of office of the Governor during whose incumbency they were appointed, unless removed sooner for cause, but they shall remain on the board until their successors are appointed or until they are reappointed. </section><section prefix="5">No member appointed pursuant to subsection (4) of this section may be represented by a designee. </section><section prefix="6">No member appointed pursuant to subsection (4) of this section shall serve more than four (4) years unless reappointed. </section><section prefix="7">All members identified under subsection (1) of this section shall serve during their terms of office. </section><section prefix="8">All members of the board shall be reimbursed for their necessary travel and other expenses actually incurred in the discharge of their duties on the board. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall be empowered to create committees for the purpose of carrying out its statutory duties. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall be attached to the Department of Corrections for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 143, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40742</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>