<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.853</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings -- Qualifications for incentives -- Incentives available. </catch_line><order_by>853</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds and declares that: <section prefix="a">The general welfare and material well-being of the citizens of the Commonwealth depend in large measure upon the development of tourism in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">It is in the best interest of the Commonwealth to provide incentives for the creation of new tourism attractions and the expansion of existing tourism attractions within the Commonwealth in order to advance the public purposes of relieving unemployment by preserving and creating jobs that would not exist if not for the incentives offered by the authority to approved companies, and by preserving and creating sources of tax revenues for the support of public services provided by the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">The authorities granted by KRS 148.851 to 148.860 are proper governmental and public purposes for which public moneys may be expended; and </section><section prefix="d">That the creation or expansion of tourism development projects is of paramount importance mandating that the provisions of KRS 139.536 and KRS 148.851 to 148.860 be liberally construed and applied in order to advance public purposes. </section></section><section prefix="2">To qualify for incentives provided in KRS 139.536 and 148.851 to 148.860, the following requirements shall be met: <section prefix="a">For a tourism attraction project: <section prefix="1">The total eligible costs shall exceed one million dollars ($1,000,000), except for a tourism attraction project located in a county designated as an enhanced incentive county at the time the eligible company becomes an approved company as provided in KRS 148.857(6), the total eligible costs shall exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); </section><section prefix="2">In any year, including the first year of operation, the tourism attraction project shall be open to the public at least one hundred (100) days; and </section><section prefix="3">In any year following the third year of operation, the tourism attraction project shall attract at least twenty-five percent (25%) of its visitors from among persons who are not residents of the Commonwealth; </section></section><section prefix="b">For an entertainment destination center project: <section prefix="1">The total eligible costs shall exceed five million dollars ($5,000,000); </section><section prefix="2">The facility shall contain a minimum of two hundred thousand (200,000) square feet of building space adjacent or complementary to an existing tourism attraction project or a major convention facility; </section><section prefix="3">The incentives shall be dedicated to a public infrastructure purpose that shall relate to the entertainment destination center project; </section><section prefix="4">In any year, including the first year of operation, the entertainment destination center project shall: <section prefix="a">Be open to the public at least one hundred (100) days per year; </section><section prefix="b">Maintain at least one (1) major theme restaurant and at least three </section></section></section></section><section prefix="3">additional entertainment venues, including but not limited to <section prefix="a">An approved company may be granted a sales tax incentive based on the </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">For a tourism development project other than a lodging facility project <section prefix="a">A sales tax incentive shall be allowed to an approved company </section><section prefix="b">The sales tax incentive shall not exceed the lesser of the total </section></section><section prefix="2">For a tourism attraction project located in an enhanced incentive county <section prefix="a">A sales tax incentive shall be allowed to the approved company </section><section prefix="b">The sales tax incentive shall not exceed the lesser of the total </section></section><section prefix="3">For a lodging facility project described in KRS 148.851(14)(e) or (f): <section prefix="a">A sales tax incentive shall be allowed to the approved company </section><section prefix="b">The sales tax incentive shall not exceed the lesser of total amount </section></section><section prefix="4">Any unused incentives from a previous year may be carried forward to </section><section prefix="5">If the approved company is an entertainment destination center that has <section prefix="a">Reinvest in the original entertainment destination project one </section><section prefix="b">Report to the authority at the end of each fiscal year the amount of </section></section></section></section>live entertainment, multiplex theaters, large-format theater, motion simulators, family entertainment centers, concert halls, virtual reality or other interactive games, museums, exhibitions, or other cultural and leisure-time activities; and c. Maintain a minimum occupancy of sixty percent (60%) of the total gross area available for lease with entertainment and food and drink options not including the retail sale of tangible personal property; and 5. In any year following the third year of operation, the entertainment destination center project shall attract at least twenty-five percent (25%) of its visitors from among persons who are not residents of the Commonwealth; (c) For a theme restaurant destination attraction project: 1. The total eligible costs shall exceed five million dollars ($5,000,000); 2. In any year, including the first year of operation, the attraction shall: a. Be open to the public at least three hundred (300) days per year and for at least eight (8) hours per day; and b. Generate no more than fifty percent (50%) of its revenue through the sale of alcoholic beverages; 3. In any year following the third year of operation, the theme restaurant destination attraction project shall attract a minimum of fifty percent (50%) of its visitors from among persons who are not residents of the Commonwealth; and 4. The theme restaurant destination attraction project shall: a. At the time of final approval, offer a unique dining experience that is not available in the Commonwealth within a one hundred (100) mile radius of the attraction; b. In any year, including the first year of operation, maintain seating capacity of four hundred fifty (450) guests and offer live music or live musical and theatrical entertainment during the peak business hours that the facility is in operation and open to the public; or c. Within three (3) years of the completion date, the attraction shall obtain a top two (2) tier rating by a nationally accredited service and shall maintain a top two (2) tier rating through the term of the agreement; (d) For a lodging facility project: 1. a. The eligible costs shall exceed five million dollars ($5,000,000) unless the provisions of subdivision b. of this subparagraph apply. b. i. If the lodging facility is an integral part of a major convention or sports facility, the eligible costs shall exceed six million dollars ($6,000,000); and ii. If the lodging facility includes five hundred (500) or more guest rooms, the eligible costs shall exceed ten million dollars ($10,000,000); and 2. In any year, including the first year of operation, the lodging facility shall: a. Be open to the public at least one hundred (100) days; and b. Attract at least twenty-five percent (25%) of its visitors from among persons who are not residents of the Commonwealth; and (e) An expansion of any tourism development project shall in all cases be treated as a new stand-alone project. (3) The incentives offered under the Kentucky Tourism Development Act shall be as follows: Kentucky sales tax imposed on sales generated by or arising at the tourism development project; and described in KRS 148.851(14)(e) or (f), or a tourism attraction project described in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph: over a period of ten (10) years, except as provided in subparagraph 5. of this paragraph; and amount of the sales tax liability of the approved company and its lessees or a percentage of the approved costs as specified by the agreement, not to exceed twenty-five percent (25%); at the time the eligible company becomes an approved company as provided in KRS 148.857(6): over a period of ten (10) years; and amount of the sales tax liability of the approved company and its lessees or a percentage of the approved costs as specified by the agreement, not to exceed thirty percent (30%); over a period of twenty (20) years; and of the sales tax liability of the approved company and its lessees or a percentage of the approved costs as specified by the agreement, not to exceed fifty percent (50%); any succeeding year during the term of the agreement until the entire specified percentage of the approved costs has been received through sales tax incentives; and dedicated at least thirty million dollars ($30,000,000) of the incentives provided under the agreement to a public infrastructure purpose, the agreement may be amended to extend the term of the agreement up to two (2) additional years if the approved company agrees to: hundred percent (100%) of any incentives received during the extension that were outstanding at the end of the original term of the agreement; and incentives received during the extension and how the incentives were reinvested in the original entertainment destination project. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 37, effective June 26, 2009. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 154.29-020. </former-codification><lrc-note>(6/26/2009). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 37, subsection (3)(b)1. and 2. (this statute), by replacing an incorrect reference to "KRS 148.851(13)(e) or (f)" with the correct reference to "KRS 148.851(14)(e) or (f)." (1/25/2009).  This is former KRS 154.29-020 as amended by 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 3, and renumbered by the Reviser of Statutes under KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43429</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>