<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.443</section_number><catch_line>Veterinary assistants. </catch_line><order_by>443</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A veterinary assistant may work only under the direct supervision of a veterinarian except for the routine administration of drugs, vaccines, parasite control agents, and growth stimulating implants for food animals prescribed by a veterinarian and under the indirect supervision of a veterinarian where a veterinarian-client-patient relationship exists. </section><section prefix="2">Duties of a veterinary assistant shall exclude diagnosing, prescribing medication or treatment, and performance of surgical procedures other than castrating and dehorning of food animals. </section><section prefix="3">A veterinarian shall utilize the service of a veterinary assistant in accordance with the terms and provisions of this chapter. Unauthorized utilization of veterinary assistants shall be considered as aiding and abetting an unlicensed person to practice veterinary medicine as described in KRS 321.351. </section></text><history> Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/92).  This statute was created in 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, which contains the enrolled text of Senate Bill 250. A committee substitute for this bill was adopted by the House with a floor amendment, and the Senate subsequently concurred in this action by the House; this amended substitute thus became the enrolled version of the bill. In drafting the House Committee Substitute, the original Section 10 of the bill was deleted in its entirety, but internal section references within the bill were not renumbered to reflect this deletion. Therefore, in codifying this statute, the internal section reference within Acts ch. 299, sec. 8, has been changed pursuant to KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>