<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.357</section_number><catch_line>Block grant program status report. </catch_line><order_by>357</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission or its designated review body shall review the actual use and distribution of all block grant funds made available during the preceding year to any state administering agency. </section><section prefix="2">Any state administering agency receiving block grant funds shall, within thirty (30) days following December 31, 1982, June 30, 1983, and each six (6) months thereafter, submit to the Commission a report for each block grant received to be known as the "Block Grant Program Status Report." </section><section prefix="3">The Block Grant Program Status Report shall show for the programs and services provided under each block grant for the preceding six (6) months the following: <section prefix="a">Appropriations, allotments, expenditures, encumbrances, and available balance. </section><section prefix="b">The level of service budgeted, defined in terms of objectives and beneficiaries. </section><section prefix="c">The level of services delivered during the period. </section><section prefix="d">Alternatives for improved service delivery. </section><section prefix="e">Any changes in service authorized or necessary as a result of unanticipated changes in clientele, resources, or for other reasons. </section><section prefix="f">An evaluation of results, including a description of measurements used. </section></section><section prefix="4">Staff assigned by the Commission to review block grant applications and other block grant reports and documents submitted by state administering agencies shall be authorized to independently investigate and audit for the Commission all matters pertaining to the application for and expenditure of federal block grant and other funds included in any block grant program administered by any state administering agency. </section><section prefix="5">The Commission or its designated review body shall be authorized to subpoena any reports, or records or documents from any state agency regarding any block grant program administered by a state agency for the purposes of investigating or auditing such program. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>