<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="424" order_by="424">LEGAL NOTICES </unit></structure><section_number>424.290</section_number><catch_line>Election ballot. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Not less than three (3) days before any primary or regular election the county clerk shall cause to be published in a newspaper a copy of the face of the voting machines, or where an electronic or electromechanical voting system is used, a copy of the ballot cards or supplementary material on which appear the names of candidates or issues to be voted upon. Where the lists of candidates or issues to be voted upon differ for various precincts within the county, the county clerk shall cause to be published only one (1) set of data with appropriate notations showing the differences in the various precincts. If supplemental paper ballots have been approved as provided in KRS 118.215, the paper ballot shall be published at the same time as other material required to be published by this subsection. The cost of publication shall be paid by the county, except that the cost of publishing any voting data required to be published by this subsection that is limited to a city election or a district election other than a school district election shall be paid by the city or the district as the case may be.  </section><section prefix="2">"Copy," as used in subsection (1) of this section, means a summary of candidates and issues to be voted upon showing all the pertinent information that will appear, upon which the voters will cast their votes at a particular polling place.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 84, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 527, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 15. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 67, effective June 16, 1972. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>