<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.751</section_number><catch_line>Abandonment of vehicle on county road or city street -- Penalty -- Removal -- Disposition. </catch_line><order_by>751</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who leaves a vehicle upon a county road or city street under circumstances indicating an abandonment, shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned for not less than ten (10) days nor more than thirty (30) days. A vehicle left upon a county road or city street for three (3) consecutive days shall be presumed to be abandoned. </section><section prefix="2">The public authority having jurisdiction over a particular county road or city street shall cause a vehicle that is presumed to be abandoned under subsection (1) of this section and that is fit for future use to be removed by some person engaged in the business of storing or towing motor vehicles and the provisions of KRS 376.275 shall apply in disposing of the vehicle. Any money obtained in disposing of a vehicle that is in excess of any liens shall be paid by the seller to the owner and if the owner cannot be located, the excess money shall escheat to the state pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 393. A vehicle shall be registered or transferred in the county where the sale is conducted upon an affidavit by the seller that the provisions of KRS 376.275 have been met. The affidavit shall contain information as prescribed by the transportation cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">If a vehicle that is presumed abandoned under subsection (1) of this section is, in the opinion of the public authority, unfit for future use, the public authority may dispose of it immediately in a manner as it deems appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(9). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 3. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 105, secs. 1 to 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6449</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>