<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="80" order_by="80">LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>80.120</section_number><catch_line>Plans -- Contracts -- Surveys -- Maps -- Right of access. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall: <section prefix="a">Prepare the proper plans and specifications for the construction of low-income housing; </section><section prefix="b">Select the location and determine the size, type, and method of construction; </section><section prefix="c">Make the necessary estimates of the probable cost of construction and of the acquisition of the land and rights for the sites; </section><section prefix="d">Enter into the necessary contracts to build the necessary buildings; and </section><section prefix="e">Cause a survey and map to be made of all lands, structures, rights of way, franchises, easements or other interests in land, owned by any person, the acquisition of which may be deemed necessary for the construction of the low-income housing, and cause the map and survey to be filed in its office. </section></section><section prefix="2">The members of the authority, or its agents and employees, after reasonable notice to the occupants, owners, or owners' agent in charge thereof, may enter upon such lands and structures for the purpose of making surveys and maps. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 927a-4, 2741x-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>