<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.277</section_number><catch_line>Board of sanitation tax district -- Members, appointment, tenure, removal, compensation -- Officers, employees. </catch_line><order_by>277</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The affairs of each sanitation tax district shall be conducted by a board composed of five (5) members, all of whom shall be appointed by the county judge/executive of the county subject to the approval of the fiscal court. Not more than three (3) members of the board shall be affiliated with the same political party. </section><section prefix="2">Each member shall be at least twenty-five (25) years of age and a resident of the county. No officer or employee of a city or county, whether holding a paid or unpaid position, shall be eligible for appointment as a member of the board. </section><section prefix="3">On the first day of the first month which starts more than thirty (30) days after the creation of a sanitation tax district, or as soon thereafter as may be practical, the county judge/executive, subject to the approval of the fiscal court, shall appoint one (1) member for a term of two (2) years, two (2) members for a term of three (3) years, and two (2) members for a term of four (4) years. The first year of each term shall end on the first day of July which occurs at least six (6) months after the creation of the sanitation tax district. Upon the expiration of each of the terms and thereafter, the term of each member shall be four (4) years, ending on July first. A member is eligible to succeed himself, and shall continue in office until his successor has been appointed and qualified. Vacancies in the membership shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term by the county judge/executive, subject to the approval of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="4">Any member of the board may be removed for cause, after hearing by the county judge/executive, and after at least ten (10) days' notice in writing has been given to the member. The notice shall embrace the charges preferred against him. At the hearing he may be represented by counsel. The finding of the county judge/executive shall be final and removal results in vacancy in the office. </section><section prefix="5">Each member of the board shall be paid ten dollars ($10) for each meeting of the board attended by the member. </section><section prefix="6">The board in accordance with its bylaws shall elect from its members a chairman and a vice chairman. It may employ a secretary-treasurer and other officers and employees as it deems requisite for the performance of its duties. The board may require those officers and employees as it determines to execute faithful performance bonds, in sums as fixed by the board. The premiums for the bonds shall be paid by the district. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 41. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24542</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>