<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.581</section_number><catch_line>Duration and renewal. </catch_line><order_by>581</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A registration of a mark pursuant to KRS 365.561 to 365.613 shall be effective for a term of five (5) years from the date of registration and, may be renewed for a like term upon application filed within six (6) months prior to the expiration of the term, in a manner complying with the requirements of the Secretary as set out in administrative regulation. A renewal fee of five dollars ($5), payable to the Secretary, shall accompany the application for renewal of the registration. </section><section prefix="2">A registration may be renewed for successive periods of five (5) years in this manner. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State shall notify registrants of the necessity of renewing their registrations at least six (6) months prior to their pending expiration by writing to the last known address of the registrants. </section><section prefix="4">Any registration in effect on July 15, 1994, shall continue in effect for the remainder of the unexpired term and may be renewed by filing an application for renewal with the Secretary, if the application for renewal complies with the requirements of the Secretary as set out in administrative regulations and is accompanied by the renewal fee prescribed in subsection (1) of this section and submitted within six (6) months prior to the expiration of the registration. </section><section prefix="5">All applications for renewal pursuant to this section, whether of registrations made under KRS 365.561 to 365.613 or of registrations effected under any prior state law, shall include a verified statement that the mark has been and is still in use, and include a specimen showing actual use of the mark on or in connection with the goods or services. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 468, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>