<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.210</section_number><catch_line>Justices, county judges/executive, county attorneys, and mayors or council members of consolidated local government not to be interested in public improvements -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No justice of the peace, while he is a member of the fiscal court, shall, directly or indirectly: <section prefix="a">Become interested in or receive benefits or emoluments from any contract let by the fiscal court of his county with relation to the building of roads or any internal improvements; </section><section prefix="b">Work or supervise work, for compensation, on any public road, bridge, culvert, fill, quarry pit, or any other road work or internal improvement under any contract made with the fiscal court; or </section><section prefix="c">Furnish, for compensation, any material to the county to be used in the construction of any road or bridge or other internal improvement. </section></section><section prefix="2">No county judge/executive, county attorney, or mayor or council member of a consolidated local government shall, directly or indirectly, receive any benefits or emoluments from, furnish any material or other thing of value to be used in, or be interested in any contract let by the fiscal court or consolidated local government for, the construction of any roads, bridges, or parts thereof, or any other public or internal improvement. </section><section prefix="3">Any officer who violates any of the provisions of this section shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200) or imprisoned in the county jail not less than ten (10) nor more than forty (40) days, or both, and shall forfeit his office. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2002. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766a-1 to 3766a-5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22903</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>