<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.627</section_number><catch_line>Revocation. </catch_line><order_by>627</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An advance directive made pursuant to KRS 311.623 may be revoked by: <section prefix="a">A writing declaring an intention to revoke, which writing shall be signed and dated by the grantor; </section><section prefix="b">An oral statement of intent to revoke made by a grantor with decisional capacity in the presence of two (2) adults, one (1) of whom shall be a health care provider; or </section><section prefix="c">Destruction of the document by the grantor or by some person in the grantor's presence and at the grantor's direction. </section></section><section prefix="2">An oral statement by a grantor with decisional capacity to revoke an advance directive shall override any previous written advance directive made. </section><section prefix="3">Any revocation made pursuant to this section shall become effective immediately. An attending physician or health care facility shall not be required to administer treatment in accordance with the revocation until the time notice of the revocation is received. Upon receiving notice of the revocation, the attending physician or health care facility shall record, in the grantor's medical record, the time, date, and place of the notice receipt. No physician or health care facility shall be subject to any liability for acting in good faith upon the knowledge, or lack thereof, of the existence or revocation of an advance directive. </section><section prefix="4">The designation of a health care surrogate made pursuant to KRS 311.623 may be revoked in whole or in part or the surrogate's powers reduced or limited at any time by the grantor, if the grantor has decisional capacity. A new designation shall revoke any prior designation unless the revocation, in whole or in part, is specifically negated. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30565</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>