<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.210</section_number><catch_line>Power of Governor or state department to employ attorneys -- Compensation -- Employment by more than one department. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor, or any department with the approval of the Governor, may employ and fix the term of employment and the compensation to be paid to an attorney or attorneys for legal services to be performed for the Governor or for such department. An attorney hired for the collection of revenue owed to the state by a resident shall not be hired by personal service contract. The compensation and expenses of any attorney or attorneys employed under the provisions of this section shall be paid out of the appropriations made to such department as other salaries, compensation and expenses are paid, except when the terms of employment provide that the compensation shall be on a contingent basis, and in such event the attorneys may be paid the amount specified out of the moneys recovered by them or out of the general fund. If the Governor approves the employment, the terms of employment shall be duly entered by executive order upon the executive journal in the Office of the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">An attorney may be employed pursuant to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section to render legal services for one (1) or more departments, boards, program cabinets, offices or commissions. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 532, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74 Art. 1, sec. 12. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. II, sec. 4. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=650</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>