<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">C MILK AND MILK PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>217C.070</section_number><catch_line>Advisory committees -- Membership -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for health and family services shall appoint a grade A milk advisory committee composed of eight (8) appointive members. Three (3) members shall be processors, or representatives thereof; three (3) members shall be producers, or representatives thereof; and two (2) members shall be citizens at large, as representatives of consumers. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary for health and family services shall appoint a milk-for-manufacturing advisory committee composed of eight (8) appointive members. Four (4) members shall be processors, or representatives thereof; two (2) members shall be producers, or representatives thereof; and two (2) members shall be citizens at large, as representatives of consumers. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary for health and family services or his designated representative shall be an ex officio member and secretary of each committee. The appointments to each committee shall be made for a term of four (4) years, or until their successors are appointed and qualify, except that the terms of office of the members first appointed shall be as follows: two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) members shall be appointed for two (2) years, two (2) members shall be appointed for three (3) years and two (2) members shall be appointed for four (4) years and the respective terms of the first members shall be designated by the secretary for health and family services at the time of their appointment. Such members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for necessary traveling expenses. Procedures for selection of advisory nominees shall be in accordance with the regulations of the secretary. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec.  525, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 469, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, secs. 107(1) and (2). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>