<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6407</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocity -- Terms and conditions.  </catch_line><order_by>6407</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The certification requirements established within this chapter may be waived for a person moving into the Commonwealth from another jurisdiction, and a fire sprinkler inspector's certification granted, if the person meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The other jurisdiction grants the same privileges to certified fire sprinkler inspectors of Kentucky as Kentucky grants to certified or licensed fire sprinkler inspectors of that other jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="b">The individual is certified or licensed in the other jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="c">The certification or licensing requirements of the other jurisdiction are substantially similar to the requirements in this chapter; and </section><section prefix="d">The individual submits a notarized letter stating that he or she has read, is familiar with, and will abide by this chapter and the administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section></section><section prefix="2">An individual seeking a fire sprinkler inspector's certification under this section shall: <section prefix="a">Submit a completed fire sprinkler inspector's written or electronic application form as provided by the department; and </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Provide a certificate of insurance that is issued by an insurance company or other legal entity permitted to transact business in Kentucky with a general liability coverage of at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). Liability insurance shall cover the legal liability of the certified fire sprinkler inspector as the result of erroneous acts or failure to act in his or her capacity as a fire sprinkler inspector and shall be in the form of a certificate of insurance executed by an insurer permitted to do business in this state or exported by a licensed surplus lines broker to an eligible carrier pursuant to KRS 304.10-020 to 304.10-210; or </section><section prefix="2">Submit an affidavit from a sprinkler contractor that he or she is covered as an employee of a sprinkler contractor that is in good standing and currently licensed by the department. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 33, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 33, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36631</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>