<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle.     </catch_line><order_by>17A-005</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Association" means an entity, other than an employer-organized association, that has been organized and is maintained in good faith for purposes other than that of obtaining insurance for its members and that has a constitution and bylaws; </section><section prefix="2">"At the time of enrollment" means: <section prefix="a">At the time of application for an individual, an association that actively markets to individual members, and an employer-organized association that actively markets to individual members; and </section><section prefix="b">During the time of open enrollment or during an insured's initial or special enrollment periods for group health insurance; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Base premium rate" means, for each class of business as to a rating period, the lowest premium rate charged or that could have been charged under the rating system for that class of business by the insurer to the individual or small group, or employer as defined in KRS 304.17A-0954, with similar case characteristics for health benefit plans with the same or similar coverage; </section><section prefix="4">"Basic health benefit plan" means any plan offered to an individual, a small group, or employer-organized association that limits coverage to physician, pharmacy, home health, preventive, emergency, and inpatient and outpatient hospital services in accordance with the requirements of this subtitle. If vision or eye services are offered, these services may be provided by an ophthalmologist or optometrist. Chiropractic benefits may be offered by providers licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 312; </section><section prefix="5">"Bona fide association" means an entity as defined in 42 U.S.C. sec. 300gg-91(d)(3); </section><section prefix="6">"Church plan" means a church plan as defined in 29 U.S.C. sec. 1002(33); </section><section prefix="7">"COBRA" means any of the following: <section prefix="a">26 U.S.C. sec. 4980B other than subsection (f)(1) as it relates to pediatric vaccines; </section><section prefix="b">The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. sec. 1161 et seq. other than sec. 1169); or </section><section prefix="c">42 U.S.C. sec. 300bb; </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Creditable coverage" means, with respect to an individual, coverage of the individual under any of the following: <section prefix="1">A group health plan; </section><section prefix="2">Health insurance coverage; </section><section prefix="3">Part A or Part B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act; </section><section prefix="4">Title XIX of the Social Security Act, other than coverage consisting solely of benefits under section 1928; </section><section prefix="5">Chapter 55 of Title 10, United States Code, including medical and dental care for members and certain former members of the uniformed services, and for their dependents; for purposes of Chapter 55 of Title 10, United States Code, "uniformed services" means the Armed Forces and the Commissioned Corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and of the Public Health Service; </section><section prefix="6">A medical care program of the Indian Health Service or of a tribal organization; </section><section prefix="7">A state health benefits risk pool; </section><section prefix="8">A health plan offered under Chapter 89 of Title 5, United States Code, such as the Federal Employees Health Benefit Program; </section><section prefix="9">A public health plan as established or maintained by a state, the United States government, a foreign country, or any political subdivision of a state, the United States government, or a foreign country that provides health coverage to individuals who are enrolled in the plan; </section><section prefix="10">A health benefit plan under section 5(e) of the Peace Corps Act (22 U.S.C. sec. 2504(e)); or </section><section prefix="11">Title XXI of the Social Security Act, such as the State Children's Health Insurance Program. </section></section><section prefix="b">This term does not include coverage consisting solely of coverage of excepted benefits as defined in subsection (14) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Dependent" means any individual who is or may become eligible for coverage under the terms of an individual or group health benefit plan because of a relationship to a participant; </section><section prefix="10">"Employee benefit plan" means an employee welfare benefit plan or an employee pension benefit plan or a plan which is both an employee welfare benefit plan and an employee pension benefit plan as defined by ERISA; </section><section prefix="11">"Eligible individual" means an individual: <section prefix="a">For whom, as of the date on which the individual seeks coverage, the aggregate of the periods of creditable coverage is eighteen (18) or more months and whose most recent prior creditable coverage was under a group health plan, governmental plan, or church plan. A period of creditable coverage under this paragraph shall not be counted if, after that period, there was a sixty-three (63) day period of time, excluding any waiting or affiliation period, during all of which the individual was not covered under any creditable coverage; </section><section prefix="b">Who is not eligible for coverage under a group health plan, Part A or Part B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. secs. 1395j et seq.), or a state plan under Title XIX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. secs. 1396 et seq.) and does not have other health insurance coverage; </section><section prefix="c">With respect to whom the most recent coverage within the coverage period described in paragraph (a) of this subsection was not terminated based on a factor described in KRS 304.17A-240(2)(a), (b), and (c); </section><section prefix="d">If the individual had been offered the option of continuation coverage under a COBRA continuation provision or under KRS 304.18-110, who elected the coverage; and </section><section prefix="e">Who, if the individual elected the continuation coverage, has exhausted the continuation coverage under the provision or program; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Employer-organized association" means any of the following: <section prefix="a">Any entity that was qualified by the commissioner as an eligible association prior to April 10, 1998, and that has actively marketed a health insurance program to its members since September 8, 1996, and which is not insurer-controlled; </section><section prefix="b">Any entity organized under KRS 247.240 to 247.370 that has actively marketed health insurance to its members and that is not insurer-controlled; or </section><section prefix="c">Any entity that is a bona fide association as defined in 42 U.S.C. sec. 300gg-91(d)(3), whose members consist principally of employers, and for which the entity's health insurance decisions are made by a board or committee, the majority of which are representatives of employer members of the entity who obtain group health insurance coverage through the entity or through a trust or other mechanism established by the entity, and whose health insurance decisions are reflected in written minutes or other written documentation. </section></section> Except as provided in KRS 304.17A-200, 304.17A.210, and 304.17A-220, and except as otherwise provided by the definition of "large group" contained in subsection (30) of this section, an employer-organized association shall not be treated as an association, small group, or large group under this subtitle, provided that an employer-organized association that is a bona fide association as defined in subsection (5) of this section shall be treated as a large group under this subtitle; <section prefix="13">"Employer-organized association health insurance plan" means any health insurance plan, policy, or contract issued to an employer-organized association, or to a trust established by one (1) or more employer-organized associations, or providing coverage solely for the employees, retired employees, directors and their spouses and dependents of the members of one (1) or more employer-organized associations; </section><section prefix="14">"Excepted benefits" means benefits under one (1) or more, or any combination thereof, of the following: <section prefix="a">Coverage only for accident, including accidental death and dismemberment, or disability income insurance, or any combination thereof; </section><section prefix="b">Coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance; </section><section prefix="c">Liability insurance, including general liability insurance and automobile liability insurance; </section><section prefix="d">Workers' compensation or similar insurance; </section><section prefix="e">Automobile medical payment insurance; </section><section prefix="f">Credit-only insurance; </section><section prefix="g">Coverage for on-site medical clinics; </section><section prefix="h">Other similar insurance coverage, specified in administrative regulations, under which benefits for medical care are secondary or incidental to other insurance benefits; </section><section prefix="i">Limited scope dental or vision benefits; </section><section prefix="j">Benefits for long-term care, nursing home care, home health care, community-based care, or any combination thereof; </section><section prefix="k">Such other similar, limited benefits as are specified in administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="l">Coverage only for a specified disease or illness; </section><section prefix="m">Hospital indemnity or other fixed indemnity insurance; </section><section prefix="n">Benefits offered as Medicare supplemental health insurance, as defined under section 1882(g)(1) of the Social Security Act; </section><section prefix="o">Coverage supplemental to the coverage provided under Chapter 55 of Title 10, United States Code; </section><section prefix="p">Coverage similar to that in paragraphs (n) and (o) of this subsection that is supplemental to coverage under a group health plan; and </section><section prefix="q">Health flexible spending arrangements; </section></section><section prefix="15">"Governmental plan" means a governmental plan as defined in 29 U.S.C. sec. 1002(32); </section><section prefix="16">"Group health plan" means a plan, including a self-insured plan, of or contributed to by an employer, including a self-employed person, or employee organization, to provide health care directly or otherwise to the employees, former employees, the employer, or others associated or formerly associated with the employer in a business relationship, or their families; </section><section prefix="17">"Guaranteed acceptance program participating insurer" means an insurer that is required to or has agreed to offer health benefit plans in the individual market to guaranteed acceptance program qualified individuals under KRS 304.17A-400 to 304.17A-480; </section><section prefix="18">"Guaranteed acceptance program plan" means a health benefit plan in the individual market issued by an insurer that provides health benefits to a guaranteed acceptance program qualified individual and is eligible for assessment and refunds under the guaranteed acceptance program under KRS 304.17A-400 to 304.17A-480; </section><section prefix="19">"Guaranteed acceptance program" means the Kentucky Guaranteed Acceptance Program established and operated under KRS 304.17A-400 to 304.17A-480; </section><section prefix="20">"Guaranteed acceptance program qualified individual" means an individual who, on or before December 31, 2000: <section prefix="a">Is not an eligible individual; </section><section prefix="b">Is not eligible for or covered by other health benefit plan coverage or who is a spouse or a dependent of an individual who: <section prefix="1">Waived coverage under KRS 304.17A-210(2); or </section><section prefix="2">Did not elect family coverage that was available through the association or group market; </section></section><section prefix="c">Within the previous three (3) years has been diagnosed with or treated for a high-cost condition or has had benefits paid under a health benefit plan for a high-cost condition, or is a high risk individual as defined by the underwriting criteria applied by an insurer under the alternative underwriting mechanism established in KRS 304.17A-430(3); </section><section prefix="d">Has been a resident of Kentucky for at least twelve (12) months immediately preceding the effective date of the policy; and </section><section prefix="e">Has not had his or her most recent coverage under any health benefit plan terminated or nonrenewed because of any of the following: <section prefix="1">The individual failed to pay premiums or contributions in accordance with the terms of the plan or the insurer had not received timely premium payments; </section><section prefix="2">The individual performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or made an intentional misrepresentation of material fact under the terms of the coverage; or </section><section prefix="3">The individual engaged in intentional and abusive noncompliance with health benefit plan provisions; </section></section></section><section prefix="21">"Guaranteed acceptance plan supporting insurer" means either an insurer, on or before December 31, 2000, that is not a guaranteed acceptance plan participating insurer or is a stop loss carrier, on or before December 31, 2000, provided that a guaranteed acceptance plan supporting insurer shall not include an employer-sponsored self-insured health benefit plan exempted by ERISA; </section><section prefix="22">"Health benefit plan" means any hospital or medical expense policy or certificate; nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, and health service corporation contract or certificate; provider sponsored integrated health delivery network; a self-insured plan or a plan provided by a multiple employer welfare arrangement, to the extent permitted by ERISA; health maintenance organization contract; or any health benefit plan that affects the rights of a Kentucky insured and bears a reasonable relation to Kentucky, whether delivered or issued for delivery in Kentucky, and does not include policies covering only accident, credit, dental, disability income, fixed indemnity medical expense reimbursement policy, long-term care, Medicare supplement, specified disease, vision care, coverage issued as a supplement to liability insurance, insurance arising out of a workers' compensation or similar law, automobile medical-payment insurance, insurance under which benefits are payable with or without regard to fault and that is statutorily required to be contained in any liability insurance policy or equivalent self-insurance, short-term coverage, student health insurance offered by a Kentucky-licensed insurer under written contract with a university or college whose students it proposes to insure, medical expense reimbursement policies specifically designed to fill gaps in primary coverage, coinsurance, or deductibles and provided under a separate policy, certificate, or contract, or coverage supplemental to the coverage provided under Chapter 55 of Title 10, United States Code, or limited health service benefit plans; </section><section prefix="23">"Health care provider" or "provider" means any facility or service required to be licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 216B, pharmacist or home medical equipment and services provider as defined pursuant to KRS Chapter 315, and any of the following independent practicing practitioners: <section prefix="a">Physicians, osteopaths, and podiatrists licensed under KRS Chapter 311; </section><section prefix="b">Chiropractors licensed under KRS Chapter 312; </section><section prefix="c">Dentists licensed under KRS Chapter 313; </section><section prefix="d">Optometrists licensed under KRS Chapter 320; </section><section prefix="e">Physician assistants regulated under KRS Chapter 311; </section><section prefix="f">Advanced practice registered nurses licensed under KRS Chapter 314; and </section><section prefix="g">Other health care practitioners as determined by the department by administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A; </section></section><section prefix="24"><section prefix="a">"High-cost condition," pursuant to the Kentucky Guaranteed Acceptance Program, means a covered condition in an individual policy as listed in paragraph (c) of this subsection or as added by the commissioner in accordance with KRS 304.17A-280, but only to the extent that the condition exceeds the numerical score or rating established pursuant to uniform underwriting standards prescribed by the commissioner under paragraph (b) of this subsection that account for the severity of the condition and the cost associated with treating that condition. </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner by administrative regulation shall establish uniform underwriting standards and a score or rating above which a condition is considered to be high-cost by using: <section prefix="1">Codes in the most recent version of the "International Classification of Diseases" that correspond to the medical conditions in paragraph (c) of this subsection and the costs for administering treatment for the conditions represented by those codes; and </section><section prefix="2">The most recent version of the questionnaire incorporated in a national underwriting guide generally accepted in the insurance industry as designated by the commissioner, the scoring scale for which shall be established by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="c">The diagnosed medical conditions are: acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), angina pectoris, ascites, chemical dependency cirrhosis of the liver, coronary insufficiency, coronary occlusion, cystic fibrosis, Friedreich's ataxia, hemophilia, Hodgkin's disease, Huntington chorea, juvenile diabetes, leukemia, metastatic cancer, motor or sensory aphasia, multiple sclerosis, muscular dystrophy, myasthenia gravis, myotonia, open heart surgery, Parkinson's disease, polycystic kidney, psychotic disorders, quadriplegia, stroke, syringomyelia, and Wilson's disease; </section></section><section prefix="25">"Index rate" means, for each class of business as to a rating period, the arithmetic average of the applicable base premium rate and the corresponding highest premium rate; </section><section prefix="26">"Individual market" means the market for the health insurance coverage offered to individuals other than in connection with a group health plan. The individual market includes an association plan that is not employer related, issued to individuals on an individually underwritten basis, other than an employer-organized association or a bona fide association, that has been organized and is maintained in good faith for purposes other than obtaining insurance for its members and that has a constitution and bylaws; </section><section prefix="27">"Insurer" means any insurance company; health maintenance organization; self-insurer or multiple employer welfare arrangement not exempt from state regulation by ERISA; provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network; self-insured employer-organized association, or nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, or health service corporation authorized to transact health insurance business in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="28">"Insurer-controlled" means that the commissioner has found, in an administrative hearing called specifically for that purpose, that an insurer has or had a substantial involvement in the organization or day-to-day operation of the entity for the principal purpose of creating a device, arrangement, or scheme by which the insurer segments employer groups according to their actual or anticipated health status or actual or projected health insurance premiums; </section><section prefix="29">"Kentucky Access" has the meaning provided in KRS 304.17B-001(17); </section><section prefix="30">"Large group" means: <section prefix="a">An employer with fifty-one (51) or more employees; </section><section prefix="b">An affiliated group with fifty-one (51) or more eligible members; or </section><section prefix="c">An employer-organized association that is a bona fide association as defined in subsection (5) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="31">"Managed care" means systems or techniques generally used by third-party payors or their agents to affect access to and control payment for health care services and that integrate the financing and delivery of appropriate health care services to covered persons by arrangements with participating providers who are selected to participate on the basis of explicit standards for furnishing a comprehensive set of health care services and financial incentives for covered persons using the participating providers and procedures provided for in the plan; </section><section prefix="32">"Market segment" means the portion of the market covering one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">Individual; </section><section prefix="b">Small group; </section><section prefix="c">Large group; or </section><section prefix="d">Association; </section></section><section prefix="33">"Participant" means any employee or former employee of an employer, or any member or former member of an employee organization, who is or may become eligible to receive a benefit of any type from an employee benefit plan which covers employees of the employer or members of the organization, or whose beneficiaries may be eligible to receive any benefit as established in Section 3(7) of ERISA; </section><section prefix="34">"Preventive services" means medical services for the early detection of disease that are associated with substantial reduction in morbidity and mortality; </section><section prefix="35">"Provider network" means an affiliated group of varied health care providers that is established to provide a continuum of health care services to individuals; </section><section prefix="36">"Provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network" means any provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network created and qualified under KRS 304.17A-300 and KRS 304.17A-310; </section><section prefix="37">"Purchaser" means an individual, organization, employer, association, or the Commonwealth that makes health benefit purchasing decisions on behalf of a group of individuals; </section><section prefix="38">"Rating period" means the calendar period for which premium rates are in effect. A rating period shall not be required to be a calendar year; </section><section prefix="39">"Restricted provider network" means a health benefit plan that conditions the payment of benefits, in whole or in part, on the use of the providers that have entered into a contractual arrangement with the insurer to provide health care services to covered individuals; </section><section prefix="40">"Self-insured plan" means a group health insurance plan in which the sponsoring organization assumes the financial risk of paying for covered services provided to its enrollees; </section><section prefix="41">"Small employer" means, in connection with a group health plan with respect to a calendar year and a plan year, an employer who employed an average of at least two (2) but not more than fifty (50) employees on business days during the preceding calendar year and who employs at least two (2) employees on the first day of the plan year; </section><section prefix="42">"Small group" means: <section prefix="a">A small employer with two (2) to fifty (50) employees; or </section><section prefix="b">An affiliated group or association with two (2) to fifty (50) eligible members; </section></section><section prefix="43">"Standard benefit plan" means the plan identified in KRS 304.17A-250; and </section><section prefix="44">"Telehealth" has the meaning provided in KRS 311.550. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1209, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 85, sec. 46, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2001; ch. 476, sec. 17, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 521, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 1, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42568</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>