<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.082</section_number><catch_line>National Guard Facilities Construction Act. </catch_line><order_by>082</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section may be cited as the National Guard Facilities Construction Act. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of this section is to provide funds for the construction of National Guard facilities at the following locations, at the estimated cost shown: </section>Location  Facility          Estimated Cost Expected        Federal    State        Funds    Funds Louisville  Maintenance Shop   $    75,000 $    6,000 Hickman  Armory    210,000 80,000 Lexington  Armory    340,000 145,000 Lexington  Maintenance Shop   75,000 6,000 Frankfort  Aviation Maintenance Shop  85,000 6,800 Ravenna  Armory    190,000 75,000 Russellville Armory    170,000 70,000 Frankfort  Department of Military Affairs   Building and State Government   Emergency Operations Center   250,000 470,000 TOTAL      $1,395,000 $858,800  Any of these facilities may be constructed at such other locations at which National Guard units may be established. <section prefix="3">Proceeds from the sale of facilities now held by the Department of Military Affairs which are obsolete or surplus to the needs of the department shall be deposited to the capital construction fund to the credit of the Department of Military Affairs. Such amounts credited and such additional funds as are available for general use within the capital construction fund may be used for construction of facilities for the Department of Military Affairs to carry out the provisions of this section. Any unexpended balances remaining at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse, but shall carry forward into subsequent fiscal years. Upon certification by the adjutant general that any project which was planned in anticipation of receipt of federal funds, that such federal funds will not be received on a timely basis, state funds designated for such projects may revert to capital construction fund to the credit of the Department of Military Affairs for other construction projects. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 8. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 231, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>