<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.230</section_number><catch_line>Board of Veterinary Examiners -- Membership -- Qualifications -- Appointment -- Terms -- Vacancies -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text>There hereby is created a board to be known as the "Kentucky Board of Veterinary Examiners." The board shall consist of eight (8) members appointed by the Governor, and the Commissioner of Agriculture or his designee. Seven (7) members shall be citizens of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and shall each have been lawfully engaged in the practice of veterinary medicine in this Commonwealth for at least two (2) years next preceding the date of his appointment. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. The four (4) appointed members serving on July 14, 1992, shall continue to serve as board members until their respective terms expire. The four (4) appointed members to be added to the board by this section, shall originally be appointed as follows: one (1) member to a one (1) year term, one (1) member for a two (2) year term, one (1) member for a three (3) year term, and one (1) member for a four (4) year term. All appointed members thereafter shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. Any vacancy in the appointed membership of the board shall be filled for the unexpired term by appointment by the Governor. Each member of the board shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day of service actually given in carrying out his duties under this chapter, in addition to his necessary traveling, hotel, and contingent expenses incurred in attending the meetings of the board and in the performance of his duties. </text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 15. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31388</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>