<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94">PUBLIC WORKS IN CITIES OTHER THAN THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>94.810</section_number><catch_line>Creation -- Powers -- Fees -- Joint city-county motor vehicle parking authorities. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city by ordinance may create motor vehicle parking authorities, or at any time, the legislative body of a city by ordinance and the fiscal court of the county containing the city may enter into an agreement to form a joint city-county motor vehicle parking authority. Such parking authorities shall have the power of acquisition, creation and operation of public street and off-street parking facilities. The fees charged need not be limited to the cost of operation and administration but may be for revenue.  </section><section prefix="2">If a city, already having a motor vehicle parking authority in existence, enters into an agreement to form a joint parking authority with the county, the agreement shall provide for the assumption of the debts and liabilities of the existing parking authority by the joint parking authority and the transfer of any assets of the existing parking authority, including real property and improvements, to the joint parking authority.  </section><section prefix="3">The termination of an agreement between a city and county to form a joint parking authority will not result in the continued existence of a city motor vehicle parking authority, unless specifically provided for in the agreement.  </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 1.</history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><lrc-note>(1982).  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>