<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.547</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 278.547 to 278.5499. </catch_line><order_by>547</order_by><text>As used in KRS 278.547 to 278.5499, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Specialized telecommunications equipment" means devices such as, but not limited to telecommunications devices for the deaf, amplified phones, loud ringers, visual alert signalers, tactile signalers, captioned telephones, and appropriate wireless devices. </section><section prefix="2">"Telecommunications relay service" means a procedure by which a deaf, hard-of-hearing, or speech-impaired user of specialized telecommunications equipment can communicate with an intermediary party, who then verbally relays the first party's message or request to a third party, or vice versa. The service includes, but is not limited to the switching, transmitting, and the voice and typed translation of calls. </section><section prefix="3">"Telecommunications Access Program" means the program to furnish specialized telecommunications equipment to deaf, hard-of-hearing, and speech-impaired persons in order that they may use the telecommunications relay service. The program shall include maintenance and repair of the equipment. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 3, effective July 1, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>