<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.3407</section_number><catch_line>Conditional parole of state inmates to be served in local facility -- Administrative regulations -- Work release. </catch_line><order_by>3407</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department may promulgate administrative regulations to implement conditional parole of state inmates incarcerated in state corrections institutions or local correctional facilities or county jails to place those individuals closer to their communities prior to release. A parolee placed on conditional parole shall serve that term in a local correctional facility or county jail in a county in which the fiscal court has agreed to house parolees if beds are available in the local correctional facility or county jail. </section><section prefix="2">The department may authorize parolees on conditional parole to be placed on work release. If a person placed in a county jail on conditional parole under subsection (1) of this section is granted work release, he or she shall pay the work release fees required by law to the jailer. The amount of work release fees paid by a parolee shall be deducted from the amount which the Department of Corrections shall pay for the placement of that parolee. </section><section prefix="3">Local correctional facilities or county jails housing parolees under subsection (1) of this section shall have the same rights and obligations as county jails housing felons pursuant to KRS 532.100. </section><section prefix="4">Administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (1) of this section relating to eligibility of an individual for conditional parole shall take into consideration, at a minimum, the following information about the individual: <section prefix="a">The offense for which the individual was convicted and his or her rehabilitation efforts while incarcerated; </section><section prefix="b">The security classification while incarcerated in the state correctional institution; </section><section prefix="c">Conduct while incarcerated in the state correctional institution; </section><section prefix="d">Ability to find employment in the community; and </section><section prefix="e">The availability of additional applicable education, treatment or intervention, and training for employment in the local correctional facility or county jail, if needed by the individual. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 39, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39557</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>