<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.700</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>As used in KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738, unless otherwise provided: <section prefix="1">"Applicant" means an individual who applies for a license as a home inspector; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Home Inspectors established in KRS 198B.704; </section><section prefix="3">"Client" means a person who contracts with a licensed home inspector to obtain a home inspection and subsequent written home inspection report; </section><section prefix="4">"Home inspection" means a visual analysis performed for compensation for the purpose of providing a professional opinion and home inspection report by a licensed home inspector, regarding the condition of a residential dwelling and the dwelling's attached garages and carports, any reasonable accessible installed components, and the operation of the dwelling's systems, including any controls normally operated by the owner of the dwelling, for systems and components in the standards of practice established by the board. Home inspection shall not include a code compliance inspection, or an inspection required under the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974, 42 U.S.C. secs. 5401 et seq., as amended, and rules and regulations issued thereunder, or KRS 227.600 regarding manufactured homes; </section><section prefix="5">"Home inspection report" means a written report prepared by a licensed home inspector for compensation and issued after a home inspection. The report shall include the following: <section prefix="a">A report on any system or component inspected that, in the professional opinion of the inspector, is significantly deficient; </section><section prefix="b">The inspector's recommendation to repair or monitor deficiencies reported under paragraph (a) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="c">A list of any systems or components that were designated for inspection in the standards of practice adopted by the board but that were not inspected; and </section><section prefix="d">The reason a system or component listed under paragraph (c) of this subsection was not inspected; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Home inspector" means an individual who performs home inspections for compensation; </section><section prefix="7">"Licensee" means a person who performs home inspections and who is licensed under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 as a home inspector; and </section><section prefix="8">"Residential dwelling" means a structure consisting of at least one (1) but not more than four (4) units, each designed for occupancy by a single family, whether the units are occupied or unoccupied. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 297, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39899</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>