<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.9-120</section_number><catch_line>Administrative complaint -- Hearing for denial, suspension, or revocation of license. </catch_line><order_by>9-120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may file an administrative complaint against any person if it appears on grounds satisfactory to the commissioner that a potential or actual violation of this subtitle has been committed and when the person may be subject to the penalties of KRS 286.9-071, 286.9-110, and 286.9-991. The commissioner shall serve the administrative complaint to the last known address of the person named in the complaint. Service shall be by certified mail or personal delivery. The person named in the administrative complaint shall be entitled to an administrative hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B but only upon timely receipt of a written answer and request for an administrative hearing within twenty (20) days of the mailing or hand delivery of the administrative complaint. If timely requested, an administrative hearing shall be held in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. If an answer is not timely filed, or a written request for a hearing is not timely filed, the commissioner may enter a final order. </section><section prefix="2">No license shall be denied, limited, conditioned, restricted, probated, suspended, or revoked unless the applicant or licensee is afforded the opportunity for a hearing to be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 815, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 18, effective January 1, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 601, sec. 11, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 353, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 341, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.120. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14918</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>