<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.585</section_number><catch_line>Duty of Department for Community Based Services. </catch_line><order_by>585</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Community Based Services shall be the lead administrative agency for family preservation services and may receive funding for the implementation of these services. The Department for Community Based Services shall: <section prefix="a">Provide the coordination of and planning for the implementation of family preservation services; </section><section prefix="b">Provide standards for family preservation services programs; </section><section prefix="c">Monitor these services to ensure they meet measurable standards of performance as set forth in state law and as developed by the Department for Community Based Services; and </section><section prefix="d">Provide the initial training and approve any ongoing training required by providers of family preservation services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Community Based Services may provide family preservation services directly or may contract with a private, nonprofit social service agency to provide these services. In the event the department provides family preservation services with state caseworkers, those caseworkers and cases shall be excluded for the overall caseworker/case averages provided on a quarterly basis to the Legislative Research Commission and the Governor's office under KRS 199.461. Family preservation services caseworkers and cases shall be included in the report as a separate category. </section><section prefix="3">In the event a nonprofit social service agency is contracted by the Department for Community Based Services, to provide family preservation services, the contract shall include: <section prefix="a">Requirements for provider acceptance of any client referred by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for family preservation services; </section><section prefix="b">Limitation of caseload to four (4) or fewer families per caseworker; </section><section prefix="c">Provision of twenty-four (24) hour crisis intervention services to families served by the program; </section><section prefix="d">Provision for training of family preservation services staff to meet the following minimum standards: <section prefix="1">Intensive training of not less than forty (40) hours to any therapist before family preservation services clients are assigned. This training is to be provided by individuals with recognized expertise regarding family preservation services and is to concern itself with the required knowledge skills, and techniques for success within the family preservation services model; </section><section prefix="2">A plan for the continuing education of staff therapists after the initial forty (40) hours; </section><section prefix="3">Training of not less than twenty (20) hours for a paraprofessional family aide before provision of services without the direct supervision of a family preservation services caseworker; </section></section><section prefix="e">Provide for and conduct internal program evaluation and cooperate with external evaluation as directed by the Department for Community Based Services; </section></section><section prefix="4">To qualify for continued funding under subsection (3) of this section, an agency contracting to provide family preservation services shall demonstrate an annual success rate of seventy-five percent (75%) in avoiding out-of-home placement six (6) months after the cessation of family preservation services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 206, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 29, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 170, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>