<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">A OCCUPATIONAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319A.110</section_number><catch_line>Application for license. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure as an occupational therapist or as an occupational therapy assistant shall file a written application on a form provided by the board, showing to the satisfaction of the board that the person: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character; and </section><section prefix="b">Has successfully completed the academic requirements of an educational program in occupational therapy or for occupational therapy assistants accredited by the American Occupational Therapy Association's Accreditation Council for Occupational Therapy Education or its equivalent. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant shall submit to the board evidence of successful completion of a period of supervised fieldwork experience arranged by the recognized educational institution where the applicant met the academic requirements. To be considered for licensure, the following minimum amount of supervised fieldwork experience shall have been completed: <section prefix="a">The equivalent of twenty-four (24) weeks for an occupational therapist; and </section><section prefix="b">The equivalent of sixteen (16) weeks for an occupational therapy assistant. </section></section><section prefix="3">An applicant for licensure as an occupational therapist or as an occupational therapy assistant shall pass an examination as provided for in KRS 319A.120. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31264</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>