<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.030</section_number><catch_line>Additional organizational units in cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, in addition to the departments, divisions, offices, and branches set forth in KRS 15A.020, shall consist of the following organizational units: <section prefix="a">Kentucky State Corrections Commission, supported by the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="b">Criminal Justice Council, supported by the Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services; </section><section prefix="c">Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, supported by the Department of Criminal Justice Training; and </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky Parole Board, supported by the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except for the Kentucky Parole Board, which shall be attached to the cabinet for administrative and support services only, each agency specified in this section shall: <section prefix="a">Perform its duties as specified by law; </section><section prefix="b">Except as otherwise provided by law, be under the general direction and control of the secretary; </section><section prefix="c">Perform such other duties as may be assigned to the secretary; and </section><section prefix="d">Report to the secretary. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 41, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective March 3, 2000; and ch. 218, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 606, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 377, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1029</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>