<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.627</section_number><catch_line>Urban-county department of health and board of health -- Establishment -- Jurisdiction -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>627</order_by><text>In each county of the Commonwealth containing any city with a population of over 100,000 at the time of merger creating an urban-county form of government, there is hereby established an urban-county department of health which shall be known as the "(name of city) - (name of county) Urban-County Department of Health." The department when established shall be governed by a board which shall be a body politic and corporate, and shall be known as the "(name of city) - (name of county) Urban-County Board of Health." The board shall have jurisdiction throughout the county, including within all municipalities of the county with respect to and in accordance with the provisions of KRS 212.626 to 212.639. The board may, in its corporate name, sue and be sued, contract and be contracted with, acquire real, personal and mixed property by deed, purchase, gift, devise, lease or otherwise, and mortgage, pledge, sell, convey or otherwise dispose of same. The board may make appropriate rules and regulations and do all things reasonable or necessary in order to carry out the work and to properly perform the duties intended as required under the provisions of KRS 212.626 to 212.639. The title to all property acquired for purposes of KRS 212.626 to 212.639 whether real, personal and mixed, or whether acquired by deed, gift, purchase, devise, or otherwise, shall vest in the board and shall be exempt from taxation. When and after the board and department established under the provisions of KRS 212.626 to 212.639 are organized and except as otherwise provided herein, the board and department shall succeed to and be vested with all of the functions, obligations, powers, duties and privileges now being exercised by the city-county board of health and city-county department of health, and thereupon the city-county board of health and city-county department of health shall cease to exist and all laws and amendments to any such laws, relating to and governing the city-county board of health and city-county department of health, in conflict with the provisions of KRS 212.626 to 212.639 shall, to the extent of such conflict, stand and be repealed. </text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1977 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8648</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>