<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.730</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary hearings -- Emergency suspension -- Persons not licensed to show cause -- Cease and desist order. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The procedures set forth in KRS Chapter 13B shall govern the board's conduct of disciplinary hearings. </section><section prefix="2">The board may summarily suspend a license for up to ninety (90) days before a final adjudication or during an appeal of the board's determination if the board finds that the licensee would represent a clear and immediate danger to the public's health, safety, or property if allowed to perform home inspections. The summary suspension may be renewed upon a hearing before the board for up to ninety (90) days. </section><section prefix="3">If the board: <section prefix="a">Determines that an individual is not licensed under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 and is engaged in or believed to be engaged in activities for which a license is required under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738, the board shall issue an order to that individual requiring the individual to show cause why the individual should not be ordered to cease and desist from the activities. The show cause order shall set forth a date, time, and place for a hearing at which the individual shall appear and show cause why the individual should not be subject to licensing under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738; </section><section prefix="b">Prior to a hearing, the board may issue a cease and desist order that identifies the individual and describes activities that are the subject of the order. </section></section><section prefix="4">A cease and desist order issued under this section shall be enforceable in a Circuit Court of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 11, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 16, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39907</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>