<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.32-150</section_number><catch_line>Benefits. </catch_line><order_by>32-150</order_by><text>The benefits or services which a corporation subject to the provisions of this subtitle may contract to make available to its members or subscribers shall include all of the services made available by hospitals, or other licensed health care institutions, doctors of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, podiatry, licensed optometrists, licensed psychologists, nursing services, appliances, drugs, medicine, ambulance service, and other health services or related items as the governing board of any corporation may approve; but no corporation subject to the provisions of this subtitle may offer to its members or subscribers any certificate or form which would provide for a cash payment or allowance for sickness, accident, disability, or death, other than payments of or toward the charges made by the purveyors of the health services covered by the certificates issued by the corporation; or for any form of casualty or life insurance unless the corporation shall first comply with the statutes of this state applicable to companies offering such forms of insurance. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a corporation from reimbursing its members or subscribers for payments made by them directly to the purveyors of health services covered by certificates for services which members or subscribers have received. </text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 32, sec. 15, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29777</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>