<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.450Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 227.450 to 227.500.   </catch_line><order_by>450Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 227.450 to 227.500 unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Alteration" means any change, modification, or adjustment to an existing electrical system or conduit; </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="3">"Division" means the Electrical Division within the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="4">"Electrical contractor" means any licensed individual, partnership, or corporation that is licensed to engage in, offers to engage in, or advertises or holds itself out to be qualified to engage in designing, planning, superintending, contracting of, or assuming responsibility for the installation, alteration, or repair of any electrical system used for the purpose of furnishing heat, light, or power, and employs electrical workers to engage in this practice. If the electrical contractor is not a master electrician, the electrical contractor shall employ at least one (1) full-time master electrician; </section><section prefix="5">"Electrical system" means any electrical work subject to standards provided within the National Electrical Code as adopted in the Uniform State Building Code, as promulgated by the Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="6">"Electrician" means any person licensed by the department who is employed by an electrical contractor and is engaged in the construction, alteration, or repair of any electrical system used for the purpose of furnishing heat, light, or power; </section><section prefix="7">"Electrical" pertains to the installation, alteration, or repair of wires and conduits for the purpose of transmitting electricity, and the installation of fixtures and equipment in connection therewith; </section><section prefix="8">"Electrical inspector" means any person certified by the commissioner of housing, buildings and construction pursuant to KRS 227.489 who, for compensation, inspects the construction and installation of electrical conductors, fittings, devices, and fixtures for light, heat, or power service equipment to ascertain the compliance with the National Electrical Code incorporated in the Uniform State Building Code promulgated pursuant to KRS 198B.050 or the standards of safety of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="9">"Department" means the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; and </section><section prefix="10">"Repair" means the reconstruction or renewal of any part of an existing building for the purpose of its maintenance. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 403, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 15, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 42, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>