<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.565</section_number><catch_line>Employer's contributions -- Reset of amortization period -- Payment of actuarially required contribution rate.   </catch_line><order_by>565</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Each employer participating in the State Police Retirement System as provided for in KRS 16.505 to 16.652, each employer participating in the County Employees Retirement System as provided for in KRS 78.510 to 78.852, and each employer participating in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System as provided for in KRS 61.510 to 61.705 shall contribute annually to the respective retirement system an amount equal to the percent, as computed under subsection (2) of this section, of the creditable compensation of its employees to be known as the "normal contributions," and an additional amount to be known as the "actuarially accrued liability contribution" which shall be computed by amortizing the total unfunded actuarially accrued liability over a period of thirty (30) years using the level-percentage-of-payroll amortization method. This method shall be used beginning with the 2007 actuarial valuation. The initial thirty (30) year amortization period shall begin with the 2007 actuarial valuation, except as provided by paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">Effective with the 2013 actuarial valuation, the amortization period for the Kentucky Employees Retirement System, the County Employees Retirement System, and the State Police Retirement System shall be reset to a new thirty (30) year period for purposes of calculating the actuarially accrued liability contribution prescribed by this subsection. </section><section prefix="c">Any significant increase in the actuarially accrued liability due to benefit improvements after the 2007 valuation shall be amortized using the level-percentage-of-payroll amortization method over a separate thirty (30) year period commencing in the year of the actuarial valuation in which the benefit improvements are first reflected. </section></section><section prefix="2">The normal contribution rate shall be determined by the entry age normal cost funding method. The actuarially accrued liability shall be determined by actuarial method consistent with the methods prescribed for determining the normal contribution rate. Normal contributions and the actuarially accrued liability contribution shall be determined on actuarial bases adopted by the board. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Normal contribution and the actuarially accrued liability contribution rates shall be determined by the board on the basis of the annual actuarial valuation last preceding the July 1 of a new biennium. </section><section prefix="b">The board may amend contribution rates as of July 1 of the second year of a biennium for the County Employees Retirement System, if it is determined on the basis of a subsequent actuarial valuation that amended contribution rates are necessary to satisfy the requirements of subsections (1) and (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">Effective for employer contribution rates payable on or after July 1, 2014, the board shall not have the authority to amend contribution rates as of July 1 of the second year of the biennium for the Kentucky Employees Retirement System and the State Police Retirement System. </section></section><section prefix="4">The system shall advise each employer prior to the beginning of each biennium, or prior to July 1 of the second year of a biennium for employers participating in the County Employees Retirement System, of any change in the employer contribution rate. Based on the employer contribution rate, each employer shall include in the budget sufficient funds to pay the employer contributions as determined by the board under subsections (1) to (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The General Assembly shall pay the full actuarially required contribution rate, as prescribed by this section, to the Kentucky Employees Retirement System and the State Police Retirement System in fiscal years occurring on or after July 1, 2014. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any other provision of KRS Chapter 61 to the contrary, the board shall establish employer contribution rates for the County Employees Retirement System that will phase in to the full actuarially required contribution for the health insurance fund over a ten (10) year period using the 2007-2008 fiscal year employer contribution for the health insurance fund as a base employer rate and incrementally increasing the employer rate from fiscal year 2008-2009 through fiscal year 2017-2018. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 53, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 77, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 15, effective June 27, 2008. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 24, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 489, sec. 2. effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 246, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 40. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 17. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 34. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 7. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2, provides, "The provisions of subsection (6) of Section 1 of this Act [KRS 61.565(6)] shall become effective for the contribution rates paid by employers participating in the County Employees Retirement System on or after July 1, 2009."(6/27/2008). A manifest clerical or typographical error in 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 15 (this statute), has been corrected in codification by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). (6/27/2008). 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 43, provides "Notwithstanding any provision of KRS 61.565 or 61.702 to the contrary, the employer contribution rates for the County Employees Retirement Systems (sic) from July 1, 2008, through June 30, 2009, shall be 13.5 percent, consisting of 7.76 percent for pension and 5.74 percent for insurance, for nonhazardous duty employees; and 29.5 percent, consisting of 15.04 percent for pension and 14.46 percent for insurance, for hazardous duty employees."  (10/19/2004). 2004 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 9, provides, "Notwithstanding KRS 61.565, the employer contribution rate for an entity participating in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System or State Police Retirement System shall be as follows:  (1)  From July 1, 2004, through June 30, 2005, the contribution rates shall be no  more than 5.89 percent for nonhazardous duty employees, 18.84 percent for  hazardous duty employees, and 21.58 percent for employees of the State  Police Retirement System. This provision shall be retroactive to July 1, 2004;  and  (2) From July 1, 2005, through June 30, 2006, the employer contribution rate shall  be no more than 5.89 percent for nonhazardous duty employees, 18.84 percent  for hazardous duty employees, and 21.58 percent for employees of the State  Police Retirement System." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>