<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-740</section_number><catch_line>Vehicle emission inspection stations. </catch_line><order_by>20-740</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may enter into an agreement with one (1) or more independent contractors, subject to public bidding, to provide for the construction, equipment, establishment, maintenance, and operation of official vehicle emission inspection stations in the numbers and locations required to provide vehicle owners reasonably convenient access to inspection facilities. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall be prohibited from entering into an agreement with any independent contractor who is engaged in the business of manufacturing, selling, maintaining or repairing vehicles and vehicle replacement or repair parts in the Commonwealth, except that the independent contractor shall not be precluded from maintaining or repairing any vehicle owned or operated by the independent contractor. </section><section prefix="3">The agreement authorized by this section shall contain provisions relating to the following: <section prefix="a">That the Commonwealth shall not be required to purchase any asset or assume any liability if the agreement is not renewed; </section><section prefix="b">That the contractor is authorized to collect the inspection fee for a test in the amount fixed by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">That the Commonwealth shall be reimbursed by the contractor for not less than ten percent (10%) of the inspection fee, except for programs operated by air pollution control districts; </section><section prefix="d">That reports and documentation shall be submitted to the cabinet if required concerning the operation of the official vehicle emission inspection stations; and </section><section prefix="e">That the cabinet has discretion to investigate the operation of the official vehicle emission inspection stations as the conditions and circumstances of the operation may indicate, and that the cabinet may revoke the contract if it finds that the stations are not operated in accordance with KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765 or that the contractor has failed or refused to submit records or documentation required by KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section></section><section prefix="4">The agreement may contain any provisions deemed necessary by the cabinet for the administration or enforcement of KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.474. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10370</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>