<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.070</section_number><catch_line>Contents of application -- Documentation to be submitted -- Certificate of registration or renewal denied, when. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person seeking a title and registration or renewal registration for operation of a motorboat shall apply to the county clerk of the county as provided in KRS 235.050 and make application on a form furnished by the Transportation Cabinet. The application shall contain the full name and signature, Social Security number or federal tax identification number, citizenship of applicant, date of birth, sex, present resident address, situs for ad valorem tax assessment, the make of the boat, hull identification number (HIN), if any, length, beam, model, and horsepower of motor, maximum capacity, type of hull material, intended use of the boat, and whether the fuel is gasoline, diesel, or other. The application shall state whether the motorboat is equipped with marine toilet facilities and shall state if the marine sanitation device for the toilet is properly operating and properly used for the water body where the motorboat is kept or operated. It shall also state whether the applicant has been previously licensed or registered as an owner, and if so, when and by what state or county, whether any license registration or certificate number has been canceled, suspended, revoked, or refused, and if so, the date of and reason for cancellation, suspension, revocation, or refusal, and such other information as may be required. </section><section prefix="2">Every applicant shall submit the motorboat title or registration with the application as required below: <section prefix="a">If the motorboat is titled in Kentucky, the applicant shall submit the title with the application for title and registration; </section><section prefix="b">If the motorboat is registered in Kentucky but has not been titled in Kentucky, the applicant shall submit the certificate of registration with the application for title and registration; </section><section prefix="c">If the applicant is applying for a registration renewal, he shall submit the certificate of registration; </section><section prefix="d">If the motorboat is titled in another jurisdiction, the applicant shall submit the title with the application for title and registration; </section><section prefix="e">If the motorboat is registered in another jurisdiction, but not titled in any jurisdiction, the applicant shall submit the certificate of registration with the application for title and registration; and </section><section prefix="f">Vessels holding a United States certificate of documentation shall be exempt from the provisions of this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">Every applicant shall certify that the statements made in the application are true. The clerk shall inform the applicant that making false statements on the application regarding a marine boat toilet may lead to being fined under KRS 235.990. </section><section prefix="4">The clerk shall, after determining that the applicant has complied with the law concerning applications, issue a current certificate of registration or renewal thereof. </section><section prefix="5">No certificate of registration or renewal thereof for the operation of a motorboat shall be issued, if the motorboat is equipped with toilet facilities but is not equipped with a storage container or treatment or disposal system of a type approved under regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 263, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 6. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  1998 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 13 provides that the amendment to this statute in that Act "shall be enforced until July 15, 2000, only by the issuance of a warning and the distribution of information about Sections 1 to 8 of [that] Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11050</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>