<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.030</section_number><catch_line>Rationale and purpose of program -- Division of Emergency Management. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The General Assembly recognizes that the rationale and purpose of the comprehensive emergency management program of the Commonwealth has evolved from a program for response to threats to national security, enemy attack, and other national defense needs, to a program for response to all hazards, but primarily, domestic hazards and threats including natural, man-made, technological, industrial, or environmental emergencies or disasters, for which civil government is primarily responsible. Because of major changes in the rationale and necessity for emergency management capabilities, as well as the urgent requirement for multiagency participation and inter-agency coordination to ensure timely, effective, and appropriate disaster and emergency response in the Commonwealth, and to otherwise modernize and improve the administration, effectiveness, and relevance of the comprehensive emergency management program for the contemporary needs of the citizens of the Commonwealth, the General Assembly declares: <section prefix="1">A Division of Emergency Management is hereby created as the emergency management agency of state government which shall develop the comprehensive emergency management program of the Commonwealth on behalf of the Governor, and in consultation with the cabinet secretaries of state government, other appropriate state agency heads, local elected chief executives, local emergency management directors, and local emergency planning committees, for the purpose of developing and enhancing comprehensive emergency management program policies, plans, or procedures to provide for a coordinated responsive, and integrated emergency management system in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">The division may accept on behalf of the Commonwealth any grant, contribution, or fund, federal or otherwise, made to assist in meeting the costs of carrying out the provisions and purposes of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, and fully comply with all funding requirements imposed by the receipt and use of the grant, contribution, or fund; and </section><section prefix="3">The term "Division of Emergency Management" shall constitute and designate the official name of the emergency management agency of state government created pursuant to subsection (1) of this section and "Division of Emergency Management," in the exact order or form as specified in this subsection, shall not be utilized by or assigned to any other agency of state or local government, or other state or local entity, or any political subdivision of the Commonwealth to constitute or designate the official name of any such agency, entity, or political subdivision. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>