<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="316" order_by="316">EMBALMERS AND FUNERAL DIRECTORS </unit></structure><section_number>316.030</section_number><catch_line>Embalmer's license -- Qualifications -- Funeral director's license -- Qualifications -- Restriction on place of practice -- Apprenticeship. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in, or attempt to engage in, embalming or funeral directing in the Commonwealth of Kentucky unless the person is licensed under the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">All Kentucky-licensed persons who practice embalming or funeral directing in Kentucky shall practice from a funeral establishment that is licensed to operate under the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member of every firm, and one (1) officer and one (1) stockholder of every corporation, that engages in embalming and funeral directing in Kentucky, shall be a Kentucky-licensed embalmer and a Kentucky-licensed funeral director. </section><section prefix="4">One board shall issue an embalmer's license to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">Has graduated from high school or possesses a High School Equivalency Diploma; </section><section prefix="d">Has received an associate degree in funeral services from a college or university accredited by the American Board of Funeral Service Education; </section><section prefix="e">Has served an apprenticeship of one (1) year in a Kentucky funeral establishment under the supervision of a Kentucky-licensed embalmer; </section><section prefix="f">Has taken an active part during the apprenticeship in assisting with the embalming of at least twenty-five (25) dead human bodies under the direct supervision of a Kentucky-licensed embalmer; </section><section prefix="g">Has paid to the board an examination fee of seventy-five dollars ($75); and </section><section prefix="h">Has passed an examination prepared or approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall issue a funeral director's license to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">Has graduated from high school or possesses a High School Equivalency Diploma; </section><section prefix="d">Has served an apprenticeship of three (3) consecutive years in a Kentucky funeral establishment under the supervision of a Kentucky-licensed funeral director. An associate degree in funeral services from a college or university accredited by the American Board of Funeral Service Education shall substitute for two (2) years of the apprenticeship. The completion of thirty (30) semester credit hours or the equivalent from an accredited college or university shall substitute for one (1) year of the apprenticeship. At no time shall more than two (2) years of the apprenticeship be substituted; </section><section prefix="e">Has taken an active part during the apprenticeship in assisting with the management of at least twenty-five (25) funerals under the direct supervision of a Kentucky-licensed funeral director; </section><section prefix="f">Has paid to the board an examination fee of seventy-five dollars ($75); and </section><section prefix="g">Has passed an examination prepared or approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="6">An applicant may serve embalming and funeral directing apprenticeships concurrently. </section><section prefix="7">At the beginning of an apprenticeship, an applicant for an embalmer's or a funeral director's license shall: <section prefix="a">Appear before the board; </section><section prefix="b">Pay to the board a registration fee of thirty dollars ($30); and </section><section prefix="c">File with the board the sworn statement of the supervising Kentucky-licensed embalmer or the Kentucky-licensed funeral director averring that the applicant will work full-time under supervision in the funeral establishment and will receive a regular salary. </section></section><section prefix="8">An applicant shall work full-time in the funeral establishment during the apprenticeship and shall receive a regular salary. </section><section prefix="9">An applicant shall file with the board semiannually during the apprenticeship sworn statements by the applicant and the supervising Kentucky-licensed embalmer or Kentucky-licensed funeral director setting out the number of hours worked, the number of embalmings or funerals in which the applicant has assisted, and the salary received. </section><section prefix="10">A Kentucky-licensed embalmer or a Kentucky-licensed funeral director shall not supervise more than five (5) applicants serving apprenticeships at any one (1) time. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 9. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 3, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599a-7. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31055</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>