<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-140</section_number><catch_line>Benchmarks to measure performance of economy and progress -- Periodic evaluations of projects and programs. </catch_line><order_by>10-140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall establish objective benchmarks to measure the performance of Kentucky's economy and progress toward achievement of the mission statement, goals, and guiding principles. Criteria used in establishing the benchmarks shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Use of the statistical information commonly provided by governmental agencies, or specific data gathered by authorization of the board; </section><section prefix="b">Comparison of regions and areas within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">Comparisons of Kentucky to other states, the nation, and international areas; </section><section prefix="d">Inclusion of measures of income, earnings, and employment; and </section><section prefix="e">Goals for achievement of appropriate levels over time. </section></section><section prefix="2">Examples of appropriate benchmarks include, but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Kentucky's gross state product as compared with the midwestern and southeastern states and the United States gross national product; </section><section prefix="b">Personal income data used to compare Kentucky to national income and an average of benchmark states; </section><section prefix="c">Wage and salary growth compared by counties, regions, and states; and </section><section prefix="d">Earnings-weighted job indices to compare metropolitan areas, rural areas, and other subdivisions of the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">The University of Kentucky, Center for Business and Economic Research, and the University of Louisville, Bureau of Economic Research, annually shall prepare jointly and submit to the Governor, the General Assembly, and the board a report detailing and grading Kentucky's progress with regard to each benchmark. The board shall publish the report and make it available to the public at no cost. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall evaluate the effectiveness of established implementation activities. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall conduct periodic evaluations of projects funded or otherwise assisted by the cabinet to determine the return on cabinet investments and to ensure compliance with commitments made as conditions of cabinet investment. Results of the evaluations shall be reported to the board, the General Assembly, and the public. </section><section prefix="6">The board may retain outside independent agencies to evaluate the effectiveness of economic development programs and systems and to certify the results of reports prepared pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>