<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.207</section_number><catch_line>Declaration and payment of estimated tax required by KRS 141.206. </catch_line><order_by>207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The declaration and payment of estimated tax required by KRS 141.206(6) shall contain the following information: <section prefix="a">For a nonresident individual partner, member, or shareholder, the amount of estimated tax calculated under KRS 141.020 for the taxable year; and </section><section prefix="b">For a corporate partner or member that is doing business in Kentucky only through its ownership interest in a pass-through entity, the amount of estimated tax calculated under KRS 141.040 for the taxable year. </section></section><section prefix="2">The declaration of estimated tax required under this section shall be filed with the department by the pass-through entity in the same manner and at the same times as provided by: <section prefix="a">KRS 141.300, for a nonresident individual partner, member, or shareholder; and </section><section prefix="b">KRS 141.042, for a corporate partner or member. </section></section><section prefix="3">The payment of estimated tax shall be made in installments by the pass-through entity in the same manner and at the same times as provided by: <section prefix="a">KRS 141.305, for a nonresident individual partner, member, or shareholder; and </section><section prefix="b">KRS 141.044, for a corporate partner or member. </section></section><section prefix="4">A pass-through entity required to make a declaration and payment of estimated tax shall be subject to the penalty provisions of KRS 131.180 and 141.990 for any declaration underpayment or any installment not paid on time. </section></text><history> Created 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 5, effective June 4, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 4, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29092</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>