<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.29-311</section_number><catch_line>Suspension, revocation, or refusal of license of foreign or alien society. </catch_line><order_by>29-311</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the commissioner upon investigation finds that a foreign or alien society transacting or applying to transact business in this state: <section prefix="a">Has exceeded its powers; </section><section prefix="b">Has failed to comply with any of the provisions of this subtitle; </section><section prefix="c">Is not fulfilling its contracts in good faith; or </section><section prefix="d">Is conducting its business fraudulently or in a manner hazardous to its members or creditors or the public; </section></section> the commissioner shall notify the society of the deficiency or deficiencies and state in writing the reasons for his or her dissatisfaction. The commissioner shall issue a written notice to the society requiring that the deficiency or deficiencies which exist are corrected. After the notice, the society shall have a thirty (30) day period in which to comply with the commissioner's request for correction; and if the society fails to comply, the commissioner shall notify the society of the findings of noncompliance and require the society to show cause on a date named why its license should not be suspended, revoked, or refused. If on that date the society does not present good and sufficient reason why its authority to do business in this state should not be suspended, revoked, or refused, the commissioner may suspend or refuse the license of the society to do business in this state until satisfactory evidence is furnished to the commissioner that suspension or refusal should be withdrawn or the commissioner may revoke the authority of the society to do business in this state. <section prefix="2">Nothing contained in this section shall be taken or construed as preventing any society from continuing in good faith all contracts made in this state during the time the society was legally authorized to transact business herein. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1402, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 31, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>