<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.170</section_number><catch_line>Approved electric lamps and multigas detectors required -- Unauthorized devices for making lights and fires forbidden. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All underground mines shall be worked exclusively by the use of approved electric lamps for personal lighting. </section><section prefix="2">A mine operator shall provide an MSHA-approved, handheld, multigas detector that can measure methane, oxygen, and carbon monoxide to each group of two (2) or more miners working in close proximity of each other underground, the foreman, fireboss, and to each person who works alone, such as pumpers, examiners, and outby miners. The mine operator shall make available one (1) multigas detector at the working face for use by any miner working on the section. Miners shall be trained in the proper use and calibration of the multigas detectors and shall document that the training has been provided. Signs shall be prominently posted at places miners gather with instructions on the proper use of multi-gas detectors. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall at any time carry into any mine any intoxicants. No person shall at any time enter any underground mine with matches, pipes, cigars, cigarettes, or any device for making lights or fire not authorized or approved, and the licensee shall at frequent intervals search, or cause to be searched, any person entering or about to enter the mine or inside the mine, to prevent the person from taking, carrying, or using the articles therein. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 18, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 32, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 16. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 24, effective March 25, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-26. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32992</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>