<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.390</section_number><catch_line>Members and shareholders -- Requirements for membership. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each incorporator of a cooperative shall be a member thereof but no other person may become a member thereof unless such other person agrees to use telephone service furnished by the cooperative when it is made available through its facilities. Membership in a cooperative shall be evidenced by a certificate of membership which shall not be transferable, except as provided in the bylaws. The bylaws may prescribe additional qualifications and limitations in respect of membership, provided that ownership of shares of stock, if any are authorized, shall not be a condition of membership in the cooperative. </section><section prefix="2">In case the issuance of shares of stock is provided for in the articles of incorporation, ownership thereof shall be evidenced by share certificates. No share of stock shall be issued except for cash, or for property at its fair value, in an amount equal to the par value of such share of stock. </section><section prefix="3">Membership and share certificates shall contain such provisions, consistent with KRS 279.310 to 279.600 and the articles of incorporation of the cooperative, as shall be prescribed by its bylaws. </section><section prefix="4">No member or shareholder shall be liable or responsible for any debts of the cooperative and the property of the members and shareholders shall not be subject to execution therefor except as the member or shareholder may become personally liable by reason of his or her own acts or conduct. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 48, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 9, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>