<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.320</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by special nonbeverage alcohol license -- Issuance to certain charitable, public, or private institutions -- Federal ethanol permit.   </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A special nonbeverage alcohol license shall authorize the holder to purchase alcohol for nonbeverage purposes only from the holder of a distiller's license, wholesaler's license, or distributor's license and possess alcohol for use in the manufacture and sale of any of the following products, when they are unfit for beverage purposes: <section prefix="a">Denatured alcohol produced, and sold pursuant to Acts of Congress and regulations promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="b">Patent, proprietary, medicinal, pharmaceutical, antiseptic, and toilet preparations; </section><section prefix="c">Flavoring extracts, syrups, and food products; and </section><section prefix="d">Scientific, chemical, mechanical, and industrial products. </section></section><section prefix="2">KRS Chapter 242 shall not prevent the issuance of special nonbeverage alcohol licenses to persons located in dry or moist territory nor prevent licensees from exercising the privileges granted in the license. </section><section prefix="3">A special nonbeverage alcohol license may also be issued to any duly authorized and bona fide hospital, museum, laboratory, charitable, educational, or similar public or private institution, to a drug store employing a licensed pharmacist, or to a licensed physician. The license shall authorize the licensee to purchase or possess alcohol and to use it only for nonbeverage purposes. </section><section prefix="4">The holder of a special nonbeverage alcohol license may produce, possess, and use alcohol in the manufacture of nonbeverage fuel ethanol if the holder also holds a basic permit from the applicable federal agency authorizing ethanol production. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 72, effective June 25, 2013. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-127. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43039</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>