<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.135</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities -- Members -- Executive Director -- Duties -- Autism Spectrum Disorders Subcommittee.   </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities is created within the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities is established to comply with the requirements of the Developmental Disabilities Act of 1984 and any subsequent amendment to that act. </section><section prefix="3">The members of the Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities shall be appointed by the Governor to serve as advocates for persons with developmental disabilities. The council shall be composed of twenty-six (26) members. <section prefix="a">Ten (10) members shall be representatives of: the principal state agencies administering funds provided under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 as amended; the state agency that administers funds provided under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA); the state agency that administers funds provided under the Older Americans Act of 1965 as amended; the single state agency designated by the Governor for administration of Title XIX of the Social Security Act for persons with developmental disabilities; higher education training facilities, each university-affiliated program or satellite center in the Commonwealth; and the protection and advocacy system established under Public Law 101-496. These members shall represent the following: <section prefix="1">Office of Vocational Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="2">Office for the Blind; </section><section prefix="3">Division of Exceptional Children, within the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="4">Department for Aging and Independent Living; </section><section prefix="5">Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="6">Department of Public Advocacy, Protection and Advocacy Division; </section><section prefix="7">University-affiliated programs; </section><section prefix="8">Local and nongovernmental agencies and private nonprofit groups concerned with services for persons with developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="9">Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; and </section><section prefix="10">Department for Public Health, Division of Maternal and Child Health. </section></section><section prefix="b">At least sixty percent (60%) of the members of the council shall be composed of persons with developmental disabilities or the parents or guardians of persons, or immediate relatives or guardians of persons with mentally impairing developmental disabilities, who are not managing employees or persons with ownership or controlling interest in any other entity that receives funds or provides services under the Developmental Disabilities Act of 1984 as amended and who are not employees of a state agency that receives funds or provides services under this section. Of these members, five (5) members shall be persons with developmental disabilities, and five (5) members shall be parents or guardians of children with developmental disabilities or immediate relatives or guardians of adults with mentally impairing developmental disabilities who cannot advocate for themselves. Six (6) members shall be a combination of individuals in these two (2) groups, and at least one (1) of these members shall be an immediate relative or guardian of an institutionalized or previously institutionalized person with a developmental disability or an individual with a developmental disability who resides in an institution or who previously resided in an institution. </section><section prefix="c">Members not representing principal state agencies shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years. Members shall serve no more than two (2) consecutive three (3) year terms. Members shall serve until their successors are appointed or until they are removed for cause. </section><section prefix="d">The council shall elect its own chair, adopt bylaws, and operate in accordance with its bylaws. Members of the council who are not state employees shall be reimbursed for necessary and actual expenses. The cabinet shall provide personnel adequate to insure that the council has the capacity to fulfill its responsibilities. The council shall be headed by an executive director. If the executive director position becomes vacant, the council shall be responsible for the recruitment and hiring of a new executive director. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities shall: <section prefix="a">Develop, in consultation with the cabinet, and implement the state plan as required by Part B of the Developmental Disabilities Act of 1984, as amended, with a goal of development of a coordinated consumer and family centered focus and direction, including the specification of priority services required by that plan; </section><section prefix="b">Monitor, review, and evaluate, not less often than annually, the implementation and effectiveness of the state plan in meeting the plan's objectives; </section><section prefix="c">To the maximum extent feasible, review and comment on all state plans that relate to persons with developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="d">Submit to the secretary of the cabinet, the commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, and the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services any periodic reports on its activities as required by the United States Department of Health and Human Services and keep records and afford access as the cabinet finds necessary to verify the reports; </section><section prefix="e">Serve as an advocate for individuals with developmental disabilities and conduct programs, projects, and activities that promote systematic change and capacity building; </section><section prefix="f">Examine, not less than once every five (5) years, the provision of and need for federal and state priority areas to address, on a statewide and comprehensive basis, urgent needs for services, supports, and other assistance for individuals with developmental disabilities and their families; and </section><section prefix="g">Prepare, approve, and implement a budget that includes amounts paid to the state under the Developmental Disabilities Act of 1984, as amended, to fund all programs, projects, and activities under that Act. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities shall appoint a subcommittee, which shall include members of the Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders, to monitor the implementation of the state plan as developed by the commission beginning October 1, 2006. The subcommittee shall prepare, and the council shall submit, the report as required under KRS 194A.622 (10). </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch, 146, sec. 22, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 17, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 118, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 156, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 138, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40939</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>