<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-675</section_number><catch_line>Coverage for services received in an assisted living community or adult day care facility. </catch_line><order_by>14-675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any short-term nursing home insurance policy issued on or after July 15, 2002, which provides coverage for assisted living benefits shall cover services received in any assisted living community which: <section prefix="a">Meets the requirements of KRS 194A.700 to 194A.729 and any administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 194A.700 to 194A.729; and </section><section prefix="b">Meets any additional requirements of an assisted living community set forth in the short-term nursing home insurance policy approved by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any short-term nursing home insurance policy issued on or after July 15, 2002, which provides coverage for adult day care services shall cover services received in any adult day care facility which: <section prefix="a">Meets the requirements of KRS 205.950 or 216B.0443 and any administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 205.950 or 216B.0443; and </section><section prefix="b">Meets any additional requirements of an adult day care center set forth in the short-term nursing home insurance policy approved by the commissioner. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1174, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17193</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>