<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.431</section_number><catch_line>School finance officer -- Certification requirements -- Continuing education -- Financial reports. </catch_line><order_by>431</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local district superintendent shall appoint a finance officer who shall be responsible for the cash, investment, and financial management of the school district. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A person initially employed as a school finance officer on or after July 1, 2015, shall obtain certification from the Department of Education prior to holding the position and entering the duties of the position of school finance officer. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to prescribe the criteria and procedures to be used in the certification process for a school finance officer. </section><section prefix="c">The administrative regulations promulgated under this subsection shall specify: <section prefix="1">The initial qualification requirements for school finance officer certification; </section><section prefix="2">The certification application and appeal process; and </section><section prefix="3">The certification renewal process. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The school finance officer shall be required to complete forty-two (42) hours of continuing education every two (2) years from a provider approved by the Department of Education. The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to identify and prescribe the criteria for fulfilling the requirements of this subsection. The administrative regulations shall specify: <section prefix="a">The topics of continuing education; </section><section prefix="b">Qualifications for continuing education providers; </section><section prefix="c">Consequences for failure to meet the continuing education requirement; and  </section><section prefix="d">Requirements for reinstatement of school finance officer certification.  </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The finance officer shall present a detailed monthly financial report for board approval to include the previous month's revenues and expenditures of the district. The monthly report shall be posted on the district's Web site for a minimum of six (6) months after its approval. </section><section prefix="b">Within six (6) months following the end of each fiscal year, the finance officer shall submit to the Kentucky Department of Education a detailed annual financial report to include the district's total assets, liabilities, revenues, and expenditures. The annual report shall be posted on the district's Web site and department's Web site for a minimum of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The Department of Education shall review each district's annual financial report and shall provide, within two (2) months of receipt, the local board of education a written report indicating the financial status of the district. The department's written report shall be posted on the department's Web site and the district's Web site for a minimum of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of education shall annually present to the Interim Joint Committee on Education a copy of the department's written report for each district.  </section></section><section prefix="d">Nothing in this subsection shall lessen the obligation of a school district to publish its financial statements in accordance with the provisions of KRS 424.220. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43528</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>