<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.707</section_number><catch_line>Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee -- Co-chairs -- Membership -- Duties.   </catch_line><order_by>707</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault shall create a Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee. </section><section prefix="2">The Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee shall be co-chaired by the executive director of the Kentucky Association of Sexual Assault Programs and the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police or the commissioner's designee. </section><section prefix="3">The membership of the Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee shall consist of the following: <section prefix="a">The executive director of the Kentucky Board of Nursing or the executive director's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The executive director of the Kentucky Nurses Association or the executive director's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The executive director of the Kentucky Hospital Association or the executive director's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The director of the Department of Kentucky State Police Crime Lab; </section><section prefix="e">The chief medical examiner or the chief medical examiner's designee; </section><section prefix="f">The commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="g">The director of the Victims' Advocacy Division of the Office of the Attorney General or the director's designee; </section><section prefix="h">A sexual assault nurse examiner serving on the Governor's Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault; </section><section prefix="i">A representative from a sexual assault response team serving on the Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault; </section><section prefix="j">A physician appointed by the co-chairs of the Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault; and </section><section prefix="k">A Commonwealth's attorney or an assistant Commonwealth's attorney appointed by the co-chairs of the Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault. </section></section><section prefix="4">Members appointed under subsection (3)(h) to (k) of this section shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authority and shall not serve longer than four (4) years without reappointment. </section><section prefix="5">The Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee shall: <section prefix="a">Serve in an advisory capacity to the Kentucky Board of Nursing in accomplishing the duties set forth under KRS 314.142; </section><section prefix="b">Serve in an advisory capacity to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet in the development of the statewide sexual assault protocol required under KRS 216B.400(4); </section><section prefix="c">Develop a model protocol for the operation of sexual assault response teams which shall include the roles of sexual assault nurse examiners, physicians, law enforcement, prosecutors, and victim advocates; </section><section prefix="d">Provide information and recommendations concerning the activities of the agency or organization represented by each individual committee member as related to sexual assault issues and programs within the purview of the agency or organization; and </section><section prefix="e">Recommend to the Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault any changes in statute, administrative regulation, training, policy, and budget to promote a multidisciplinary response to sexual assault. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 69, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 305, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 69, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40962</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>