<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.550</section_number><catch_line>Specific authority over oil and gas operators. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>Without limiting its general authority, the department shall have the specific authority to require of and from all operators of any oil or gas property in this Commonwealth: <section prefix="1">Identification of producing leases, submitted on the form on which production is required by the department to be reported; </section><section prefix="2">The making of driller's logs, and filing of all logs and downhole surveys made; </section><section prefix="3">The drilling, casing, operation, and plugging of wells in such manner as to prevent: <section prefix="a">The escape of oil or gas from one pool into another, or into mineral bearing stratum; </section><section prefix="b">The detrimental intrusion of water into an oil or gas pool or into mineral-bearing stratum that is avoidable by efficient operations; and </section><section prefix="c">Blowouts, cavings, seepages, and fires; </section></section><section prefix="4">The filing of the reports and plats with the department for transmittal to the Kentucky Geological Survey as may be prescribed by rules and regulations promulgated hereunder. All such reports and plats shall be transmitted by the department to the Kentucky Geological Survey within thirty (30) days after receipt thereof by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 7, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33109</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>