<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.0734</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 177.0734 and 177.0736. </catch_line><order_by>0734</order_by><text>As used in KRS 177.0734 and 177.0736, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Fully controlled access highways" means highways, limited to interstate and state parkways, that shall give preference to through traffic, shall have access only at selected public roads or streets, shall have no highway grade crossing or intersection, and shall further conform with the Federal Highway Administration's (FHWA's) adopted standards as contained in Federal Highway Program Manual (FHPM) 6-8-3-8 and to administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="2">"Logo signs" means signs that consist of a business identification symbol, name, brand, trademark, or combination thereof that may be attached to specific service signs, pursuant to the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="3">"Specific service signs" means official signs, erected on the rights-of-ways of fully controlled or partially controlled access highways or roads as defined in KRS 177.010, that shall include, but not be limited to, the display of the words "Gas", "Food", "Lodging", "Attractions", or "Camping" or combinations thereof and shall have space for one (1) or more logo signs that may be attached to the official signs. The erection and maintenance of the official signs shall conform with the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A; and </section><section prefix="4">"Partially controlled access highway" means a highway that gives preference to through traffic, that has access only at selected public roads or streets, and that may have a limited number of highway at-grade intersections and private driveway connections. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5256</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>