<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.220</section_number><catch_line>Legislative intent. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby recognizes that certain streams of Kentucky possess outstanding and unique scenic, recreational, geological, fish and wildlife, botanical, historical, archaeological and other scientific, aesthetic, and cultural values. It is the policy of the General Assembly to complement dam construction and development projects on Kentucky watercourses with other equally important and beneficial uses of our water resources. Therefore, it is hereby declared that in order to afford the citizens of the Commonwealth an opportunity to enjoy natural streams, to attract out-of-state visitors, to assure the well-being of our tourist industry, to preserve for future generations the beauty of certain areas untrammeled by man, it is in the interest of the Commonwealth to preserve some streams or portions thereof in their free-flowing condition because their natural, scenic, scientific, and aesthetic values outweigh their value for water development and control purposes now and in the future. For aesthetic, as well as ecological reasons, the foremost priority shall be to preserve the unique primitive character of those streams in Kentucky which still retain a large portion of their natural and scenic beauty, and to prevent future infringement on that beauty by impoundments or other man-made works. Since the stream areas are to be maintained in a natural state, they will also serve as areas for the perpetuation of Kentucky's wild fauna and flora. Few such streams remain in the Eastern portion of the United States, and the General Assembly feels a strong obligation to the people of Kentucky to preserve these remnants of their proud heritage. It is the purpose of KRS 146.200 to 146.360 to establish a Wild Rivers System by designating certain streams for immediate inclusion in the system and by prescribing the procedures and criteria for protecting and administering the system. It is not the intent of KRS 146.200 to 146.360 to require or to authorize acquisition of all lands or interests in lands within the boundaries of the stream areas but to assure preservation of the scenic, ecological and other values and to provide proper management of the recreational, wildlife, water and other resources. It is the intent of KRS 146.200 to 146.360 to impose reasonable regulations as to the use of private and public land within the authorized boundaries of wild rivers for the general welfare of the people of the Commonwealth, and where necessary, to enable the department to acquire easements or lesser interests in or fee title to lands within the authorized boundaries of the wild rivers, so that the public trust in these unique natural rivers might be kept. </text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 2. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29304</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>