<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.035</section_number><catch_line>Family accountability, intervention, and response teams -- Purpose -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created in each judicial district a family accountability, intervention, and response team that shall develop enhanced case management plans and opportunities for services for children referred to the team. The family accountability, intervention, and response team shall consist of not more than fifteen (15) persons. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the team shall include the following representatives as appointed by their agencies or organizations: <section prefix="a">A court-designated worker in that judicial circuit or district; </section><section prefix="b">The members of the regional interagency council specified in KRS 200.509(1)(a) to (d) and (f), or corresponding members of the local interagency council if one exists; </section><section prefix="c">A representative from the cabinet knowledgeable about services available through the cabinet and authorized to facilitate access to services; </section><section prefix="d">A representative from the office of a county attorney within the judicial district; </section><section prefix="e">A representative from the Department for Public Advocacy; </section><section prefix="f">A representative from a local public school within the judicial district; </section><section prefix="g">A representative of law enforcement; and  </section><section prefix="h">Other persons interested in juvenile justice issues, as identified by the family accountability, intervention, and response team, who are necessary for a complete representation of resources within each judicial circuit or district. </section></section><section prefix="3">A court-designated worker from within the judicial circuit or district shall lead the team and be responsible for convening and staffing the team. </section><section prefix="4">The team shall adopt a case management approach and process for reviewing: <section prefix="a">Referrals from the court-designated worker involving cases in which a child has failed to appear for a preliminary intake inquiry, declined to enter into a diversion agreement, or failed to complete the terms of the agreement; and </section><section prefix="b">Status offense cases if the court-designated worker, after reviewing the complaint, has determined that no further action is necessary. </section></section><section prefix="5">After reviewing the actions taken by the court-designated worker, including referrals made for the child and his or her family, efforts to address barriers to successful completion, and whether other appropriate services are available to address the needs of the child and his or her family, the team may: <section prefix="a">Refer the case back to the court-designated worker to take further action as recommended by the team; or </section><section prefix="b">Advise the court-designated worker to refer the case to the county attorney if the team has no further recommendations to offer. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 26, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43500</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>