<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.020</section_number><catch_line>Major organizational units. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall consist of the following major organizational units: <section prefix="a">The Office of the Secretary, which shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">The secretary to be appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.255; and </section><section prefix="2">The deputy secretary appointed under KRS 12.040; </section></section><section prefix="b">The Department of Highways, headed by a commissioner, appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="c">The Department of Vehicle Regulation, headed by a commissioner, appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.040. The Motor Vehicle Commission established in KRS 190.058 shall be attached to the Department of Vehicle Regulation for administrative purposes; </section><section prefix="d">The Department of Rural and Municipal Aid, headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="e">The Department of Aviation, headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.040. The Kentucky Airport Zoning Commission established by KRS 183.861 shall be attached to the Department of Aviation for administrative purposes; </section><section prefix="f">The Office of Support Services, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="g">The Office of Transportation Delivery, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="h">The Office of Audits, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="i">The Office of Human Resource Management, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="j">The Office of Information Technology, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="k">The Office of Legal Services, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="l">The following offices, which shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary: <section prefix="1">The Office of Public Affairs, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="2">The Office of Budget and Fiscal Management, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section><section prefix="3">The Office for Civil Rights and Small Business Development, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; and </section><section prefix="4">The Office of Inspector General, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; </section></section><section prefix="m">The following offices, which shall be attached to the Department of Highways: <section prefix="1">The Office of Project Development, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040, who shall be a registered professional engineer under KRS Chapter 322, and who shall be known as the deputy state highway engineer for project development; </section><section prefix="2">The Office of Project Delivery and Preservation, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040, who shall be a registered professional engineer under KRS Chapter 322, and who shall be known as the deputy state highway engineer for project delivery and preservation; </section><section prefix="3">The Office of Highway Safety, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; and </section><section prefix="4">Highway District Offices One through Twelve, each district office to be headed by an executive director, also known as the chief district engineer, appointed under KRS 12.040, who shall be a registered professional engineer under KRS Chapter 322; and </section></section><section prefix="n">The following offices, which shall be attached to the Department of Rural and Municipal Aid: <section prefix="1">Office of Local Programs, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040; and </section><section prefix="2">Office of Rural and Secondary Roads, headed by an executive director appointed under KRS 12.040. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The position of director in the Division of Environmental Analysis is a policy-making position under KRS 18A.175. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 12, sec. 45, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 417, sec. 2, effective December 1, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 333, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 406, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 34. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009). During the processing of Senate Bill 182, which became 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, the following sentence was inadvertently inserted twice in subsection (1) of this statute: "The Motor Vehicle Commission established in KRS 190.058 shall be attached to the Department of Vehicle Regulation for administrative purposes." This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected during codification by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h).  (6/25/2009). This section was amended by 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12 and 13, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>