<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.501</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 250.491 to 250.631. </catch_line><order_by>501</order_by><text>As used in KRS 250.491 to 250.631: <section prefix="1">"Person" includes individual, partnership, corporation, and association; </section><section prefix="2">"Distribute" means to offer for sale, sell, exchange, or barter commercial feed; </section><section prefix="3">"Distributor" means any person who distributes; </section><section prefix="4">"Commercial feed" means all materials except unmixed seed, whole and unprocessed, when not adulterated within the meaning of KRS 250.541(1) which are offered for sale as feed or for mixing in feed. The director by administrative regulation may exempt from this definition, or from specific provision of KRS 250.491 to 250.631, commodities such as hay, straw, stover, silage, cobs, husks, hulls, and individual chemical compounds or substances when the commodities, compounds, or substances are not intermixed or mixed with other materials, and are not adulterated within the meaning of KRS 250.541(1); </section><section prefix="5">"Feed ingredient" means each of the constituent materials making up a commercial feed; </section><section prefix="6">"Mineral feed" means a commercial feed intended to supply primarily mineral elements or inorganic nutrients; </section><section prefix="7">"Drug" means any article intended for use in the diagnosis, cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of disease in animals other than man and articles other than feed intended to affect the structure or any function of the animal body; </section><section prefix="8">"Customer-formula feed" means commercial feed which consists of: <section prefix="a">A mixture of two (2) or more commercial feeds; </section><section prefix="b">A mixture of one (1) or more commercial feeds and one (1) or more feed ingredients; or </section><section prefix="c">A mixture of two (2) or more feed ingredients; </section></section> each batch of which is manufactured according to the specific instructions of the final purchaser; <section prefix="9">"Manufacture" means to grind, mix or blend, or further process a commercial feed for distribution; </section><section prefix="10">"Brand name" means any word, name, symbol, or device, or any combination thereof, identifying the commercial feed of a distributor or registrant and distinguishing it from that of others; </section><section prefix="11">"Product name" means the name of the commercial feed which identifies it as to kind, class, or specific use; </section><section prefix="12">"Label" means a display of written, printed, or graphic matter upon or affixed to the container in which a commercial feed is distributed, or on the invoice or delivery slip with which a commercial feed is distributed; </section><section prefix="13">"Labeling" means written, printed, or graphic matter used in promoting the sale of feed; </section><section prefix="14">"Ton" means a net weight of two thousand (2,000) pounds avoirdupois or nine hundred eight (908) kilograms; </section><section prefix="15">"Percent" or "percentages" means percentages by weights; </section><section prefix="16">"Official sample" means a sample of feed taken by the director or his agent in accordance with the provisions of subsections (3), (5), or (6) of KRS 250.581; </section><section prefix="17">"Pet food" means any commercial feed prepared and distributed for consumption by pets; </section><section prefix="18">"Offered for sale" means to hold for sale, sell, exchange, or barter commercial feed; </section><section prefix="19">"Pet" means any domesticated animal normally maintained in or near the household of the owner; </section><section prefix="20">"Specialty pet" means any domesticated animal pet normally maintained in a cage or tank, such as, but not limited to, gerbils, hamsters, canaries, psittacine birds, mynahs, finches, tropical fish, goldfish, snakes, and turtles; </section><section prefix="21">"Specialty pet food" means any commercial feed prepared and distributed for consumption by specialty pets; </section><section prefix="22">"Quantity statement" means the net weight (mass), net volume (liquid or dry), or count; </section><section prefix="23">"Formula feed" means two (2) or more ingredients proportioned, mixed, and processed according to specifications; and </section><section prefix="24">"Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act" means 21 U.S.C. secs. 301 et seq. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 1. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12167</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>