<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.288</section_number><catch_line>Measurement and documentation of cost savings resulting from 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2 -- Reinvestment or distribution of savings -- Determination of average cost of services -- Budget allocations. </catch_line><order_by>288</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall measure and document cost savings resulting from amendments to or creation of statutes in KRS Chapters 27A, 196, 197, 431, 439, 532, 533, and 534 contained in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2. Measured and documented savings shall be reinvested or distributed as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall establish a baseline for measurement using the average number of inmates incarcerated at each type of penitentiary as defined in KRS 197.010 and at local jails in fiscal year 2010-2011. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall determine the average cost of: <section prefix="a">Incarceration for each type of penitentiary as defined in KRS 197.010 and for local jails, including health care costs, transportation costs, and other related costs, for one (1) inmate for one (1) year for the immediately preceding fiscal year; </section><section prefix="b">Providing probation and parole services for one (1) parolee for one (1) year for the immediately preceding fiscal year; and </section><section prefix="c">Reentry services and peer support as a condition of parole for those with opiate addiction and other substance abuse disorders. </section></section><section prefix="4">Beginning with the budget request for the 2012-2014 fiscal biennium, savings shall be estimated from the baseline established in subsection (2) of this section as follows: <section prefix="a">The estimated average reduction of inmates due to mandatory reentry supervision as required by KRS 439.3406 multiplied by the appropriate average cost as determined in subsection (3)(a) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">The estimated average reduction of inmates due to accelerated parole hearings as required by KRS 439.340 multiplied by the appropriate average cost as determined in subsection (3)(a) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">The estimated average increase of parolees due to paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection multiplied by the average cost as determined in subsection (3)(b) of this section; and </section><section prefix="d">The estimated average reduction of parolees due to parole credit for good behavior as provided in KRS 439.345 multiplied by the average cost as determined in subsection (3)(b) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="5">The following amounts shall be allocated or distributed from the estimated amount of savings that would otherwise remain in the general fund: <section prefix="a">Twenty-five percent (25%) shall be distributed to the local corrections assistance fund established by KRS 441.207; </section><section prefix="b">Fifty percent (50%) shall be distributed for the following purposes: <section prefix="1">To the department to provide or to contract for the provision of substance abuse treatment in county jails, regional jails, or other local detention centers that employ evidence-based practices in behavioral health treatment or medically assisted treatment for nonstate inmates with opiate addiction or other substance abuse disorders; </section><section prefix="2">For KY-ASAP programs operating under KRS Chapter 15A in county jails or in facilities under the supervision of county jails that employ evidence-based behavioral health treatment or medically assisted treatment for inmates with opiate addiction or other substance abuse disorders; </section><section prefix="3">To KY-ASAP to provide supplemental grant funding to community mental health centers for the purpose of offering additional substance abuse treatment resources through programs that employ evidence-based behavioral health treatment or medically assisted treatment; </section><section prefix="4">To KY-ASAP to address neonatal abstinence syndrome by providing supplemental grant funding to community substance abuse treatment providers to offer residential treatment services to pregnant women through programs that employ evidence-based behavioral health treatment or medically assisted treatment; </section><section prefix="5">To provide supplemental funding for traditional KY-ASAP substance abuse programming under KRS Chapter 15A; </section><section prefix="6">To the department for the purchase of an FDA-approved extended-release treatment for the prevention of relapse to opiate dependence with a minimum of fourteen (14) days' effectiveness with an opioid antagonist function for use as a component of evidence-based medically assisted treatment for inmates with opiate addiction or substance abuse disorders participating in a substance abuse treatment program operated or supervised by the department; </section><section prefix="7">To the Department for Public Advocacy to provide supplemental funding to the Social Worker Program for the purpose of creating additional social worker positions to develop individualized alternative sentencing plans; and </section><section prefix="8">To the Prosecutors Advisory Council to enhance the use of rocket docket prosecutions in controlled substance cases; and </section></section><section prefix="c">In enacting the budget for the department and the judicial branch, beginning in the 2012-2014 fiscal biennium and each fiscal biennium thereafter, the General Assembly shall: <section prefix="1">Determine the estimated amount necessary for reinvestment in: <section prefix="a">Expanded treatment programs and expanded probation and parole services provided by or through the department; and </section><section prefix="b">Additional pretrial services and drug court case specialists provided by or through the Administrative Office of the Courts; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Shall allocate and appropriate sufficient amounts to fully fund these reinvestment programs. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">The amount of savings shall be estimated each year of the 2012-2014 fiscal biennium, and for each year of each fiscal biennium thereafter, as specified in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">In submitting its budget request for the 2012-2014 fiscal biennium and each fiscal biennium thereafter, the department shall estimate the amount of savings measured under this section and shall request the amount necessary to distribute or allocate those savings as provided in subsection (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">In submitting its budget request for the 2012-2014 fiscal biennium and each fiscal biennium thereafter, the judicial branch shall request the amount necessary to distribute or allocate those savings as provided in subsection (5) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 3, effective March 25, 2015. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.68, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43999</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>