<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.620</section_number><catch_line>Variance from requirements of KRS 353.610. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding KRS 353.610, if an application is submitted for a permit to drill, deepen, or reopen a well closer to a boundary or to another well than prescribed in KRS 353.610 and the application is accompanied by the written consent of all owners of oil and gas interests in the adjacent premises directly affected by the prescribed boundary distances in KRS 353.610, which will be offset by the proposed well, the department shall issue a permit for the well. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 353.610, the department may issue a permit for a well to be drilled, deepened, or reopened closer to a boundary or another well than prescribed in KRS 353.610, if the director, after notice and hearing, finds that topographical or other conditions are such as to make compliance with the requirements of KRS 353.610 unduly burdensome or in conflict with reasonably prudent methods and practices for the production of oil or gas. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding KRS 353.610, the department shall issue a permit for a well to be drilled, deepened, or reopened closer to a boundary than prescribed in KRS 353.610 if a pooling order has been issued pursuant to KRS 353.630. </section><section prefix="4">If a permit is issued to drill, deepen, or reopen a well under subsection (1) or (2) of this section at a location closer to a well or boundary than prescribed in KRS 353.610, the department shall permit a like variance from the requirements of KRS 353.610 on all premises offset and adversely affected by the well. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 268, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 14, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33124</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>