<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29">A JURIES </unit></structure><section_number>29A.100</section_number><catch_line>Postponement of service or excusing of juror -- Breastfeeding mothers to be excused. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the request of a prospective juror prior to assignment to a trial court, the Chief Circuit Judge, or after the juror's assignment to a trial court, the trial judge may excuse such juror upon a showing of undue hardship, extreme inconvenience, or public necessity. On the day on which the prospective jurors are summonsed to appear, any person not previously excused who desires to be excused shall be heard. </section><section prefix="2">The Chief Circuit Judge may designate and authorize one (1) or more judges of the court, the court's clerk, a deputy clerk, the court's administrator, or a deputy court administrator to excuse a juror from service for a period not to exceed ten (10) days or to postpone jury service for a period not to exceed twelve (12) months. The reasons for excuse or postponement shall be entered in the space provided on the juror qualification form. </section><section prefix="3">In his or her discretion the judge may excuse a juror from service entirely, reduce the number of days of service, or may postpone the juror's service temporarily for a period of time not to exceed, however, twenty-four (24) months. Whenever possible the judge shall favor temporary postponement of service or reduced service over permanent excuse. When excusing a juror, the judge shall record the juror's name, as provided in KRS 29A.080, and the reasons for granting the excuse. </section><section prefix="4">The judge shall excuse a mother who is breastfeeding a child or expressing breastmilk from jury service until such time as the child is old enough that the mother is no longer breastfeeding the child. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 21, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21127</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>