<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.704</section_number><catch_line>Preparation and submission of strategic plan to further education of low income parents -- Parties included in planning process. </catch_line><order_by>704</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall undertake a joint planning process with appropriate state, local, and private education institutions, interested agencies, and citizens to ensure that opportunities for low income parents to continue or improve their education shall continue with the implementation of the public assistance program funded by federal block grant dollars under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 602 et seq. To this end, by July 31, 1998, the cabinet shall convene and provide staff services for an advisory group of interested parties to evaluate opportunities and strategies and make recommendations for continued participation by low income parents in education activities, including, but not limited to, representatives of: <section prefix="a">The state university system; </section><section prefix="b">The state community college system; </section><section prefix="c">Private colleges and universities; </section><section prefix="d">State vocational and technical schools; </section><section prefix="e">The Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority; </section><section prefix="f">Basic and secondary education programs, including literacy, adult basic education, GED, and high school programs; </section><section prefix="g">Advocacy and citizens groups representing low income parents, including low income parents in sufficient number to represent at least one quarter (1/4) of the total group; </section><section prefix="h">Providers of child care and other supportive services; and </section><section prefix="i">Two (2) members each from the Senate, as appointed by the President of the Senate, and the House of Representatives, as appointed by the Speaker of the House. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall prepare a strategic plan for continuation of education opportunities for low income parents, based on the recommendations of the advisory group. The cabinet shall submit the plan to the Legislative Research Commission and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare no later than July 31, 1999. At a minimum, the plan shall set forth strategies, including any funding necessary, to: <section prefix="a">Create work study opportunities; and </section><section prefix="b">Increase the access to child care funding. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7800</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>