<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.165</section_number><catch_line>County clerk to prepare application transmittal record. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text>Not later than 3 p.m. on the next business day after an application for a first certificate of registration or title for a vehicle is received by him, the county clerk shall prepare on forms supplied by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, an application transmittal record. <section prefix="1">The clerk shall indicate thereon in the spaces provided, the name of his county, the date or time period the transmittal relates to and, in the order they are to be attached to the transmittal record, a notation for each application attached consisting of the applicant's last name and initials or if the applicant is other than an individual, the name commonly used by the applicant and any other information required upon the form as indicated thereon. </section><section prefix="2">The clerk shall ensure that the original of all applications noted on the transmittal, together with the original of all required supporting documents are attached to the transmittal record in the order shown thereon, and shall thereafter sign and date the original of the transmittal record as of the date the transmittal is being forwarded to Frankfort. </section><section prefix="3">The county clerk shall place the original of each application record, with the original of each application shown thereon, and its required supporting documents, together with the acknowledgment of the transmittal record, in the envelope or other container provided by the Department of Vehicle Regulation and forward to the Division of Motor Vehicle Licensing in Frankfort. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6166</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>