<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.080</section_number><catch_line>Powers of fiscal court. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court may: <section prefix="a">Appropriate county funds according to the provisions of KRS 68.210 to 68.360 for lawful purposes; </section><section prefix="b">Sell and convey any real estate or personal property belonging to the county, and buy land for the use of the county, when necessary, for the lawful purposes of the county as provided for in this section and KRS 67.083. The fiscal court may appoint one (1) or more commissioners to sell or buy real estate under this subsection, subject to the approval of the fiscal court, and convey it to the purchaser, under the direction of the court, or have it conveyed to the court, by deed properly executed and recorded. <section prefix="1">When real property is purchased, the county shall pay no more than the highest appraised value, as determined by a Kentucky certified real property appraiser as defined in KRS 324A.010, or the price determined through exercising the power of eminent domain, if that power is used. A valuation of the real property shall not be required if the purchase price is forty thousand dollars ($40,000) or less; </section><section prefix="2">When real property is conveyed or sold, the county shall convey or sell it in accordance with KRS 67.0802; and </section><section prefix="3">When personal property is conveyed or sold, the county shall convey or sell it in accordance with KRS 67.0802; </section></section><section prefix="c">Regulate and control the fiscal affairs of the county; </section><section prefix="d">Cause correct accounts and records to be kept of all receipts and disbursements of the public funds of the county, employ a competent person to keep such accounts and records, pay such person a reasonable compensation for such services, and have the accounts of the county and all county officers audited, when necessary and in accordance with the provisions of KRS 43.070 and 64.810; </section><section prefix="e">Exercise all the corporate powers of the county unless otherwise provided by law; </section><section prefix="f">Establish all appointive offices, set the duties of those offices, and approve all appointments to those offices; and </section><section prefix="g">Investigate all activities of the county government. </section></section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall: <section prefix="a">Appropriate county funds, according to the provisions of KRS 68.210 to 68.360, for purposes required by law; </section><section prefix="b">As needed, cause the construction, operation, and maintenance of all county buildings and other structures, grounds, roads and other property; </section><section prefix="c">Adopt an administrative code for the county; and </section><section prefix="d">Provide for the incarceration of prisoners according to the provisions of KRS Chapter 441. </section></section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court shall not exercise executive authority except as specifically assigned by statute. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 25, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 927, 1834, 1840. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (12/14/94).  1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 1, deleted the definition of Kentucky certified real property appraiser formerly contained in KRS 324A.010 and referenced in subsection (1) of this statute. Section 4 of that same Act created KRS 324A.035, which requires the Real Estate Appraisers Board to establish by administrative regulation classifications of appraisers. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23687</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>