<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-951</section_number><catch_line>Statement of foreign qualification.   </catch_line><order_by>1-951</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before transacting business in this Commonwealth, a foreign limited liability partnership shall file a statement of foreign qualification. The statement shall contain: <section prefix="a">The name of the foreign limited liability partnership which satisfies the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The street address of the partnership's chief executive office and, if different, the street address of an office of the partnership in this Commonwealth, if any; </section><section prefix="c">The partnership's registered office and the name of its registered agent at that office, which shall comply with KRS 14A.4-010; and </section><section prefix="d">Its jurisdiction of organization. </section></section><section prefix="2">The status of a partnership as a foreign limited liability partnership remains effective, regardless of changes in the partnership, until it is canceled pursuant to KRS 362.1-105(4) or revoked pursuant to KRS 14A.9-080. </section><section prefix="3">If the name of a foreign limited liability partnership is not distinguishable upon the records of the Secretary of State, then it may file a statement of foreign qualification using a fictitious name that is distinguishable upon the records of the Secretary of State, in which instance the statement of foreign qualification shall be filed under the fictitious name, shall recite that the partnership has filed the statement of foreign qualification under a fictitious name, and shall include in the statement its real name in its jurisdiction of organization. </section><section prefix="4">Whether a foreign limited liability partnership is transacting business in the Commonwealth shall be determined under KRS 14A.9-010(2). </section><section prefix="5">The consequences to a foreign limited liability partnership transacting business without a statement of foreign qualification shall be as set forth in KRS 14A.9-020. </section><section prefix="6">A statement of foreign qualification shall authorize the foreign limited liability partnership to transact business in this Commonwealth subject to the right of the Commonwealth to revoke the statement. </section><section prefix="7">A foreign limited liability partnership, having filed a statement of foreign qualification, shall have the same as, but no greater rights than, and shall have the same, but no greater privileges than, and except as otherwise provided by this subchapter, shall be subject to the same duties, restrictions, penalties, and liabilities now or later imposed on, a limited liability partnership. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 120, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 99, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 70, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification>KRS 362.1-1102. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41484</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>