<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.1-410</section_number><catch_line>Written or oral notice -- How given -- When effective.   </catch_line><order_by>1-410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notice under this chapter shall be in writing unless oral notice is reasonable under the circumstances. Notice by electronic transmission is written notice. </section><section prefix="2">Notice may be communicated in person; by mail or other method of delivery; or by telephone, voice mail, or other electronic means. If these forms of personal notice are impracticable, notice may be communicated by a newspaper of general circulation in the area where published; or by radio, television, or other form of public broadcast communication. </section><section prefix="3">Written notice by a domestic or foreign corporation to its shareholder, if in a comprehensible form, shall be effective: <section prefix="a">Upon deposit in the United States mail, if mailed postpaid and correctly addressed to the shareholder's address shown in the corporation's current record of shareholders; or </section><section prefix="b">When electronically transmitted to the shareholder in a manner authorized and in accordance with the shareholder's instructions, if any. </section></section><section prefix="4">Written notice to a domestic or foreign corporation authorized to transact business in this state may be addressed to its registered agent at its registered office or to the corporation or its secretary at its principal office address of record with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, written notice, if in a comprehensible form, shall be effective at the earliest of the following: <section prefix="a">When received; </section><section prefix="b">Five (5) days after its deposit in the United States mail, if mailed postpaid and correctly addressed; or </section><section prefix="c">On the date shown on the return receipt, if sent by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, and the receipt is signed by or on behalf of the addressee. </section></section><section prefix="6">Oral notice shall be effective when communicated, if communicated in a comprehensible manner. </section><section prefix="7">If this chapter prescribes notice requirements for particular circumstances, those requirements, shall govern. If articles of incorporation or bylaws prescribe notice requirements not inconsistent with this section or other provisions of this chapter, those requirements shall govern. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 52, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 52, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 13, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>