<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8923</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition of appropriate sites, facilities, and funding. </catch_line><order_by>8923</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of acquiring all or part of the facilities necessary to collect, transport, and treat wastewater, the commission may purchase facilities and equipment from member entities and others for mutually agreed upon terms not to exceed the actual value of the facilities and equipment. Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a member entity of the commission or other entity may convey ownership of the facility or equipment to the commission without an election or voter approval. </section><section prefix="2">If a member entity has any outstanding debt obligation related to any facility or equipment proposed to be acquired by the commission, the commission may either make sufficient purchase payment to the owner to cover debt obligations or assume the debt obligations in its name pursuant to a sales agreement and any other instruments deemed appropriate by legal counsel. If the commission makes cash payment to the owner for the equipment or facility, it shall be a condition of sale that any outstanding debt obligation associated with the equipment or facility be retired by the owner at the time of sale. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may secure funding from state and federal grants and loan programs, nonprofit associations, and private lending institutions and may issue revenue bonds to acquire, construct, improve, or extend facilities for the collection, transportation, or treatment of wastewater. Loans and bonds shall be payable solely from the revenues derived pursuant to contracts for wastewater collection, transportation, and treatment services with member entities or other entities. </section><section prefix="4">For the purpose of securing appropriate sites, facilities, and required funding, the commission shall be vested with all the powers, duties, and responsibilities as delegated and granted to a governmental agency under the terms and provisions of KRS 58.010 to 58.190 and KRS Chapter 224A. </section><section prefix="5">A commission shall not assume responsibility for payment of any fines or penalties incurred by a member entity or other party and owed at the time of formation of a commission or contracting with that party, as a result of an agreed order, enforcement action, or other resolution of alleged violation of any provision of the Clean Water Act. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.12, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39885</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>