<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.050</section_number><catch_line>Financial disclosure by officers, candidates, and public servants. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each officer, each public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g), and each candidate shall file a statement of financial disclosure with the commission, as follows: <section prefix="a">Each officer and each public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g) who occupies his position during any portion of a calendar year shall file the statement for that portion of the calendar year he occupied the position on or before April 15 of the following year, whether or not he remains an officer or public servant as listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g). </section><section prefix="b">Each officer and public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g) who does not remain an officer or public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g) for the entire calendar year shall file the statement for the portion of the calendar year that the person served as an officer or public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g). The statement shall be filed with the commission within thirty (30) days after the date the person no longer serves as an officer or public servant listed in KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (g). </section><section prefix="c">A candidate shall file the statement reflecting the previous calendar year with the commission no later than February 15. </section></section><section prefix="2">The statement of financial disclosure shall be filed on a form prescribed by the commission. The commission shall provide copies of the form upon request without charge. </section><section prefix="3">The statement shall include the following information for the preceding calendar year: <section prefix="a">Name and entire residential and business address of filer; </section><section prefix="b">Title of position or office whereby filing is required; </section><section prefix="c">Any other occupations of filer and spouse; </section><section prefix="d">Positions held by the filer or his spouse in any business, and the name and address of the business; </section><section prefix="e">Names and addresses of all businesses in which the filer, his spouse, or dependent children has or had an interest of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) at fair market value or five percent (5%) ownership interest or more; </section><section prefix="f">The name and address of any source of gross income exceeding one thousand dollars ($1,000) from any one (1) source to the filer, his spouse, or dependent child, as well as information concerning the nature of the business, and the form of the income; </section><section prefix="g">Sources of retainers received by the filer or his spouse relating to matters of the state agency for which the filer works or supervises or of any other entity of state government for which the filer would serve in a decision-making capacity, including each source's name and address; </section><section prefix="h">Any representation or intervention for compensation by the filer or his spouse for any person or business before a state agency for which the filer works or supervises or before any entity of state government for which the filer would serve in a decision-making capacity, including the name and address of the person or business; </section><section prefix="i">All positions of a fiduciary nature held by the filer or his spouse in a business, including the name and address of the business; </section><section prefix="j">Information, including a street address or location, regarding any real property in which there is an interest of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more held by the filer, his spouse, or dependent children; </section><section prefix="k">Sources, including each source's name and address, of gifts of money or property with a retail value of more than two hundred dollars ($200) from any one (1) source to the filer, his spouse, or dependent children, except those from a member of the filer's family; and </section><section prefix="l">Identity, including an address, of creditors owed more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), except debts arising from the purchase of consumer goods. </section></section> Paragraphs (a) to (l) of this subsection shall not require disclosure of specific dollar amounts or of privileged information. </text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 5, effective December 1, 2000; and ch. 475, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 72, effective September 16, 1993. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> December 1, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission.  (7/15/98).  A reference to "KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (i)" in subsection (1) of this statute has been changed in codification to "KRS 11A.010(9)(a) to (h)" under KRS 7.136(1)(e) and (h). 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 1, eliminated the former paragraph (g) of KRS 11A.010(9) and renumbered the remaining subsections accordingly. Other actions within Acts Chapter 429, including in the section that amended this statute, used the "(a) to (h)" range in new language and modified existing language to use the "(a) to (h)" range. It seems clear from context, and this has been confirmed by the drafter of the bill, that this change was intended here as well but was inadvertently overlooked. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=596</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>