<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.020</section_number><catch_line>Designation of offenses. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any offense defined outside this code for which a law outside this code provides a sentence to a term of imprisonment in the state for: <section prefix="a">At least one (1) but not more than five (5) years shall be deemed a Class D felony; </section><section prefix="b">At least five (5) but not more than ten (10) years shall be deemed a Class C felony; </section><section prefix="c">At least ten (10) but not more than twenty (20) years shall be deemed a Class B felony; </section><section prefix="d">For at least twenty (20) but not more than fifty (50) years or for life shall be deemed a Class A felony. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any offense defined outside this code for which a law outside this code provides a sentence to a definite term of imprisonment with a maximum which falls between ninety (90) days and twelve (12) months shall be deemed a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">Any offense defined outside this code for which a law outside this code provides a sentence to a definite term of imprisonment with a maximum of less than ninety (90) days shall be deemed a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Any offense defined outside this code for which a law outside this code provides a sentence to a fine only or to any other punishment, whether in combination with a fine or not, other than death or imprisonment shall be deemed a violation. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 74, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 309, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective December 22, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 274, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20028</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>