<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.180</section_number><catch_line>Extension of system to other governmental units. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the approval of the board, the secretary may enter into agreements with any municipality or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth to furnish services and facilities of the cabinet to the municipality or political subdivision in the administration of its personnel on merit principles. Any such agreement shall provide for the reimbursement to the cabinet, under contract, of the reasonable cost of the services and facilities furnished, as determined by the secretary. All municipalities and political subdivisions of the Commonwealth are hereby authorized to enter into these agreements. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary may cooperate with the governmental agencies of other jurisdictions charged with personnel administration in conducting joint tests and establishing joint lists from which eligibles shall be certified for appointment in accordance with the provisions of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may, upon the request of the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and upon the approval of the board, furnish merit system services to "local" departments of health. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 96, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 78, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.180, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 36, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 8; and ch. 308, sec. 19. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.300. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1384</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>