<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.1-030</section_number><catch_line>Default and mandatory rules. </catch_line><order_by>1-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in the terms of the trust, this chapter governs the duties and powers of a trustee, relations among trustees, and the rights and interests of a beneficiary. </section><section prefix="2">The terms of a trust prevail over any provision of this chapter, except: <section prefix="a">The requirements for creating a trust; </section><section prefix="b">The duty of a trustee to act in good faith and in the interests of the beneficiaries; </section><section prefix="c">The requirement that a trust and its terms be for the benefit of its beneficiaries, and that the trust have a purpose that is lawful, not contrary to public policy, and possible to achieve; </section><section prefix="d">The power of the court to change or terminate a trust under Subchapter 4 of this chapter;  </section><section prefix="e">The effect of a spendthrift provision and the rights of certain creditors and assignees to reach a trust as provided in Subchapter 5 of this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">The power of the court under KRS 386B.7-020 to require, dispense with, or modify or terminate a bond; </section><section prefix="g">The power of the court under KRS 386B.7-080(2) to adjust a trustee’s compensation as specified in the terms of the trust which is unreasonably low or high; </section><section prefix="h">The duty to notify and report under KRS 386B.8-130(2); </section><section prefix="i">The effect of an exculpatory term under KRS 386B.10-080; </section><section prefix="j">The rights under KRS 386B.10-100, 386B.10-110, and 386B.10-120 of a person other than a trustee or beneficiary; </section><section prefix="k">Periods of limitation for commencing a judicial proceeding; </section><section prefix="l">The power of the court to take such action and exercise such jurisdiction as may be necessary in the interests of justice; and </section><section prefix="m">The subject-matter jurisdiction of the court and venue for commencing a proceeding as provided in KRS 386B.2-030 and 386B.2-040.  </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>