<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.070</section_number><catch_line>District to take over existing sewer facilities -- Duration of control and functions.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the district created under KRS 76.010 to 76.210 has organized, thereupon and by virtue of KRS 76.010 to 76.210, the existing sewer and drainage system and facilities of the city forming a district pursuant to KRS 76.010, together with all contracts, books, maps, plans, papers and records, of whatever description pertaining to or relating to the design, construction, maintenance, operation, and affairs of the existing sewer and drainage system, shall be assigned, transferred, and dedicated to the use of and be in possession, and under the jurisdiction, control, and supervision, of the district under KRS 76.010 to 76.210 created, and the district is empowered to take possession thereof for its use and purposes. The district created under KRS 76.010 to 76.210 shall thereafter have complete jurisdiction, control, possession, and supervision, of the existing sewer and drainage system, and of all of the facilities of the city for the disposal of sewage and storm water, and shall continue to exercise such power so long thereafter as any bonds or liabilities of the district remain unpaid or have not been otherwise discharged. When all of the bonds issued by the district and all its obligations have been paid in full or have been otherwise discharged, the district shall nevertheless continue to function as contemplated by KRS 76.010 to 76.210 until dissolved and disposition of its property and assets provided for.  </section><section prefix="2">The rights and powers given in this section shall apply in the whole of the district area. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall make and spread upon its records adequate descriptions, by map or otherwise, of the district area. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 48, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 52. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 2. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43633</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>