<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.542</section_number><catch_line>Designation of principal and contingent beneficiaries -- Rights -- Effects of change in certain conditions. </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Prior to the first day of the month in which the member receives his or her first retirement allowance and prior to the member filing a notification of retirement or a request for refund: <section prefix="a">Each member may designate on the form prescribed by the board a principal beneficiary and contingent beneficiary for his or her account. The principal beneficiary or contingent beneficiary designated by the member shall be: <section prefix="1">One (1) or more persons; or </section><section prefix="2">The member's estate; or </section><section prefix="3">A trust; </section></section><section prefix="b">If multiple persons are designated as provided by paragraph (a)1. of this subsection, the member shall indicate the percentage of total benefits each person is to receive. <section prefix="1">If percentages are not indicated, payments will be disbursed equally to the named beneficiaries. </section><section prefix="2">If the percentages indicated do not total one hundred percent (100%), each beneficiary shall receive an increased or decreased percentage which is proportional to the percentage allotted him or her by the member. </section><section prefix="3">If any of the multiple beneficiaries die prior to the member's death, the remaining beneficiaries shall be entitled to the deceased beneficiary's percentage of the total benefits, and each shall receive a percentage of the deceased's share which is equal to the percentage allotted them by the member; and </section></section><section prefix="c">The principal and contingent beneficiary designation established by the member pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection shall remain in full force and effect until changed by the member, except: <section prefix="1">A final divorce decree terminates an ex-spouse's status as beneficiary, unless the member has on file in the retirement office a beneficiary designation that redesignates the ex-spouse as beneficiary subsequent to the issuance of the divorce decree; </section><section prefix="2">If a beneficiary or beneficiaries are convicted of any crime which prohibits that person or persons from receiving the benefits under KRS 381.280, the beneficiary or beneficiaries shall not be eligible for any of the benefits and the remaining beneficiary or beneficiaries or, if none, the member's estate, shall become the beneficiary; </section><section prefix="3">When a notification of retirement has been filed at the retirement office, the designation of beneficiary on the notification of retirement, which shall be one (1) person, his estate, or a trust, shall supersede the designation of all previous beneficiaries, unless the notification of retirement is withdrawn, invalid, or voided. If the notification of retirement is withdrawn, invalid, or voided, the prior beneficiary designation on file with the system shall remain in full force and effect until changed by the member; and </section><section prefix="4">When a request for refund has been filed at the retirement office, the member's estate shall become the member's beneficiary if the member dies. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If the member dies prior to the first day of the month in which the member would have received his or her first retirement allowance and prior to filing a notification of retirement or a request for refund, any retirement benefits shall be payable to the principal beneficiary, except that: <section prefix="a">If the death of the principal beneficiary or beneficiaries precedes the death of the member, or if the principal beneficiary is terminated by a divorce decree, the contingent beneficiary or beneficiaries become the principal beneficiary or beneficiaries; </section><section prefix="b">If the principal beneficiary is one (1) person and is the member's spouse and they are divorced on the date of the member's death, the contingent beneficiary or beneficiaries become the principal beneficiary or beneficiaries; </section><section prefix="c">If the member is survived by his principal beneficiary or beneficiaries who subsequently die prior to having on file at the retirement office the necessary forms prescribed under authority of KRS 61.590, the contingent beneficiary shall become the principal beneficiary or beneficiaries; and </section><section prefix="d">If the deaths of all the principal beneficiaries and all of the contingent beneficiaries precede the death of the member, the estate of the member becomes the beneficiary. </section></section><section prefix="3">Prior to the first day of the month in which the member would have received his or her first retirement allowance, a monthly benefit payable for life shall not be offered if the beneficiary designated under subsection (1) of this section is more than one (1) person, the member's estate, or a trust. </section><section prefix="4">When a notification of retirement has been filed at the retirement office: <section prefix="a">The designation of beneficiary on the notification of retirement shall supersede the designation of all previous beneficiaries; </section><section prefix="b">The beneficiary designated by the member on the member's notification of retirement shall be one (1) person, the member's estate, or a trust; and </section><section prefix="c">If the death of the beneficiary named on the notification of retirement precedes the first day of the month in which the member receives his or her first retirement allowance, the member may designate another beneficiary on the member's notification of retirement. </section></section><section prefix="5">After the first day of the month in which the member receives his or her first retirement allowance and subsequent thereto, a member shall not have the right to change his beneficiary, except that: <section prefix="a">The estate of the retired member becomes the beneficiary if the date of death of the beneficiary precedes or coincides with the date of death of the retired member; </section><section prefix="b">The estate of the retired member becomes the beneficiary if the retired member had designated a person as beneficiary who was the spouse or who later married the member and they were divorced on the date of the retired member's death. An ex-spouse who was the named beneficiary on the member's notification of retirement shall be reinstated as the member's beneficiary for the payment options provided by KRS 61.635(2), (3), (4), and (8)(b) if they are remarried to each other as of the date of the retired member's death; and </section><section prefix="c">The estate of the member shall not receive monthly payments if the member selected one (1) of the payment options provided by KRS 61.635(2), (3), (4), and (8)(b). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 485, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 14. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 28. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22966</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>