<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.606</section_number><catch_line>Medical association, hospital, or its medical staff to report actions taken against licensed physicians -- Violations to be reported by physicians -- Reports by court clerks. </catch_line><order_by>606</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to assist the board in the enforcement of KRS 311.595(20) and (21), any professional medical association or society operating in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or any hospital or medical staff of said hospital located in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, shall report all actions taken against a licensed physician as described in KRS 311.595(20) and (21) to the board within thirty (30) days of the final adjudication of said action together with all pertinent documents to include but not limited to transcripts, pleadings and certified copy of the final order. </section><section prefix="2">In order to assist the board in the enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 311, any licensed physician who observes another licensed physician violating a provision of KRS Chapter 311 shall submit a written report to the board, or to the board and the concerned medical association or society, or to the board and the concerned hospital or medical staff of the hospital within ten (10) days of observing such a violation or obtaining other direct knowledge of such a violation; the report shall contain the name of the licensed physician believed to be in violation of a provision of KRS Chapter 311, a detailed account of the concerned actions, a list of all other witnesses to said actions, and the name of the physician submitting the report. </section><section prefix="3">All clerks of the Circuit and District Courts in the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall report to the secretary of the board all criminal convictions of licensees that may occur in their respective courts. The report shall contain the name of the licensee, the sentence imposed against the licensee, and whether the sentence imposed upon the licensee has been appealed. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 256, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30548</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>