<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="343" order_by="343">APPRENTICESHIP </unit></structure><section_number>343.020</section_number><catch_line>Apprenticeship and Training Council. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Governor shall appoint an Apprenticeship and Training Council composed of four (4) representatives from employer organizations, four (4) representatives from employee organizations, and three (3) at-large members who shall serve for a term of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified. The commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards, the commissioner of the Department for Workforce Investment, and the chancellor for the Technical Institutions' Branch in the Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall be ex officio members of the council. The chairman shall be elected by vote of the Apprenticeship and Training Council. </section><section prefix="b">The regular members of the council shall each have one (1) vote. In the event of a tie vote among the regular members, the commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards shall have the right to cast the tie-breaking vote. Each member of the council shall receive his or her actual and necessary expenses incurred in attending its meetings. </section><section prefix="c">The council shall meet at the call of the commissioner and shall aid him or her in formulating policies for the effective administration of this chapter. The commissioner with the advice of the council shall have the authority to make and revise such rules and regulations as he or she may deem appropriate to carry out the provisions and purposes of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">On July 15, 2014, the term of the at-large members appointed on December 31, 2011, shall expire, and the Governor shall appoint three (3) at-large members representing the general public to the Apprenticeship and Training Council. </section><section prefix="b">Subsequent members shall serve terms of four (4) years and shall serve until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall be attached to the Labor Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1864, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 147, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 62, effective July 1, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 40, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42987</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>