<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.353</section_number><catch_line>Referral for review and consideration -- Review standards and criteria -- Vote required for approval. </catch_line><order_by>353</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission shall refer each block grant application received to the designated review body for review and consideration. </section><section prefix="2">The designated review body shall review and consider each block grant application according to the following standards and criteria, and shall make an affirmative finding of fact that: <section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, block grant and other funds specified in the application have been included in an appropriation provision or any branch budget bill enacted by the General Assembly in anticipation of such application; </section><section prefix="b">Any excess in the total amount of block grant funds sought over the total amount of such funds anticipated and included in an appropriation provision or any branch budget bill, has been included in a surplus expenditure plan approved by the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="c">A budget reduction plan specifying programs and services to be eliminated or to be reduced in scope if federal funding diminishes or is cut, has been included; </section><section prefix="d">The budget reduction plan does not propose to increase the ratio of state funds to federal funds if federal funding diminishes or is cut; </section><section prefix="e">Block grant and other funds to be provided under the application are fairly and equitably distributed among those programs, services, or recipients eligible for block grant funding; </section><section prefix="f">Block grant and other funds to be provided under the application are not to be used to fund programs or services that would duplicate or supplant existing programs or services funded by the private sector; </section><section prefix="g">The intended uses of block grant and other funds specified in the application are in compliance with the applicable federal and state laws pertaining to such block grant funds; and </section><section prefix="h">The amount of block grant and other funds to be retained by the state administering agency for administrative purposes does not exceed an amount allowable under federal law. </section></section><section prefix="3">For the purpose of the review and consideration of a block grant application, the findings of fact and any other reports or recommendations of the designated review body need only be approved by a majority of the members present at the public hearing held according to KRS 45.352. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 323, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22244</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>