<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.061</section_number><catch_line>Permits for schools and charitable organizations. </catch_line><order_by>061</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority may issue a permit, without the payment of any taxes or license fee, to any accredited college, university, school, Young Men's Christian Association, Young Men's Hebrew Association, or organization which in the judgment of the authority is of like character, to hold boxing or kickboxing shows or exhibitions upon a sufficient showing that the matches or exhibitions are to be held by and between bona fide students or members of such accredited colleges, universities, schools, Young Men's Christian Associations, Young Men's Hebrew Associations, or organizations which in the judgment of the authority are of like character. </section><section prefix="2">Any regularly organized post of the American Legion, and any organization operating solely for charitable purposes from which no individual, partnership, or corporation derives any monetary gain, may hold boxing or kickboxing shows or exhibitions without the payment of the license fee prescribed by KRS 229.071. Any post of the American Legion or other organization holding shows or exhibitions under this section shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 229.031 and 229.051. </section><section prefix="3">No show permitted by subsections (1) and (2) of this section may be conducted without a permit to hold the specific match and accompanying program of events at a specified location on a specified date. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10776</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>