<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.725</section_number><catch_line>Authority's duty to bring action for penalties or injunctive relief -- Venue. </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall bring an action for the recovery of penalties provided for in KRS 151.990, the payment of fees provided for in KRS 151.720, or for a restraining order, or a temporary or permanent injunction for the prevention or correction of a condition constituting or threatening to constitute a violation of the administrative regulations promulgated by the authority, the long-range water resource plan, or a drought response plan developed by the authority. </section><section prefix="2">All actions for penalties and injunctive relief for violations of the administrative regulations promulgated by the authority, the long-range water resource plan, or a drought response plan developed by the authority shall be brought by the authority in the: <section prefix="a">Circuit Court having jurisdiction of the defendant; </section><section prefix="b">Circuit Court of the county in which the condition constituting or threatening to constitute a violation of the administrative regulations of the authority, the long-range water resource plan or a drought response plan developed by the authority is occurring; or </section><section prefix="c">In the Franklin Circuit Court. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created  1992 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2164</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>