<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.230</section_number><catch_line>Case permanency plans. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For each child placed in the custody of the cabinet by an order of commitment, the cabinet shall file a case permanency plan for the child with the court and send a copy to the Administrative Office of the Courts Citizen Foster Care Review Board Program as soon as the plan is prepared but no later than thirty (30) days after the effective date of the order. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 620.090(5), if a child remains in the temporary custody of the cabinet for longer than forty-five (45) days and if a request is submitted by the Administrative Office of the Courts Citizen Foster Care Review Board Program, the cabinet shall provide a copy of the case permanency plan for the child. </section><section prefix="2">The case permanency plan shall include, but need not be limited to: <section prefix="a">A concise statement of the reasons why the child is in the custody of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">A statement of the actions which have been taken with regard to the child to the date of the plan; </section><section prefix="c">A statement of the proposed actions which may be taken or are contemplated with regard to the child during the next six (6) months and during the entire duration of the time the child is in the custody of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="d">Contemplated placements for the child; </section><section prefix="e">If the child is placed outside the home, reasons why the child cannot be protected adequately in the home, the harms the child may suffer if left in the home, factors which may indicate when the child can be returned to the home, and efforts the cabinet or others are making to return the child to the home; </section><section prefix="f">If the child is placed outside the home, the steps that the cabinet will take to minimize the harm to the child as a result of the action, both at the time of removal and on a long-term basis; </section><section prefix="g">A description of the type of home, child-caring facility, child-placing agency or facility in which the child is to be placed or has been placed, and a statement why the placement is appropriate for the child, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Age; </section><section prefix="2">Educational needs; </section><section prefix="3">Medical needs; </section><section prefix="4">Emotional needs; </section><section prefix="5">Relationship with parents; and </section><section prefix="6">Number of children the home is authorized to care for and the number of children currently residing in the home; </section></section><section prefix="h">If the placement is outside the child's original county of residence, documentation that no closer placement is appropriate or available, and the reasons why the placement made was chosen; </section><section prefix="i">A description of the services for the child and his family to be provided or arranged by the cabinet to facilitate the return of the child to his own home or to another permanent placement; </section><section prefix="j">A list of objectives and specific tasks, together with specific time frames for each task, for which the parents have agreed to assume responsibility, including a schedule of regular visits with the child; </section><section prefix="k">A projected schedule of time intervals by which each of the services, objectives, and tasks outlined in the case permanency plan should be accomplished and a schedule of time intervals which have already been accomplished or are in the process of accomplishment; </section><section prefix="l">If the child is to remain at home, a description of the potential harm which could befall the child and measures that are being taken to prevent or minimize such harm; and </section><section prefix="m">If the child is to remain at home, reasons why he cannot be placed in foster care or why such care is not needed. </section></section><section prefix="3">Under no circumstance shall a child be placed in a home, facility, or other shelter with a child who has been committed to the Department of Juvenile Justice for commission of a sex crime as defined in KRS 17.500, unless the child committed for the commission of a sex crime is kept segregated from other children in the home, facility, or other shelter that have not been committed for the commission of a sex crime. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 52, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 59, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 84, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20212</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>