<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.973</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary powers of Attorney General -- Hearing -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>973</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General may deny, suspend, or revoke any license granted under KRS 367.940 or levy civil penalties not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500) or both or place the licensee on probation for up to twelve (12) months for any of the following causes: <section prefix="a">Obtaining a license through false statement or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="b">Conducting, or undertaking a substantial step toward conducting his business in an unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive manner; </section><section prefix="c">Entry of a final civil judgment against the licensee for a violation of KRS 367.934 to 367.974, or for entry of a final judgment of conviction for a violation of KRS 367.991; </section><section prefix="d">Entry of a final judgment of conviction against the licensee for any crime involving moral turpitude; or </section><section prefix="e">Violating any of the provisions of KRS 367.932 to 367.974 or any lawful order or administrative regulation made or promulgated under KRS 367.932 to 367.974. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Attorney General shall, before denying, suspending, or revoking a license or imposing fines, file a complaint alleging the grounds upon which the licensee may have his license denied, revoked, or suspended or have fines imposed. A copy of the complaint, together with any exhibits, shall be served upon the defendant licensee at the licensee's last known address. The complainant shall show certification that there has been service by writing to the last known address. The answer shall be returned to the Attorney General's office within twenty (20) days of receipt of the complaint by the defendant licensee. Upon receipt of an answer to a complaint, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">Any person aggrieved by a final order issued under authority of this section shall have the right of an appeal by filing a petition with the Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 351, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>