<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4013</section_number><catch_line>Application for licensure as elevator mechanic -- Contents -- Eligibility requirements.    </catch_line><order_by>4013</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An application for licensure as an elevator mechanic shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">Name; </section><section prefix="b">Residential address; </section><section prefix="c">Name and address of the applicant's employer, if employed; </section><section prefix="d">The number of years the applicant has engaged in the business of installing, maintaining, or servicing elevators or fixed guideway systems; </section><section prefix="e">The types of elevators or fixed guideway systems the applicant installed, maintained, or serviced during the applicant's years of experience; </section><section prefix="f">Identification of the type of license, whether an elevator mechanic license or an accessibility and residential elevator mechanic license, sought by the applicant; and </section><section prefix="g">Upon request by the department, supplemental documentation of information required by this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant for an elevator mechanic license or an accessibility and residential elevator mechanic license shall demonstrate one (1) or more of the following to be eligible for licensure: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Proof the applicant for an elevator mechanic license has not less than thirty-six (36) months of work experience in the elevator industry, in construction, maintenance, service, repair, or any combination of these activities as verified by current and previous employers, or equivalent experience while serving in the United States military services; and </section><section prefix="2">Passage of a written, oral, or computerized examination administered by the department or the department's designee based upon the most recent referenced codes and standards for full licensure; </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Proof the applicant for an accessibility and residential elevator mechanic license has not less than twelve (12) months of work experience in the elevator industry, in construction, maintenance, service, repair, or any combination of the activities verified by current and previous employers, or equivalent experience while serving in the United States military services; and </section><section prefix="2">Passage of a written, oral, or computerized examination administered by the department or the department's designee based upon the most recent referenced codes and standards for the accessibility and residential elevator mechanic license the applicant seeks; </section></section><section prefix="c">Proof the applicant has worked without direct and immediate supervision as an elevator constructor, maintenance, or repair person for not less than three </section></section><section prefix="3">years immediately prior to July 1, 2011; </section>(d) Certificate of completion from a nationally recognized training program for the elevator industry such as the National Elevator Industry Educational Program, National Association of Elevator Contractors, or an equivalent program approved by the commissioner for elevator mechanic licensure; (e) For accessibility and residential elevator mechanic licensure, a certificate of completion from a nationally recognized training program specifically designed for the accessibility and private residence lift, such as the National Association of Elevator Contractors, or an equivalent program approved by the commissioner; or (f) 1. Certificate of completion of an apprenticeship program for elevator mechanics, having standards substantially equal to those of KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540; and 2. Proof of registration with the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, United States Department of Labor, or a state apprenticeship council. </text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 6, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction and the "executive director" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 6, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction and the "commissioner" of housing, buildings and construction, respectively, to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41874</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>