<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">B LICENSING AND PUBLIC EMPLOYMENT QUALIFICATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>335B.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 335B.020 to 335B.070, unless the context requires otherwise:  <section prefix="1">"Occupation" includes all occupations, trades, vocations, professions, businesses, or employment of any kind for which a license is required to be issued by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, its agencies, or political subdivisions.  </section><section prefix="2">"License" includes all licenses, permits, certificates, registrations, or other means required to engage in an occupation which are granted or issued by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, its agents or political subdivisions before a person can pursue, practice, or engage in any occupation.  </section><section prefix="3">"Public employment" includes all employment with the Commonwealth of Kentucky, its agencies, or political subdivisions.  </section><section prefix="4">"Conviction of crime" shall be limited to convictions of felonies, high misdemeanors, and misdemeanors for which a jail sentence may be imposed.  No other criminal conviction shall be considered unless moral turpitude is involved.  </section><section prefix="5">"Hiring or licensing authority" shall mean the person, board, commission, or department of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, its agencies or political subdivisions, responsible by law for the hiring of persons for public employment or the licensing of persons for occupations.  </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31982</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>