<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon proof that any person employed by the Labor Cabinet as a labor inspector has taken any part in any strike, lockout or similar labor dispute, the person shall forfeit his or her office. </section><section prefix="2">The following civil penalties shall be imposed, in accordance with the provisions in KRS 336.985, for violations of the provisions of this chapter: <section prefix="a">Any person who violates KRS 336.110 shall for each offense be assessed a civil penalty of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000); </section><section prefix="b">Any corporation, association, organization, or person that violates KRS 336.190 and 336.200 shall be assessed a civil penalty of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each offense. Each act of violation, and each day during which such an agreement remains in effect, shall constitute a separate offense; and </section><section prefix="c">Any employer who violates the provisions of KRS 336.220 shall be assessed a civil penalty of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each violation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1726, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. --Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 19. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 27. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 33a-8, 33a-13. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>