<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.825</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of KRS 260.775 to 260.845 -- Authority to promulgate administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>825</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director shall enforce, administer, and implement the provisions of KRS 260.775 to 260.845 through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of the enforcement of KRS 260.775 to 260.845, the director is authorized during normal business hours to enter any public or private premises, including any vehicle of transport, for the purpose of obtaining samples, gaining access to milk, milk samples, and records pertaining to milk handling, milk weights, milk test results, and milk payments. The director may: <section prefix="a">Collect samples obtained by sampler-weighers or testers for inspection purposes; </section><section prefix="b">Inspect equipment and other devices used in testing or sampling and weighing milk to determine the accuracy of this equipment and devices. Accuracy may be determined by requiring sampler-weighers and testers to operate equipment and devices to determine the accuracy of equipment, devices, and procedures; </section><section prefix="c">Condemn inaccurate or improperly operating equipment; and </section><section prefix="d">Examine and copy records and take testimony for the purpose of ascertaining facts necessary to administer KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section></section><section prefix="3">At the request of producers, processors, handlers, sampler-weighers, or testers, the director may test for milk components or other tests of milk quality. </section><section prefix="4">The director shall employ qualified persons to assist in the enforcement of KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section><section prefix="5">The director shall establish and maintain milk-testing facilities to determine if milk has been sampled, weighed, and tested correctly. The testing facility established shall be officially named the "Division of Regulatory Services Dairy Laboratory." The director shall, with approval of the board of trustees of the University of Kentucky, fix the salaries of the analysts, inspectors, and supporting staff. </section><section prefix="6">The director shall cooperate with other federal, state, and local enforcement agencies. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 19, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 11, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>