<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.750</section_number><catch_line>Income benefits for death -- Additional lump-sum payment for deaths occurring within four years of injury. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>If the injury causes death, income benefits shall be payable in the amount and to or for the benefit of the persons following, subject to the maximum limits specified in subsections (3) and (4) of this section: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If there is a widow or widower and no children of the deceased, to such widow or widower 50 percent of the average weekly wage of the deceased, during widowhood or widowerhood. </section><section prefix="b">To the widow or widower, if there is a child or children living with the widow or widower, 45 percent of the average weekly wage of the deceased, or 40 percent, if such child is not or such children are not living with a widow or widower, and in addition thereto, 15 percent for each child. Where there are more than two (2) such children, the indemnity benefits payable on account of such children shall be divided among such children, share and share alike. </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) years' indemnity benefits in one (1) lump sum shall be payable to a widow or widower upon remarriage. </section><section prefix="d">To the children, if there is no widow or widower, 50 percent of such wage for one (1) child, and 15 percent for each additional child, divided among such children, share and share alike. </section><section prefix="e">The income benefits payable on account of any child under this section shall cease when he dies, marries, or reaches the age of eighteen (18), or when a child over such age ceases to be physically or mentally incapable of self-support, or if actually dependent ceases to be actually dependent, or, if enrolled as a full-time student in any accredited educational institution, ceases to be so enrolled or reaches the age of 22. A child who originally qualified as a dependent by virtue of being less than 18 years of age may, upon reaching age 18, continue to qualify if he satisfies the tests of being physically or mentally incapable of self-support, actual dependency, or enrollment in an educational institution. </section><section prefix="f">To each parent, if actually dependent, 25 percent. </section><section prefix="g">To the brothers, sisters, grandparents, and grandchildren, if actually dependent, 25 percent to each such dependent. If there should be more than one (1) of such dependents, the total income benefits payable on account of such dependents shall be divided share and share alike. </section><section prefix="h">The income benefits of each beneficiary under paragraphs (f) and (g) above shall be paid until he, if a parent or grandparent, dies, marries, or ceases to be actually dependent, or, if a brother, sister, or grandchild, dies, marries, or reaches the age of eighteen (18) or if over that age ceases to be physically or mentally incapable of self-support, or ceases to be actually dependent. </section><section prefix="i">A person ceases to be actually dependent when his or her income from all sources exclusive of workers' compensation income benefits is such that, if it had existed at the time as of which the original determination of actual dependency was made, it would not have supported a finding of dependency. In any event, if the present annual income of an actual dependent person including workers' compensation income benefits at any time exceeds the total annual support received by the person from the deceased employee, the workers' compensation benefits shall be reduced so that the total annual income is no greater than such amount of annual support received from the deceased employee. In all cases, a person found to be actually dependent shall be presumed to be no longer actually dependent three (3) years after each time as of which the person was found to be actually dependent. This presumption may be overcome by proof of continued actual dependency as defined in this subsection, but full payments shall not be suspended during the pendency of any proceeding to determine dependency. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the cessation of income benefits under this section to or on account of any person, the income benefits of the remaining persons entitled to income benefits for the unexpired part of the period during which their income benefits are payable shall be that which such persons would have received if they had been the only persons entitled to income benefits at the time of the decedent's death. </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of this section, the average weekly wage of the employee shall be taken as not more than the average weekly wage of the state as determined in KRS 342.740. In no case shall the aggregate weekly income benefits payable to all beneficiaries under this section exceed the maximum income benefit that was or would have been payable for total disability to the deceased, including benefits to his dependents. </section><section prefix="4">The maximum weekly income benefits payable for all beneficiaries in case of death shall not exceed 75 percent of the average weekly wage of the deceased as calculated under KRS 342.140, subject to the maximum limits in subsection (3) above. The maximum aggregate limitation shall not operate in case of payment of two (2) years' income benefits to the widow or widower upon remarriage as provided under paragraph (c) of subsection (1) of this section, to prevent the immediate recalculation and payments of benefits to the remaining beneficiaries as provided under subsection (2) of this section, but the weekly income benefits as to such remaining beneficiaries shall not exceed the weekly income benefit that was or would have been payable for total disability to the deceased. The classes of beneficiaries specified in paragraphs (a), (b), and (d) of subsection (1) of this section shall have priority over all other beneficiaries in the apportionment of income benefits. If the provisions of this subsection should prevent payment to other beneficiaries of the income benefits to the full extent otherwise provided for by this section, the gross remaining amount of income benefits payable to such other beneficiaries shall be apportioned by class, proportionate to the interest of each class in the remaining amount. Parents shall be considered to be in one class and those specified in paragraph (f) of subsection (1) in another class. </section><section prefix="5">All relations of dependency referred to in this section shall mean dependency existing at the time of the accident to the employee or at the time his or her disability from an occupational disease began. </section><section prefix="6">In addition to other benefits as provided by this chapter, if death occurs within four (4) years of the date of injury as a direct result of a work-related injury, a lump-sum payment of fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) shall be made to the deceased's estate, from which the cost of burial and cost of transportation of the body to the employee's place of residence shall be paid. Annually, the commissioner shall compute, in accordance with KRS 342.740, the increase or decrease in the state average weekly wage, and consistent therewith, shall adjust the amount of the lump-sum payment due under this subsection for injuries occurring in the succeeding year. </section><section prefix="7">All benefits awarded pursuant to this section, other than those provided in subsection (6) of this section, shall be subject to the limitations contained in KRS 342.730(4). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1846, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 39, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 31, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 28, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1977. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32550</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>