<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.026</section_number><catch_line>Credits allowed transferred district employee. </catch_line><order_by>026</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, full-time service in a local school for not less than one hundred forty (140) days during the school year entitles an employee who transfers to the Department of Education to a full year of experience credit on the Personnel Cabinet pay schedule and a full year for the purpose of accumulation of annual leave and sick leave in the Department of Education. </section><section prefix="2">An employee of a local school district who transfers to become an employee of the Department of Education after June 30, 1983, shall be allowed to transfer accrued sick leave up to the maximum allowed for transfers for teachers between school districts as provided by KRS 161.155(4). The employee shall be allowed credit for each year of experience in the local school system for the purposes of determining salary in accordance with the current Personnel Cabinet pay schedule, and the rate of accumulation of annual and sick leave in the Department of Education. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of determining eligibility for additional leave or other benefits based on longevity of service, an employee transferring from a school district to the Department of Education after June 30, 1983, shall be given credit for each year of service in the school district, as determined under subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 363, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 508, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts Ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts Ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3097</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>