<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.240</section_number><catch_line>Joint exercise of power by state agencies with other public agencies. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any power or powers, privileges or authority exercised or capable of exercise by a public agency of this state may be exercised and enjoyed jointly with any other public agency of this state, and jointly with any public agency of any other state or of the United States to the extent that the laws of the United States permit such joint exercise or enjoyment. Any agency of the state government when acting jointly with any public agency may exercise and enjoy all of the powers, privileges and authority conferred by KRS 65.210 to 65.300 upon a public agency. </section><section prefix="2">Any two (2) or more public agencies may enter into agreements with one another for joint or cooperative action pursuant to the provisions of KRS 65.210 to 65.300. Appropriate action by ordinance, resolution or otherwise pursuant to law, of the governing bodies of the participating public agencies shall be necessary before any such agreement may enter into force. </section><section prefix="3">A state-supported institution of higher education and one (1) or more county or independent public school districts may enter into agreements under KRS 65.210 to 65.300 for the purposes specified in KRS 65.230, notwithstanding any other provision of the statutes restricting, qualifying or limiting their authority to do so. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 4(1) and (2). </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23376</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>