<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.473</section_number><catch_line>Limits for district board of education on personal property tax rates -- Public hearing and recall not applicable. </catch_line><order_by>473</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event that a general tax rate applicable to real property levied by a district board of education will produce a percentage increase in revenue from personal property less than the percentage increase in revenue from real property, the district board of education may levy a general tax rate applicable to personal property which will produce the same percentage increase in revenue from personal property as the percentage increase in revenue from real property; however, in no event shall the general tax rate levied by the district board of education applicable to personal property exceed the prior year general tax rate applicable to personal property levied by the respective district board of education. </section><section prefix="2">The general tax rate applicable to personal property levied by a district board of education under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not be subject to the public hearing provisions of KRS 160.470(7) and to the recall provisions of KRS 160.470(8). </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. III, sec. 109, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3742</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>