<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.14-040</section_number><catch_line>Revocation of dissolution.   </catch_line><order_by>14-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A corporation may revoke its dissolution within one hundred twenty (120) days of its effective date. </section><section prefix="2">Revocation of dissolution shall be authorized in the same manner as the dissolution was authorized unless that authorization permitted revocation by action of the board of directors alone, in which event the board of directors may revoke the dissolution without shareholder action. </section><section prefix="3">After the revocation of dissolution is authorized, the corporation may revoke the dissolution delivering to the Secretary of State for filing articles of revocation of dissolution, together with a copy of its articles of dissolution, that set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation; </section><section prefix="b">The effective date of the dissolution that was revoked; </section><section prefix="c">The date that the revocation of dissolution was authorized; </section><section prefix="d">If the corporation's board of directors (or incorporators) revoked the dissolution, a statement to that effect; </section><section prefix="e">If the corporation's board of directors revoked a dissolution authorized by the shareholders, a statement that revocation was permitted by action by the board of directors alone pursuant to that authorization; and </section><section prefix="f">If shareholder action was required to revoke the dissolution, the information required by subsection (1)(c) or (1)(d) of KRS 271B.14-030. </section></section><section prefix="4">Revocation of dissolution shall be effective upon the effective date of the articles of revocation of dissolution. </section><section prefix="5">When the revocation of dissolution is effective, it shall have the effect provided in KRS 14A.7-030(3). </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 94, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 140, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40433</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>