<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="107" order_by="107">MUNICIPAL IMPROVEMENTS -- ALTERNATE METHODS </unit></structure><section_number>107.370</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>In addition to its general powers specified in KRS 107.310 to 107.500, the board, after approval of any proposed project by resolution of the fiscal court, shall have power to finance and construct buildings and related facilities for the joint or separate use of any one (1) or more of the governmental units within the territorial limits of the county, or of federal agencies, and to convey or lease said buildings and facilities in whole or in part, or space therein, to said governmental units or federal agencies in accordance with the provisions of KRS 107.310 to 107.500. The board may cause any such building and related facilities to be designed in anticipation of reasonably foreseeable future needs; and to the extent the capacity thereof may be surplus to needs existing at the time of occupancy, such surplus capacity may be leased to nongovernmental persons or parties, subject to cancellation upon reasonable notice when such capacity or facilities shall be required for the purposes of governmental units. Said board shall have the government, management, regulation, control and operation of any buildings financed, constructed and leased pursuant to the provisions of KRS 107.310 to 107.500 and shall have the power to improve, reconstruct, repair and maintain said buildings and all additions thereto; provided, however, that the board may contract with the lessee of any building for the maintenance and operation of such building. The board shall also have power, acting in the name of the district, as follows: <section prefix="1">To condemn, appropriate, lease, rent, purchase and hold any real estate, regardless of whether the same be then held for a governmental or public use, and materials or personal property needed or deemed useful in connection with buildings constructed or to be constructed pursuant to KRS 107.310 to 107.500; </section><section prefix="2">To enter upon any lots or lands for the purpose of surveying or examining the same for a proper public purpose under KRS 107.310 to 107.500; </section><section prefix="3">To design, order, contract for and construct, reconstruct and maintain such buildings and related facilities and to make all necessary or desirable improvements to the grounds and premises under its control; </section><section prefix="4">To determine, allocate and adjust space in said buildings to be used by any governmental unit; </section><section prefix="5">To construct, maintain and operate auditoriums, public meeting places, and parking facilities in conjunction with or as a part of said buildings; </section><section prefix="6">To operate any such buildings, to receive and collect any moneys due on account of such operation or otherwise relating to such buildings and to expend such moneys for proper purposes; and in connection therewith to let concessions for the operation of restaurants, cafeterias, public telephones, news and cigar stands, and vending machines, the above concessions for operations of said restaurants, cafeterias, public telephones, news and cigar stands and vending machines shall be let on open and competitive bidding, and to employ such managers, superintendents, architects, engineers, attorneys, auditors, clerks, foremen, custodians, and other employees, as it may deem necessary for the proper carrying on and operation of any such buildings and to fix compensation of all such employees; provided, however, that no contract of employment shall be made for a longer fixed period than four (4) years, but may be extended or renewed from time to time thereafter; </section><section prefix="7">To make and enter into all leases, contracts and other agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the execution of its powers under KRS 107.310 to 107.500. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 21. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27182</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>