<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.040</section_number><catch_line>Application for license as broker or sales associate. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every applicant for a license, whether as broker or sales associate, shall state whether the applicant has ever had any broker's or sales associate's license revoked or suspended. Every applicant for a license shall furnish a sworn statement setting forth his business and residence address. </section><section prefix="2">Every applicant for a broker's or sales associate's license shall apply in writing upon forms prepared or furnished by the commission. The applicant shall state the name of the person or company with which he will be associated in the business of real estate and the location of the place for which the license is desired. The applicant also shall set forth the period of time, if any, during which he has been engaged in the real estate business. </section><section prefix="3">Every applicant for a license shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age and shall have attained a high school diploma or its equivalent. After an applicant passes the required examination, the commission shall issue a license to him. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 9. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31549</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>