<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="436" order_by="436">OFFENSES AGAINST MORALITY </unit></structure><section_number>436.510</section_number><catch_line>Witnesses in investigation or prosecution for gambling. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any prosecution or any investigation by an examining court or grand jury of gambling violations, it shall be no exemption for a witness that his testimony may incriminate himself.  </section><section prefix="2">It shall be no exemption for the buyer of a lottery ticket, in any prosecution against the seller of a lottery ticket, that his testimony may incriminate himself.  </section><section prefix="3">No testimony given in the proceedings stated in subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall be used against the testifying witness in any prosecution except for false swearing.  </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, a witness testifying in any prosecution against the seller of a lottery ticket, shall be discharged from all liability for any offense necessarily disclosed in his testimony.  </section><section prefix="5">A witness testifying in any prosecution for gambling shall be discharged from all liability for gambling disclosed in his testimony.  </section><section prefix="6">No person against whom a witness testifies in any prosecution for gambling shall testify as to any gambling by the witness.  </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 334. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1328a, 1973, 2579. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>