<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4023</section_number><catch_line>Renewal, expiration, termination, and reinstatement of license issued under KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540 -- Inactive license.  </catch_line><order_by>4023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each person licensed under the provisions of KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540 shall annually, on or before the last day of the licensee's birth month, renew his or her license. </section><section prefix="2">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed after the anniversary date of the license, during which time a licensee may continue to practice and may renew his or her license upon meeting the requirements promulgated through administrative regulations by the department. </section><section prefix="3">A license not renewed before the end of the sixty (60) day grace period shall terminate based on the failure of the licensee to renew in a timely manner. Upon termination, the licensee shall be ineligible to practice in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">After the sixty (60) day grace period, a former licensee with a terminated license may have the license reinstated upon meeting the requirements promulgated through administrative regulations by the department. An applicant for reinstatement after termination of the license shall not be required to submit to any examination as a condition for reinstatement, if the reinstatement application is made within three (3) years from the date of termination. </section><section prefix="5">A suspended license is subject to expiration and termination and shall be renewed as provided in this section. Renewal shall not entitle the licensee to engage in the practice until the suspension has ended or is otherwise removed by the department and the right to practice is restored by the department. </section><section prefix="6">A revoked license is subject to reinstatement, expiration, or termination but may not be renewed. </section><section prefix="7">An applicant for renewal or reinstatement of a license shall show evidence of completing at least eight (8) hours of continuing education provided by the National Elevator Industry Educational Program, National Association of Elevator Contractors, or another provider approved by the department. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing the permissible content of continuing education programs and the qualifications of the providers. </section><section prefix="8">When applicable, an applicant for renewal or reinstatement of an elevator contractor license shall submit proof that the applicant has complied with workers' compensation and unemployment insurance laws and administrative regulations and has obtained general liability coverage of at least one million dollars ($1,000,000) for injury or death of any number of persons in any one (1) occurrence, with coverage of at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) for property damage in any one (1) occurrence. </section><section prefix="9">The department may, through the promulgation of administrative regulations: <section prefix="a">Establish an inactive license for licensees who are not actively engaging in the elevator or fixed guideway system business, but who wish to maintain their license; </section><section prefix="b">Determine continuing education requirements for reactivation; </section><section prefix="c">Waive the insurance requirements established in subsection (8) of this section for inactive licensees; and </section><section prefix="d">Establish reactivation procedures. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 11, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 11, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>