<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.803</section_number><catch_line>Early mathematics testing program -- Purposes -- Development and requirements of program -- Annual reports. </catch_line><order_by>803</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Early Mathematics Testing Program is created to lower the number of high school graduates in Kentucky who require remediation in mathematics upon enrollment in postsecondary education institutions, by providing information to primarily high school sophomores and juniors statewide regarding their level of mathematics knowledge in relation to standards required for community and technical colleges and university level mathematics courses early enough for students to address deficiencies while still in high school. </section><section prefix="2">The testing program shall be a computer website-based program that incorporates a variety of diagnostic mathematics tests to identify knowledge and skills needed for postsecondary education courses. </section><section prefix="3">The testing program shall be developed and conducted by a public university. The Council on Postsecondary Education, with the advice of the Department of Education, shall develop a process to solicit, review, and select a proposal for the development and implementation of the computer website-based testing program. The council shall approve the location of the program at a public university no later than September 1, 2000. The university shall be the fiscal agent for the testing program and shall receive the funds appropriated by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="4">The program shall be available to all interested Kentucky public and private high school students in grades ten (10) and eleven (11). Student participation in the program shall be voluntary, and program test scores shall not be: <section prefix="a">Placed on a student's high school transcript; or </section><section prefix="b">Used by postsecondary education institutions in the admissions process. </section></section><section prefix="5">The computer website testing program shall be available to all Kentuckians for evaluation of an individual's mathematics knowledge and skills. </section><section prefix="6">The program shall encourage the active participation of all public and private high schools in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="7">The computer website testing program shall: <section prefix="a">Develop or adopt appropriate tests to determine the level of mathematics knowledge of high school students in relation to the standards of placement tests given at the community and technical colleges and undergraduate public universities. In the development or adoption of the tests, consideration shall be given to the program of studies and the minimum requirements for high school graduation established in KRS 156.160 and the alignment of these standards with postsecondary course standards; </section><section prefix="b">Develop a structure to permit each participating student the opportunity to take the computer-based test at school in the presence of school personnel or at the student’s home in the presence of his or her parents or guardian; </section><section prefix="c">Score the completed tests and provide the test scores and diagnostic information on a student’s knowledge and skills electronically to the student and the high school upon completion of the test in the form of electronic mail or printable files or screens. </section><section prefix="d">Provide the following information for up to three (3) participating postsecondary education institutions specified by the student as a possible college choice: <section prefix="1">The student's test score; </section><section prefix="2">A list of mathematics courses required for the student's intended major at a postsecondary education institution; </section><section prefix="3">A list of any remedial courses the student might be required to take based on the student's current level of mathematics knowledge as demonstrated on the test; </section><section prefix="4">The estimated cost of the remedial courses the student might be required to take; and </section><section prefix="5">The high school courses and the specific mathematical concepts or functions a student should consider studying in order to address any deficiencies; </section></section><section prefix="e">Encourage the chair of the mathematics department or the academic dean at each of the participating postsecondary education institutions specified by the student as a possible college choice to send a personalized letter to the student that: <section prefix="1">Encourages the student to take additional high school mathematics courses to address deficiencies in mathematics knowledge; or </section><section prefix="2">Congratulates the student who does well on the test for his or her achievement and encourages continued study in mathematics; and </section></section><section prefix="f">Develop and implement a strategy to raise awareness and encourage participation in the program, targeting high school students, parents, high school faculty and administrators, mathematics departments or faculty at postsecondary education institutions, and the general public. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Kentucky Department of Education shall provide assistance as necessary to the Kentucky Early Mathematics Testing Program to implement the provisions of this section and KRS 158.801. </section><section prefix="9">The public university that conducts the testing program shall submit an annual report to the Kentucky Board of Education and the Council on Postsecondary Education regarding its activities, and the effects of the program on levels of remediation required by participating students. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 258, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3600</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>