<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.440</section_number><catch_line>Procedure on review -- Witness fees -- Finality of decisions. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The manner in which appeals are presented and hearings and appeals conducted shall be in accordance with regulations prescribed by the secretary for determining the rights of the parties, and such hearings to be conducted in a summary manner. A complete record shall be kept of all proceedings in connection with any appeal. All testimony at any hearing upon an appeal shall be recorded either stenographically or mechanically, but need not be transcribed unless further appealed. No examiner, referee or member of the commission shall participate in any hearing in which he is an interested party. </section><section prefix="2">Witnesses subpoenaed pursuant to proceedings under KRS 341.420 and 341.430 shall be allowed fees in accordance with rates allowed by law. Such fees and all expenses of proceedings before the Office of Employment and Training, Department of Workforce Investment, or commission involving disputed claims shall be deemed a part of the expense of administering this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">In the absence of an appeal therefrom, decisions of the commission shall become final twenty (20) days after the date they are made. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 152, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 103. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1954. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-11. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>