<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.702</section_number><catch_line>Educational and vocational programs for parents receiving public assistance -- Reports by cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>702</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall take all necessary actions to ensure that parents receiving public assistance may engage in educational and vocational programs where assessment shows their chances of achieving self-sufficiency will improve. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall file quarterly progress reports and an annual report with the Legislative Research Commission and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare documenting the results of the cabinet's efforts to enable parents receiving public assistance to participate in activities to achieve self-sufficiency. The annual report shall identify the number and proportion of parents, compared to the previous state fiscal year and the last full year of activity under the Job Opportunities and Basic Skills Program who: <section prefix="a">Participated in each type of educational, vocational training, or work activity, including post-secondary education; </section><section prefix="b">Successfully completed educational or vocational programs; </section><section prefix="c">Earned income due to work activity, including work study programs, while receiving public assistance; </section><section prefix="d">Became ineligible for public assistance due to increases in earnings; and </section><section prefix="e">Became ineligible for public assistance for other reasons, including but not limited to penalties or expiration of time limits. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7798</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>