<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.410</section_number><catch_line>Content of contracts -- Powers of president in regard to contracts. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any contract executed by the corporation pursuant to this chapter shall specify the reasons for which any contract may be suspended, revoked, or terminated by the corporation, including, but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Commission of a violation of this chapter or administrative regulations adopted pursuant thereto; </section><section prefix="b">Failure to accurately account for lottery tickets, revenues, or prizes as required by the corporation; </section><section prefix="c">Commission of any fraud, deceit, or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="d">Insufficient sale of tickets; </section><section prefix="e">Conduct prejudicial to public confidence in the lottery; </section><section prefix="f">Any material change in any matter considered by the corporation in executing the contract with the retailer; </section><section prefix="g">Failure to meet any of the objective criteria established by the board pursuant to KRS 154A.400(1). </section></section><section prefix="2">If, in the discretion of the president, such denial, revocation, suspension or rejection of renewal is in the best interests of the lottery, the public welfare, or the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the president may suspend, revoke, or terminate, after notice and a hearing, any contract issued pursuant to this chapter. Such contract may, however, be temporarily suspended by the president without prior notice, pending any prosecution, hearing, or investigation, whether by a third party or by the president. A contract may be suspended, revoked, or terminated by the president for one (1) or more of the reasons enumerated in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 10, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3026</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>