<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="363" order_by="363">WEIGHTS, MEASURES, AND MILLERS' TOLLS </unit></structure><section_number>363.440</section_number><catch_line>Dealer's duties and liabilities. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text>Any person, firm, or corporation engaged in the business of grain buying, custom grain storage and/or grain banking, resale of grain, and grain used for feed manufacturing and who purchases or makes sales based on moisture content must show moisture contents of these commodities as determined on an approved moisture measuring testing device. In the case of grain storage and/or grain banking, moisture content must be determined both when the grain is put in storage and when it is taken out and the same discount schedule used when grain is put into storage must be used when grain is taken out. When small grain, corn and soybeans is bought and the seller is discounted according to the moisture content, this moisture content must be determined by a moisture measuring device approved by the Department of Agriculture. Any person who, by himself or by his agent or as agent of another person, uses in determining moisture content any grain moisture measuring device which has not been tested and approved for use by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture shall be guilty of a misdemeanor; except that the use of a newly purchased grain moisture measuring device prior to regular inspection and approval shall not be considered a misdemeanor if the user of such device has given notice to the Kentucky Department of Agriculture of the purchase and intended use of such new device. Such notice shall be given by either certified or registered mail not later than ten (10) days prior to the date of such intended use. In an emergency situation, a person may substitute an untested moisture measuring device in place of an approved device for a period of not more than twenty-four (24) hours before notifying the department of its emergency use and making arrangements for its inspection.  </text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>