<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.770</section_number><catch_line>Assistant county attorneys, stenographers, secretaries, and other staff positions. </catch_line><order_by>770</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county attorney, with the approval of the Prosecutors Advisory Council, may appoint one (1) assistant county attorney for each District Judge in excess of one (1) in his judicial district unless prior approval is obtained from the Prosecutors Advisory Council for additional appointments; except no assistant county attorney may be appointed in multicounty judicial districts in which there are fewer District Judges than county attorneys unless prior approval is obtained from the Prosecutors Advisory Council for additional appointments. </section><section prefix="2">The number of assistant county attorney positions, stenographic, secretarial and clerical positions and other personnel positions shall be based on real need to be determined with the advice and consent of the Prosecutors Advisory Council. </section><section prefix="3">Assistant county attorneys shall not be prohibited from engaging in the private practice of law. </section><section prefix="4">Any personnel appointed by the county attorney, under this section, who assist in the prosecutorial duties of District Court, shall be appointed for the duration of the unexpired part of the term of the county attorney, and subject to removal at the discretion of the county attorney. </section><section prefix="5">All salaries paid to personnel appointed under this section shall be paid from the State Treasury to the extent such personnel assist in prosecutorial duties. Such salaries shall be commensurate with the appointee's education, experience, training and responsibility, and be based upon the guidelines established by the Prosecutors Advisory Council, which guidelines shall be comparable with the classification and compensation plan for comparable positions maintained by the state Personnel Cabinet, pursuant to KRS 64.640. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 15, effective January 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1008</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>