<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="527" order_by="527">OFFENSES RELATING TO FIREARMS AND WEAPONS </unit></structure><section_number>527.080</section_number><catch_line>Using restricted ammunition during the commission of a crime -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of using restricted ammunition during the commission of a crime when he commits any felony offense under this code and is armed at the time of the commission of the offense or in the immediate flight therefrom with a firearm loaded, as defined in KRS 237.060, with armor-piercing ammunition as defined in KRS 237.060 or flanged ammunition as defined in KRS 237.060. </section><section prefix="2">Using restricted ammunition during the commission of a crime is: <section prefix="a">A Class D felony if no shot is fired; </section><section prefix="b">A Class C felony if a shot is fired and no person is killed or wounded thereby; </section><section prefix="c">A Class B felony if a shot is fired and a person other than the defendant or an accomplice of the defendant is wounded by the shot; and </section><section prefix="d">A Class A felony if a shot is fired and a person other than the defendant or an accomplice of the defendant is killed by the shot. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section are intended to be a separate offense from the underlying crime, which shall be punished separately. If a person is convicted of this offense, his sentence shall be served consecutively to the sentence for the underlying offense. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any person who is justified in acting pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 503. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19963</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>