<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.157</section_number><catch_line>Removal -- Effect of compact -- Membership upon establishment of consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>157</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any member of a planning commission may be removed by the appropriate appointing authority for inefficiency, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or conflict of interest. Any appointing authority who exercises the power to remove a member of the planning commission shall submit a written statement to the commission setting forth the reasons for removal, and the statement shall be read at the next meeting of the planning commission, which shall be open to the general public. The member so removed shall have the right of appeal in the Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding subsection (1) of this section, and KRS 100.143, when a city of the first class and a county containing such city have in effect a compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the terms of the appointed members on the commission shall be for three (3) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified. Upon the effective date of the compact, the mayor, and county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court, shall adjust the terms of the sitting members so that the terms of one (1) of each of their appointments expire in one (1) year, the term of one (1) of each of their appointments expire in two (2) years and the term of one (1) of each of their appointments expire in three (3) years. Upon expiration of these staggered terms, successors shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2) of this section, and KRS 100.143, upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing that city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the terms of the appointed citizen members of the planning commission shall be for three (3) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified, and the term of office of members appointed shall be staggered. Members appointed to the planning commission prior to consolidation of a city of the first class and the county containing the city pursuant to KRS Chapter 67C shall continue to serve as members of the planning commission for the consolidated local government, and shall serve the remainder of the terms for which the members were appointed and until their successors are appointed and qualified pursuant to KRS 100.137(2). </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 138, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 16. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26698</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>