<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.500</section_number><catch_line>Declaration of policy of KRS 353.500 to 353.720. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby declared to be the public policy of this Commonwealth to foster conservation of all mineral resources, to encourage exploration for such resources, to protect correlative rights of land and mineral owners, to prohibit waste and unnecessary surface loss and damage and to encourage the maximum recovery of oil and gas from all deposits thereof now known and which may hereafter be discovered; and to promote safety in the operation thereof. To that end, KRS 353.500 to 353.720 is enacted and shall be liberally construed to give effect to such public policy. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly finds that governmental responsibility for regulating all aspects of oil and gas exploration, production, development, gathering, and transmission rests with state government. The department shall promulgate regulations relating thereto and take all actions necessary to assure efficient oil and gas operations and to protect the property, health, and safety of the citizens of the Commonwealth in a manner consistent with KRS Chapter 353, and to the exclusion of all other nonstate governmental entities except as provided in KRS Chapter 100. The department shall promulgate regulations relating to gathering lines within six (6) months after June 24, 2003. Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting the rights of local governmental units to regulate the use of streets, highways, and rights-of-way. The department shall report quarterly to the Legislative Research Commission beginning July 1, 2003, through December 31, 2004. The report shall detail progress made in carrying out this section, and the efficacy of the regulatory programs implemented. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><lrc-note>.  The interstate compact to conserve oil and gas was ratified, approved, and confirmed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the Governor directed to sign the compact by joint resolution of the 1942 General Assembly (Acts 1942, ch. 267). Section 1 of the compact was repealed, amended, and reenacted by joint resolution of the 1948 General Assembly, authorizing the execution of the interstate compact to conserve oil and gas and any renewal thereof within the Governor's discretion (Acts 1948, ch. 288). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33104</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>