<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="421" order_by="421">WITNESSES </unit></structure><section_number>421.550</section_number><catch_line>No cause of action created -- Immunity of jailers or chief administrator acting in good faith -- Indemnification -- Defense by Attorney General. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in KRS 421.510 to 421.540, or KRS 15.245, 196.280, or 421.500 creates a cause of action for money damages against the state, a county, a municipality, or any of their agencies, public officials, or employees. </section><section prefix="2">The jailer or chief administrator of a juvenile detention facility, regional jail, or county jail, or any of their respective designees who acts in good faith in making available the release information required by KRS 196.280, or in good faith fails or is unable to provide the release information required by KRS 196.280, shall be immune from any criminal liability. </section><section prefix="3">The jailer or chief administrator of a juvenile detention facility, regional jail, or county jail, or any of their respective designees, who acts in good faith in making available the release information required by KRS 196.280, or in good faith fails or is unable to provide the release information required by KRS 196.280, and who is sued for any act or omission in relation to KRS 196.280, and who has a judgment rendered against him and who personally suffers actual financial loss, unreimbursed from any source, by the enforcement and satisfaction of the judgment, including any costs or attorney's fees awarded pursuant thereto, shall be indemnified by the Commonwealth from funds appropriated to the Finance and Administration Cabinet for the payment of judgments, to the extent of his actual financial loss. The indemnification shall not be construed to abrogate or limit any privilege, immunity, or matter of defense otherwise available to the person claiming indemnification and shall not constitute a waiver of any privilege, immunity, or matter of defense, including the sovereign immunity of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The Attorney General shall defend the jailer, chief administrator, or designee upon request, in any suit related to the provision of information under KRS 196.280. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18081</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>