<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.041</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of firearms or ammunition owned by unit of local government -- Disposition of proceeds upon sale.   </catch_line><order_by>041</order_by><text>KRS 45A.343 and 45A.425 to the contrary notwithstanding: <section prefix="1">When a police department, sheriff's department, or other agency of city, county, urban-county, or charter county government or other unit of local government disposes of firearms or ammunition owned by that unit of local government, the disposition shall be by: <section prefix="a">Public auction to persons eligible under federal law to purchase the type of firearm or ammunition being offered for sale; </section><section prefix="b">Trade to the federally licensed firearms dealer providing new firearms or ammunition to the agency; </section><section prefix="c">Transfer to another government agency or government-operated museum in Kentucky for official use or display; or </section><section prefix="d">Sale to the employee to whom the firearm was issued, if all of the following provisions are satisfied: <section prefix="1">The firearm was issued to the employee as his or her service weapon; </section><section prefix="2">The employee is retiring or an employee's service weapon is being replaced; </section><section prefix="3">The employee is otherwise authorized by law to own or possess the firearm; and </section><section prefix="4">The sale price of the firearm is the fair market value of the firearm, not to exceed the actual cost of the firearm to the unit of government; and </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If the firearms or ammunition are sold, the proceeds of the sale shall be utilized solely for the purchase of body armor meeting or exceeding National Institute of Justice standards, firearms, ammunition, or range facilities, or a combination thereof, by the agency of government. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 128, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44239</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>