<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.860</section_number><catch_line>Medical and accident insurance for students.   </catch_line><order_by>860</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education is authorized to provide medical and accident insurance for students enrolled in the state secondary area technology centers and area vocational education centers. The Department of Education may enter into a contract or contracts with one (1) or more sureties or insurance companies or their agents to provide appropriate medical and accident insurance coverage and to provide group coverage to all students enrolled in state-operated schools under its jurisdiction. The appropriate group coverage shall be issued by one (1) or more sureties or insurance companies authorized to transact business in this state, and such coverage shall be approved by the commissioner of insurance. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the medical and accident insurance program. The Kentucky Board of Education may fix the rate of fees for all secondary students, the provisions of KRS 156.856 with respect to fees for secondary students notwithstanding, as he or she deems necessary to meet the expense in whole or in part for appropriate student medical and accident insurance. </section><section prefix="3">The limits of liability and other appropriate provisions for student medical and accident insurance authorized by this section shall be set by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 31, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 182, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 43, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 18, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 52, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 151B.175 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 34, effective July 1, 1990, which prevailed over an amendment to KRS 163.089 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 269, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 163.089. KRS 151B.175. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>151B.175</former-codification-former-code><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The subsequent repeal, with reenactment and amendment, of this section prevails over its amendment by a prior Act of the 1990 Regular Session pursuant to KRS 446.260. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42207</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>