<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.060</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of director of Division of Mine Safety.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director of the Division of Mine Safety shall be a citizen of Kentucky and shall be thoroughly familiar with all methods of safety pertaining to the operation of mines. </section><section prefix="2">The director shall have a practical knowledge of: <section prefix="a">The different systems of working and ventilating coal mines; </section><section prefix="b">The nature, chemistry, and properties of noxious, poisonous, and explosive gases, the dangers due to these gases, and the prevention of these dangers; </section><section prefix="c">The dangers incident to blasting and the prevention of these dangers; </section><section prefix="d">The methods for the management and extinguishment of mine fires; </section><section prefix="e">The methods for rescue and relief work in mine disasters; </section><section prefix="f">The application of electricity in mining operations; </section><section prefix="g">The application of mechanical loading in mining operations; </section><section prefix="h">The equipment and explosives manufactured for use in coal mines; </section><section prefix="i">The methods used in locating oil and gas wells when drilled through any coal seam; </section><section prefix="j">The proper manner of drilling and plugging oil and gas wells; </section><section prefix="k">Mining engineering; and </section><section prefix="l">The methods for the prevention of explosions in mines due to gas or dust. </section></section><section prefix="3">The director shall be capable of efficiently reporting on any proposed development in mining operations or the possibility of operating any coal or clay seam. </section><section prefix="4">The director shall hold a mine inspector's or mine safety specialist's certificate. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 58, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 3, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 14. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 64. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-4. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44527</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>