<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1431</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 218A.1431 to 218A.1438 and KRS 218A.141. </catch_line><order_by>1431</order_by><text>As used in KRS 218A.1431 to 218A.1438 and KRS 218A.141, the following definitions apply: <section prefix="1">"Manufacture" means the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, conversion, or processing of methamphetamine, or possession with intent to manufacture, either directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of natural origin or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis, except that this term does not include activities: <section prefix="a">By a practitioner incident to administering or dispensing of a controlled substance in the course of his professional practice; or </section><section prefix="b">By a practitioner, or by his authorized agent under his supervision, for the purpose of, or incident to, research, teaching, or chemical analysis; or </section><section prefix="c">By a pharmacist incident to dispensing of a controlled substance in the course of his professional practice. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Methamphetamine" means any substance that contains any quantity of methamphetamine, including its salts, isomers, and salts of isomers. </section><section prefix="3">"Traffic" means to distribute, dispense, sell, transfer, or possess with intent to distribute, dispense, or sell methamphetamine. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 58, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>