<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.070</section_number><catch_line>Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology which shall consist of eight (8) members to be appointed by the Governor. Three (3) members shall be audiologists, three (3) members shall be speech-language pathologists, one (1) shall be an otolaryngologist and one (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. The audiologists and speech-language pathologists members shall hold a Kentucky license from the board of speech-language pathology and audiology and shall practice in Kentucky. One (1) of the speech-language pathologist members shall be employed in the public schools of the Commonwealth. The members of the board shall serve until the expiration of the term for which they have been appointed or until their successors are qualified. All appointments made shall be for a term of three (3) years except for appointments to fill vacancies caused by a reason other than the expiration of a member's term which shall be filled for the remaining portion of the member's term. No person shall be appointed to serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall reorganize annually and select a chairman. Four (4) members of the board shall constitute a quorum to do business. The board shall hold at least one (1) regular meeting each year. Additional meetings may be held upon call of the chairman or at the written request of any two (2) members of the board. All meetings of the board shall be open and public. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 5, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 27. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31898</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>