<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.160</section_number><catch_line>Annual report of commissioner -- Record and index of inspections and reports -- Certified copies. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of the department shall annually make a report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission of his proceedings during the preceding calendar year. The annual report shall be prepared and printed as soon as possible after the close of the calendar year. The annual report shall cover the complete operation of the mines in this Commonwealth during the preceding calendar year, enumerating all accidents occurring in or about any such mines during that year, and giving such other information as the commissioner deems useful, and making such suggestions as he deems important as to further legislation on the subject of mining. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall keep and index a permanent record of all inspections made by himself and of all reports relating to inspection of mines furnished to him by mine inspectors. All such records of the department shall be public records and shall, at all times, be open to the inspection of the public, and shall be laid before the Governor or the Legislative Research Commission upon their request at any time. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall furnish certified copies of any such records, when requested to do so, upon payment of such fee as is generally charged by courts of record for certified copies. Such fee shall be paid into the Treasury of the state. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 10, effective March 20, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 13. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739-10, 2739-11. </history><metadata><effective> March 20, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32925</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>