<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIX" order_by="39">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES, ENFORCEMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="426" order_by="426">ENFORCEMENT OF JUDGMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>426.200</section_number><catch_line>Sale of land -- Place of -- Advertisement -- Appraisement.   </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Land shall be sold under execution to the highest bidder at the courthouse door of the county in which it lies. Only so much land shall be sold as will satisfy the execution under which the sale is made. </section><section prefix="2">The officer making the sale shall first advertise the time and place of sale by written notice describing the land to be sold, posted at the courthouse door and three other places in the vicinity of the land for fifteen days next preceding the sale, or by newspaper notice if required by KRS 426.560. </section><section prefix="3">Before a sale of land, the officer shall have the land appraised, under oath, by two disinterested, intelligent housekeepers of the county, who may be sworn by him. If the appraisers disagree, the officer shall act as umpire. If a part of a tract only is sold, the part sold shall, after the sale, be revalued in like manner. The appraisal shall be in writing, signed by the persons making it, subject to inspection by the public prior to the sale, and returned with the execution. The officer shall refer to and explain the proceeding in his return on the execution, which return shall be recorded in full. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 428, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1682. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40159</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>