<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.285</section_number><catch_line>Powers of cabinet -- Forms -- Reports -- Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>285</order_by><text>In addition to the specific authority granted by other provisions of KRS Chapters 202A, 202B, and 210, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall have authority to prescribe the form of applications, records, reports, and medical certificates provided for under KRS Chapters 202A, 202B, and 210 and the information required to be contained therein; to require reports from the head of any hospital relating to the admission, examination, diagnosis, release, or discharge of any patient; to visit hospitals regularly to review the hospitalization procedures of all new patients admitted between visits; to investigate by personal visit complaints made by any persons on behalf of any patients or by any patients themselves; and to adopt such rules and regulations not inconsistent with the provisions of KRS Chapters 202A, 202B, and 210 as it may find to be reasonably necessary for proper and efficient hospitalization of the mentally ill. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 322, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 267, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 38, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 25. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (9). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 59. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 39 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8264</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>