<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.660</section_number><catch_line>Voluntary coverage. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An employer that has in its employment any employee exempted under KRS 342.650 may elect to be subject to this chapter. This election on the part of the employer shall be made by the employer securing the payment of compensation to these exempted employees in accordance with KRS 342.340. Any employee, otherwise exempted under KRS 342.650, of the employer shall be deemed to have elected to come under this chapter, if at the time of the injury for which liability is claimed, his or her employer has in force an election to be subject to this chapter with respect to the employment in which the employee was injured and the employee has not, either upon entering into employment or within five (5) days after the filing of an election by the employer, given to his or her employer and to the commissioner notice in writing that he or she elects not to be subject to this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">An employer within the scope of subsection (1) of this section, within five (5) days after securing the payment of compensation in accordance with KRS 342.340, shall give the commissioner written notice of its election to be subject to this chapter. The employer shall post and keep posted on the premises where any employee or employees, otherwise exempted under KRS 342.650, works, printed notices furnished by the commissioner stating its acceptance of this chapter. Failure to give the notices required by this paragraph shall not void or impair the employer's election to be subject to or relieve it of any liability under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">Any employer who has complied with subsection (2) of this section may withdraw its acceptance of this chapter, by filing written notice with the commissioner of the withdrawal of its acceptance. A withdrawal shall become effective 60 days after the filing of notice or on the date of the termination of the security for payment of compensation, whichever last occurs. The withdrawal shall not be effective until the employer shall theretofore post notice of the withdrawal where the affected employee or employees work or shall otherwise notify the employees of withdrawal. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1838, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 15, sec. 93, effective April 4, 1994. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32536</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>