<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.205Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 65.205 to 65.209.   </catch_line><order_by>205Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 65.205 to 65.209: <section prefix="1">"Energy improvement" means any permanent improvement fixed to real property and intended to increase the efficiency of energy use or decrease water or energy consumption or demand, generate electricity, provide thermal energy, or regulate temperature, including but not limited to a product, device, technology, or interacting group of products, devices, or technologies on the customer's side of an electric, gas, water, or other energy meter; </section><section prefix="2">"Energy project" means the installation or modification of an energy improvement, including any associated project or financing costs; </section><section prefix="3">"Energy project assessment district" or "EPAD" means a geographic area designated by a local government pursuant to KRS 65.206, within which energy projects may be undertaken and financed through the imposition of an assessment pursuant to KRS 65.205 to 65.209; </section><section prefix="4">"Local government" means any city, county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, or unified local government of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="5">"Program" means an EPAD program established by a local government pursuant to KRS 65.206; and </section><section prefix="6">"Real property" excludes residential property consisting of fewer than five (5) units. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>