<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.270</section_number><catch_line>Centralized canteen operation -- Management -- Use of proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text>There shall be established and maintained within the Department of Corrections a centralized canteen operation which shall be incorporated and self-supporting. Each institution administered by the department and each institution which operates under a contract between the state and a private provider shall participate in the canteen operation. The directors of the canteen shall be as follows: the commissioner of the Department of Corrections, the deputy commissioner of Adult Institutions, the executive director of the Division of Administrative Services, and the wardens of all state and private correctional institutions. All profits from the canteen, including the sale of handicrafts made by inmates to the general public, shall be used exclusively for the benefit of the inmates of the department. The directors of the canteen may consolidate the assets of the existing state and private canteens for this purpose and to employ the staff and inmates necessary to efficiently manage the canteen. Assets and profits from the operation of private canteens shall be accounted for separately and utilized exclusively for the benefit of inmates in private prisons. </text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 39, effective July 14, 1992. --  Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 120, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6820</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>