<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.750</section_number><catch_line>Order of protection for family member or member of unmarriedcouple upon filing of petition or action under KRS Chapter 403.  </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>(1)Any family member or any member of an unmarried couple may file for andreceive protection under this chapter from domestic violence and abuse,notwithstanding the existence of or intent to file an action under this chapter byeither party.(2)(a)Any family member or member of an unmarried couple who files apetition for an order of protection based upon domestic violence or abuseshall make known to the court any custody or divorce actions involvingboth the petitioner and the respondent that are pending in any court.(b)If the petitioner or respondent to an order of protection initiates an actionunder this chapter, the party initiating the action shall make known to thecourt the existence and status of any orders of protection, which shallremain effective and enforceable until superseded by order of the court inwhich the case is filed.(3)If a family member or member of an unmarried couple files an action fordissolution of marriage, child custody, or visitation, the court hearing the caseshall have jurisdiction to issue an order of protection upon the filing of a verifiedmotion either at the commencement or during the pendency of the action.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 8, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. --Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 45, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Actsch. 172, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec.6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 8, effectiveJuly 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>