<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.879</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against local ordinances specifically applicable to residential care facilities for persons with a disability -- Information to be provided by Cabinet for Health and Family Services -- Facilities not exempted from general application ordinances.   </catch_line><order_by>879</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">"Local government" means a city, county, charter county, urban-county government, consolidated local government, or unified local government; </section><section prefix="c">"Persons with a disability" has the same meaning as in KRS 100.982; and </section><section prefix="d">"Residential care facility" means a residence, including a group home or staffed residence, operated and maintained by: <section prefix="1">A private agency receiving state or federal funds; or </section><section prefix="2">A government agency; </section></section> that provides services in a homelike setting for persons with a disability. </section><section prefix="2">A local government shall not adopt or enforce any licensing or other requirements specifically applicable to residential care facilities providing services for persons with a disability beyond those required by statutes or administrative regulations of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or the federal government. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A local government may adopt a resolution by its legislative body requesting the cabinet to provide information on each residential care facility within the requesting local government’s boundaries. The cabinet shall provide information to the local government within thirty (30) days of the receipt of the resolution requesting this information. The information provided by the cabinet shall be limited to: <section prefix="1">The physical location of the residential care facility or facilities; and </section><section prefix="2">The name and contact information for the individual or organization primarily responsible for the oversight of the facility or facilities. </section></section><section prefix="b">Once a resolution has been filed by a local government, the cabinet shall: <section prefix="1">Provide that local government updated information if: <section prefix="a">The number of residential care facilities within the jurisdiction changes; </section><section prefix="b">The physical location changes; or </section><section prefix="c">The name and contact information for the individual or organization primarily responsible for the oversight changes; or </section></section><section prefix="2">Provide an annual update of the information provided in this subsection, in the event that the provisions of subparagraph 1. of this paragraph do not occur. </section></section><section prefix="c">The information provided in this subsection shall only be for the use of the local government’s law enforcement agencies, fire protection services, or emergency service providers. The information provided by the cabinet shall not be subject to the provisions of KRS 61.872 to 61.884. This exemption applies solely to the local government receiving the information. </section></section><section prefix="4">This section shall not be construed to exempt residential care facilities from compliance with local government ordinances that apply generally within the jurisdiction, including but not limited to business licensing requirements, occupational license taxes, nuisance and property maintenance codes, public and fire safety ordinances, health and sanitation ordinances, zoning requirements as provided under KRS 100.984, or any other type of local ordinance of general application. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>