<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="119" order_by="119">ELECTION OFFENSES AND PROSECUTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>119.165</section_number><catch_line>False personation of a voter -- Nonresident or unqualified person voting. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who falsely personates a registered voter, and receives and casts a ballot by means of such personation, shall be guilty of a Class D felony. An attempt at such personation shall constitute a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who, by means other than falsely personating a registered voter, votes at an election in this state when he is a resident of another state or country, or votes more than once at an election, or votes by use of the naturalization papers of another person, shall be guilty of a Class D felony. Any person who knowingly votes or attempts to vote in a precinct other than the one in which he resides shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, unless by voting in a precinct in which he does not live he is enabled to vote in a race or on a matter in which he could not vote in his proper precinct in which case he shall be guilty of a Class D felony. Any person who lends or hires his or another's naturalization papers to be used for the purpose of voting shall be subject to the same penalty. </section><section prefix="3">Any resident of this state who, by means other than falsely personating a registered voter, votes at a regular or special election before he has resided in this state thirty (30) days, or in the county and precinct where the election is held the time required by law, or before he has attained full age, or before he has become a citizen, shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who, by means other than falsely personating a registered voter, votes in a primary election knowing that he is not qualified as provided in KRS 116.055, shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who applies for or receives a ballot at any voting place other than the one at which he is entitled to vote, under circumstances not constituting a violation of any of the provisions of subsections (1) to (4) of this section, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 74, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 77. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>