<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.216</section_number><catch_line>Statements of expenditures. </catch_line><order_by>216</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each executive agency lobbyist, employer, and real party in interest shall file with the commission, with the updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211(2), a statement of expenditures as specified in subsections (2) and (3) of this section. An executive agency lobbyist shall file a separate statement of expenditures under this section for each employer engaging him. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">In addition to the information required by paragraph (b) of this subsection, a statement filed by an executive agency lobbyist shall show the total amount of expenditures made by the lobbyist during the reporting period covered by the statement by the executive agency lobbyist. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">If, during a fiscal year, the real party in interest, the employer or any executive agency lobbyist he engaged made expenditures to or on behalf of a particular elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, a particular executive agency official, or a particular member of the staff of any of those officials, the real party in interest, employer, or executive agency lobbyist also shall state the name of the official or employee on whose behalf the expenditures were made, the total amount of the expenditures made, a brief description of the expenditures made, and the approximate date the expenditures were made. </section><section prefix="2">Expenditures shall be reported on the expenditure statement for the reporting period that includes the date on which the expenditure was made. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">In addition to the information required by subsection (2)(b) of this section, a statement filed by a real party in interest or an employer shall show the total amount of expenditures during the period covered by the statement. As used in this subsection, "expenditures" does not include the expenses of maintaining office facilities or support services for executive agency lobbyists. </section><section prefix="b">An employer or real party in interest shall not be required to show any expenditure on a statement filed under this subsection if the expenditure is reported on a statement filed under subsection (2)(a) or (b) of this section by an executive agency lobbyist engaged by the employer. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any statement required to be filed under this section shall be filed at the times specified in KRS 11A.211. Each statement shall cover expenditures made during the prior fiscal year. </section><section prefix="5">If it is impractical or impossible for an executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest to determine exact dollar amounts or values of expenditures, reporting of good faith estimates, based on reasonable accounting procedures, constitutes compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="6">Executive agency lobbyists, employers, and real parties in interest shall retain receipts or maintain records for all expenditures that are required to be reported pursuant to this section. These receipts or records shall be maintained for a period ending on the thirtieth day of June of the second fiscal year after the year in which the expenditure was made. </section><section prefix="7">At least ten (10) days before the date on which the statement is filed, each employer, executive agency lobbyist, or real party in interest who is required to file an expenditure statement under subsection (2)(b) of this section shall deliver a copy of the statement, or the portion showing the expenditure, to the official or employee who is listed in the statement as having received the expenditure or on whose behalf it was made. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 542, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 48, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>