<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="343" order_by="343">APPRENTICESHIP </unit></structure><section_number>343.070</section_number><catch_line>Settlements of controversies or complaints. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the complaint of either party to the agreement, or upon his or her own initiative, the supervisor may investigate or determine if there has been a violation of the terms of the apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement approved under this chapter. He may conduct inquiries and other proceedings necessary to any investigation and determination. The parties to the agreement shall, after reasonable notice, be given an informal hearing before the supervisor. </section><section prefix="2">The determination of the supervisor shall be filed with the commissioner. If no appeal therefrom is filed with the commissioner within fifteen (15) days, the determination shall become final. Any party aggrieved by any determination or action of the supervisor may appeal to the commissioner, who shall hold an administrative hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">Any party to an apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement aggrieved by a final order of the commissioner may appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1867, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 316, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42991</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>