<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.360</section_number><catch_line>Certification of inspectors. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall establish a program to certify persons as inspectors solely for on-site sewage disposal systems.  Persons eligible for certification shall include sanitarians, engineers, soil scientists, and other qualified persons as determined by regulation by the cabinet.  In order to be certified by the cabinet, eligible persons shall: <section prefix="a">Attend a training session concerning the proper construction and installation of on-site sewage disposal systems conducted by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Indicate sufficient skill and competency necessary for proper inspection of on-site sewage disposal systems by adequate performance on an examination prescribed by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Pay a reasonable fee related to the cost of conducting training and certification sessions to be utilized to defray the cost of conducting the sessions; and </section><section prefix="d">Renew the certificates of competence at reasonable intervals. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person shall approve the construction, installation, or alteration of an on-site sewage disposal system unless it is in conformance with the regulations issued by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may revoke or suspend any certification issued pursuant to this section upon proof that the certified person has: <section prefix="a">Knowingly violated the provisions of this chapter or the regulations of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Practiced fraud or deception in applying for or obtaining a certificate; </section><section prefix="c">Is incompetent to perform inspection services; </section><section prefix="d">Permitted the certification to be used directly or indirectly by another to obtain or perform inspections; or </section><section prefix="e">Is guilty of such other unprofessional or dishonorable conduct of a character likely to deceive or defraud the public. </section></section><section prefix="4">Upon appeal of any decision to revoke or suspend a certification, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 107, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8388</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>