<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="505" order_by="505">PROTECTION AGAINST UNFAIR OR OPPRESSIVE PROSECUTION </unit></structure><section_number>505.020</section_number><catch_line>Prosecution for multiple offenses. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a single course of conduct of a defendant may establish the commission of more than one (1) offense, he may be prosecuted for each such offense. He may not, however, be convicted of more than one (1) offense when: <section prefix="a">One offense is included in the other, as defined in subsection (2); or </section><section prefix="b">Inconsistent findings of fact are required to establish the commission of the offenses; or </section><section prefix="c">The offense is designed to prohibit a continuing course of conduct and the defendant's course of conduct was uninterrupted by legal process, unless the law expressly provides that specific periods of such conduct constitute separate offenses. </section></section><section prefix="2">A defendant may be convicted of an offense that is included in any offense with which he is formally charged. An offense is so included when: <section prefix="a">It is established by proof of the same or less than all the facts required to establish the commission of the offense charged; or </section><section prefix="b">It consists of an attempt to commit the offense charged or to commit an offense otherwise included therein; or </section><section prefix="c">It differs from the offense charged only in the respect that a lesser kind of culpability suffices to establish its commission; or </section><section prefix="d">It differs from the offense charged only in the respect that a less serious injury or risk of injury to the same person, property or public interest suffices to establish its commission. </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 44, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>