<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="330" order_by="330">AUCTIONEERS AND AUCTION HOUSE OPERATORS </unit></structure><section_number>330.030Auctioneer's</section_number><catch_line>license required -- When auction house operator's license required.   </catch_line><order_by>030Auctioneer's</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is unlawful for any person to advertise or act as an auctioneer or apprentice auctioneer within the Commonwealth, or advertise or act as an auctioneer or apprentice auctioneer of real or personal property located within the Commonwealth, without a license issued by the board. </section><section prefix="2">It is unlawful for any person to advertise or act as a limited livestock auctioneer within the Commonwealth without a license issued by the board. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">It is unlawful for any person to advertise or act as an auction house operator within the Commonwealth without a license issued by the board. </section><section prefix="b">An auction house operator shall be a licensed auctioneer or apprentice auctioneer if he or she acts as an auctioneer or apprentice auctioneer. If licensed as an auctioneer, an auction house operator license shall not be required. </section><section prefix="c">If an auction house operator conducts and operates more than one (1) auction house, a license shall be issued for each location, and the initial and renewal fees shall be applicable. </section><section prefix="d">This subsection applies to each co-owner or manager of an auction house who actively participates in the operation of the auction house, but who is not an auctioneer. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>