<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.125</section_number><catch_line>Regional planning council. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as set forth in subsection (8) of this section, each area development district shall establish a regional planning council to act in an advisory capacity on planning matters throughout the district. </section><section prefix="2">The regional planning council shall be composed of one (1) representative from each planning unit in the area development district. Each representative shall be appointed annually by the planning commission of each planning unit in the district. To be eligible for appointment to the council, a person shall be a member of the planning commission, or the planning commission's professional staff. </section><section prefix="3">At its first regular meeting in each year, the council shall elect from its membership a president and vice president. The vice president shall have the authority to act as president of the council during the absence or disability of the president. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall meet at the call of the president, but at least quarterly in each year. </section><section prefix="5">To insure compatible treatment of planned development throughout the district, the council may review comprehensive plans of planning units within the district for regional impact, may develop regional transportation, infrastructure, and land use plans for the district, and may make recommendations regarding the regional impact of proposed comprehensive plans and plan amendments of planning units within the district. </section><section prefix="6">The area development district shall provide staff and technical support as requested by the council. Existing land use planning services and functions of the area development district shall be placed under the direction and control of the council. </section><section prefix="7">The council may offer training and education opportunities in the area of planning and zoning matters to planning commission members and staff in the district. </section><section prefix="8">The requirements of this section shall not apply to any area development district in which fifty percent (50%) or more of the population resides in cities or counties which participate in a regional planning authority, council of governments, or other agency which is authorized to perform regional planning functions as described in this section. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>