<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Dentistry -- Members -- Qualifications -- Terms -- Meetings -- Quorum -- Vacancies -- Compensation -- Annual reports. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Dentistry shall consist of ten (10) members, each appointed by the Governor to a four (4) year term. Seven (7) members of the board shall be licensed dentists appointed from a list of three (3) names recommended for each board position by the resident licensed dentists of Kentucky at an annual election at a time selected by the Kentucky Board of Dentistry. Two (2) members of the board shall be dental hygienists licensed to practice dental hygiene in the Commonwealth. Each appointment to the board of a licensed dental hygienist shall be made from a list of three (3) names recommended for this position by the resident licensed dental hygienists of Kentucky at an annual election at a time selected by the board. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. One (1) nonvoting ex officio representative from each the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville shall represent the dental schools' interests. One (1) nonvoting ex officio representative from a hygiene program not associated with the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville shall represent the dental hygiene programs' interests. The hygiene school seats shall rotate on a yearly basis. One (1) nonvoting ex officio representative from the Department for Public Health shall represent the department's interests. </section><section prefix="2">Individuals seeking board appointment, other than the citizen member, shall have been an actual resident and licensed practicing dentist or dental hygienist of the Commonwealth for not less than five (5) years immediately preceding his or her appointment to the board, be in good standing with the board, and shall not have been disciplined by the board in the past eight (8) years. A voting member shall not receive compensation from or have a financial interest in any dental college or dental department of any institution of learning, dental supply business, or any entity over which the board has regulatory authority or sets standards for. For this subsection alone, a private admonishment shall not count as discipline. </section><section prefix="3">No board member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. A member appointed to a partial term vacancy exceeding two (2) years shall be deemed to have served one (1) full term. A former member may be reappointed following an absence of one (1) term. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall annually: <section prefix="a">Meet at least four (4) times a year; </section><section prefix="b">At the first meeting of the board after July 1, elect officers of the board by majority vote of the members present; and </section><section prefix="c">Set a schedule of at least four (4) regular meetings for the next twelve (12) month period. </section></section><section prefix="5">A majority of the voting members of the board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A member of the board who misses three (3) regular meetings in one (1) year shall be deemed to have resigned from the board, and his or her position shall be deemed vacant. </section><section prefix="b">The failure of a board member to attend a special or emergency meeting shall not result in any penalty. </section><section prefix="c">The year specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall begin with the first meeting missed and end three hundred sixty-five (365) days later or with the third meeting missed, whichever occurs earlier. </section><section prefix="d">The Governor shall appoint a person of the same class to fill the vacancy within ninety (90) days. </section><section prefix="e">A person removed under this subsection shall not be reappointed to the board for four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="7">Each voting member of the board shall receive any necessary expenses incurred in attending its meetings. Each voting member shall receive as compensation two hundred dollars ($200) for each day actually engaged in the duties of his or her office. </section><section prefix="8">Annual reports and recommendations from the board shall be sent by February 1 each year to the Governor and the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 556, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998, prevails over ch. 552, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2(1). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2636-3, 2636-18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 552 and 556. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 556, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30807</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>