<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.7-060</section_number><catch_line>Removal of trustee. </catch_line><order_by>7-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The settlor, a cotrustee, or a beneficiary may request the court to remove a trustee, or a trustee may be removed by the court on its own initiative. </section><section prefix="2">The court may remove a trustee if: <section prefix="a">The trustee has committed a breach of trust; </section><section prefix="b">Lack of cooperation among cotrustees substantially impairs the administration of the trust; </section><section prefix="c">Because of unfitness, unwillingness, or persistent failure of the trustee to administer the trust effectively, the court determines that removal of the trustee best serves the interests of the beneficiaries; </section><section prefix="d">There has been a substantial change of circumstances or removal is requested by all of the qualified beneficiaries, the court finds that removal of the trustee best serves the interests of all of the beneficiaries and is not inconsistent with a material purpose of the trust, and a suitable cotrustee or successor trustee is available; or </section><section prefix="e">For a wholly charitable trust, removal is requested by all of the qualified beneficiaries, notice is given to the Attorney General, and the court finds that removal of the trustee best serves the interests of all of the beneficiaries. This provision shall not limit the rights of the Attorney General under any common law or statutory law of this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">Pending a final decision on a request to remove a trustee, or in lieu of or in addition to removing a trustee, the court may order such appropriate relief under KRS 386B.10-010(2) as may be necessary to protect the trust property or the interests of the beneficiaries. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 55, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43118</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>