<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.8-180</section_number><catch_line>Conduct of examination -- Cost of investigation or hearing. </catch_line><order_by>8-180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the conduct of any examination, investigation, or hearing, the commissioner or an officer designated by the commissioner may compel the attendance of any person or obtain any documents by subpoenas; administer oaths or affirmations in the examination of the directors, officers, agents, employees of any mortgage loan company, or mortgage loan broker or any other person concerning the business and conduct of affairs or any person subject to the provisions of this subtitle, and in connection therewith may require and compel the production of any books, records, papers, or other documents relevant to the inquiry. </section><section prefix="2">In the contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, Franklin Circuit Court, upon application by the commissioner, may issue to the person an order requiring him or her to appear before the commissioner, or the officer designated by the commissioner, there to produce documentary evidence if so ordered or to give evidence touching the matter under investigation or in question. Failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt of court. </section><section prefix="3">The cost of any investigation or hearing conducted under KRS 286.8-190 may be assessed to and collected from the mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker in question by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 784, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 294.180. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14878</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>