<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="438" order_by="438">OFFENSES AGAINST PUBLIC HEALTH AND SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>438.305</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 438.305 to 438.340. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text>As used in KRS 438.305 to 438.340, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">"Alternative nicotine product" means a noncombustible product containing nicotine that is intended for human consumption, whether chewed, absorbed, dissolved, or ingested by any other means. </section><section prefix="b">"Alternative nicotine product" does not include any product regulated as a drug or device by the United States Food and Drug Administration under Chapter V of the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Manufacturer" means any person who manufactures or produces tobacco products within or without this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="3">"Nonresident wholesaler" means any person who purchases cigarettes or other tobacco products directly from the manufacturer and maintains a permanent location or locations outside this state at which Kentucky cigarette tax evidence is attached or from which Kentucky cigarette tax is reported and paid; </section><section prefix="4">"Proof of age" means a driver's license or other documentary or written evidence that the individual is eighteen (18) years of age or older; </section><section prefix="5">"Resident wholesaler" means any person who purchases at least seventy-five percent (75%) of all cigarettes or other tobacco products purchased by that person directly from the cigarette manufacturer on which the cigarette tax provided for in KRS 138.130 to 138.205 is unpaid, and who maintains an established place of business in this state at which the person attaches cigarette tax evidence or receives untaxed cigarettes; </section><section prefix="6">"Sample" means a tobacco product, alternative nicotine product, or vapor product distributed to members of the general public at no cost; </section><section prefix="7">"Subjobber" means any person who purchases tobacco products, on which the Kentucky cigarette tax has been paid, from a wholesaler licensed pursuant to KRS 138.195, and makes them available to a retail establishment for resale; </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Tobacco product" means any cigarette, cigar, snuff, smokeless tobacco product, smoking tobacco, chewing tobacco, and any kind or form of tobacco prepared in a manner suitable for chewing or smoking, or both, or any kind or form of tobacco that is suitable to be placed in a person's mouth. </section><section prefix="b">"Tobacco product" does not include any alternative nicotine product, vapor product, or product regulated as a drug or device by the United States Food and Drug Administration under Chapter V of the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">"Vapor product" means any noncombustible product that employs a heating element, battery, power source, electronic circuit, or other electronic, chemical, or mechanical means, regardless of shape or size and including the component parts and accessories thereto, that can be used to deliver vaporized nicotine or other substances to users inhaling from the device. "Vapor product" includes but is not limited to any electronic cigarette, electronic cigar, electronic cigarillo, electronic pipe, or similar product or device and every variation thereof, regardless of whether marketed as such, and any vapor cartridge or other container of a liquid solution or other material that is intended to be used with or in an electronic cigarette, electronic cigar, electronic cigarillo, electronic pipe, or other similar product or device. </section><section prefix="b">"Vapor product" does not include any product regulated as a drug or device by the United States Food and Drug Administration under Chapter V of the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective April 10, 2014. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 2, effective March 5, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> April 10, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42967</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>