<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.027</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of public library facilities construction fund -- Requirement that department report assistance awards to Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue. </catch_line><order_by>027</order_by><text>There is established a public library facilities construction fund to assist local libraries with debt service payments for new library facilities and library improvements. The Department for Libraries and Archives is authorized to enter into long-term written memoranda of agreement with local libraries or other governing bodies to assist in debt service payments relating to library construction or renovation projects. The agreements shall specify the rights, duties, and obligations of both the local public library, or other governing body, and the department. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish the application process, criteria for selecting projects for assistance, a minimum level of local participation, and the process to be followed in the construction of facilities. The department shall report assistance awards to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue within thirty (30) days of execution of any memorandum of agreement. </text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 504, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 6, (4) at 635. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4740</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>