<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.425</section_number><catch_line>Powers of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For this purpose, the commissioner, or the commissioner's authorized representative, may enter the place of employment of any employer to inspect and copy payrolls and other employment records, to compare character of work and operations on which persons employed by him or her are engaged, to question such persons, and to obtain other information necessary to the administration and enforcement of KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14). </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner or the commissioner's authorized representative may examine witnesses under oath, and require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any documentary evidence relating to the subject matter of any investigation undertaken pursuant to KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14). If a person fails to attend, testify or produce documents under or in response to a subpoena, the Circuit Court in the judicial circuit where the hearing is being held, on application of the commissioner or the commissioner's representative, may issue an order requiring the person to appear before the commissioner or the commissioner's authorized representative, or to produce documentary evidence, and any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as contempt. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner may endeavor to eliminate pay practices unlawful under KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14) by informal methods of conference, conciliation and persuasion, and supervise the payment of wages owing to any employee under KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14). </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner may issue regulations not inconsistent with the purpose of KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14), necessary or appropriate to carry out its provisions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1738, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 119. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32091</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>