<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.065</section_number><catch_line>Allocation of costs of eliminating grade crossings between railroad and governmental unit. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text>The entire construction costs of projects for the elimination of hazards of railroad-highway crossings, including the separation or protection of grades at crossings, the reconstruction of existing railroad grade crossing structures, and the relocation of highways to eliminate railroad grade crossings which may be paid for in whole or part from state funds, including, but not limited to, the cost of preparing the plans and specifications and supervising the improvement, the acquisition of necessary property, the construction of approaches, drainage structures, roadways and pavements, accommodations for public utilities, and damages paid to abutting property owners, shall be allocated between the railroad involved, and the governmental unit or units involved in the same ratio as the net benefit received by such railroad from the project bears to the net benefit accruing to the public using the highway, and in no case shall the net benefit to any railroad or railroads be deemed to be more than ten percent (10%) of the total benefit resulting from the project. The Department of Highways shall be responsible for determining the proportion of the benefits derived by the railroad from the project, and shall fix standards for the determining of said benefits which shall be consistent with the standards adopted for similar purposes by the United States Bureau of Public Roads under the Federal-Aid-Highway Act of 1944. The cost of maintenance of all structures for the elimination of railroad grade crossings, and of installations for the protection of existing grade crossings, constructed or installed under this section, shall be borne by the governmental unit or units constructing them. Before any state funds shall be expended for any project constructed under this section, a contract shall be entered into between the railroad and the governmental unit or units involved setting forth the duties of each as to construction and maintenance of the project. </text><history>Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1958</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>