<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.064</section_number><catch_line>Pretrial release of person arrested for assault, sexual offense, orviolation of protective order -- Conditions -- Hearing -- Victim entitled tocopy of conditions of release -- Entry of conditions into Law InformationNetwork -- Penalty.  </catch_line><order_by>064</order_by><text>(1)In making a decision concerning pretrial release of a person who is arrested fora violation of KRS Chapter 508 or 510, or charged with a crime involving aviolation of an order of protection as defined in KRS 403.720 and 456.010, thecourt or agency having authority to make a decision concerning pretrial releaseshall review the facts of the arrest and detention of the person and determinewhether the person:(a)Is a threat to the alleged victim or other family or household member; and(b)Is reasonably likely to appear in court.(2)Before releasing a person arrested for or charged with a crime specified insubsection (1) of this section, the court shall make findings, on the record ifpossible, concerning the determination made in accordance with subsection (1)of this section, and may impose conditions of release or bail on the person toprotect the alleged victim of domestic violence or abuse and to ensure theappearance of the person at a subsequent court proceeding. The conditionsmay include:(a)An order enjoining the person from threatening to commit or committingacts of domestic violence or abuse against the alleged victim or otherfamily or household member;(b)An order prohibiting the person from harassing, annoying, telephoning,contacting, or otherwise communicating with the alleged victim, eitherdirectly or indirectly;(c)An order directing the person to vacate or stay away from the home of thealleged victim and to stay away from any other location where the victimis likely to be;(d)An order prohibiting the person from using or possessing a firearm orother weapon specified by the court;(e)An order prohibiting the person from possession or consumption ofalcohol or controlled substances;(f)Any other order required to protect the safety of the alleged victim and toensure the appearance of the person in court; or(g)Any combination of the orders set out in paragraphs (a) to (f) of thissubsection.(3)If conditions of release are imposed, the court imposing the conditions on thearrested or charged person shall:(a)Issue a written order for conditional release; and(b)Immediately distribute a copy of the order to pretrial services.(4)The court shall provide a copy of the conditions to the arrested or chargedperson upon release. Failure to provide the person with a copy of theconditions of release does not invalidate the conditions if the arrested orcharged person has notice of the conditions.(5)If conditions of release are imposed without a hearing, the arrested or chargedperson may request a prompt hearing before the court to review the conditions.Upon request, the court shall hold a prompt hearing to review the conditions.(6)The victim, as defined in KRS 421.500, of the defendant's alleged crime, or anindividual designated by the victim in writing, shall be entitled to a free certifiedcopy of the defendant's conditions of release, or modified conditions of release,upon request to the clerk of the court which issued the order releasing thedefendant. The victim or the victim's designee may personally obtain thedocument at the clerk's office or may have it delivered by mail.(7)The circuit clerk or the circuit clerk's designee, in cooperation with the courtthat issued the order releasing the defendant, shall cause the conditions ofrelease to be entered into the computer system maintained by the clerk and theAdministrative Office of the Courts within twenty-four (24) hours following itsfiling, excluding weekends and holidays. Any modification of the releaseconditions shall likewise be entered by the circuit clerk, or the circuit clerk'sdesignee.(8)The information entered under this section shall be accessible to any agencydesignated by the Department of Kentucky State Police as a terminal agencyfor the Law Information Network of Kentucky.(9)All orders issued under this section which require entry into the LawInformation Network of Kentucky shall be entered on forms prescribed by theAdministrative Office of the Courts. If the conditions of pretrial release arecontained in an order which is narrative in nature, the prescribed form shall beused in addition to the narrative order.(10)Any person who violates any condition of an order issued pursuant to thissection is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 44, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 309, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended2000 Ky. Acts ch. 400, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Actsch. 345, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>