<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.977</section_number><catch_line>Necessary disclosures for rental-purchase agreement. </catch_line><order_by>977</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For each rental-purchase agreement, the lessor shall disclose the following items as applicable: <section prefix="a">A brief description of the leased property, sufficient to identify the property to the consumer and lessor; </section><section prefix="b">The number, amount, and timing of all lease payments necessary to acquire ownership of the property; </section><section prefix="c">The maximum amount of all initial and periodic payments and other charges to acquire ownership of the property pursuant to the ownership provision of the rental-purchase agreement; </section><section prefix="d">A statement that the consumer will not own the property until the consumer has made the number of payments and the total of payments necessary to acquire ownership; </section><section prefix="e">A statement that the total of payments does not include other charges such as late payment, default, pickup, and reinstatement fees, and that the consumer should see the contract for an explanation of these charges; </section><section prefix="f">If applicable, a statement that the consumer is responsible for the fair market value of the property if it is lost, stolen, damaged, or destroyed; </section><section prefix="g">A statement indicating whether the property is new or used; however, a statement that indicates new property is used is not a violation of KRS 367.976 to 367.985; </section><section prefix="h">A statement of the cash price of the property. If the agreement involves a lease for five (5) or more items, a statement of the aggregate cash price of all items shall satisfy this requirement; </section><section prefix="i">The total of initial payments required to be paid before consummation of the agreement or delivery of the property, whichever is later; </section><section prefix="j">A statement clearly summarizing the terms of the consumer's options to purchase; </section><section prefix="k">A statement identifying the party responsible for maintaining or servicing the property while it is being leased, together with the description of that responsibility and a statement that, if any part of a manufacturer's express warranty covers the leased property at the time the consumer acquires ownership of the property, it will be transferred to the consumer, if allowed by the terms of the warranty; and </section><section prefix="l">The date of the transaction and the identities of the lessor and consumer. </section></section><section prefix="2">With respect to matters specifically governed by the Federal Consumer Credit Protection Act, compliance with that act shall satisfy the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to a lessor who complies with the disclosure requirements of Section 182 of the Federal Consumer Credit Protection Act, 15 U.S.C.A. 1667a, 90 Stat. 250, with respect to a rental-purchase agreement entered into with a consumer. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 304, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was created by two separate 1990 Acts which are identical and have therefore been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35149</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>