<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.525</section_number><catch_line>Consolidation of districts. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petition for consolidating two (2) or more districts shall contain a unanimous resolution by each board of supervisors and filed with the commission requesting the mutual consolidation of these districts. The petition shall contain, as a minimum, the proposed name of the consolidated district, a description of the territory of the district, a statement that there is a need  for the consolidation and that the consolidation is in the interest of each board of supervisors and the general public, and other information required by the commission. The commission may conduct public meetings and public hearings for the consideration of the petition. </section><section prefix="2">Within sixty (60) days after a petition for consolidation of two (2) or more districts has been received by the commission, it shall give due notice of the consolidation being considered and allow comments to be received for a minimum of thirty (30) days. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall determine the feasibility of the petition to consolidate the districts, and if the commission determines that the consolidation is feasible, the commission shall certify that determination to each of the district boards involved in the request. In making that determination the commission shall give regard and weight to the attitudes of each board of supervisors, the attitudes of owners and occupiers of lands lying within the district, and other economic and social factors relevant to the determination. </section><section prefix="4">Upon receipt from the commission of a certification that the commission has determined that the consideration is feasible, the boards shall proceed to consolidate the affairs of the districts. The boards shall file a verified application with the Secretary of State for the dissolution of the existing districts and the establishment of a new consolidated district. The application shall state the proposed procedure, the seven (7) supervisors to remain on the newly-formed board appointed by the commission, and set forth a full accounting of all assets and resources consolidated from each district into the newly-formed district. The Secretary of State shall issue to the board a certificate of consolidation and shall record a copy of the certificate in his office. </section><section prefix="5">Application to the Secretary of State shall provide the following information: <section prefix="a">The name which is proposed for the new district; </section><section prefix="b">The land to be included in the new district; and </section><section prefix="c">The term of office of each of the supervisors to serve on the newly-formed board of supervisors. </section></section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12762</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>