<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.071</section_number><catch_line>Corporation license tax -- Apportionment of capital when corporation holds stock in other corporations. </catch_line><order_by>071</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding KRS 136.070, a bank holding company as defined in KRS 286.3-900 that holds directly or indirectly stock or securities in financial institutions subject to the tax imposed by KRS 136.500 to 136.570 equal to or greater than fifty percent (50%) of its total assets may, at the option of the taxpayer, compute its "capital" under KRS 136.070(2) as follows: <section prefix="1">Determine the corporation's total capital as provided in KRS 136.070(2). </section><section prefix="2">Deduct from the amount determined in subsection (a) of this section, the book value of its investment in the stock and securities of any financial institutions subject to the tax imposed by KRS 136.500 to 136.570 in which it owns more than fifty percent (50%) of the outstanding stock. </section></section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding KRS 136.070, a corporation other than a bank holding company that holds directly or indirectly stock or securities in other corporations equal to or greater than fifty percent (50%) of its total assets may, at the option of the taxpayer, compute capital employed in the business using one (1) of the following options: <section prefix="1">The corporation and its subsidiaries may file a consolidated license tax return that computes capital employed in the business under KRS 136.070 and includes the parent corporation and all subsidiary corporations in which the parent corporation owns more than fifty percent (50%) of the outstanding stock; or </section><section prefix="2">The corporation may file a separate license tax return and deduct from capital, determined in accordance with KRS 136.070(2), the book value of its investment in the stock and securities of any corporation in which it owns more than fifty percent (50%) of the outstanding stock. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of determining the ratio of stock and securities to total assets, as it relates to subsection (1) of this section, the value shall be the value of the accounts as reflected on financial statements prepared for book purposes as of the last day of the calendar or fiscal year. The term "stock and securities" as used in this section means shares of stock in any corporation, certificates of stock or interest in any corporation, notes, bonds, debentures, and evidences of indebtedness. The term "book value" means the value as shown on financial statements prepared for book purposes as of the last day of the calendar or fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 2, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 4, effective April 21, 2004. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 1. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> March 18, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 instructs the Reviser of Statutes to adjust KRS references throughout the statutes to conform with the 2006 renumbering of the Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. Such an adjustment has been made in this statute.  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 160, provides that amendments made to KRS 136.071 in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 2, shall apply to corporation license tax returns due without regard to extension on or after April 15, 2004. (4/21/2004).  2004 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 7, provides that the amendments to KRS 136.071 in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 4, are retroactively effective for tax periods beginning on or after January 1, 2003. (6/24/2003).  On April 3, 2003, the Governor vetoed 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 194 (House Bill 390), sec. 19, which had repealed this section. In his veto message, the Governor stated: "House Bill 390 by its title and in its substance, is an appropriations bill subject to the line item veto provisions afforded the Governor under Section 88 of Kentucky's Constitution." .  Acts 1976, ch. 25, รยง 2 provides "The provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 1977." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28499</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>