<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.0452</section_number><catch_line>Standards for timely receipt of voter registration application -- Removal of names from registration books -- Confidentiality of registration location. </catch_line><order_by>0452</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of determining whether a voter registration application is received during the period in which registration books are open under KRS 116.045(2), an application shall be deemed timely received: <section prefix="a">In the case of registration with a motor vehicle driver's license application, if the valid voter registration form of the applicant is accepted by the circuit clerk before the registration books are closed; </section><section prefix="b">In the case of registration by mail, if the valid voter registration form of the applicant is legibly postmarked before the registration books are closed; </section><section prefix="c">In the case of registration with a voter registration agency, if the valid voter registration form of the applicant is accepted at the voter registration agency before the registration books are closed; and </section><section prefix="d">In any other case, if the valid voter registration form of the applicant is received by the appropriate county clerk before the registration books are closed. </section></section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall send notice to each applicant of the disposition of the application. </section><section prefix="3">The name of a registered voter shall not be removed from the registration books except: <section prefix="a">Upon request of the voter; </section><section prefix="b">As provided by KRS 116.113, upon notice of death, declaration of incompetency, or conviction of a felony; or </section><section prefix="c">Upon failure to respond to a confirmation mailing sent pursuant to KRS 116.112(3) and failure to vote or appear to vote and, if necessary, correct the registration record of the voter's address in an election during the period beginning on the date of the notice and ending on the day after the date of the second general election for Federal office that occurs after the date of the notice. </section></section><section prefix="4">The identity of the voter registration agency or circuit clerk's office through which any particular voter is registered shall not be disclosed to the public. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27299</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>