<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.290</section_number><catch_line>Board's findings and recommendations -- Report on children frequently moved. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local citizen foster care review board shall submit to the court within fourteen (14) days of the six (6) month review its findings and recommendations. The findings and recommendations for each child under review shall include but need not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Whether there is a plan for permanence; </section><section prefix="b">Whether the plan is progressing; and </section><section prefix="c">The appropriateness of the current placement or plan for permanence. If the local foster care review board determines that a current placement or plan for permanence is inappropriate, a separate notification shall be provided to the court, and the cabinet which shall summarize the position of the local foster care review board, the response of the cabinet, if any, to the concerns expressed by the local foster care review board, and any action proposed by the local foster care review board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The local foster care review board shall submit to the court, with a copy to the cabinet, within fourteen (14) days of each meeting of the board, a list of each case reviewed in which a child has been moved three (3) or more times within a six (6) month period. The list shall include the name of the case, the court number, if available, the cabinet case number, the age, sex, and race of the child, and the number of moves that have occurred. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 398, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 90, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 278 and 398 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>