<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.820</section_number><catch_line>Slow-moving vehicle emblem or reflective tape required -- Display -- Regulations for mounting emblem or reflective tape. </catch_line><order_by>820</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, all slow-moving vehicles sold, leased, or rented in, or for use within, the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall have affixed to them as standard equipment a slow-moving vehicle emblem. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, the slow-moving vehicle emblem shall be displayed as herein provided on all slow-moving vehicles operated day or night upon the public roads within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">The slow-moving vehicle emblem shall be mounted as near the center of the rear of the slow-moving vehicle as is practicable, and the lower edge of the emblem shall be mounted at least three (3) feet or more above the road surface, and shall be maintained in a clean, reflective condition. </section><section prefix="4">As an alternative to the slow-moving vehicle emblem, one (1)-inch-wide white or silver reflective tape may be used on motorless slow-moving vehicles as follows: <section prefix="a">The rear of the vehicle shall be covered with a minimum of one hundred (100) square inches of the reflective tape; </section><section prefix="b">The reflective tape on the rear of the vehicle shall, at a minimum, outline the entire rear of the vehicle; </section><section prefix="c">Each side of the vehicle shall be covered with a minimum of thirty-six (36) square inches of reflective tape; and </section><section prefix="d">The highest point of the left front of the vehicle shall be covered with a minimum of twenty-four (24) square inches of reflective tape. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 2, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39989</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>