<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.666</section_number><catch_line>Powers of commission -- Authority to promulgate administrative regulations -- Lists of legislative agents -- Trust and agency account. </catch_line><order_by>666</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall have jurisdiction over the administration of this code and enforcement of the civil penalties prescribed by this code. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall have jurisdiction over the disposition of complaints filed pursuant to KRS 6.686. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may administer oaths; issue subpoenas; compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, books, accounts, documents, and testimony; and have the deposition of witnesses taken in the manner prescribed by the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure for taking depositions in civil actions. If a person disobeys or refuses to comply with a subpoena, or if a witness refuses to testify to a matter regarding which he may be lawfully interrogated, the Franklin Circuit Court may, on application of the commission, compel the obedience by proceedings for contempt as in the case of disobedience of a subpoena issued from the Circuit Court or a refusal to testify in Circuit Court. Each witness subpoenaed under this section shall receive for his attendance the fees and mileage provided for witnesses in Circuit Court, which shall be audited and paid upon the presentation of proper vouchers sworn to by the witness. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may render advisory opinions in accordance with KRS 6.681. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement this code. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall prescribe and provide forms for reports, statements, notices, and other documents required by this code. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall determine whether the required statements and reports have been filed and, if filed, whether they conform with the requirements of this code. The commission shall promptly give notice to the filer to correct or explain any omission or deficiency. </section><section prefix="8">Unless otherwise provided in this code, the commission shall make each report and statement filed under this code available for public inspection and copying during regular office hours at the expense of any person requesting copies of them and at a charge not to exceed actual cost, not including the cost of staff required. </section><section prefix="9">The commission may preapprove leases or contracts pursuant to KRS 6.741. </section><section prefix="10">The commission shall compile and maintain a current index organized alphabetically by name of legislative agent and name of employer of all reports and statements filed with the commission in order to facilitate public access to the reports and statements. </section><section prefix="11">The commission shall preserve all filed statements and reports for at least two (2) years from the date of receipt. </section><section prefix="12">The commission shall provide to the Legislative Research Commission and each member of the General Assembly a list of every legislative agent and employer registered with the commission, including the name of each entity he represents and the date of his registration. The list shall be furnished on or before the tenth day of every month. Changes in the lists shall be furnished on Friday of each week that the General Assembly is convened in regular or extraordinary session. </section><section prefix="13">Upon the sine die adjournment of a regular session of the General Assembly, the commission shall provide to the Registry of Election Finance a list of each person who was registered as a legislative agent or employer at any point during the period in which the General Assembly was convened in regular session. Upon the convening, and within fifteen (15) days after the sine die adjournment of, any extraordinary session, the commission shall provide to the Registry of Election Finance a list of each person who was registered as a legislative agent or employer at any point during that period. </section><section prefix="14">In order to carry out the provisions of this code, the commission may contract with any public or private agency or educational institution or any individual for research studies, the gathering of information, the printing and publication of its reports, consulting, or for any other purpose necessary to discharge the duties of the commission. </section><section prefix="15">The commission may conduct research concerning governmental ethics and implement any public educational programs it considers necessary to give effect to this code. </section><section prefix="16">No later than December 1 of each year, the commission shall report to the Legislative Research Commission on the commission's activities in the preceding fiscal year. The report shall include, but not be limited to, a summary of commission determinations and advisory opinions. The report may contain recommendations on matters within the commission's jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="17">No later than July 1 of each odd-numbered year, beginning July 1, 1995, the commission shall submit a report to the Legislative Research Commission which shall contain recommendations for any statutory revisions it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="18">All funds received by the commission from any source shall be placed in a trust and agency account for use by the commission in the administration and enforcement of the provisions of this code. Funds in the trust and agency account shall not lapse. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 41, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>