<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.460</section_number><catch_line>Persons with disabilities or members of their families to be included in membership of boards and committees affecting them -- Prohibition against discrimination. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text>To ensure opportunities for participation by persons with disabilities and their families in the development of policies, support, and services that affect them: <section prefix="1">Persons with one (1) or more disabilities, or members of their families, who receive the services and support of an advisory board, committee, commission, task force, or ad hoc committee of any executive cabinet or any of its subdivisions shall be included in the membership of each of these advisory boards, committees, commissions, task forces, or ad hoc committees. </section><section prefix="2">Persons with one (1) or more disabilities, or members of their families, shall be included in the membership of local community-based agency governing boards that receive funds directly or indirectly from any executive cabinet or any of its subdivisions to provide services and support to persons with disabilities and their families. </section><section prefix="3">Persons with one (1) or more disabilities, or members of their families, shall be included in the membership of any advisory committee, board, or commission funded or administered by any executive cabinet or any of its subdivisions whose purpose is to establish criteria for services and support for persons with disabilities, or to develop standards that govern these services and support. </section><section prefix="4">Persons with one (1) or more disabilities shall not be discriminated against and shall be given an equal opportunity for membership on any other advisory board, committee, commission, task force, or ad hoc committee consistent with and to the extent required by the Federal Americans with Disabilities Act; </section><section prefix="5">The requirements of this section and KRS 12.465 shall only apply to an advisory board, committee, commission, task force, or ad hoc committee that is created specifically to develop or oversee policies or programs related to persons living with a disability or their families, except that the provisions of subsection (4) of this section shall apply. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 13, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=680</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>