<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.011</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>011</order_by><text>As used in this chapter unless the context clearly indicates otherwise the following definitions shall apply: <section prefix="1">"Advertise" includes the use of handbills, placards, posters, billboards, pictures, printed or written material or newspapers or other publications, or radio, television, Internet, and other communication media; </section><section prefix="2">"Authority" means the Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority; </section><section prefix="3">"Boxing" means a contest or exhibition in which a person delivers blows with the fist which may be reasonably expected to disable or inflict injury and in which boxers compete for money, a prize, or other pecuniary gain; </section><section prefix="4">"Exhibition," means an event or engagement in which the participants show or display their skills without necessarily striving to win or involve amateurs not under the jurisdiction of the Kentucky High School Athletic Association, the National Collegiate Athletic Association, the Amateur Athletic Union, Golden Gloves, USA Boxing, USA Wrestling, or a public show to which an admission ticket is required, or other charge is made, or invitation; </section><section prefix="5">"Kickboxing" means a boxing contest or exhibition where the participants are allowed to throw kicks or foot blows at the opponent in addition to punching with the hands and in which kickboxers compete for money, a prize, or other pecuniary gain; </section><section prefix="6">"Mixed martial arts" means any form of unarmed contest or exhibition in which participants compete for money, a prize, or other pecuniary gain, or for which admission or donations are collected from the audience. Mixed martial arts may include any element or combination of elements of boxing, kickboxing, wrestling, or other martial arts. Exhibitions where participants are judged on form and style and where punches and kicks are pulled shall not be included in this definition; </section><section prefix="7">"Person" includes an individual, partnership, corporation, association or club; </section><section prefix="8">"Professional" is a boxer, kickboxer, mixed martial arts contestant, or wrestler who competes for a money prize, or other pecuniary gain; </section><section prefix="9">"Show" means any organized grouping of boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling matches, contests, or exhibitions coming under the jurisdiction of the Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority; and </section><section prefix="10">"Professional wrestling" means an activity or performance of athletic and wrestling skill between individuals who are not under the jurisdiction of the Kentucky High School Athletic Association, the National Collegiate Athletic Association, or USA Wrestling, in which the participants struggle hand-to-hand primarily for the purpose of providing entertainment to spectators rather than conducting a bona fide athletic contest. The outcome of these matches may be predetermined. Participating wrestlers may not be required to use their best efforts in order to win. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10765</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>