<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.080</section_number><catch_line>"Calendar year," "calendar quarter," "week," and "week of unemployment" defined. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">Except in so far as the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet by regulation prescribes the equivalent thereof to meet particular conditions: <section prefix="a">"Calendar year" means a year beginning on January 1; and </section><section prefix="b">"Calendar quarter" means three (3) consecutive months beginning on January 1, April 1, July 1, or October 1; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Week" means such period of seven (7) consecutive calendar days as the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet regulation prescribes; and </section><section prefix="3">"Week of unemployment" means any period of seven (7) consecutive days, as prescribed by the Education and Workforce DevelopmentCabinet in administrative regulations, during which a worker performed less than full-time work and earned less than an amount equal to one and one-fourth (1-1/4) times the benefit rate determined for him in accordance with the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 341.380. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 70, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 133, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 565, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(24). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 6. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 20, secs. 1 and 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32242</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>