<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.375</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Electronic or electromechanical voting system" means a system of casting votes by use of marking devices and tabulating ballots employing automatic tabulating equipment or data processing equipment. </section><section prefix="2">"Automatic tabulating equipment" means apparatus necessary to automatically examine and count votes as designated on ballots and data processing machines which can be used for counting ballots and tabulating results. </section><section prefix="3">"Voting device" means either an apparatus in which paper ballots or ballot cards are used in connection with an implement by which a voter registers his votes with ink or other substance or by punching, or an apparatus by which such votes are registered electronically, so that in either case the votes so registered may be computed and tabulated by means of automatic tabulating equipment. </section><section prefix="4">"Ballot card" means a tabulating card on which votes may be recorded by a voter by use of a voting punch device or by marking with a pen or special marking device. </section><section prefix="5">"Ballot label" means the cards, papers, booklet, pages or other material on which appear the names of candidates and the questions to be voted on by means of ballot cards or voting machines. </section><section prefix="6">"Ballot" or "official ballot" means the voting machine ballot label, ballot cards, paper ballots, an absentee ballot, or a supplemental paper ballot which has been authorized for the use of voters in any primary, general or special election by the Secretary of State or the county clerk. </section><section prefix="7">"Voting punch device" means an apparatus in which ballots or ballot cards are inserted for the piercing of ballots by the voter. The hole may be in the form of a round dot, rectangle, square, or any other shape that will clearly indicate the intent of the voter. </section><section prefix="8">"Vote marking device" means any approved device for marking a paper ballot with ink or other substance which will enable the ballot to be tabulated by means of automatic tabulating equipment. </section><section prefix="9">"Secrecy envelope" means the envelope handed to the voter with his ballot into which the voter shall place his voted ballot cards. </section><section prefix="10">"Precinct ballot counter" means an automatic tabulating device used at the precinct to tabulate and process ballots. </section><section prefix="11">"Voting machine" or "machine" shall include lever machines and, as far as applicable, any electronic or electromechanical unit and supplies utilized or relied upon by a voter in casting and recording his votes in an election. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27442</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>