<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.340</section_number><catch_line>Prosecution/grand jury level. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text>The prosecution/grand jury level of the system shall consist of at least the following information: <section prefix="1">Listing of each charged offense by name and KRS number; </section><section prefix="2">Level of offense charged or degree of offense charged for each offense in subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="3">Number of charged offenses; </section><section prefix="4">If the case was disposed of by the prosecutor, the nature of such disposition and the date of such disposition; </section><section prefix="5">A listing of the charges disposed of in subsection (4) of this section; </section><section prefix="6">A correlation of the number of offenses charged at arrest and the number of offenses brought before the grand jury, offense by offense; </section><section prefix="7">Listing of each charged offense, and the level thereof, brought before the grand jury; </section><section prefix="8">Listing of the disposition of each charged offense brought before the grand jury; </section><section prefix="9">Date of indictment; </section><section prefix="10">Listing of each charged offense, and the level thereof, for which the offender was indicted; </section><section prefix="11">Listing of the number of criminal complaints brought before the prosecutor by written complaint, the offense alleged, and the disposition thereof; and </section><section prefix="12">Listing of the number of criminal complaints sought by citizens upon which no action was taken by the prosecutor, the offense alleged, and the date of disposition. </section>All data required by this section shall be supplied to the circuit clerk by each Commonwealth's and county attorney, if it is not already in the possession of the clerk. </text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20954</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>