<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="404" order_by="404">CONTRACTS AND SEPARATE ESTATE OF MARRIED WOMEN </unit></structure><section_number>404.060</section_number><catch_line>Married women as parties to actions. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A married woman may sue, and be sued, as a single woman.  </section><section prefix="2">She may defend an action against her and her husband for herself, and for him also if he fail to defend.  </section><section prefix="3">If a husband desert his wife, she may bring or defend for him any action which he might bring or defend, and shall have the powers and rights with reference thereto which he would have had but for such desertion.  </section><section prefix="4">If a female party to an action marry, her husband may be made a party by a motion, causing the fact to be stated upon the record; and the action shall not be delayed by reason of the marriage.  </section><section prefix="5">But if a wife be adjudged mentally disabled, or imprisoned, the actions mentioned in subsections (1), (2) and (3), of this section must be prosecuted or defended by her guardian, conservator, or curator, if she have one, and if she have none, must be prosecuted by her next friend, or defended by her guardian ad litem. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 129, effective July 1, 1982. -- Transferred 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1953, from C.C. sec. 34. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982</effective><note>. 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 140 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17540</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>