<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC ADVOCACY </unit></structure><section_number>31.050</section_number><catch_line>Public advocacy plans -- Review and approval or denial by public advocate -- Funding by department and governmental unit -- Recordkeeping -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The public advocate shall review and approve or deny or suggest modifications to all plans which are submitted to the Department of Public Advocacy for defense of indigent persons. </section><section prefix="2">If the plan for defense of indigent persons is approved, the public advocate may allot a sufficient sum, subject to the approval of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet to the county or counties in the judicial circuit involved for the purpose of assisting the said plan. </section><section prefix="3">At the end of each funding period, any moneys not expended shall revert to the state Department of Public Advocacy. </section><section prefix="4">Counties, urban-counties, charter counties, consolidated local governments, and other units submitting applications under this chapter shall be obligated to pay and shall pay all costs incurred in their own defense of indigent programs which are in excess of the maximum amount allotted or other maximum amount of grant as specified in this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The fiscal court; legislative body of the urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government; or nonprofit corporation is authorized to seek and apply for and solicit funds for the operation of the defense of the indigent from any source, public or private, and to receive donations, grants, awards, and similar funds from any legal source. </section><section prefix="6">A defending attorney shall keep appropriate records respecting each needy person whom he or she represents under this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">The public advocate, nonprofit organization, or person administering a public advocacy plan shall submit an annual report to the Department of Public Advocacy showing the number of persons represented under this chapter, the crimes involved, the outcome of each case, and the expenditures, totalled by kind, made in carrying out the responsibilities imposed by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 22, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 2. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21219</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>