<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6403</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for certification prior to July 1, 2012 -- Pending certification.  </catch_line><order_by>6403</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for certification as a fire sprinkler inspector under this chapter making application to the department prior to July 1, 2012, shall be certified by the department without completing the certification requirements as established in this chapter if: <section prefix="a">The applicant is currently certified by the state of Kentucky, or </section><section prefix="b">The applicant is currently licensed, certified, or registered as a fire sprinkler inspector in another state whose standards are substantially equal to those in this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to July 1, 2012, the department may issue a pending certification to an applicant. A pending certification shall allow the applicant to act in the capacity applied for until the applicant's permanent certification is issued or the application is denied. </section><section prefix="3">After July 1, 2012, certification under this section shall cease. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 31, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts. ch. 116, sec. 31, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Acts. ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>