<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.120</section_number><catch_line>Division of income of interstate business for tax purposes -- Apportionment. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Business income" means income arising from transactions and activity in the regular course of a trade or business of the corporation and includes income from tangible and intangible property if the acquisition, management, or disposition of the property constitutes integral parts of the corporation's regular trade or business operations; </section><section prefix="b">"Commercial domicile" means the principal place from which the trade or business of the corporation is managed; </section><section prefix="c">"Compensation" means wages, salaries, commissions, and any other form of remuneration paid or payable to employees for personal services; </section><section prefix="d">"Financial organization" means any bank, trust company, savings bank, industrial bank, land bank, safe deposit company, private banker, savings and loan association, credit union, cooperative bank, investment company, or any type of insurance company; </section><section prefix="e">"Nonbusiness income" means all income other than business income; </section><section prefix="f">"Public service company" means any business entity subject to taxation under KRS 136.120; </section><section prefix="g">"Sales" means all gross receipts of the corporation not allocated under subsections (3) through (7) of this section, except as provided by KRS 141.121; and </section><section prefix="h">"State" means any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, and any foreign country or political subdivision thereof. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any corporation which is required by KRS 141.010(14)(b) to allocate and apportion its net income shall allocate and apportion its net income as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="3">Rents and royalties from real, intangible or tangible personal property, capital gains and losses, interest, or patent or copyright royalties, to the extent that they constitute nonbusiness income, shall be allocated as provided in subsections (4) through (7) of this section. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Net rents and royalties from real property located in this state are allocable to this state. </section><section prefix="b">Net rents and royalties from tangible personal property are allocable to this state if and to the extent that the property is utilized in this state; or in their entirety if the corporation's commercial domicile is in this state and the corporation is not organized under the laws of or taxable in the state in which the property is utilized. </section><section prefix="c">The extent of utilization of tangible personal property in a state is determined by multiplying the rents and royalties by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of days of physical location of the property in the state during the rental or royalty period in the taxable year and the denominator of which is the number of days of physical location of the property everywhere during all rental or royalty periods in the taxable year. If the physical location of the property during the rental or royalty period is unknown or unascertainable by the corporation, the tangible personalty is utilized in the state in which the property was located at the time the rental or royalty payer obtained possession. </section><section prefix="d">Net rents and royalties from intangible personal property located in this state are allocable to this state. For purposes of this section, royalties from property leased in Kentucky shall be considered as royalties from intangible personal property. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Capital gains and losses from sales or other dispositions of real property located in this state are allocable to this state. </section><section prefix="b">Capital gains and losses from sales or other dispositions of tangible personal property are allocable to this state if the property had a situs in this state at the time of the sale, or the corporation's commercial domicile is in this state and the corporation is not taxable in the state in which the property had a situs. </section><section prefix="c">Capital gains and losses from sales or other dispositions of intangible personal property are allocable to this state if the corporation's commercial domicile is in this state. </section></section><section prefix="6">Interest is allocable to this state if the corporation's commercial domicile is in this state. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Patent and copyright royalties are allocable to this state if and to the extent that the patent or copyright is utilized by the payer in this state; or if and to the extent that the patent or copyright is utilized by the payer in a state in which the corporation is not taxable and the corporation's commercial domicile is in this state. </section><section prefix="b">A patent is utilized in a state to the extent that it is employed in production, fabrication, manufacturing, or other processing in the state or to the extent that a patented product is produced in the state. If the basis of receipts from patent royalties does not permit allocation to states or if the accounting procedures do not reflect states of utilization, the patent is utilized in the state in which the corporation's commercial domicile is located. </section><section prefix="c">A copyright is utilized in a state to the extent that printing or other publication originates in the state. If the basis of receipts from copyright royalties does not permit allocation to states or if the accounting procedures do not reflect states of utilization, the copyright is utilized in the state in which the corporation's commercial domicile is located. </section></section><section prefix="8">Except as provided in subsection (9) of this section, all business income shall be apportioned to this state by multiplying the income by a fraction, the numerator of which is the property factor, representing twenty-five percent (25%) of the fraction, plus the payroll factor, representing twenty-five percent (25%) of the fraction, plus the sales factor, representing fifty percent (50%) of the fraction, and the denominator of which is four (4), reduced by the number of factors, if any, having no denominator, provided that if the sales factor has no denominator, then the denominator shall be reduced by two (2). <section prefix="a">The property factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the average value of the corporation's real and tangible personal property owned or rented and used in this state during the tax period and the denominator of which is the average value of all the corporation's real and tangible personal property owned or rented and used during the tax period; provided, however, that property which has been certified as a pollution control facility as defined in KRS 224.1-300 shall be excluded from the property factor. <section prefix="1">Property owned is valued at its original cost. If the original cost of any property is not determinable or is nominal or zero (0) the property shall be valued by the department pursuant to administrative regulations promulgated by the department. Property rented is valued at eight (8) times the net annual rental rate. Net annual rental rate is the annual rental rate paid by the corporation less any annual rental rate received by the corporation from subrentals, provided that the rental and subrentals are reasonable. If the department determines that the annual rental or subrental rate is unreasonable, or if a nominal or zero (0) rate is charged, the department may determine and apply the rental rate as will reasonably reflect the value of the property rented by the corporation. </section><section prefix="2">The average value of property shall be determined by averaging the values at the beginning and ending of the tax period but the department may require the averaging of monthly values during the tax period if reasonably required to reflect properly the average value of the property. </section></section><section prefix="b">The payroll factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the total amount paid or payable in this state during the tax period by the corporation for compensation, and the denominator of which is the total compensation paid or payable by the corporation everywhere during the tax period. Compensation is paid or payable in this state if: <section prefix="1">The individual's service is performed entirely within the state; </section><section prefix="2">The individual's service is performed both within and without the state, but the service performed without the state is incidental to the individual's service within the state; or </section><section prefix="3">Some of the service is performed in the state and the base of operations or, if there is no base of operations, the place from which the service is directed or controlled is in the state, or the base of operations or the place from which the service is directed or controlled is not in any state in which some part of the service is performed, but the individual's residence is in this state. </section></section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The sales factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the total sales of the corporation in this state during the tax period, and the denominator of which is the total sales of the corporation everywhere during the tax period. </section><section prefix="2">Sales of tangible personal property are in this state if: <section prefix="a">The property is delivered or shipped to a purchaser, other than the United States government, or to the designee of the purchaser within this state regardless of the f.o.b. point or other conditions of the sale; or </section><section prefix="b">The property is shipped from an office, store, warehouse, factory, or other place of storage in this state and the purchaser is the United States government. </section></section><section prefix="3">Sales, other than sales of tangible personal property, are in this state if the income-producing activity is performed in this state; or the income-producing activity is performed both in and outside this state and a greater proportion of the income-producing activity is performed in this state than in any other state, based on costs of performance. </section></section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">If the allocation and apportionment provisions of this section do not fairly represent the extent of the corporation's business activity in this state, the corporation may petition for or the department may require, in respect to all or any part of the corporation's business activity, if reasonable: <section prefix="1">Separate accounting; </section><section prefix="2">The exclusion of any one (1) or more of the factors; </section><section prefix="3">The inclusion of one (1) or more additional factors which will fairly represent the corporation's business activity in this state; or </section><section prefix="4">The employment of any other method to effectuate an equitable allocation and apportionment of income. </section></section><section prefix="b">A corporation may elect the allocation and apportionment methods for the corporation's business income provided for in subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph. The election, if made, shall be irrevocable for a period of five years. <section prefix="1">All business income derived directly or indirectly from the sale of management, distribution, or administration services to or on behalf of regulated investment companies, as defined under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended, including trustees, and sponsors or participants of employee benefit plans which have accounts in a regulated investment company, shall be apportioned to this state only to the extent that shareholders of the investment company are domiciled in this state as follows: <section prefix="a">Total business income shall be multiplied by a fraction, the numerator of which shall be Kentucky receipts from the services for the tax period and the denominator of which shall be the total receipts everywhere from the services for the tax period. </section><section prefix="b">For purposes of subdivision a. of this subparagraph, Kentucky receipts shall be determined by multiplying total receipts for the tax period from each separate investment company for which the services are performed by a fraction. The numerator of the fraction shall be the average of the number of shares owned by the investment company's shareholders domiciled in this state at the beginning of and at the end of the investment company's taxable year, and the denominator of the fraction shall be the average of the number of the shares owned by the investment company shareholders everywhere at the beginning of and at the end of the investment company's taxable year. </section><section prefix="c">Nonbusiness income shall be allocated to this state as provided in subsections (4) through (7) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">All business income derived directly or indirectly from the sale of securities brokerage services by a business which operates within the boundaries of any area of the Commonwealth, which on June 30, 1992, was designated as a Kentucky Enterprise Zone, as defined in KRS 154.655(2), shall be apportioned to this state only to the extent that customers of the securities brokerage firm are domiciled in this state. The portion of business income apportioned to Kentucky shall be determined by multiplying the total business income from the sale of these services by a fraction determined in the following manner: <section prefix="a">The numerator of the fraction shall be the brokerage commissions and total margin interest paid in respect of brokerage accounts owned by customers domiciled in Kentucky for the brokerage firm's taxable year; and </section><section prefix="b">The denominator of the fraction shall be the brokerage commissions and total margin interest paid in respect of brokerage accounts owned by all of the brokerage firm's customers for that year. </section><section prefix="c">Nonbusiness income shall be allocated to this state as provided in subsections (4) through (7) of this section. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="10">Public service companies and financial organizations required by KRS 141.010(14)(b) to allocate and apportion net income shall allocate and apportion such income as follows: <section prefix="a">Nonbusiness income shall be allocated to this state as provided in subsections (4) through (7) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Business income shall be apportioned to this state by multiplying the business income by a fraction, the numerator of which is the property factor, representing twenty-five percent (25%) of the fraction, plus the payroll factor, representing twenty-five percent (25%) of the fraction, plus the sales factor, representing fifty percent (50%) of the fraction, and the denominator of which is four (4), reduced by the number of factors, if any, having no denominator, provided that if the sales factor has no denominator, then the denominator shall be reduced by two (2). The payroll factor shall be determined as provided in subsection (8)(b) of this section. The property factor and sales factor shall be determined as provided by administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="c">An affiliated group electing to file a consolidated return under KRS 141.200(4) or required to file a consolidated return under KRS 141.200(11) that includes a public service company, a provider of communications services or multichannel video programming services as defined in KRS 136.602, or financial organization shall determine the amount of payroll to be included in the apportionment factor as provided in subsection (8)(b) of this section. The amount of property and sales of the public service company, provider of communications services or multichannel video programming services as defined in KRS 136.602, or financial organization to be included in the apportionment factors of the affiliated group shall be determined in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the department under paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="11">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007, a corporation that: <section prefix="a">Owns an interest in a limited liability pass-through entity; or </section><section prefix="b">Owns an interest in a general partnership organized or formed as a general partnership after January 1, 2006; </section></section> shall include the proportionate share of sales, property, and payroll of the limited liability pass-through entity or general partnership when apportioning income, and shall include the proportionate share of sales in calculating the tax due pursuant to KRS 141.0401. The phrases "an interest in a limited liability pass-through entity" and "an interest in a general partnership organized or formed as a general partnership after January 1, 2006," shall extend to each level of multiple-tiered pass-through entities. </text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 6, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 481, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 11, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 543, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, Pt. VII, sec. 19, effective July 29, 1985. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 10. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 4; and ch. 163, sec. 4. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 176, Part I, sec. 6. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 3. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 10. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4281b-32. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4 provides that the amendments made to this section by that Act "shall apply to taxable periods beginning after December 31, 2007." (6/28/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 701, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the reorganization of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. Such a correction has been made in this section. (6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007."  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29077</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>