<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.550</section_number><catch_line>Dental laboratories -- Employees -- Prohibitions. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dental laboratory shall employ at least one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">A certified dental technician who shall supervise all work performed in accordance with a written laboratory procedure work order issued by a dentist licensed pursuant to this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">A dentist licensed pursuant to this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">No dentist shall use the services of any dental laboratory to construct, alter, repair, or duplicate any denture, plate, bridge, splint, orthodontic, or prosthetic appliance, without first furnishing the commercial dental laboratory a written procedure work order. Both the commercial dental laboratory and the dentist producing the work order shall keep a copy on file for two (2) years, and all laboratory procedure work orders required by this subsection shall be open to inspection by the board. </section><section prefix="3">A dental laboratory that employs or contracts with a dentist licensed according to this chapter may construct, alter, repair, or duplicate any denture, plate, bridge, splint, orthodontic, or prosthetic appliance without a work order from a referring dentist if the patient is seen or evaluated, or whose care is supervised by the referring dentist. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>