<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.315</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Law Enforcement Council.   </catch_line><order_by>315</order_by><text>The Kentucky Law Enforcement Council is hereby established as an independent administrative body of state government to be made up as follows: <section prefix="1">The Attorney General of Kentucky, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, the commissioner of the Department of Criminal Justice Training, the chief of police of the Louisville Metro Police Department, the chief of police of the Lexington-Fayette Urban County Division of Police, the director of the Southern Police Institute of the University of Louisville, the dean of the College of Justice and Safety of Eastern Kentucky University, the president of the Kentucky Peace Officers Association, the president of the Kentucky Association of Chiefs of Police, the Kentucky president of the Fraternal Order of Police, and the president of the Kentucky Sheriffs' Association shall be ex officio members of the council, as full voting members of the council by reason of their office. The United States attorneys for the Eastern and Western Districts of Kentucky may confer and designate a local law enforcement liaison who shall serve on the council in an advisory capacity only without voting privileges. Each ex officio member may designate in writing a person to represent him or her and to vote on his or her behalf. Designees of the Department of Kentucky State Police, Department of Criminal Justice Training, Louisville Metro Police Department, and the Lexington-Fayette Urban County Division of Police shall be the head of the agency's training division or the agency's deputy chief or deputy commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Twelve (12) members shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of four (4) years from the following classifications: a city manager or mayor, a county judge/executive, three (3) Kentucky sheriffs, a member of the Kentucky State Bar Association, five (5) chiefs of police, and a citizen of Kentucky not coming within the foregoing classifications. No person shall serve beyond the time he or she holds the office or employment by reason of which he or she was initially eligible for appointment. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment and the successor shall be appointed for the unexpired term. Any member may be appointed for additional terms. </section><section prefix="3">No member may serve on the council with the dual membership as the representative of more than one (1) of the aforementioned groups or the holder of more than one (1) of the aforementioned positions. In the event that an existing member of the council assumes a position entitling him to serve on the council in another capacity, the Governor shall appoint an additional member from the group concerned to prevent dual membership. </section><section prefix="4">Membership on the council does not constitute a public office, and no member shall be disqualified from holding public office by reason of his membership. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 18, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 534, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>