<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.225</section_number><catch_line>Client Assistance Program. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Client Assistance Program which is assigned for administrative purposes to the Office of Legal and Legislative Services within the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Client Assistance Program shall pursue legal, administrative, and other appropriate remedies to ensure the protection of rights of individuals with disabilities who are receiving treatment, services, or rehabilitation under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended. If additional resources are required to perform the duties and responsibilities of the Client Assistance Program, the cabinet, on behalf of the Client Assistance Program, may contract with other state agencies to obtain necessary legal or other professional services. </section><section prefix="3">The Office of Legal and Legislative Services shall serve as the agency in charge of all personnel, equipment, records, files, and funds pertaining to the Client Assistance Program as provided for in the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, as amended. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 22, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 48, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 44, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>