<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.205</section_number><catch_line>Challenges.   </catch_line><order_by>205</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The military judge and members of a general or special court-martial may be challenged by the accused or the trial counsel for cause stated to the court. The military judge or the court shall determine the relevancy and validity of challenges for cause, and may not receive a challenge to more than one (1) person at a time. Challenges by the trial counsel shall ordinarily be presented and decided before those by the accused are offered. </section><section prefix="b">If the exercise of a challenge for cause reduces the court below the minimum number of members required by KRS 35.075, all parties shall, notwithstanding KRS 35.145, either exercise or waive any challenge for cause then apparent against the remaining members of the court before additional members are detailed by the court. However, peremptory challenges shall not be exercised at that time. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each accused and trial counsel is entitled to one (1) peremptory challenge of members of the court. The military judge may not be challenged except for cause. </section><section prefix="b">If the exercise of a peremptory challenge reduces the court below the minimum number of members required by KRS 35.075, the parties shall, notwithstanding KRS 35.145, either exercise or waive any remaining peremptory challenge not previously waived against the remaining members of the court before additional members are detailed to the court. </section><section prefix="c">Whenever additional members are detailed to the court, and after any challenges for cause against such additional members are presented and decided, each accused and the trial counsel are entitled to one (1) peremptory challenge against members not previously subject to peremptory challenge. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 42, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 27. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 40, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41916</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>