<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.24-200</section_number><catch_line>Special meetings of members of mutual insurer. </catch_line><order_by>24-200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A special meeting of the members of a mutual insurer may be held for any lawful purpose. The meeting shall be called by the corporate secretary pursuant to request of the insurer's president or of its board of directors, or upon request in writing signed by not less than one-tenth (1/10) of the insurer's members. The meeting shall be held at such time as the secretary may fix, but not less than ten (10) nor more than thirty (30) days after receipt of the request. If the secretary fails to issue such call, the president, directors, or members making the request may do so.  </section><section prefix="2">Not less than ten (10) days' written notice of the meeting shall be given. Notice addressed to the insurer's members at their respective post office addresses last of record with the insurer and deposited, postage prepaid, in a letter depository of the United States post office, shall be deemed to have been given when so mailed. In lieu of mailed notice the insurer may publish the notice in such publication or publications as shall afford a majority of its members a reasonable opportunity to have actual advance notice of the meeting. The notice shall state the purpose of the meeting, and no business shall be transacted at the meeting of which notice was not so given.  </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 24, sec. 20, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29552</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>