<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.160</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of carcasses -- How and when made. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All carcasses of domestic livestock, poultry, and fish which have died or which have been destroyed on account of any disease, except as determined and permitted by the state veterinarian or other representative of the board, shall be disposed of by: <section prefix="a">Complete incineration of the entire carcass and all of its parts and products; </section><section prefix="b">Boiling the carcass and all of its parts and products in water or heating it with steam at a temperature above boiling, continuously for two (2) hours or more; </section><section prefix="c">Burying the carcass and all of its parts and products in the earth at a point which is never covered with the overflow of ponds or streams and which is not less than one hundred (100) feet distant from any watercourse, sinkhole, well, spring, public highway, residence, or stable. The carcass shall be placed in an opening in the earth at least four (4) feet deep, the abdominal and thoracic cavities opened wide their entire length with a sharp instrument, and the entire carcass covered with two (2) inches of quicklime and at least three (3) feet of earth. </section><section prefix="d">Removal of the carcass by a duly-licensed rendering establishment; </section><section prefix="e">Deposition of the carcass in a contained landfill approved pursuant to KRS Chapter 224; </section><section prefix="f">Composting of the carcass in a facility according to the board's administrative regulations and approved in accordance with KRS Chapter 224; </section><section prefix="g">Any combination of the methods set forth in paragraphs (a) to (f) of this subsection; or </section><section prefix="h">Any other scientifically-proven method of disposal approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The owner shall dispose of the carcass of domestic livestock, poultry, and fish as provided in subsection (1) of this section, within forty-eight (48) hours after the carcass is found unless the carcass is otherwise preserved in cold storage. </section><section prefix="3">The board is authorized to promulgate administrative regulations to implement this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 233, effective July 15, 1980. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 63c-8. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>