<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.410</section_number><catch_line>Evaluation of textbooks and programs. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief state school officer shall prepare minimum manufacturing standards, delineate content specifications, in accordance with the curriculum requirements of the program of studies for Kentucky schools: grades K-12, and formulate other criteria for use in the evaluation of textbooks and programs in Kentucky. Criteria shall require that all materials be suitable for use with a diverse population and be free of social, ethnic, racial, religious, age, gender, and geographic bias. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the duty of the chief state school officer to prepare all necessary forms for use in the evaluation of textbooks and programs, such as advertising for textbook bids; forms for bids, bonds, and contracts; and other forms. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall have authority to prescribe: <section prefix="a">Administrative regulations pertaining to all textbook samples for use on the state and local levels; and </section><section prefix="b">Shall have authority to promulgate administrative regulations relating to the agents and representatives of textbooks and programs, as to the methods and procedures for use in adoptions on the state and local levels. </section></section><section prefix="4">The chief state school officer, on or before May 1 prior to any adoption year, shall properly advertise the subjects for which textbook adoptions will be made and notify the different publishers of the textbooks. The publishers, on or before July 15, of any adoption year, shall file with the chief state school officer textbook samples, filing fees, textbook bids and bonds, and other specified information relative to the books that they desire to offer for adoption. </section><section prefix="5">The chief state school officer shall: <section prefix="a">Review the bid information submitted by the publishers; </section><section prefix="b">Verify that the bid complies with the specifications; and </section><section prefix="c">Prepare a list of textbooks and programs, for consideration by the State Textbook Commission indicating those in compliance with the standards and specifications and those not in compliance, detailing areas of noncompliance. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 148, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 3, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3179</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>