<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.065</section_number><catch_line>State-owned vehicles -- How marked -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every state-owned motor vehicle, except as provided in subsection (2), shall have an official license plate. Except as provided in subsections (2), (3), and (4) on one (1) door on each side of every state-owned vehicle shall be the great seal of the Commonwealth and the words "For Official Use Only." </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Revenue, the Transportation Cabinet, the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the Public Protection Cabinet, and the Attorney General may authorize registration under KRS 186.020 and be issued regular license plates for vehicles used for investigatory purposes. The Administrative Office of the Courts may authorize registration under KRS 186.020 and be issued regular license plates for vehicles used by justices and judges of the Supreme Court and Court of Appeals. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor and the Lieutenant Governor may each use one (1) state-owned motor vehicle on which it shall not be necessary to have the state seal or the words "For Official Use Only." </section><section prefix="4">The Justices and Judges of the Supreme Court and Court of Appeals may each use state-owned motor vehicles on which it shall not be necessary to have the state seal or the words "For Official Use Only." </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 234, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(7). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 23, secs. 1, 2, and 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5946</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>