<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.339</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for refusal to issue or renew a license, suspension or revocation of a license, administrative reprimand, probation, or fine -- Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>339</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may deny or refuse to renew a license, may suspend or revoke a license, may issue an administrative reprimand, or may impose probationary conditions or fines not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500) when the licensee has engaged in unprofessional conduct that has endangered or is likely to endanger the health, welfare, or safety of the public. Unprofessional conduct shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Obtaining or attempting to obtain a license by fraud, misrepresentation, concealment of material facts, or making a false statement to the board; </section><section prefix="b">Being convicted of a felony in any court if any act for which the licensee or applicant for license was convicted is determined by the board to have a direct bearing on whether the person is trustworthy to serve the public as a licensed diabetes educator. "Conviction," as used in this paragraph, shall include a finding or verdict of guilty, an admission of guilt, or a plea of nolo contendere in a court of law; </section><section prefix="c">Violating any lawful order or administrative regulation promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Violating any provision of KRS 309.325 to 309.339 or administrative regulation promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Evidence of gross negligence or gross incompetence in the practice of diabetes education; and </section><section prefix="f">Violating the standards of practice or the code of ethics as promulgated by administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="2">All administrative hearings for the disciplinary action against a license or certificate holder shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 8, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39850</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>