<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.280</section_number><catch_line>Notice of hearing on appraisers' report -- Form. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the report of the appraisers is filed the secretary shall cause a notice to be sent to each landowner named in the report whose property is shown to be affected by the proposed improvement. </section><section prefix="2">The notice given by the secretary shall be substantially as follows:   "In re drainage district No. .... of .... County (or of .... Counties), Kentucky.   "Notice is hereby given to all owners of property in (drainage), (levee), (reclamation) district known as (insert name of district), the boundaries of which district are as follows: (here insert boundary description and also a separate description of any property added by the appraisers, together with the name of the owner), and to all persons whose property may be affected, that the board of appraisers has filed in the office of the secretary of the board its report in which it states and shows the benefits, damages and the assessments of benefits made upon all property in the district, the classification thereof and an appraisal of the value of the property necessary to be taken or used, or which will be affected by the making of the improvement. This proceeding is set for hearing on the .... day of ...., 19... . The report is on file in my office and subject to inspection by any person. Any person desiring to file written objections thereto, must do so on or before the day set for the hearing. Upon your failure to appear or file written objections to the report by that date, it will be construed by the board that you have no reasons to offer why it should not be confirmed.   "Done by me as secretary of the .... board on this the .... day of ...., 19...                                                                     ............. Secretary." </section><section prefix="3">The clerk shall also post a copy of the above notice at the front door of the courthouse of the county where the proceeding is pending, within five (5) days after the report is filed in his office, and shall cause it to be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 238, effective January 2, 1978; ch. 140, sec. 102. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 102. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 192. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380b-17. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>