<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.660</section_number><catch_line>Duties of the cabinet -- Authority for administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>The cabinet shall: <section prefix="1">Administer all funds appropriated to implement the provisions of KRS 200.650 to 200.676; </section><section prefix="2">Identify and coordinate all available financial resources for early intervention within the Commonwealth from federal, state, local, and private sources, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Title V of the Federal Social Security Act relating to maternal and child health; </section><section prefix="b">Title XIX of the Federal Social Security Act relating to Medicaid and the Early Periodic Screening Diagnostic and Treatment (EPSDT) program; </section><section prefix="c">The Federal Head Start Act; </section><section prefix="d">The Federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, Parts B and H; </section><section prefix="e">The Federal Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1964 Title I, Chapter I, Part B, Subpart 2 as amended; </section><section prefix="f">The Federal Developmentally Disabled Assistance and Bill of Rights Act, P.L. 100-146; </section><section prefix="g">Other federal programs; and </section><section prefix="h">Private insurance. </section></section><section prefix="3">Develop a sliding fee scale of the cost of early intervention services to families, including those circumstances where no fee shall be required; </section><section prefix="4">Make available, in addition to the services specified in KRS 200.654(7), social skill development and behavioral therapy services to infants and toddlers with a diagnosis of pervasive developmental disorders; </section><section prefix="5">Enter into contracts with service providers within a local community aided by the district committee in identifying providers; </section><section prefix="6">Develop procedures to monitor and evaluate services that are provided to infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="7">Develop procedures to ensure that early intervention services identified on the individualized family service plan are provided to eligible infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families in a timely manner pending resolution of any disputes among public agencies or service providers; and </section><section prefix="8">In conjunction with the council and district early intervention committees, promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, necessary to implement the provisions of KRS 200.650 to 200.676. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7326</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>