<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.370</section_number><catch_line>Search and seizure. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When an officer or any reputable citizen files an affidavit with any Circuit or District Judge, describing premises or a vehicle, where alcoholic beverages are sold, disposed of or possessed in violation of this chapter, the judge shall by his warrant cause the premises or vehicle to be searched for the detection of any alcoholic beverages which are possessed, or kept for disposition, in violation of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">Any officer receiving such a warrant shall immediately execute it on the day it is received. </section><section prefix="3">If admission is not given on demand, the officers enforcing the warrant shall force an entrance into the premises or vehicle. If the officer finds that alcoholic beverages are being illegally sold, disposed of or possessed, he shall seize the alcoholic beverages, arrest the keeper or person in charge of the premises, vehicle or alcoholic beverages and carry the person arrested and the alcoholic beverages before the judge that has issued the warrant. </section><section prefix="4">No search warrant as provided for in this section shall be quashed if it and the affidavit on which it is based are sufficient on the face. If the search warrant is quashed no property taken by virtue of it shall be ordered returned unless the person from whose possession the property was taken both alleges and proves that he was in lawful possession of the property. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 221, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554c-34. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11293</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>