<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.130</section_number><catch_line>Inspection fees. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owner or user of a boiler or pressure vessel required by this chapter to be inspected shall pay to the department, upon completion of inspection, reasonable fees not to exceed the cost of inspection as established by the commissioner upon advice of the board pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">All other inspections, including shop inspections and inspection of secondhand or used boilers made by the boiler inspector shall be charged for at the rate set by regulation promulgated by the commissioner upon advice of the board pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">All fees received by the department shall be held in a trust and agency fund from which the expenses of administering this chapter and other department responsibilities may be paid and no portion of said fund shall lapse into the general fund at the end of each fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 526, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 8, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11108</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>