<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="94" order_by="94">PUBLIC WORKS IN CITIES OTHER THAN THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>94.815</section_number><catch_line>Appointment -- Terms -- Removal of members -- Status of authority. </catch_line><order_by>815</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A city parking authority shall consist of five (5) persons appointed by the mayor with the approval of the city legislative body, to serve as commissioners of the local parking authority.  Three (3) of the commissioners who are first appointed shall be designated to serve for terms of one (1), two (2), and three (3) years, respectively, and the remaining two (2) of such commissioners shall be designated to serve for terms of four (4) years each, from the date of their appointment.  Upon expiration of the staggered terms, the successors shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years.  Appointments to complete unexpired terms of office shall be made in the same manner as the original appointments.  </section><section prefix="2">A joint city-county parking authority shall consist of six (6) commissioners.  Three </section><section prefix="3">of the commissioners shall be appointed by the mayor with the approval of the </section>city legislative body.  Three (3) of the commissioners shall be appointed by the county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court.  The three (3) commissioners who are first appointed by the mayor shall be designated to serve for terms of one (1), two (2) and three (3) years respectively and the same shall be true for the commissioners initially appointed by the county judge/executive.  Upon expiration of the staggered terms, the successors shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years.  Appointments to complete unexpired terms of office shall be made in the same manner.  (3) The commissioners shall constitute the governing body of the parking authority and shall adopt such bylaws, rules and regulations as are necessary for governing of the authority.  Any commissioner may be removed from office upon a vote of a majority of the members of the governing body which approved his appointment for inefficiency, neglect of duty, misfeasance, nonfeasance, or malfeasance, after at least ten (10) days' written notice of the hearing to the member whose conduct is in question and to all members of the governing body.  At the hearing the member may be represented by counsel and may appear personally and present such pertinent evidence as he wishes.  If after the hearing the governing body determines that he is guilty of the charges they shall remove the member from the authority within seven (7) days, and there shall be a vacancy of the office.  <section prefix="4">The commissioners of a motor vehicle parking authority are a body corporate constituting a public corporation and a governmental agency within the meaning of KRS 58.010, and shall have all the powers granted by KRS 58.010 to 58.170.  </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 384, sec. 559, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 2.</history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by two 1978 acts which do not appear to be in conflict and which have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25931</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>