<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">JUDICIAL RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>21.427</section_number><catch_line>Health insurance and benefits for recipients -- Premium reimbursement plan -- Coordination with all state-administered retirement systems or plans.   </catch_line><order_by>427</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The board of trustees of the Judicial Form Retirement System shall arrange by appropriate contract or on a self-insured basis for a group hospital and medical insurance plan for recipients of a retirement allowance from the Judicial Retirement Plan, and their dependents. For recipients, or dependents, eligible for Medicare coverage, the board shall provide Medicare supplement hospital and medical insurance coverage. For recipients, or dependents, not eligible for Medicare coverage, the board shall provide hospital and medical insurance coverage comparable to that provided under the major state employees' group insurance, and the board may arrange for the recipients to be included in the major state employees group. For recipients of a retirement allowance who are not eligible for the same level of hospital and medical benefits as recipients living in Kentucky, the board shall provide a medical insurance premium reimbursement plan as described in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">For the purpose of this section, the "dependent" of a recipient means the spouse or minor children, or both, of a recipient who is a living former member of the Judicial Retirement Plan, or the minor children of a deceased former member whose surviving spouse is the recipient. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Depending upon the number of months of service credit upon which the retirement allowance was based, and upon there having been at least forty-eight (48) months of judicial service, all or a portion of the premium required to provide hospital and medical benefits under this section shall be paid from the judicial retirement fund, as follows: </section><section prefix="b">For members who begin participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or <section prefix="1">Participation in the health insurance coverage and benefits provided </section><section prefix="2">A member who meets the minimum service requirements as provided by </section><section prefix="3">The minimum service required to participate in benefits as provided by </section><section prefix="4">The minimum service required to participate in benefits as provided by </section><section prefix="5">The monthly insurance contribution amount provided by this paragraph </section><section prefix="6">Under no circumstances shall the cost of coverage be paid for the </section></section><section prefix="c">The health insurance payments provided by this subsection shall be made by </section><section prefix="d">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, any member with the <section prefix="1">Upon request of the member, the Judicial Retirement System shall </section><section prefix="2">A member who elects hospital and medical benefits under this </section></section></section>   Months of Judicial Service Percentage of Premium     240 or more  100%     180 to 239, inclusive  75%     120 to 179, inclusive  50%     48 to 119, inclusive  25%  This paragraph shall not apply to members who begin participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014. after January 1, 2014: under this section shall not be allowed until the member has earned at least one hundred eighty (180) months of service credited under KRS 21.345 to 21.580 or another state-administered retirement system. subparagraph 1. of this paragraph shall be eligible for a monthly insurance benefit upon retirement of ten dollars ($10) for each year of service as a participating member of the Judicial Retirement Plan. subparagraph 1. of this subparagraph shall be waived for a member who is disabled in the line of duty as defined in KRS 61.621, and the member shall be entitled to the health benefits payable under this subsection as though the member has twenty (20) years of service in the Judicial Retirement Plan. subparagraph 1. of this subparagraph shall be waived for a member who is killed in the line of duty as described in KRS 61.621, and the member's spouse and eligible dependents shall be entitled to the health benefits the member would have received if he or she had retired with twenty (20) years of service in the Judicial Retirement Plan. shall be increased July 1 of each year by one and one-half percent (1.5%). The increase shall be cumulative and shall continue to accrue after the member's retirement for as long as a monthly insurance contribution is payable to the retired member. spouse, dependents, or beneficiaries of a member who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, except as provided by subparagraph 4. of this paragraph. the fund only if the recipient agrees to pay the remaining, if any, amount of the premium by deduction from his retirement allowance or by another method equally insuring the payment by him. minimum number of months of judicial service required by paragraph (a) or (b) of this subsection who is also eligible for benefits, or who is receiving benefits from any retirement plan or system administered by the Commonwealth shall be entitled to hospital and medical benefits as described in paragraph (a) of this subsection except that the number of months of service credit used in calculating the level of benefits shall be the sum of service credited to the member in all the state-administered retirement systems or plans. compute the member's combined service in all the state-administered retirement systems or plans and calculate the portion of the member's premium to be paid by the Judicial Retirement Plan, according to the criteria established in paragraph (a) of this subsection. For members who begin participating in the Legislators' Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014, the state-administered retirement systems or plans shall pay to the Judicial Retirement Plan the applicable percentage of the plan's cost of the retiree's hospital and medical premium which shall be equal to the percentage of the member's number of months of service in the applicable state-administered retirement systems or plans divided by his total combined service. The amounts paid by all the state-administered retirement systems or plans shall not be more than one hundred percent (100%) of the premium amount adopted by the respective boards of trustees. subsection shall lose any claim to insurance benefits under any of the other state-administered retirement systems or plans. <section prefix="3">The board shall establish a medical insurance premium reimbursement plan for recipients of a retirement allowance who are not eligible for the same level of hospital and medical benefits as recipients living in Kentucky having the same Medicare hospital and medical insurance eligibility status. An eligible recipient shall file proof of payment for hospital and medical insurance premiums at the retirement office. Reimbursement to eligible recipients shall be made on a quarterly basis. The recipient shall be eligible for reimbursement of substantiated medical insurance premiums for an amount not to exceed the total monthly contribution determined by the board of trustees. The plan shall not be made available if all recipients are eligible for the same level of coverage as recipients living in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">Premiums paid for hospital and medical insurance procured under this section shall be exempt from any premium tax which might otherwise be required under KRS Chapter 136. The payment of premiums by the judicial retirement fund shall not constitute income to the recipient. No commission shall be paid for hospital and medical insurance procured under this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 29, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1988.</history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42657</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>