<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.163</section_number><catch_line>Earthquake and tornado emergency procedure system.   </catch_line><order_by>163</order_by><text>The board of each local school district, and the governing body of each private and parochial school or school district, shall establish an earthquake and tornado emergency procedure system in every public or private school building in its jurisdiction having a capacity of fifty (50) or more students, or having more than one (1) classroom. The earthquake and tornado emergency procedure system shall include, but not be limited to, all of the following: <section prefix="1">A school building disaster plan, ready for implementation at any time, for maintaining the safety and care of students and staffs. A drop procedure and safe area evacuation practice shall be held at least twice during each school year, with the first practice for a drop procedure and a safe area evacuation being held within the first thirty (30) instructional days of each school year and one (1) practice being held during the month of January; </section><section prefix="2">A drop procedure. As used in this section, "drop procedure" means an activity by which each student and staff member takes cover under a table or desk, dropping to his or her knees, with the head protected by the arms, and the back to the windows; </section><section prefix="3">A safe area. As used in this section, "safe area" means a designated space including an enclosed area with no windows, a basement or the lowest floor using the interior hallway or rooms, or taking shelter under sturdy furniture; </section><section prefix="4">Protective measures to be taken before, during, and following an earthquake or tornado; and </section><section prefix="5">A program to ensure that the students and the certificated and classified staff are aware of, and properly trained in, the earthquake and tornado emergency procedure system. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 133, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 433, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). This statute was amended with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 126 and 133, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>