<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.050</section_number><catch_line>Examination for license -- Fee -- Supervision and temporary licensure -- Designation as "health service provider." </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before granting a license to practice psychology and to use the title "licensed psychologist" the board shall require the applicant to pass an examination in psychology and to fulfill all requirements for supervised experience. </section><section prefix="2">The applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Pay a fee not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300); </section><section prefix="b">Have received a doctoral degree in psychology that is acceptable to the board from a regionally accredited educational institution; provided, however, the board may grant a license to an individual otherwise qualified under this chapter who has received a doctoral degree in psychology that is acceptable to the board from an educational institution outside the United States, if the educational institution would otherwise be accredited by a regional accrediting body if located in the United States; </section><section prefix="c">Have passed the national EPPP examination at the doctoral level; and </section><section prefix="d">Have had at least two (2) years of supervised professional experience satisfactory to the board, one (1) year of which shall be an internship. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon acceptance of the application to sit for the examination in psychology, the applicant may practice psychology under the supervision of a licensed psychologist under conditions of supervision and temporary licensure established by the board. The board shall establish a grace period not to exceed sixty (60) days to allow for the employment and supervision of the applicant by an agency from the time the applicant's degree requirements are completed to the submission of the complete application. During this period of supervision, the applicant for licensure may not supervise certified psychologists, licensed psychological associates, other applicants for licensure, or temporarily licensed persons, nor shall he engage in an independent practice, except under the employment of his supervising psychologist. Upon certification to the board of completion of the two (2) years of supervision satisfactory to the board, the applicant shall be examined on psychological practice, ethical principles, and the law. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall grade and keep the examinations and results on file for one (1) year. Upon written request to the board, an applicant may arrange to discuss his or her performance on the examination. </section><section prefix="5">Upon successful completion of the examination process, the board shall issue a license to practice psychology and the applicant may use the title "licensed psychologist." </section><section prefix="6">Licensed psychologists may function independently without supervision. Licensed psychologists who have the designation "health service provider" may retain that designation and may employ and supervise certified psychologists and licensed psychological associates. Licensed psychologists who have the designation "health service provider" may supervise no more than a total of six (6) certified psychologists, licensed psychological associates, or applicants for licensure at one (1) time. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">From July 15, 2010, until July 1, 2013, the designation "health service provider" shall be made on the license of those licensed psychologists who have completed one (1) year of supervised experience under conditions of temporary licensure approved by the board or who have completed one (1) year of supervised experience acceptable to the board after achieving licensure status as a licensed psychologist. </section><section prefix="b">Beginning July 1, 2013, the designation "health service provider" shall be made on the license of those licensed psychologists who have completed one (1) additional year of supervised experience satisfactory to the board in health care service delivery. This year of supervised experience shall be in addition to the supervised experience requirement for licensure as a licensed psychologist. Health service providers may provide supervision of direct health care services by applicants for licensure, certified psychologists, and licensed psychological associates. Health service providers may supervise no more than a total of six (6) certified psychologists, licensed psychological associates, or applicants for licensure at one (1) time. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 7, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 11; and ch. 290, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 5. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31226</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>