<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.329</section_number><catch_line>Division of Ombudsman and Workers' Compensation Specialist Services -- Functions -- Ombudsman program -- Toll-free telephone access. </catch_line><order_by>329</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Ombudsman and Workers' Compensation Specialist Services shall be headed by a director appointed by the commissioner with the approval of the Governor, in accordance with KRS 12.050 and 342.230. The functions of the division shall include: <section prefix="a">Serving as an information source for employees, employers, medical, vocational, and rehabilitation personnel, carriers, and self-insurers; </section><section prefix="b">Responding to inquiries and complaints relative to the workers' compensation program; </section><section prefix="c">Advising all parties of their rights and obligations under this chapter; </section><section prefix="d">Assisting workers in obtaining medical reports, job descriptions, and other materials pertinent to a claim for benefits and preparing all documents necessary for a claim application; and </section><section prefix="e">Performing other duties as required by the commissioner through administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">The employee, employer, carrier, self-insured administrator, and medical provider shall promptly comply with reasonable information requests from an ombudsman. </section><section prefix="3">The ombudsman program shall be staffed with personnel trained in techniques performed by ombudsmen and who are familiar with medical and vocational rehabilitation principles and knowledgeable about the provisions of this chapter and applicable administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="4">A toll-free telephone number shall be provided throughout the Commonwealth to insure easy access by all parties to the division. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1818, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 71, effective December 12, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 2, sec. 7, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32477</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>