<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.201</section_number><catch_line>Public library service appropriations -- Public library services improvement and equalization fund -- Purposes -- Restrictions -- Distribution formula. </catch_line><order_by>201</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For grants to public libraries for promoting, aiding, and equalizing public library service in Kentucky, there may be funds appropriated out of the general expenditure fund of the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to any other funds appropriated to the Department for Libraries and Archives, there shall be appropriated annually to the department out of the general expenditure fund of the State Treasury an amount sufficient to provide the following assistance to local public libraries: <section prefix="a">The department shall first distribute to each county public library system a foundation grant based upon the county population using the last official census as follows: <section prefix="1">Counties with a population of twenty-two thousand (22,000) or less shall receive nine thousand dollars ($9,000); </section><section prefix="2">Counties with a population between twenty-two thousand one (22,001) and forty-five thousand (45,000) shall receive eight thousand dollars ($8,000); and </section><section prefix="3">Counties with a population over forty-five thousand (45,000) shall receive seven thousand dollars ($7,000); and </section></section><section prefix="b">The department shall distribute the remaining funds appropriated for this program to each county public library system, based on the county's share of the state population, at a rate of fifty-three cents ($0.53) per capita in fiscal year 1997-98 and seventy-three cents ($0.73) per capita in fiscal year 1998-99 and each year thereafter to be used for the following purposes: <section prefix="1">Purchase, upgrading, and maintenance of the technology necessary to enable the staff and the public to have access to electronic information; </section><section prefix="2">Purchase of library materials and equipment; </section><section prefix="3">Maintenance and operation of bookmobiles and extension programs; </section><section prefix="4">Staff training and compensation; </section><section prefix="5">Building maintenance; </section><section prefix="6">Debt service; </section><section prefix="7">Resource-sharing; </section><section prefix="8">Program development; and </section><section prefix="9">All other local library needs and services; and </section></section><section prefix="c">For counties which do not have a public library, the department shall make the foundation grant and per capita distribution to a recognized library organization for the purpose of providing or establishing countywide public library service under existing departmental guidelines. </section></section><section prefix="3">The appropriation necessary to fund the formula foundation grants and a seventy-three cents ($0.73) per capita distribution shall constitute the base for the agency's biennial budget request for this program. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">In addition to the foundation grants and per capita distribution to a local public library, there is hereby created within the Department for Libraries and Archives a public library services improvement and equalization fund to assure substantially equal public library services for all citizens of the Commonwealth. The creation of this fund is not intended to limit or prevent any public library from providing services and facilities beyond those assured by the state-supported program. </section><section prefix="b">It is intended that the proceeds of the fund created under this subsection be used to: <section prefix="1">Improve early childhood development; </section><section prefix="2">Support lifelong learning opportunities; </section><section prefix="3">Enhance economic development; </section><section prefix="4">Enrich cultural resource opportunities for all Kentuckians; and </section><section prefix="5">Expand adult education and adult literacy programs. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">Expenditures from the fund created in subsection (4) of this section shall not be made unless those expenditures: <section prefix="a">Comply with the categories of allowable costs in subsection (2)(b) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">Comply with the enterprise information technology architecture and standards developed by the Commonwealth when utilized for technology procurements. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">The fund created under subsection (4) of this section shall be distributed based on a formula using the per population assessment and equalization rate of two hundred percent (200%) of the poverty level per annual population assessment produced by the United States Bureau of Census. The exact formula and distribution of the fund shall be set forth in an administrative regulation promulgated by the Department for Libraries and Archives. </section><section prefix="b">A local public library shall not be qualified to receive funds under subsection (4) of this section, if that library's regular annual appropriation in the current fiscal year is less than the appropriation received in the previous fiscal year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 504, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 490, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 468, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 158. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 114, secs. 1 and 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 6, (1) at 635.  </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4766</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>