<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.807</section_number><catch_line>Data research initiative -- Purposes -- Implementation. </catch_line><order_by>807</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky data research initiative, a partnership between elementary and secondary schools and postsecondary education research institutions to maximize research capabilities through computer resources. The initiative shall be jointly facilitated by the Kentucky Department of Education and the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section><section prefix="2">The purposes of the data research initiative are to expand the availability of computing resources not available at the research institutions at a relatively low cost, to do education outreach to students and teachers in Kentucky's K-12 system, to expand the research institutions' presence throughout the state, and to maximize the use of computer assets that have already been purchased in K-12 systems but are often underused. </section><section prefix="3">By December 1, 2005, the commissioner of the Department of Education and the president of the Council on Postsecondary Education shall convene appropriate postsecondary education and elementary and secondary educators and administrators to determine how this initiative might be developed, funded, and utilized to enhance research capabilities in the sciences and health-related fields or other appropriate fields of research. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 173, Pt. XX, sec. 1, effective March 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> March 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3602</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>