<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.662</section_number><catch_line>District early intervention committee -- Membership -- Duties.   </catch_line><order_by>662</order_by><text>The cabinet shall establish one (1) district early intervention committee in each of the fifteen (15) area development districts. Each committee shall have from fifteen (15) to twenty-five (25) members of whom at least five (5) shall be parents, at least five (5) shall be early intervention service providers, and at least one (1) shall be a representative from each of the following: the local health department, the local office of the Department for Community Based Services, the local community center for mental health and individuals with an intellectual disability, and the local Commission for Handicapped Children. Each committee may include representatives from one (1) or more of the following: a child day-care facility, a public school, a provider of medical services, a provider of therapy services, a home health agency if operated separately from the local health department, a university or college, a family resource center, a local business, a local charity, or others deemed appropriate. Each committee shall: <section prefix="1">Advise and assist the cabinet and the council in the development, implementation, and monitoring of the Kentucky Early Intervention System; </section><section prefix="2">Identify local resources available to infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="3">Assist in identifying the unmet needs of infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="4">Assist in establishing and maintaining a point of entry to the early intervention system; and </section><section prefix="5">Assist in the establishment of local interagency agreements for early intervention services and provide a forum for coordinating district early intervention services. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 31, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 31, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>