<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.140</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited acts relating to controlled substances -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">No person shall obtain or attempt to obtain a prescription for a controlled substance by knowingly misrepresenting to, or knowingly withholding information from, a practitioner. </section><section prefix="b">No person shall procure or attempt to procure the administration of a controlled substance by knowingly misrepresenting to, or withholding information from, a practitioner. </section><section prefix="c">No person shall obtain or attempt to obtain a controlled substance or procure or attempt to procure the administration of a controlled substance by the use of a false name or the giving of a false address. </section><section prefix="d">No person shall knowingly make a false statement regarding any prescription, order, report, or record required by this chapter. </section><section prefix="e">No person shall, for the purpose of obtaining a controlled substance, falsely assume the title of or represent himself or herself to be a manufacturer, wholesaler, distributor, repacker, pharmacist, practitioner, or other authorized person. </section><section prefix="f">In order to obtain a controlled substance, no person shall present a prescription for a controlled substance that was obtained in violation of this chapter. </section><section prefix="g">No person shall affix any false or forged label to a package or receptacle containing any controlled substance. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person shall possess, manufacture, sell, dispense, prescribe, distribute, or administer any counterfeit substance. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall knowingly obtain or attempt to obtain a prescription for a controlled substance without having formed a valid practitioner-patient relationship with the practitioner or his or her designee from whom the person seeks to obtain the prescription. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall knowingly assist a person in obtaining or attempting to obtain a prescription in violation of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any subsection of this section shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39528</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>