<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.134</section_number><catch_line>Board of Kentucky Center for Education and Workforce Statistics -- Members -- Duties and functions -- Chair -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Board of the Kentucky Center for Education and Workforce Statistics is hereby established and attached to the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, Office of the Secretary. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall be composed of: <section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Education or designee; </section><section prefix="b">The executive director of the Education Professional Standards Board or designee; </section><section prefix="c">The president of the Council on Postsecondary Education or designee; </section><section prefix="d">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or designee; and </section><section prefix="e">The executive director of the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority. </section></section><section prefix="3">The duties and functions of the board shall be to: <section prefix="a">Develop a detailed data access and use policy for requests that shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Direct access to data in the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System shall be restricted to authorized staff of the office; </section><section prefix="2">Data or information that may result in any individual or employer being identifiable based on the size or uniqueness of the population under consideration may not be reported in any form by the office; and </section><section prefix="3">The office may not release data or information if disclosure is prohibited under relevant federal or state privacy laws; </section></section><section prefix="b">Establish the research agenda of the office; </section><section prefix="c">Make nominations to the Governor for the appointment of an executive director; </section><section prefix="d">Oversee compliance by the office with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, 20 U.S.C. sec. 1232g, and other relevant federal and state privacy laws; </section><section prefix="e">Ensure that reports generated by the Office for Education and Workforce Statistics are distributed to appropriate personnel within the agencies represented by the board members; and </section><section prefix="f">Provide general oversight of the office. </section></section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet shall serve as chair of the board. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall meet at least semiannually and at other times upon the call of the chair. The meetings shall be subject to the open meetings requirements of KRS 61.800 to 61.850 and 61.991. </section><section prefix="6">The board may form committees, work groups, or advisory councils to accomplish its purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 90, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). This statute was created with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 18 and 90, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43216</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>