<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.7-030</section_number><catch_line>Plan of merger.   </catch_line><order_by>7-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each constituent organization shall enter into a written plan of merger. </section><section prefix="2">The plan of merger shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of each constituent organization and the name of the constituent organization into which each constituent organization proposes to merge; </section><section prefix="b">The terms and conditions of the proposed merger, including but not limited to a statement which sets forth whether limited liability is retained by the surviving constituent organization; </section><section prefix="c">The manner and basis of converting the beneficial interest in each constituent statutory trust and the interests in each constituent organization into interests, shares, or other securities or obligations, as the case may be, of the surviving constituent organization or of any other business entity, or, in whole or in part, into cash or other property; </section><section prefix="d">The amendments to the organizational documents of the surviving constituent organization as are desired to be effected by the merger, or that no changes are desired; and </section><section prefix="e">Other provisions relating to the proposed merger that are deemed necessary or desirable. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 58, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40400</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>