<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.220</section_number><catch_line>Water resources studies. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text>The cabinet shall: <section prefix="1">Undertake for and as the official agency of the state, such studies and prepare such reports and recommendations as may be necessary to establish a statewide program of flood control (including major drainage), and a statewide program for the development of water resources; </section><section prefix="2">Study and review for the state as its official agency, all survey reports, engineering reports, and other reports concerning or affecting water related projects within the state which are proposed for construction by the federal government, the state government or any agency or subdivision thereof, or which will involve the expenditure of federal or state funds, and which might affect flood control or the development of water resources of the state, and to act as the official representative of the state in any representations, recommendations, or requests to Congress or the General Assembly concerning such projects or the priority which should be accorded them with relation to the statewide program; </section><section prefix="3">Make a continuous water resources study of data from other existing state or federal agencies and such other sources as may be available. From such studies, the cabinet shall formulate conclusions and recommendations for use by the Commonwealth in assuring the maximum beneficial use of the water resources of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="4">Cooperate with any local, state or federal agency, or the agencies of any other state engaged or proposing to engage in any work which will affect or be affected by the functions of the cabinet and may lend to or receive from any such agency such financial assistance as may be necessary within the limits of authorized expenditure; </section><section prefix="5">Have, for flood control and water resources development purposes, jurisdiction over all streams within or bordering upon the state. The cabinet shall have the authority to establish and enforce floodways along such streams; </section><section prefix="6">Have authority to accept and use gifts, contributions, donations and grants; </section><section prefix="7">Be the official state agency for determination of stream mileage. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 7. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 26. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2097</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>