<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.150</section_number><catch_line>Reports of mine inspectors. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each mine inspector shall each week report in writing to the commissioner of the department the number and condition of all mines inspected by him during the week. </section><section prefix="2">Each mine inspector shall each week deliver to the commissioner of the department a written report showing the condition of each mine inspected by him and, at the same time, shall deliver a copy of such report to the operator or the superintendent of each mine inspected and another copy thereof to the mine committee at such mine so inspected if requested and at the same time each mine inspector shall post a copy of such inspection report on a bulletin board at a prominent place of the operating company or mine where it may conveniently be read by any of the mine employees. </section><section prefix="3">Each mine inspector shall, within fifteen (15) days after the close of each calendar year, file with the commissioner a report of his proceedings during the calendar year, and give such information concerning the mines and mining conditions in his district as is appropriate and required by the commissioner. </section></text><history>Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 12. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-18. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>