<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.812</section_number><catch_line>Underground Railroad Initiative -- Duties of Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission. </catch_line><order_by>812</order_by><text>The commission shall coordinate Kentucky's Underground Railroad initiative in accordance with KRS 171.805. The commission's duties as they relate to this initiative shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Undertake a comprehensive statewide inventory of historic sites related to the Underground Railroad, and implement a master plan for site protection and development; </section><section prefix="2">Encourage and assist the state preservation officer within the Kentucky Heritage Council to nominate significant historical sites of the Kentucky Underground Railroad to the national and state registers of historic places; </section><section prefix="3">Develop and operate, in conjunction with the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, a program of public information, education, and promotion of the history of the Underground Railroad in Kentucky, to include but not be limited to implementing and maintaining a Web site connected to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">Coordinate with local, state, and federal authorities in project planning that may affect Underground Railroad sites in Kentucky and neighboring states; </section><section prefix="5">Consider the council's recommendations and, contingent on review by the council, present to the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet an annual report and plan for future action; and </section><section prefix="6">Pursue public and private funds to carry out the duties set forth in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 49, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 37, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>