<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>Definitions as used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Classification" means the systematic assignment of a prisoner to a custody level, program, and penitentiary; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="4">"Eligible sexual offender" means a sexual offender for whom the sentencing court, department officials, or both have determined that he or she: <section prefix="a">Has demonstrated evidence of a mental, emotional, or behavioral disorder, but not active psychosis or an intellectual disability; and </section><section prefix="b">Is likely to benefit from the program; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Penitentiaries" includes the state penal institutions for males at Eddyville, LaGrange, the Green River Correctional Complex, the Luther Luckett Correctional Complex, the Kentucky Correctional Institute for Women, the Northpoint Training Center, the Roederer Correctional Complex, the Eastern Kentucky Correctional Complex, the Western Kentucky Correctional Complex, Frankfort Career Development Center, Blackburn Correctional Complex, and Bell County Forestry Camp, together with the branches thereof, any private prison as provided by KRS 197.500, and any other similar institutions hereafter established; </section><section prefix="6">"Sexual offender" means any person convicted of, pleading guilty to, or entering an Alford plea to a sex crime as defined in KRS 17.500; and </section><section prefix="7">"State agency" means any department, board, commission, or agency of the state government. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 26, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 230, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 43, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 445, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 497, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. X, sec. 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3828c-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40758</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>