<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.750</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Capitol Centennial Commission. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>There is hereby created the Kentucky Capitol Centennial Commission, which shall be attached to the Division of Historic Properties for administrative purposes. The commission shall be composed of twenty-three (23) members, as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) members of the House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="3">The First Lady of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or her designee; </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Economic Development Cabinet or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="5">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Libraries and Archives; </section><section prefix="7">The director and state curator of the Division of Historic Properties; </section><section prefix="8">The chairperson of the Historic Properties Advisory Commission; </section><section prefix="9">The executive director of the Kentucky Arts Council; </section><section prefix="10">The chairperson of the Kentucky Heritage Council; </section><section prefix="11">The executive director of the Kentucky Heritage Council; </section><section prefix="12">The executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society; </section><section prefix="13">The president of the Kentucky Historical Society; </section><section prefix="14">A representative of Kentucky State University, appointed by the president of the university; </section><section prefix="15">The judge/executive of Franklin County; </section><section prefix="16">The mayor of the city of Frankfort; </section><section prefix="17">The executive director of the Frankfort Area Chamber of Commerce; </section><section prefix="18">The executive director of the Frankfort/Franklin County Tourism Commission; and </section><section prefix="19">Three (3) citizen members, one (1) of whom shall be less than thirty-five (35) years of age, from the state at large, with a demonstrated interest in Kentucky's history and substantial knowledge and appreciation of the new Capitol building, appointed by the Governor. </section>The chair of the commission shall be elected by the members from the membership of the commission. </text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4853</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>