<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.818</section_number><catch_line>Evidence-based instructional models to address needs of at-risk students -- Focus -- Components -- Training for high school teachers -- Incorporation into existing programs.   </catch_line><order_by>818</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If funds are appropriated for the purposes of funding evidence-based instructional models or if internal state or federal funds are available, the Kentucky Department of Education, in collaboration with the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, the Education Professional Standards Board, and other appropriate educational entities, shall recommend evidence-based models for addressing the needs of at-risk students. </section><section prefix="2">The evidence-based models shall include a variety of programs and curricula proven to be effective for at-risk students, and shall focus on: <section prefix="a">Identification of students at risk for inadequate academic preparation for the next grade level or at risk for dropping out of school; </section><section prefix="b">Reduction in the number of students retained in grade nine (9) and reduction of high school failure rates; </section><section prefix="c">Improvement of student performance through grade-level standards in reading and mathematics with an emphasis on grade nine (9); </section><section prefix="d">Assistance to students and their parents or legal guardians in identifying students' career and educational goals, developing individual learning plans, and the appropriate programs of study to achieve these goals; and </section><section prefix="e">Assistance to adult students in obtaining a high school diploma or a recognized postsecondary education credential that has value in the workplace. </section></section><section prefix="3">The evidence-based models shall include the following components designed to facilitate more students having a successful start in high school and successfully completing grade nine (9) requirements: <section prefix="a">The use of flexible scheduling as appropriate to increase students' time in the study of core language arts and mathematics; </section><section prefix="b">The assignment of the most effective teachers as leaders for instructional teams in grade nine (9) to improve instructional planning, delivery of instruction, and the use of reteaching strategies; </section><section prefix="c">The assignment of mentors to teach students study skills and habits necessary to become independent learners and, when possible, the use of career guidance coaches to advise students; and </section><section prefix="d">Career courses, including career exploration, in grade nine (9) to incorporate project-based instruction that requires the application of grade nine (9) level reading, mathematics, and science skills and that uses a wide variety of technology. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">If state or federal funds are available, all career and technical education teachers who teach high school students shall receive training in how to embed reading, mathematics, and science knowledge and skills in specific career and technical education courses. </section><section prefix="b">Training required under paragraph (a) of this subsection may be provided by local school districts or postsecondary education institutions, including community and technical colleges, and outside providers that have a record of working effectively with schools in redesigning the ninth grade. </section></section><section prefix="5">Career and technical education teachers shall provide evidence through the courses they teach that the students' academic achievement is increased as defined by administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education and developed in collaboration with the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section><section prefix="6">The evidence-based models shall be incorporated into career and technical education programs, career academies, and career pathway programs of study developed under KRS 157.072. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 44, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 4, effective April 19, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included the creation of this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42223</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>