<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.022</section_number><catch_line>Board to prescribe fees, charges, and fines -- Trust and agency fund -- Petty cash fund. </catch_line><order_by>022</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall, by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A, prescribe a schedule of reasonable fees, charges, and fines not to exceed the national average of other state dental boards for: <section prefix="a">Examination; </section><section prefix="b">Issuance, renewal, and reinstatement of licenses; </section><section prefix="c">Issuance, renewal, and reinstatement of registrations; </section><section prefix="d">Inspections and reinspections; </section><section prefix="e">Applications; </section><section prefix="f">Other services and materials provided by the board; </section><section prefix="g">Investigations; </section><section prefix="h">Administrative legal costs; and </section><section prefix="i">Fines for infractions. </section></section><section prefix="2">All fees, charges, or other moneys collected or received by the board shall be paid into the State Treasury and credited to a trust and agency fund which, notwithstanding KRS 45.229, shall not lapse, to be used by the board for the carrying out of the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">All disbursements by the board in the transactions of its business and in the enforcement of the provisions of this chapter shall be paid out of such trust and agency account as claims against the state in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 45 and 45A. </section><section prefix="4">The board may establish a petty cash fund not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) for the purpose of making disbursements requiring prompt cash outlay, and to carry out the provisions of KRS 45A.045 applying to the delegation of authority to purchase. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 149, effective July 15, 1980. --Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 272, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 313.360 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30809</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>