<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.156</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of jurisdiction of restored land to state agency or sale to political subdivision -- Return of money to revolving fund. </catch_line><order_by>156</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After restoration of the acquired land, the cabinet may, with the approval of the Governor, transfer jurisdiction of such land, or any portion thereof, to any state agency that can best utilize such land for public purposes. </section><section prefix="2">If the retention of such land is determined to be impractical, the cabinet may, with the approval of the Governor, sell such land to political subdivisions of the Commonwealth at the cost of acquisition and restoration or public sale to the highest bidder. Such land shall be sold subject to the condition that no surface coal mining shall be carried on thereon at any time thereafter. The proceeds of any such sale shall be credited to a revolving fund within the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever the cabinet expends funds pursuant to this section in order to satisfy the total purchase price for lands purchased pursuant to KRS 350.570, the cabinet may return to the revolving fund any moneys so used upon resale or other transfer of such land. </section></text><history>  Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 27. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(2). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 75. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 34. </history><metadata><lrc-note>The provisions of this section became operative on May 18, 1982, when the conditional approval granted by the United States Secretary of the Interior appeared in the Federal Register. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32813</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>