<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.670</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of registry reports and records -- Use of information. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All lists and medical records maintained by hospitals and medical laboratories pursuant to KRS 211.660 shall be confidential. All information collected and analyzed pursuant to KRS 211.660 and 211.665 shall be held confidential as to the identity of the individual patient. Staff of the cabinet, the department, or its designee may use the information to notify parents of available medical care and other services available for the child and family. Further disclosure shall be made only pursuant to the written consent of the child's parent or legal guardian. </section><section prefix="2">Access to information assembled by the Kentucky birth surveillance registry shall be limited to the cabinet, the department, or its designee and to qualified persons or organizations engaged in demographic, epidemiological or other similar studies related to health and health care provision. A written agreement to maintain confidentiality shall be required if access is approved for persons other than representatives of the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall maintain a record of all persons given access to the information in the Kentucky birth surveillance registry. The record shall include: the name of the person authorizing access; name, title, and organizational affiliation of person given access; dates of access; and the specific purpose for which information is to be used. This record of access shall be open to public inspection during normal operating hours of the department. </section><section prefix="4">Information assembled by the Kentucky birth surveillance registry may be disclosed in summary, statistical, or other form which does not identify particular individuals or individual sources of information. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who, in violation of a written agreement to maintain confidentiality, discloses any information provided under KRS 211.660 and 211.665 may be denied further access to confidential information maintained by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8456</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>