<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-590</section_number><catch_line>Feasibility study of hazardous waste treatment-industrial park complex plan. </catch_line><order_by>46-590</order_by><text>The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development shall cooperate with the special assistant to the Governor for coal and energy policy in examining the feasibility of a hazardous waste treatment-industrial park complex approach to the siting of hazardous waste management facilities and the promotion of industrial development. Consistent with the state policy of encouraging reuse and treatment of hazardous waste and of minimizing land disposal, the study shall be based on development of integrated facilities consisting of a variety of treatment and disposal systems at a given site associated with industrial plants. The study shall at a minimum: <section prefix="1">Survey the attitudes of various industries towards this approach; </section><section prefix="2">Survey public attitudes and perceptions towards this approach; </section><section prefix="3">Identify the advantages and disadvantages to industry, the Commonwealth, and local communities; </section><section prefix="4">Survey the degree to which the availability of hazardous waste management facilities has a bearing on the location of new industry; </section><section prefix="5">Develop a list of industry types with compatible waste streams for exchange, neutralization, or incineration; </section><section prefix="6">Identify economic or technical barriers to this approach; and </section><section prefix="7">Report its findings and recommendations to the 1982 General Assembly. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 29, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.903, and also previously codified as KRS 224.218. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10455</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>