<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.510</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 186A.500 to 186A.550. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text>As used in KRS 186A.500 to 186A.550, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Brand" means a designation that is affixed as required by this chapter, or that has previously been affixed, to a motor vehicle title that establishes a portion of the history of the motor vehicle and that shall be fixed to all subsequently issued titles for that vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">"Classic motor vehicle project" means a motor vehicle that is: <section prefix="a">At least twenty-five (25) years old; </section><section prefix="b">Not in roadworthy condition; and </section><section prefix="c">Either currently in this state and not titled or being brought into this state with a regular title from another state that does not denote it as "salvage," "junk," "rebuilt," or any similar designation; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Dealer" means a person or business as defined in KRS 190.010 who sells or offers for sale a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="4">"Junk vehicle" means a vehicle which meets the description set forth in KRS 186A.295(1)(a); </section><section prefix="5">"Motor vehicle" means a motor vehicle as defined in KRS 186.010(8)(a) and (b); </section><section prefix="6">"Owner" means a person who holds the legal title of a vehicle or a person who pursuant to a bona fide sale has received physical possession of the vehicle subject to any applicable security interest; </section><section prefix="7">"Rebuilt vehicle" means a vehicle that has been repaired to a road worthy condition after having been registered as a salvage vehicle pursuant to KRS 186A.520, or a similar salvage designation from another licensing jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="8">"Roadworthy condition" means a vehicle in a safe condition to operate on the highway and capable of transporting persons or property that complies fully with the provisions of KRS Chapter 189 pertaining to vehicle equipment; and </section><section prefix="9">"Water damage" means damage to a motor vehicle caused by submerging or partially submerging the vehicle in water to the extent that the vehicle was submerged or partially submerged at any water level above the dashboard of the vehicle, regardless of the actual dollar amount of the damage. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>