<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="386" order_by="386">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS -- LEGAL INVESTMENTS -- UNIFORM PRINCIPAL AND INCOME ACT </unit></structure><section_number>386.498</section_number><catch_line>Payment of income taxes. </catch_line><order_by>498</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A tax required to be paid by a trustee based on receipts allocated to income shall be paid from income. </section><section prefix="2">A tax required to be paid by a trustee based on receipts allocated to principal shall be paid from principal, even if the tax is called an income tax by the taxing authority. </section><section prefix="3">A tax required to be paid by a trustee on the trust's share of an entity's taxable income shall be paid proportionately: <section prefix="a">From income to the extent that receipts from the entity are allocated to income; and </section><section prefix="b">From principal to the extent that: <section prefix="1">Receipts from the entity are allocated to principal; and </section><section prefix="2">The trust's share of the entity's taxable income exceeds the total receipts described in paragraph (a) of this subsection and paragraph (b)1. of this subsection. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this section, receipts allocated to principal or income shall be reduced by the amount distributed to a beneficiary from principal or income for which the trust receives a deduction in calculating the tax. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 25, effective January 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>