<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.910</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 189.920 to 189.950. </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 189.920 to 189.950, "emergency vehicle" means any vehicle used for emergency purposes by: <section prefix="a">The Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="b">A public police department; </section><section prefix="c">The Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="d">A sheriff's office; </section><section prefix="e">A rescue squad; </section><section prefix="f">An emergency management agency if it is a publicly owned vehicle; </section><section prefix="g">An ambulance service or medical first-response provider licensed by the Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services, for any vehicle used to respond to emergencies or to transport a patient with a critical medical condition; </section><section prefix="h">Any vehicle commandeered by a police officer; </section><section prefix="i">Any vehicle with the emergency lights required under KRS 189.920 used by a paid or volunteer fireman or paid or volunteer ambulance personnel, or a paid or local emergency management director while responding to an emergency or to a location where an emergency vehicle is on emergency call; </section><section prefix="j">An elected coroner granted permission to equip a publicly or privately owned motor vehicle with lights and siren pursuant to KRS 189.920; or </section><section prefix="k">A deputy coroner granted permission to equip a publicly or privately owned motor vehicle with lights and siren pursuant to KRS 189.920. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in KRS 189.920 to 189.950, "public safety vehicle" means public utility repair vehicle; wreckers; state, county, or municipal service vehicles and equipment; highway equipment which performs work that requires stopping and standing or moving at slow speeds within the traveled portions of highways; and vehicles which are escorting wide-load or slow-moving trailers or trucks. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.  17, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011; and ch. 99, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 24, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 106, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 124, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 16, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 419, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  This section was amended by 2011 Ky. Acts chs. 17 and 99, which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 99, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39894</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>