<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="46" order_by="46">REPORT AND ACCOUNTING OF STATE FUNDS BY LOCAL OFFICERS </unit></structure><section_number>46.020</section_number><catch_line>Books and forms for system of uniform accounting. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The Department for Local Government shall prepare, and shall cause to be printed and paid for in the same manner as other books, blanks, and records for counties and county officers, all books, blanks, and records necessary for the system of uniform accounting established under KRS 46.010. The Department for Local Government shall deliver to each county, district, or other local officer charged with the duty of collecting, disbursing, or handling state funds the books, blanks, and records as are necessary for that officer. Each county, district, or other local officer receiving the books, blanks, or records shall use them in the performance of his duties with reference to the handling and disbursing of state funds. Any of these books, blanks, or records used by state officers or employees shall be printed and paid for in the same manner as other state printing. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 38, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 32, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4606a-3, 4606a-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22509</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>