<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.024</section_number><catch_line>Limits for special purpose governmental entities on personal property tax rate. </catch_line><order_by>024</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the tax rate applicable to real property levied by a special purpose governmental entity will produce a percentage increase in revenue from personal property less than the percentage increase in revenue from real property, the special purpose governmental entity may levy a tax rate applicable to personal property which will produce the same percentage increase in revenue from personal property as the percentage increase in revenue from real property. </section><section prefix="2">The tax rate applicable to personal property levied by a special purpose governmental entity under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not be subject to the public hearing provisions of KRS 132.023(2) and to the recall provisions of KRS 132.023(3). </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 88, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 343, secs. 6 and 11, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 312, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>March 21, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>.  (7/13/90) The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts Ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts Ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>