<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.100</section_number><catch_line>Matters which shall be prescribed by administrative regulation. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>Subject to limitations in applicable statutes, any administrative body which is empowered to promulgate administrative regulations shall, by administrative regulation prescribe, consistent with applicable statutes: <section prefix="1">Each statement of general applicability, policy, procedure, memorandum, or other form of action that implements; interprets; prescribes law or policy; describes the organization, procedure, or practice requirements of any administrative body; or affects private rights or procedures available to the public; </section><section prefix="2">The process for application for license, benefits available or other matters for which an application would be appropriate unless such process is prescribed by a statute; </section><section prefix="3">Fees, except for those exempted in paragraphs (a) through (j) of this subsection, to be charged by the administrative body if such fees are authorized by law and are not set by statute: <section prefix="a">State park room rates; </section><section prefix="b">Prices for food in restaurants at state facilities; </section><section prefix="c">Prices for goods at gift shops at state facilities; </section><section prefix="d">Prices for groceries and other items sold at state facilities; </section><section prefix="e">Prices charged for state publications; </section><section prefix="f">Prices charged for rides and amusement activities at state facilities; </section><section prefix="g">Admission fees to athletic and entertainment events at state facilities; </section><section prefix="h">Charges for swimming, skiing, horseback riding, and similar recreational activities at state facilities; </section><section prefix="i">Charges for boat and equipment rentals for recreational purposes at state facilities; and </section><section prefix="j">Admission fees charged for seminars and educational courses by state administrative bodies; </section></section><section prefix="4">The procedures to be utilized by the administrative body in the conduct of hearings by or for the administrative body unless such procedures are prescribed by a statute; and </section><section prefix="5">The disciplinary procedures within the jurisdiction of the administrative body unless such procedures are prescribed by statute. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 10, effective April 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective> July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note>Acts 1984, ch. 419, effective July 13, 1984, provides:  "Section 1.  It is the intent of the General Assembly that the amendment of Section 10 by the Free Conference Committee report to 1984 HB 334 applies only to fees which are governmental in nature charged by state agencies and not to fees and charges which are proprietary in nature.  Section 2.  This resolution may be used by a court as an aid in the construction of 1984 HB 334." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=736</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>