<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.043</section_number><catch_line>Cancer research institutions matching fund. </catch_line><order_by>043</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created in the State Treasury a cancer research matching fund designated as the "cancer research institutions matching fund." The fund shall be administered by the Council for Postsecondary Education. For tax periods beginning on or after June 1, 2005, the one-cent ($0.01) surtax collected under KRS 138.140(2) shall be deposited in the fund and shall be made available for matching purposes to the following universities for cancer research: <section prefix="a">One-half (1/2) of the moneys deposited in the fund shall be made available to the University of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="b">One-half (1/2) of the moneys deposited in the fund shall be made available to the University of Louisville. </section></section><section prefix="2">All interest earned on moneys in the fund shall be credited to the fund. </section><section prefix="3">Any moneys remaining in the fund at the end of the fiscal year shall lapse to the general fund. </section><section prefix="4">To receive the funds, the universities shall provide dollar-for-dollar matching funds. The matching funds shall come from external sources to be eligible for the state match. External source contributions are those that originate outside the university and its affiliated corporations. The matching funds shall be newly generated to be eligible for state match. Newly generated contributions are those received by the university after April 1, 2005. </section><section prefix="5">Moneys transferred to the fund pursuant to subsection (1) of this section are hereby appropriated for purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="6">The following funds are not eligible for state match: <section prefix="a">Funds received from federal, state, and local government sources; and </section><section prefix="b">General fund and student-derived revenues. </section></section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 173, Pt. XXV, sec. 4, effective March 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> March 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4195</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>