<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.690</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations for relocation assistance. </catch_line><order_by>690</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall adopt such administrative regulations as may be necessary to assure: <section prefix="a">That the payments and assistance authorized by KRS 56.620 shall be administered in a manner which is fair and reasonable, and as uniform as practicable; </section><section prefix="b">That a displaced person who makes proper application for a payment authorized for such person by KRS 56.620 shall be paid promptly after a move or, in hardship cases, be paid in advance; and </section><section prefix="c">That any person aggrieved by a determination as to eligibility for a payment authorized by KRS 56.620 or the amount of a payment, may have his application reviewed by the head of the state agency. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may prescribe such other administrative regulations and procedures, consistent with the provisions of KRS 56.620, as it deems necessary or appropriate to carry out KRS 56.620. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall adopt such administrative regulations and procedures consistent with the provisions of KRS 56.620, as it deems necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of KRS 56.620 with regard to requirements of the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Any county, municipality, or other political subdivision, or any other public or private entity subject to the provisions of the Federal Uniform Relocation Act, before undertaking any project involving federal financial assistance which results in the acquisition of real property or in any person or persons being displaced from their homes, businesses, or farms, shall adopt such administrative regulations, ordinances, procedures or policies as necessary or appropriate to carry out the provisions of KRS 56.620. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 546, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22676</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>