<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.090</section_number><catch_line>Criminal records check performed for Justice and Public Safety Cabinet -- Fee -- Request conditions. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any instance that the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet is required by statute to conduct a criminal records or background check, the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet may contract with the Administrative Office of the Courts to perform that service. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, the Administrative Office of the Courts shall set a reasonable fee for a criminal records check conducted by the office in an amount no greater than the actual cost of conducting that criminal records check. </section><section prefix="b">When another statute sets the dollar amount of the fee charged for a criminal records check conducted by the Administrative Office of the Courts, the office shall charge that fee. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall be required to accept a criminal records check request only when the request is made: <section prefix="a">By letter, electronic mail, or facsimile transmission; or </section><section prefix="b">In person. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Administrative Office of the Courts may establish an escrow account for a person who frequently requests that the office conduct criminal records checks. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 111, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007). 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>