<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.1-735</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications, benefits, and requirements for volunteers. </catch_line><order_by>1-735</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Volunteers shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age. </section><section prefix="2">Volunteers shall not serve within a seventy-five mile radius of their legal or voting residence. </section><section prefix="3">Volunteers shall not be considered employees of the board or the Commonwealth of Kentucky; however, they shall be granted: <section prefix="a">An allowance which, at a minimum, shall equal the federal minimum wage; </section><section prefix="b">Appeal rights pursuant to the provisions of KRS 154.1-740; </section><section prefix="c">Relocation benefits; </section><section prefix="d">Health benefits; </section><section prefix="e">Social security benefits; </section><section prefix="f">Free tuition for one full-time semester at a state-supported Kentucky college or university for every twelve (12) months' service completed in the corps; and </section><section prefix="g">Workers' compensation. </section></section><section prefix="4">Volunteers may receive reimbursement for travel, provided the reimbursement does not exceed the limitations established for Executive Department employees either by law or administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, volunteers shall not be eligible to receive: <section prefix="a">Dental benefits; </section><section prefix="b">Disability insurance; </section><section prefix="c">Life insurance; </section><section prefix="d">Reimbursement for meals; or </section><section prefix="e">Unemployment insurance. </section></section><section prefix="6">All volunteers shall be expected to bring with them a minimum amount of tools to perform their tasks, but the community/user is expected to supply all other items, exclusive of clothing and other personal hygiene and grooming items. </section><section prefix="7">Volunteers shall agree in writing to: <section prefix="a">Cooperate with corps personnel with whom he is working in their common effort, and to abide by the policies and procedures set forth in the handbook and administrative regulations required by KRS 154.1-710, and other applicable state and federal laws. </section><section prefix="b">Hold the Kentucky Peace Corps harmless and to release it from any and all claims arising out of or in connection with any agreement he signs upon volunteering, excepting only that the corps shall remain liable for any harm directly attributable to its gross negligence. </section><section prefix="c">Perform the work assigned to him in an acceptable manner to the corps, or its representatives. </section><section prefix="d">Not engage in any regular work which carries monetary compensation and which falls outside the scope of the assigned corps duties. Any exceptions to this provision shall be authorized in writing by the director, and approved by the board. </section><section prefix="e">Serve the number of months, not to exceed two (2) years, deemed appropriate by the board and director to complete the task assigned. The board may extend the volunteer's contract an additional two (2) years, provided the volunteer is willing, and provided the volunteer has a special skill or expertise needed by the corps. Conversely, the board may reduce the number of months of the contract in the event of hardship. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification>KRS 154.01-735. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>