<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261">STOCKYARDS </unit></structure><section_number>261.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties -- Stop-movement order -- Action to recover fees.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any provision of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated under this chapter, or who refuses to pay the fees required in this chapter, shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or shall be imprisoned for not more than three (3) months, or both. </section><section prefix="2">In determining the fine for violations of KRS 261.350, each head of livestock that is not paid for in compliance with that section shall be considered a separate offense. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the penalties provided in subsection (1) of this section, the Commissioner of Agriculture may issue a stop-movement order on livestock to any person required to be licensed or bonded under this chapter who: <section prefix="a">Sells, buys, or otherwise markets livestock without a dealer or market agency license; </section><section prefix="b">Sells or otherwise markets livestock without a current bond or other security instrument or agreement in the sufficient required amount on file with the department; or </section><section prefix="c">Fails to remit or pay fines owed to the department. </section></section><section prefix="4">The department or the Office of the Attorney General may recover fees or administrative penalties in a civil action brought by the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1(5). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 16. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 63d-11. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 261.990: </former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40149</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>