<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.170</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of licenses -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each licensed speech-language pathologist, speech-language pathology assistant, or audiologist shall biennially, on or before January 31, pay to the board a renewal fee not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150) for a renewal of his or her license. A thirty (30) day grace period shall be allowed after January 31, during which time licenses may be renewed on payment of a renewal fee plus grace period fee which combined shall not exceed one hundred eighty dollars ($180). After expiration of the grace period, the board may renew each license upon payment of a renewal fee plus a delinquency fee which combined shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250). No person who applies for renewal, whose license has expired, shall be required to submit to any examination as a condition to renewal, if the renewal application is made within five (5) years from the date of expiration. </section><section prefix="2">A suspended license is subject to expiration and shall be renewed as provided in this chapter, but the renewal shall not entitle the licensee, while the license remains suspended and until it is reinstated, to engage in the licensed activity, or in any other activity or conduct in violation of the order of judgment by which the license was suspended. A license revoked on disciplinary grounds shall be subject to expiration as provided in this chapter, but it shall not be renewed. If it is reinstated after its expiration, the licensee, as a condition of reinstatement, shall pay a reinstatement fee in an amount equal to the renewal fee in effect on the last preceding regular renewal date before the date on which it is reinstated, plus the delinquency fee, if any, accrued at the time of its revocation. </section><section prefix="3">A person who fails to renew his or her license within the five (5) years after its expiration may not renew it, and it shall not be restored, reissued, or reinstated thereafter. The person may apply for and obtain a new license if the person meets the requirements of this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">A person applying for renewal of licensure shall show evidence of completion of </section>continuing professional education in speech-language pathology or audiology as prescribed by the board by administrative regulation. </text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 7, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 192, effective July 1, 1987. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31909</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>