<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.6-040</section_number><catch_line>Limitation on action contesting validity of revocable trust -- Distribution of trust property. </catch_line><order_by>6-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person may commence a judicial proceeding to contest the validity of a trust that was revocable at the settlor’s death within the earlier of: <section prefix="a">Two (2) years after the settlor’s death; or </section><section prefix="b">Ninety (90) days after the trustee sent the person a copy of the trust instrument and a notice informing the person of the trust’s existence, of the trustee’s name and address, and of the time allowed for commencing a proceeding. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the death of the settlor of a trust that was revocable at the settlor’s death, the trustee may proceed to distribute the trust property in accordance with the terms of the trust. The trustee is not subject to liability for doing so unless: <section prefix="a">The trustee knows of a pending judicial proceeding contesting the validity of the trust; or </section><section prefix="b">A potential contestant has notified the trustee of a possible judicial proceeding to contest the trust and a judicial proceeding is commenced within sixty (60) days after the contestant sent the notification. </section></section><section prefix="3">A beneficiary of a trust that is determined to have been invalid is liable to return any distribution received. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 49, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43112</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>