<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.600</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Women Veterans Program. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Women Veterans Program is hereby created in the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs and shall be attached to the office of the commissioner for administrative purposes. The commissioner shall designate a Women Veterans Coordinator for the Commonwealth. The Kentucky Women Veterans Program shall: <section prefix="a">Perform outreach to improve women veterans' awareness of eligibility for federal and state veterans' services and benefits; </section><section prefix="b">Assess the needs of women veterans with respect to benefits and services; </section><section prefix="c">Review programs, research projects, and other initiatives designed to address or meet the needs of Kentucky's women veterans; </section><section prefix="d">Make recommendations to the commissioner to improve benefits and services; and </section><section prefix="e">Incorporate women veterans' issues in strategic planning concerning benefits and services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The mission of the Kentucky Women Veterans Program shall be to ensure that Kentucky women veterans have equitable access to federal and state veterans' services and benefits. </section><section prefix="3">The program shall provide assistance to women who served in the United States Armed Forces or in forces incorporated as part of the United States Armed Forces, and who were discharged under conditions other than dishonorable. </section><section prefix="4">The primary components of the program shall be: <section prefix="a">Advocacy and Public Awareness. The program shall advocate for women veterans and shall work to increase public awareness about the gender specific needs of women veterans. The program shall advocate legislation and policies on the local, state, and national levels to address these issues; </section><section prefix="b">Collaboration. The program shall collaborate with federal, state, and private agencies that provide services to women veterans; </section><section prefix="c">Research and information dissemination. The program shall monitor and research issues relating to women veterans and disseminate information and opportunities throughout its network; </section><section prefix="d">Education. The program, through conferences, seminars, and training workshops with federal, state, and private agencies, shall provide guidance and direction to a woman veteran applying for grants, benefits, or services; </section><section prefix="e">Honor and Recognition. The program shall promote events and activities that recognize and honor military women; and </section><section prefix="f">Facilities. The program, through grants and other sources of funding, shall provide facilities as appropriate in support of the program. </section></section><section prefix="5">A Women Veterans Coordinating Committee shall be established. The committee's membership shall be composed of representatives of government, public, and private agencies that provide grants, benefits, or services to women veterans. The commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs shall designate the agencies represented on the committee. However, the President of the Kentucky Senate shall appoint a Senator to the committee, and the Speaker of the Kentucky House of Representatives shall appoint a Representative. The committee shall: <section prefix="a">Actively pursue the mission of the Kentucky Women Veterans Program; </section><section prefix="b">Identify policies, practices, programs, and related activities that are unresponsive or insensitive to the needs of women veterans; and </section><section prefix="c">Recommend changes, revisions, and new initiatives to address identified deficiencies. </section></section><section prefix="6">The program is authorized to accept and expend: <section prefix="a">Moneys that may be appropriated by the General Assembly; and </section><section prefix="b">Other moneys received from any other source, including donations and grants. </section></section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21879</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>