<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.020</section_number><catch_line>Departments of Workplace Standards and Workers' Claims. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Workplace Standards shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.040 and shall be divided for administrative purposes into the Division of Employment Standards, Apprenticeship and Mediation, the Division of Occupational Safety and Health Compliance, the Division of Occupational Safety and Health Education and Training, and the Division of Workers' Compensation Funds. Each of these divisions shall be headed by a director appointed by the secretary and approved by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Workers' Claims shall be headed by a commissioner who is nominated by the Workers' Compensation Nominating Commission, appointed by the Governor, and confirmed by the Senate in accordance with KRS 342.213 and 342.228. The department shall be divided for administrative purposes into the Office of Administrative Law Judges, the Office of General Counsel for Workers' Claims, the Division of Claims Processing, the Division of Information and Research, the Division of Security and Compliance, and the Division of Ombudsman and Workers' Compensation Specialist Services. The Office of Administrative Law Judges shall be headed by a chief administrative law judge appointed in accordance with KRS 342.230. Each division in the department shall be headed by a director appointed by the commissioner and approved by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050 and 342.230. The following agencies are attached to the Department of Workers' Claims for administrative purposes only: <section prefix="a">Workers' Compensation Board; </section><section prefix="b">Workers' Compensation Advisory Council; and </section><section prefix="c">Workers' Compensation Nominating Commission. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Office of General Counsel for the Labor Cabinet and the Division of Management Services are attached to the Office of the Secretary of the Labor Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1701, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 34, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 3, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 252. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4618-111, 4748g-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31991</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>