<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.400</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center -- Purposes -- Cooperative agreements -- Funding -- Referrals to specific lenders and brokers prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There may be established, as part of the borrower education initiatives established by or through the Kentucky Housing Corporation, a Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center shall be to: <section prefix="a">Provide a centralized location for information on public services made available by federal, state, or local government or community entities, to assist a homeowner who is in default, or in danger of default, on his or her home loan; and </section><section prefix="b">Attempt to assist, any homeowner who contacts the center without cost to the homeowner, with the goal of: <section prefix="1">Providing a homeowner with information, including toll-free telephone numbers for public services, made available by federal, state, or local government or community entities, including programs such as NeighborWorks and Don't Borrow Trouble, mortgage assistance programs, home repair assistance programs, and utility assistance programs; </section><section prefix="2">Determining if the homeowner has contacted his or her lender regarding any default or danger of default; and </section><section prefix="3">Providing a homeowner with counseling agencies approved by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development that may be able to assist the homeowner. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center may enter into an agreement with any public or nonprofit entity to carry out any part of the mortgage foreclosure counseling and education program. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center may solicit contributions and grants from the private sector, nonprofit entities, and the federal government to assist in carrying out the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Homeownership Protection Center shall not, directly or through an entity contracted with in accordance with subsection (3) of this section, make referrals or recommendations to or regarding specific for-profit lenders or mortgage brokers. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1, effective April 24, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> April 24, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6955</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>