<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-508</section_number><catch_line>Effectiveness of financing statement if new debtor becomes bound by security agreement. </catch_line><order_by>9-508</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a filed financing statement naming an original debtor is effective to perfect a security interest in collateral in which a new debtor has or acquires rights to the extent that the financing statement would have been effective had the original debtor acquired rights in the collateral. </section><section prefix="2">If the difference between the name of the original debtor and that of the new debtor causes a filed financing statement that is effective under subsection (1) of this section to be seriously misleading under KRS 355.9-506: <section prefix="a">The financing statement is effective to perfect a security interest in collateral acquired by the new debtor before, and within four (4) months after, the new debtor becomes bound under KRS 355.9-203(4); and </section><section prefix="b">The financing statement is not effective to perfect a security interest in collateral acquired by the new debtor more than four (4) months after the new debtor becomes bound under KRS 355.9-203(4) unless an initial financing statement providing the name of the new debtor is filed before the expiration of that time. </section></section><section prefix="3">This section does not apply to collateral as to which a filed financing statement remains effective against the new debtor under KRS 355.9-507(1). </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 99, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33813</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>