<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.8-075</section_number><catch_line>Change of control. </catch_line><order_by>8-075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "change of control" means: <section prefix="a">A transfer of voting stock which results in giving a person, directly or indirectly, the power to direct the management and policy of a mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker; or </section><section prefix="b">A transfer of at least ten percent (10%) of the outstanding voting stock of a mortgage loan company or a mortgage loan broker. </section></section><section prefix="2">A transfer of voting stock of a mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker which constitutes a change of control shall be approved in writing by the commissioner, prior to the transfer. </section><section prefix="3">The owner, president, chief executive officer or a partner shall apply to the commissioner for approval of a transfer of voting stock in his mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker which constitutes a change of control. The application must contain information which shows that the requirements of this subtitle for obtaining a license will be satisfied after the change of control. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 773, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 461, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 294.075. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14865</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>