<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.5499</section_number><catch_line>Funding mechanism for Telecommunications Access Program. </catch_line><order_by>5499</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Public Service Commission shall determine the appropriate funding mechanism for the Telecommunications Access Program established pursuant to KRS 163.525. The funding mechanism shall be designed to collect reasonably necessary funds, not to exceed two cents ($0.02) per access line per month, from subscribers of telecommunication utilities. The telecommunications industry shall not be required to absorb the cost of funding the Telecommunications Access Program. </section><section prefix="2">The Public Service Commission shall distribute the funds collected from this funding mechanism to the Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing for the purpose of implementing and operating the Telecommunications Access Program. The secretary of the cabinet to which the Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing is attached by statute or executive order shall establish oversight conditions with the Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing to ensure the funds are being used solely for the purposes consistent with this section and KRS 163.525. </section><section prefix="3">The Public Service Commission, with the advice of the Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing, shall initiate an investigation, conduct public hearings, and determine the appropriate funding mechanism for the Telecommunications Access Program no later than January 1, 1995. As part of this determination, the commission may review the funding mechanism for the telecommunications relay service pursuant to KRS 278.549. The commission shall consider whether a telecommunications utility experiences a competitive disadvantage resulting from the funding mechanism when compared to other telecommunication utilities. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 10, effective June 4, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 4, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>