<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.647</section_number><catch_line>Education Assessment and Accountability Review Subcommittee -- Members -- Duties -- Vote required to act. </catch_line><order_by>647</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A permanent subcommittee of the Legislative Research Commission to be known as the Education Assessment and Accountability Review Subcommittee is hereby created. The subcommittee shall be composed of eight (8) members appointed as follows: three (3) members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate; one (1) member of the minority party in the Senate appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the Senate; three (3) members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and one (1) member of the minority party in the House of Representatives appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the House of Representatives. Members of the subcommittee shall serve for terms of two (2) years, and the members appointed from each chamber shall elect one (1) member from their chamber to serve as co-chair. The co-chairs shall have joint responsibilities for subcommittee meeting agendas and presiding at subcommittee meetings. A majority of the entire membership of the Education Assessment and Accountability Review Subcommittee shall constitute a quorum, and all actions of the subcommittee shall be by vote of a majority of its entire membership. Any vacancy that may occur in the membership of the subcommittee shall be filled by the same appointing authority who made the original appointment. </section><section prefix="2">The subcommittee shall review administrative regulations and advise the Kentucky Board of Education concerning the implementation of the state system of assessment and accountability, established in KRS 158.6453, 158.6455, and 158.782, and for any administrative regulation promulgated under provisions of KRS 158.860. </section><section prefix="3">The subcommittee shall advise and monitor the Office of Education Accountability in the performance of its duties according to the provisions of KRS 7.410. </section><section prefix="4">On an alternating basis, each co-chair shall have the first option to set the monthly meeting date. A monthly meeting may be canceled by agreement of both co-chairs. The members of the subcommittee shall be compensated for attending meetings as provided in KRS 7.090. </section><section prefix="5">Any professional, clerical, or other employees required by the subcommittee shall be provided in accordance with the provisions of KRS 7.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 6, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective April 8, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 2, effective April 14, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3561</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>