<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.6003</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 247.6005 to 247.6035. </catch_line><order_by>6003</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.6005 to 247.6035, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the State Board of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">"Corn" means all kinds and varieties of corn, including popcorn, except sweet corn and ornamental corns; </section><section prefix="4">"Bushel" means fifty-six (56) pounds of corn by weight or as otherwise defined by the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA); </section><section prefix="5">"Producer" means every person who produces and markets corn; </section><section prefix="6">"New producer" means a producer who was not engaged in the business of producing corn at the time a referendum was conducted in accordance with the provisions of KRS 247.6001 to 247.6035; </section><section prefix="7">"Person" means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, cooperative, or other business entity; </section><section prefix="8">"Marketing year" means from September 1 to August 31 of the following year; </section><section prefix="9">"Purchaser" means any person, public or private corporation, Federal Commodity Credit Corporation, association or partnership buying, accepting for shipment, or otherwise acquiring the property in or to corn from a producer, and shall include a mortgagee, pledgee, lienor, or other person, public or private, having a claim against the producer, when the actual or constructive possession of the corn is taken as part payment or in satisfaction of a mortgage, pledge, lien, or claim; and </section><section prefix="10">"Marketed" means any quantities that are sold, bartered, or for which other items of value are exchanged. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11730</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>