<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.829</section_number><catch_line>Commission's duties with respect to legislative lobbying. </catch_line><order_by>829</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall review each registration statement, expenditure statement, and financial transaction statement filed with the commission, to determine whether the statement includes all the information required. If the statement does not include all the required information, or a legislative agent or employer has failed to file a registration statement, the commission shall send notification by certified mail to the person who filed the statement regarding the deficiency in the statement, or to the person who failed to file the statement regarding that failure. Any person so notified by the commission shall, not later than ten (10) days after receiving the notice, file a registration statement or an amended statement that does include all the information required. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall keep on file the statements required by KRS 6.807, 6.821, and 6.824. Those statements are public records and open to public inspection, and the commission shall computerize them so that the information contained in them is readily accessible to the general public. The commission shall provide copies of the statements to the general public upon request and may charge a reasonable fee not to exceed the cost of copying each statement. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall prescribe and make available an appropriate form for filing the information required by KRS 6.807, 6.821, and 6.824. The form shall contain the following notices in boldface type: "ANY PERSON WHO KNOWINGLY FILES A FALSE STATEMENT IS IN VIOLATION OF STATE LAW AND SUBJECT TO FINES AND OTHER PENALTIES." </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall publish a handbook that explains this code in clear and concise language, and make it available free of charge to members of the General Assembly, legislative agents, employers, and any other interested persons. </section><section prefix="5">On or before the fifteenth day of February of each year, the commission shall, in a manner and form it determines, publish a report containing statistical information on the registration statements filed with it during the preceding year. </section><section prefix="6">Any regulations promulgated by the commission to implement this code shall be adopted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></text><history>Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 32, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=408</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>