<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.070</section_number><catch_line>When protective order becomes effective and binding on respondent-- Mutual protective orders -- Petition hearing testimony later admissibleonly for impeachment purposes -- Interpersonal protective order intakecenter.  </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text>(1)A temporary or ordinary interpersonal protective order shall become effectiveand binding on the respondent when the respondent is given notice of theexistence and terms of the order by a peace officer or the court or uponpersonal service of the order, whichever is earlier. A peace officer or courtgiving notice of an unserved order shall make all reasonable efforts to arrangefor the order's personal service upon the respondent. Once effective, a peaceofficer or the court may enforce the order's terms and act immediately upontheir violation.(2)Costs, fees, or bond shall not be assessed against or required of a petitionerfor any filing, hearing, service, or order authorized by or required to implementthis chapter.(3)A court shall not require mediation, conciliation, or counseling prior to or as acondition of issuing an interpersonal protective order.(4)Mutual protective orders may be issued only if:(a)Separate petitions have been filed by both parties; and(b)The orders are written with sufficient specificity to allow any peace officerto identify which party has violated the order.(5)Upon proper filing of a motion, either party may seek to amend aninterpersonal protective order.(6)Testimony offered by an adverse party in a hearing ordered pursuant to KRS456.040 shall not be admissible in any criminal proceeding involving the sameparties except for purposes of impeachment.(7)(a)The Court of Justice, county and Commonwealth's attorneys, lawenforcement agencies, and victim services organizations may jointlyoperate an interpersonal protective order intake center to assist personswho apply for relief under this chapter.(b)In cases where criminal conduct is alleged, a court may suggest that apetitioner voluntarily contact the county attorney. A court may not withholdor delay relief if the petitioner elects to not contact the county attorney.(8)A person's right to apply for relief under this chapter shall not be affected bythat person leaving his or her residence to avoid dating violence and abuse,sexual assault, or stalking.(9)A court shall order the omission or deletion of the petitioner's address and theaddress of any minor children from any orders or documents to be madeavailable to the public or to any person who engaged in the acts complained ofin the petition.(10)(a)If a petition under this chapter did not result in the issuance of anon-temporary interpersonal protective order, the court in which thepetition was heard may for good cause shown order the expungement ofthe records of the case if:1.Six (6) months have elapsed since the case was dismissed; and2.During the six (6) months preceding the expungement request, therespondent has not been bound by an order of protection issued forthe protection of any person including an order of protection asdefined in KRS 403.720.(b)As used in this subsection, "expungement" has the same meaning as inKRS 431.079.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 25, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44773</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>