<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-497</section_number><catch_line>Required written consumer protection disclosures relating to self-service storage space insurance. </catch_line><order_by>9-497</order_by><text>Self-service storage space insurance shall not be transacted under this subtitle at any location unless the following consumer protection disclosures are made in writing that meets the readability standards set forth in KRS 304.14-440 and the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder prior to the sale of self-service storage space insurance: <section prefix="1">A clear and concise description of the material terms and conditions of the coverage, including a description of exclusions; </section><section prefix="2">A description of the process for filing a claim and a toll-free telephone number for reporting a claim; </section><section prefix="3">A statement that the coverage offered by the self-service storage space insurance rental agreement may be a duplication of coverage already provided by an occupant's other source of property coverage; </section><section prefix="4">A statement that if insurance is required as a condition of an operator’s rental agreement with an occupant, the requirement may be satisfied by the customer's: <section prefix="a">Purchase of self-service storage space insurance that is offered or disseminated by the self-storage facility; or </section><section prefix="b">Presentation to the self-storage facility of evidence of other applicable insurance coverage; </section></section><section prefix="5">The name and address of the underwriting insurer; </section><section prefix="6">A separate itemization of all costs for the self-service storage space insurance; </section><section prefix="7">Confirmation that the insurer underwriting coverage is authorized to transact insurance in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="8">A statement that the self-service storage space insurance is primary coverage over any other coverage which may be made available to the occupant covering the same loss. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43253</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>