<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.056</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner of parks may commission park rangers -- Powers as peace officers. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of parks, in his discretion, may employ and commission park rangers as the commissioner deems necessary to secure the parks and property of the Department of Parks and to maintain law and order and such employees, when so commissioned, shall have all of the powers of peace officers and shall have on all parks property and on public highways transversing such property in all parts of the state the same powers with respect to criminal matters and enforcement of the laws relating thereto as sheriffs, constables and police officers in their respective jurisdictions, and shall possess all the immunities and matters of defense now available or hereafter made available to sheriffs, constables and police officers in any suit brought against them in consequence of acts done in the course of their employment. </section><section prefix="2">The designation of any such employee as a peace officer shall be governed by the provisions of KRS 61.300 except that he shall not be required to have resided in the county wherein he is to serve for a period of at least two (2) years, and he shall be required to file his photograph and affidavit only with the Franklin county clerk. </section><section prefix="3">Any employee so commissioned shall be required to execute bond, subject to the provisions of KRS 62.170, for the faithful and lawful performance of his duties. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 111, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 295, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 1. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1698</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>