<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.650</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>As used in KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Air conditioning or cooling system" means a system in which heat is removed from air, surrounding surfaces, or both; </section><section prefix="2">"Apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic" means an individual in the process of learning the heating, ventilation, and air conditioning trade who assists and is under the supervision of a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor and a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning Contractors; </section><section prefix="4">"Burner service" means the servicing of oil or gas burners used for heating air or water for purposes other than the transmission of heat; </section><section prefix="5">"Certificate" means a document issued by the board to an apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic to assist a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor or a journeyman heating, ventilation, or air conditioning mechanic; </section><section prefix="6">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="8">"Heating system" means a system in which heat is transmitted by radiation, conduction, convection, or a combination of any of these methods to air, surrounding surfaces, or both. "Heating system" does not include fireplaces and free-standing stoves not incorporated into a primary heating system, electric thermal storage units, electric ceiling cable heating systems, or electric baseboard heating units; </section><section prefix="9">"Hydronic system" means a heating and cooling system using liquids to transmit or remove heat; </section><section prefix="10">"Initial heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system" means the first or original heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system installed in a building; </section><section prefix="11">"Journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic" means an individual who is licensed by the board to perform heating, ventilation, and air conditioning work under the supervision, direction, and responsibility of a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor; </section><section prefix="12">"Maintenance person or maintenance engineer" means a person who is a regular and bona fide full-time employee or agent of a property owner, property lessor, property management company, or firm, not in the heating, ventilating, and air conditioning business that has jurisdiction of property where the routine maintenance of heating, ventilating, and air conditioning is being performed, provided the maintenance shall not include replacement of heating, ventilation, or air conditioning systems; </section><section prefix="13">"Major repair" means the complete replacement of any of the following heating, ventilation, or air conditioning equipment: <section prefix="a">Furnaces; </section><section prefix="b">Condensing units; </section><section prefix="c">Heat pumps; </section><section prefix="d">Fan coil units; </section><section prefix="e">Chiller systems; or </section><section prefix="f">Heating boiler systems not covered by KRS Chapter 236; </section></section><section prefix="14">"Master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor" means a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor who is licensed by the board to advertise and practice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="15">"Permit" means a document issued by the department or its authorized agent allowing the installation of an original heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system; </section><section prefix="16">"Practice of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting" means the installation, maintenance, altering, remodeling, or repair of heating systems, ventilation systems, hydronic systems, burner service, or cooling systems; </section><section prefix="17">"Routine maintenance of heating, ventilation, or air conditioning" means the routine and periodic servicing of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems, including cleaning, inspection, and adjustments to ensure the proper operation, and the removal and replacement of component parts. "Routine maintenance of heating, ventilation, or air conditioning" shall not include the installation of complete new heating, ventilation, or air conditioning systems; and </section><section prefix="18">"Ventilation system" means a natural or mechanical system of supplying air to or removing air from any space. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, secs. 286 and 287, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 9, effective July 1, 2008. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section, in the version effective until July 1, 2010, was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 286, but that version expired prior to the July 15, 2010, effective date of the legislation. The version of this section which was set to take effect July 1, 2010, was also amended during the 2010 Regular Session of the General Assembly by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 287, and that version, as amended, is set forth above.  (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 9, to be effective July 1, 2008, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be July 1, 2010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7050</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>