<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.023</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings -- Department for Local Government to encourage growth of broadband and information technology in state. </catch_line><order_by>023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that the work of ConnectKentucky in the deployment and adoption of broadband services and information technology across the state has resulted in enhanced economic development and public safety for Kentucky communities, improved health care and educational opportunities, and a better quality of life for Kentucky citizens. Further, continued progress in the deployment and adoption of broadband services is vital to ensuring that Kentucky remains competitive and continues to create business and job growth. The General Assembly finds that Kentucky must encourage and support the partnership of the public and private sectors in the continued growth of telecommunications and information technology for Kentucky citizens and businesses. </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Local Government shall: <section prefix="a">Track the deployment and adoption of broadband and information technology in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Enable public-private partnerships among broadband providers and relevant government entities to encourage the deployment and adoption of advanced broadband services; </section><section prefix="c">Serve as a resource for all citizens, broadband providers, and technology businesses regarding broadband and information technology issues; </section><section prefix="d">Report progress on deployment and adoption to the Legislative Research Commission upon request and at least annually; and </section><section prefix="e">Ensure notification to the public of the availability of public funds for broadband and information technology investments prior to awarding any contracts or grants. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Department for Local Government may contract with a nonprofit organization to accomplish the objectives set forth in this section. The organization shall have an established competency in working with public and private sectors to accomplish wide-scale deployment and adoption of broadband and information technology. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing herein shall be construed as giving the Department for Local Government any authority, regulatory or otherwise, over providers of telecommunications and information technology. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1644</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>