<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter and specific ranges in chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards under the direction and supervision of the secretary of the Labor Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">"Department" means the Department of Workplace Standards in the Labor Cabinet; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">"Wages" includes any compensation due to an employee by reason of his or her employment, including salaries, commissions, vested vacation pay, overtime pay, severance or dismissal pay, earned bonuses, and any other similar advantages agreed upon by the employer and the employee or provided to employees as an established policy. The wages shall be payable in legal tender of the United States or checks on banks convertible into cash on demand at full face value, subject to the allowances made in this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of calculating hourly wage rates for scheduled overtime for professional firefighters, as defined in KRS 95A.210(5), "wages" shall not include the distribution to qualified professional firefighters by local governments of supplements received from the Firefighters Foundation Program Fund. For the purposes of calculating hourly wage rates for unscheduled overtime for professional firefighters, as defined in KRS 95A.210(6), "wages" shall include the distribution to qualified professional firefighters by local governments of supplements received from the Firefighters Foundation Program Fund; </section></section><section prefix="d">"Employer" is any person, either individual, corporation, partnership, agency, or firm who employs an employee and includes any person, either individual, corporation, partnership, agency, or firm acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee; and </section><section prefix="e">"Employee" is any person employed by or suffered or permitted to work for an employer. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in KRS 337.275 to 337.325, 337.345, and KRS 337.385 to 337.405, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Employee" is any person employed by or suffered or permitted to work for an employer, but shall not include: <section prefix="1">Any individual employed in agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">Any individual employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, supervisory, or professional capacity, or in the capacity of outside salesman, or as an outside collector as the terms are defined by administrative regulations of the commissioner; </section><section prefix="3">Any individual employed by the United States; </section><section prefix="4">Any individual employed in domestic service in or about a private home. The provisions of this section shall include individuals employed in domestic service in or about the home of an employer where there is more than one (1) domestic servant regularly employed; </section><section prefix="5">Any individual classified and given a certificate by the commissioner showing a status of learner, apprentice, worker with a disability, sheltered workshop employee, and student under administrative procedures and administrative regulations prescribed and promulgated by the commissioner. This certificate shall authorize employment at the wages, less than the established fixed minimum fair wage rates, and for the period of time fixed by the commissioner and stated in the certificate issued to the person; </section><section prefix="6">Employees of retail stores, service industries, hotels, motels, and restaurant operations whose average annual gross volume of sales made for business done is less than ninety-five thousand dollars ($95,000) for the five (5) preceding years exclusive of excise taxes at the retail level or if the employee is the parent, spouse, child, or other member of his or her employer's immediate family; </section><section prefix="7">Any individual employed as a baby-sitter in an employer's home, or an individual employed as a companion by a sick, convalescing, or elderly person or by the person's immediate family, to care for that sick, convalescing, or elderly person and whose principal duties do not include housekeeping; </section><section prefix="8">Any individual engaged in the delivery of newspapers to the consumer; </section><section prefix="9">Any individual subject to the provisions of KRS Chapters 7, 16, 27A, 30A, and 18A provided that the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall have the authority to prescribe by administrative regulation those emergency employees, or others, who shall receive overtime pay rates necessary for the efficient operation of government and the protection of affected employees; </section><section prefix="10">Any employee employed by an establishment which is an organized nonprofit camp, religious, or nonprofit educational conference center, if it does not operate for more than seven (7) months in any calendar year; </section><section prefix="11">Any employee whose function is to provide twenty-four (24) hour residential care on the employer's premises in a parental role to children who are primarily dependent, neglected, and abused and who are in the care of private, nonprofit childcaring facilities licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services under KRS 199.640 to 199.670; or </section><section prefix="12">Any individual whose function is to provide twenty-four (24) hour residential care in his or her own home as a family caregiver and who is approved to provide family caregiver services to an adult with a disability through a contractual relationship with a community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability established under KRS 210.370 to 210.460, or is certified or licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to provide adult foster care; </section></section><section prefix="b">"Agriculture" means farming in all its branches, including cultivation and tillage of the soil; dairying; production, cultivation, growing, and harvesting of any agricultural or horticultural commodity; raising of livestock, bees, furbearing animals, or poultry; and any practice, including any forestry or lumbering operations, performed on a farm in conjunction with farming operations, including preparation and delivery of produce to storage, to market, or to carriers for transportation to market; </section><section prefix="c">"Gratuity" means voluntary monetary contribution received by an employee from a guest, patron, or customer for services rendered; </section><section prefix="d">"Tipped employee" means any employee engaged in an occupation in which he or she customarily and regularly receives more than thirty dollars ($30) per month in tips; and </section><section prefix="e">"U.S.C." means the United States Code. </section></section><section prefix="3">As used in KRS 337.505 to 337.550, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Construction" includes construction, reconstruction, improvement, enlargement, alteration, or repair of any public works project by contract fairly estimated to cost more than two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000). No public works project, if procured under a single contract and subject to the requirements of this section, may be divided into multiple contracts of lesser value to avoid compliance with the provisions of this section; </section><section prefix="b">"Contractor" and "subcontractor" include any superintendent, foreman, or other authorized agent of any contractor or subcontractor who is in charge of the construction of the public works or who is in charge of the employment or payment of the employees of the contractor or subcontractor who are employed in performing the work to be done or being done by the contractor or subcontractor under the particular contract with any public authority; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">"Locality" shall be determined by the commissioner. The commissioner may designate more than one (1) county as a single locality, but if more than one (1) county is designated, the multicounty locality shall not extend beyond the boundaries of a state Senatorial district. The commissioner shall not designate less than an entire county as a locality. If there is not available in the locality a sufficient number of competent, skilled laborers, workmen, and mechanics to efficiently and properly construct the public works, "locality" shall include any other locality nearest the one in which the work of construction is to be performed and from which such available skilled laborers, workmen, and mechanics may be obtained in sufficient number to perform the work; and </section><section prefix="2">"Locality" with respect to contracts advertised or awarded by the Transportation Cabinet of this state shall be determined by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet. The secretary may designate any number of counties as constituting a single locality. The secretary may also designate all counties of the Commonwealth as a single locality, but he or she shall not designate less than an entire county as a locality; </section></section><section prefix="d">"Public authority" means any officer, board, or commission of this state, or any political subdivision or department thereof in the state, or any institution supported in whole or in part by public funds, including publicly owned or controlled corporations, authorized by law to enter into any contract for the construction of public works and any nonprofit corporation funded to act as an agency and instrumentality of the government agency in connection with the construction of public works, and any "private provider", as defined in KRS 197.500, which enters into any contract for the construction of an "adult correctional facility", as defined in KRS 197.500; and </section><section prefix="e">"Public works" includes all buildings, roads, streets, alleys, sewers, ditches, sewage disposal plants, waterworks, and all other structures or work, including "adult correctional facilities", as defined in KRS 197.500, constructed under contract with any public authority. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the federal government or any of its agencies furnishes by loans or grants any part of the funds used in constructing public works, and if the federal government or its agencies prescribe predetermined prevailing minimum wages to be paid to mechanics, workmen, and laborers employed in the construction of the public works, and if KRS 337.505 to 337.550 is also applicable, those wages in each classification which are higher shall prevail. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 113, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1727, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 4, effective March 20, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 67, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 92, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 426, sec. 558, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 606, sec. 113, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 115, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 85, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 492, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 340, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 1; and ch. 391, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 6. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599c-4, 1599c-39, 2290c-1, 2290c-2, 4767a-1, 4767a-17. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40839</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>