<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.306</section_number><catch_line>Conditions for receiving assistance from fund for water-related infrastructure projects. </catch_line><order_by>306</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall require the following as conditions for receiving assistance from any fund administered by the authority for infrastructure projects related to water service: <section prefix="a">Establishment and use of a financial accounting system that accounts for the operations of water treatment and distribution separately from all other operations of the applicant; </section><section prefix="b">Establishment of service rates based upon the cost of providing the service; and </section><section prefix="c">An agreement that the authority may require an audit to be conducted of the applicant at least once every two (2) years. </section></section><section prefix="2">The authority shall require all applicants within a class to use the same accounting system. The authority may accept present accounting systems in use and applied uniformly to all applicants within a class, for example, the uniform system of accounts established by the National Association of Regulatory Utility Commissioners. </section><section prefix="3">The authority may assist water providers to establish accounting systems that meet the requirements of this section. The authority may provide assistance by paying for third-party private contractors or assistance from the Kentucky Auditor of Public Accounts. </section><section prefix="4">The authority may pay for costs related to establishing a new uniform accounting system for the use of governmental agencies that merge or consolidate their water services if: <section prefix="a">The merging or consolidating entities use different accounting systems; </section><section prefix="b">The merger or consolidation is consistent with a 2020 water management planning council plan as reviewed and prioritized under KRS 151.607; and </section><section prefix="c">At least one (1) governmental agency water system is a partner in the merger or consolidation. </section></section><section prefix="5">The authority may fund the requirements of this section from the 2020 water service account. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10594</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>