<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.160</section_number><catch_line>Powers of secretary of the cabinet in providing service to handicapped persons. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for health and family services may, from the funds available, employ, by contract or otherwise such medical, clinical, technical, and other personnel that he deems necessary to effectuate the purposes of KRS 211.130 to 211.160, and fix and pay their compensation and necessary traveling expenses. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary for health and family services may, from the funds available, procure, by purchase or lease or otherwise, such property, equipment, services, facilities, and supplies that he deems necessary to effectuate the purposes of KRS 211.130 to 211.160. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary for health and family services is authorized to accept, on behalf of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, all gifts, donations, contributions, grants, devises, bequests, and conveyances of real and personal property for establishing, providing, and maintaining the services and facilities described in KRS 211.150, subject only to the condition that same shall be devoted to and used for said purposes. All funds received by the secretary for health and family services shall be deposited in the State Treasury and credited to a trust and agency fund account and expended only for purposes authorized by KRS 211.130 to 211.160. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary for health and family services may make and issue all necessary rules and regulations to carry out KRS 211.130 to 211.160; provided, however, that no educable person shall be eligible for any benefits hereunder unless he is, and has been continuously for at least twelve (12) months immediately preceding the date of his application therefor, an actual resident of this state. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary for health and family services may delegate to any division of the cabinet, or to any director thereof, any and all of his authority and duties hereunder. </section><section prefix="6">Upon request of the secretary for health and family services, approved in writing by the Governor, any cabinet, agency, or commission of the Commonwealth shall furnish without cost to the cabinet such services, facilities, and assistance as are available and, in the judgment of the secretary for health and family services and the Governor, required, to effectuate the purposes of KRS 211.130 to 211.160 or its administration which is hereby vested in the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 341, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 285, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(16). -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 4, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8353</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>