<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.8-040</section_number><catch_line>Election of directors and composition of board.   </catch_line><order_by>8-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless the organic rules require a greater number: <section prefix="a">The number of directors that must be patron members may not be fewer than: <section prefix="1">One (1), if there are two (2) or three (3) directors; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2), if there are four (4) or five (5) directors; </section><section prefix="3">Three (3), if there are six (6) through eight (8) directors; or </section><section prefix="4">One-third (1/3) of the directors if there are at least nine (9) directors; and </section></section><section prefix="b">A majority of the board of directors shall be elected exclusively by patron members. </section></section><section prefix="2">Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, if a limited cooperative association has investor members, the directors who are not elected exclusively by patron members are elected by the investor members. </section><section prefix="3">Subject to subsection (1) of this section, the organic rules may provide for the election of all or a specified number of directors by one (1) or more districts or classes of members. </section><section prefix="4">Subject to subsection (1) of this section, the organic rules may provide for the nomination or election of directors by districts or classes, directly or by district delegates. </section><section prefix="5">If a class of members consists of a single member, the organic rules may provide for the member to appoint a director or directors. </section><section prefix="6">Unless the organic rules otherwise provide, cumulative voting for directors is prohibited. </section><section prefix="7">Except as otherwise provided by the organic rules, subsection (5) of this section, or KRS 272A.3-020, 272A.5-140, 272A.5-150, and 272A.8-090, member directors shall be elected at an annual members meeting. </section><section prefix="8">Every director of a limited cooperative association, by acceptance of election or appointment as a director, including by service, shall be deemed to have consented to the jurisdiction of the courts of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for any action by, in the name of, or on behalf of the association. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 57, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41033</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>