<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.275</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declaration on backstowing and reinjection of coal processing and coal underground development waste. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that: <section prefix="a">The backstowing of coal processing and coal underground development waste is a disposal method which, under appropriate conditions, is authorized under state and federal coal mining laws; </section><section prefix="b">The state Division of Water and Department for Natural Resources, United States Environmental Protection Agency, and United States Mine Safety and Health Administration each have responsibilities under different state and federal laws relative to any proposal to backstow or reinject coal processing and coal underground development waste; and </section><section prefix="c">The maximization of coordination of agency review of such a proposal is in the best interest of each agency, the proponent, and the public-at-large. </section></section><section prefix="2">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the Energy and Environment Cabinet negotiate improved coordination among state and federal agencies in the review of proposals for backstowing or reinjection of coal processing and coal underground development waste, consistent with all requirements of KRS Chapters 224 and 350 and other state and federal laws relating to such proposals. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1885, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 323, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>