<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.120</section_number><catch_line>Statewide bicycle and bikeways program. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall develop and coordinate a statewide bicycle and bikeways program and shall coordinate plans for promotion of bicycling and promotion of bikeways with other state agencies, and units of local government in order to maximize the use of roads, streets, parks and other publicly owned lands, abandoned road beds, and other resources in the development of bikeways. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Assist and cooperate with local governments and other agencies in the development and construction of local and regional bikeway projects; </section><section prefix="b">Develop and publish policies, procedures, and standards for planning, designing, and constructing, maintaining, marking, and operating bikeways in the state, and for the safety of bicyclists, motorists, and the public; </section><section prefix="c">Develop bikeway demonstration projects and safety training programs; and </section><section prefix="d">Develop and construct a State Bikeway System. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The cabinet shall be authorized to appropriate needed funds for the program in the biennial budget, subject to approval of the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="b">The cabinet is authorized to obtain any federal, state, local, or private funds available to the cabinet, and designated for the purpose of this section and KRS 174.125. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5014</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>