<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.709</section_number><catch_line>Delivery of health services by staff -- Abuse, neglect, and exploitation of clients, policies and reporting.   </catch_line><order_by>709</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall report to the Division of Health Care any alleged or actual cases of health services being delivered by the staff of an assisted-living community. </section><section prefix="2">An assisted-living community shall have written policies on reporting and recordkeeping of alleged or actual cases of abuse, neglect, or exploitation of an adult under KRS 209.030. The only requisite components of a recordkeeping policy are the date and time of the report, the reporting method, and a brief summary of the alleged incident. </section><section prefix="3">Any assisted-living community staff member who has reasonable cause to suspect that a client has suffered abuse, neglect, or exploitation shall report the abuse, neglect, or exploitation under KRS 209.030. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 10, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 164, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>