<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280">PRIVATE TOLL BRIDGES AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>280.290</section_number><catch_line>Appeals in ferry cases. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person interested may appeal from any order of the county judge/executive concerning a ferry or ferry rates to the Circuit Court of the county, and thence to the Court of Appeals, both of which shall have jurisdiction of law and fact, but the Court of Appeals of only such facts as are certified from the Circuit Court. The appeal shall be prosecuted to the Circuit Court within thirty (30) days from the making of the order, and to the Court of Appeals in accordance with the Rules of Civil Procedure. The county attorney may take an appeal in the name of the Commonwealth from any order of the county judge/executive concerning a ferry or ferry rates, but only if some person becomes responsible to the adverse party for the cost incident thereto. </section><section prefix="2">The Circuit Court shall hear each appeal brought under subsection (1) of this section as an original case, and may command the county judge/executive to enter an order in conformity with the judgment of the Circuit Court. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 462, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 265, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1801, 1817. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14266</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>