<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.0241</section_number><catch_line>Access to and use of commission-managed lands for hunting -- Duties of commission and other state agencies -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>0241</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Commission" has the same meaning as in KRS 150.010; </section><section prefix="b">"Commission-managed lands" means those lands owned by the commission, those lands owned by the Commonwealth over which the commission holds management authority, or those privately owned lands that are leased or managed by the commission; and </section><section prefix="c">"Hunting" means the lawful pursuit, trapping, shooting, capture, collection, or killing of wildlife or the lawful attempt to do the same. </section></section><section prefix="2">Commission-managed lands shall be open to access and use for hunting except as limited by the commission for reasons of fish or wildlife management, or as otherwise limited by a statute outside KRS Chapter 150 or 235. </section><section prefix="3">The commission, in exercising its authority under the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and statutes, shall exercise its authority consistent with subsection (2) of this section, in a manner that supports, promotes, and enhances hunting opportunities to the extent authorized by law. </section><section prefix="4">Commission land management decisions and actions, including decisions made by private owners to close land managed by the commission, shall not result in any net loss of habitat land acreage available for hunting opportunities on commission-managed lands that exists on July 15, 2010. The commission shall expeditiously find replacement acreage for hunting to compensate for closures of any existing hunting land. Replacement lands shall, to the greatest extent possible, be located within the same wildlife district and shall be consistent with the hunting discipline that the commission allowed on the closed land. </section><section prefix="5">Any state agency that owns or manages lands shall assist and coordinate and cooperate with the commission to allow hunting on these lands if the lands are determined by the commission and that agency to be suitable for hunting. To ensure no net loss of land acreage available for hunting, state agencies shall cooperate with the commission to open new, additional hunting lands to replace lost hunting acreage. Lands officially designated as units within the state park system may be considered for replacement hunting lands and may be open for hunting when necessary as a wildlife control or management tool as determined by the Department of Parks. </section><section prefix="6">By October 1 of each year, the commissioner shall submit to the Legislative Research Commission and the Interim Joint Committee on Natural Resources and Environment a written report describing: <section prefix="a">The acreage managed by the commission that was closed to hunting during the previous fiscal year and the reasons for the closures; and </section><section prefix="b">The acreage managed by the commission that was opened to hunting to compensate for closures of existing land pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="7">By October 1 of each year, any state agency that owns or manages lands shall submit a written report to the commission, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Interim Joint Committee on Natural Resources and Environment describing: <section prefix="a">A list of properties that were open for hunting during the previous fiscal year; </section><section prefix="b">A list of properties that were not open for hunting during the previous fiscal year; and </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The acreage for each property and the county where each property is located, including lands on which a right-of-way exists which make the lands unsuitable for hunting, and an explanation of why the right-of-way makes the land unsuitable for hunting; and </section><section prefix="2">Parcels under fifty (50) acres. No agency shall subdivide land it owns or manages into parcels under fifty (50) acres in an attempt to avoid compliance with the provisions of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">The first report under this section shall be due no later than October 1, 2010. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1934</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>