<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.030</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The board may: <section prefix="1">Cooperate with universities and other entities in conducting the necessary scientific investigations relating to the cause, nature, prevention, and treatment of communicable diseases of livestock, poultry, and fish; </section><section prefix="2">Establish, maintain, and enforce any quarantine and other measures as it deems necessary in controlling the movement of livestock, poultry, and fish into, through, or within the state; </section><section prefix="3">Order and enforce the cleaning and disinfection of premises and all articles and materials by which communicable diseases may be transmitted, and the destruction of diseased and exposed animals and all property and materials, as may be necessary in the eradication of disease; </section><section prefix="4">Adopt, issue, and enforce administrative regulations necessary for the proper administration and enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, and for the accomplishment of the purposes intended to be accomplished by this chapter. Administrative regulations falling within the scope of KRS 257.196 shall be adopted, issued, and enforced in conformity with that section; and </section><section prefix="5">Employ necessary scientific, field, stenographic, and clerical assistants and fix their salaries. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 63c-13, 63c-14. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12342</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>