<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.11-055</section_number><catch_line>Right of aggrieved person to file written complaint with commissioner -- Commissioner's power to investigate and resolve complaints -- Suspension of license for noncompliance with subpoena -- Petition to court for enforcement. </catch_line><order_by>11-055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person aggrieved by the conduct of a licensee or agent under this subtitle in connection with the licensee's or agent's regulated activities may file a written complaint with the commissioner, who may investigate the complaint. </section><section prefix="2">In the course of the investigation initiated by a complaint or by the commissioner, the commissioner may: <section prefix="a">Subpoena witnesses; </section><section prefix="b">Administer oaths; </section><section prefix="c">Examine any individual under oath; and </section><section prefix="d">Compel the production of records, books, papers, contracts, or other documents relevant to the investigation. </section></section><section prefix="3">If any person fails to testify or to comply with a subpoena from the commissioner under this section, then the commissioner may petition the Franklin Circuit Court or any court of competent jurisdiction for enforcement. </section><section prefix="4">The license of any licensee or the designation of an agent under this subtitle who fails to comply with a subpoena of the commissioner may be suspended pending compliance with the subpoena. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner may investigate all complaints filed by any person. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 856, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 28, effective April, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was created in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 as a new section of KRS Chapter 366A. Sec. 38 of that same bill also required that all sections of KRS Chapters 287, 288, 290, 291, 294, 366, 366A, and 368 be renumbered as sections of a single KRS chapter entitled the "Kentucky Financial Services Code." Therefore, the Statute Reviser, acting under KRS 7.136(1), has codified this section as a new section of KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14971</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>