<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.210</section_number><catch_line>Retailer's powers to collect from purchaser -- Separate display of tax -- Taxes collected constitute debt to Commonwealth. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the tax shall be required to be collected by the retailer from the purchaser. The tax shall be displayed separately from the sales price, the price advertised in the premises, the marked price, or other price on the sales receipt or other proof of sales. </section><section prefix="2">The department may relieve certain retailers from the provisions of subsection (1) of this section of separate display of the tax when the circumstances of the retailer make compliance impracticable. If the retailer establishes to the satisfaction of the department that the sales tax has been added to the total amount of the sales price and has not been absorbed by the retailer, the amount of the sales price shall be the amount received exclusive of the tax imposed. </section><section prefix="3">The taxes collected under this section shall be deemed to be held in trust by the retailer for and on account of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The taxes to be collected under this section shall constitute a debt of the retailer to the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 6, effective August 1, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 5, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 410, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 9, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 21, effective February 5, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>