<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="346" order_by="346">COMPENSATION OF CRIME VICTIMS </unit></structure><section_number>346.030</section_number><catch_line>Crime Victims Compensation Board. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a board, to be known as the Crime Victims Compensation Board. The board shall consist of five (5) members, not all of whom shall be engaged in the same occupation or profession, at least one (1) of whom shall be a victim as defined in KRS 421.500(1) or a victim advocate as defined in KRS 421.570(1), and the board shall be appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">The term of office of each such member shall be four (4) years, except that of the members first appointed two (2) shall serve for terms of four (4) years, two (2) shall serve for terms of three (3) years and one (1) shall serve for a term of two (2) years, respectively. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring otherwise than by expiration of a term shall be appointed for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor shall designate one (1) member of the board as chairman thereof, to serve as such at the pleasure of the Governor. </section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall establish the compensation of the members of the board pursuant to the provisions of KRS 64.640. </section><section prefix="5">Each new board member shall receive training on the dynamics of domestic violence, child abuse, sexual assault, homicide, and other violent crimes and the criminal justice process. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 36, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32694</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>