<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.410</section_number><catch_line>General powers of Department of Highways as to turnpike projects. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>The department is hereby authorized and empowered: <section prefix="1">To construct, reconstruct, maintain, repair, operate, regulate and police turnpike projects at such locations within the Commonwealth as may be determined by the department and approved by the Governor; </section><section prefix="2">To acquire sites abutting on any turnpike project, and to construct or contract for the construction of buildings and appurtenances for service stations, garages, restaurants and other services and to lease the same to others for any of such purposes (or, if leases cannot be made on acceptable terms, to operate any and all of the same) in such manner and under such terms as the department may determine; </section><section prefix="3">To issue turnpike revenue bonds of the Commonwealth, payable solely from the tolls, revenues and other funds pledged for their payment, for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any one (1) or more turnpike projects, and to refund any of its bonds, all as provided in KRS 177.390 to 177.570; </section><section prefix="4">To fix and revise from time to time and charge and collect tolls for transit over each turnpike project constructed by it; </section><section prefix="5">To combine for financing purposes any two (2) or more turnpike projects; </section><section prefix="6">To establish rules and regulations for the use of any turnpike project; </section><section prefix="7">To acquire, hold and dispose of real and personal property in the exercise of its powers and the performance of its duties under KRS 177.390 to 177.570, without reference to KRS Chapter 56; </section><section prefix="8">To designate the locations and establish, limit and control such points of ingress and egress from each turnpike project as the department may determine to be necessary or desirable in the judgment of the department to insure the proper operation and maintenance of such project, and to prohibit entrance to such project from any point or points not so designated; </section><section prefix="9">To make and enter into all contracts and agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties and the execution of its powers under KRS 177.390 to 177.570; </section><section prefix="10">To employ consulting engineers, attorneys, accountants, construction and financial experts, superintendents, managers, and such other employees and agents as may be necessary in its judgment, and to fix their compensation; </section><section prefix="11">To receive and accept from any federal agency grants for or in aid of the construction of any turnpike project, and to receive and accept aid or contributions from any source of either money, property, labor or other things of value, to be held, used and applied only for the purposes for which such grants and contributions may be made; </section><section prefix="12">To expend any funds provided under the authority of KRS 177.390 to 177.570 in advertising the facilities and services of a turnpike project or projects to the traveling public; and </section><section prefix="13">To do all acts and things necessary or convenient to carry out the powers expressly granted in KRS 177.390 to 177.570. </section></text><history>Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 3, effective March 25, 1960. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1960 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5327</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>