<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.810</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 158.810 to 158.816. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text>For purposes of KRS 158.810 to 158.816: <section prefix="1">"Advanced manufacturing" means manufacturing that uses technology and knowledge-based processes that leverage human, intellectual, and financial capital to create globally competitive products; </section><section prefix="2">"At-risk" means a student who is academically unprepared, has inadequate academic preparation for the next educational level, or who is in danger of dropping out of school; </section><section prefix="3">"Career academy" means a small learning community within a larger high school that: <section prefix="a">Consists of a heterogeneous group of students taking classes together for at least two (2) years who are taught by a team of teachers from different disciplines; </section><section prefix="b">Provides a college-preparatory academic curriculum based on a career theme that helps students see relationships and connections between academic subjects and their applications in specific career pathways and in broad career areas such as health science, business, pre-engineering, agribusiness, and advanced manufacturing; and </section><section prefix="c">Provides opportunities through partnerships with employers, colleges, and the community for students to engage in internships and work-based learning with adult mentors to motivate students to achieve; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Career and technical education" means a program of study that leads to the development of academic and specialized occupational skills in career fields; </section><section prefix="5">"Career guidance coach" means a counselor who is assigned one hundred percent (100%) of his or her time to: <section prefix="a">The development of students', teachers', and parents' understanding of broad career themes and opportunities through career pathways; </section><section prefix="b">Academic advising and career counseling; </section><section prefix="c">Assisting students in the development of individual learning plans; and </section><section prefix="d">Providing assistance to other teachers; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Career pathway" means a coherent, articulated sequence of rigorous academic and career-related courses, commencing in ninth grade and leading to an associate degree, an industry-recognized certificate or license, or a baccalaureate or higher degree. A career pathway is developed, implemented, and maintained in partnership among secondary and postsecondary education institutions, businesses, and employers. Career pathways are available to all students, including adult learners, and are designed to lead to rewarding careers; </section><section prefix="7">"Career pathway program of study" means a coherent, articulated sequence of rigorous academic and career and technical education courses, including dual credit opportunities, that prepares secondary students for postsecondary study leading to postsecondary degrees, industry certifications, or licensure; </section><section prefix="8">"Evidence-based instructional model" or "evidence-based model" means the application of valid and relevant knowledge to education activities and programs, which are based on the findings from systematic and empirical methods including observations, experiments, and rigorous data analyses; </section><section prefix="9">"Industry certification" means certification that is awarded to a student who has passed a standardized, valid, industry-based examination that measures the knowledge and skills recognized nationally by employers or by an industry group or association within Kentucky as representing the level of proficiency that is needed to enter a specific field; </section><section prefix="10">"Technical literacy" means a student's ability to read and comprehend the language of a field of study, understand the major technical concepts of that field, and apply the appropriate mathematics concepts to typical problems encountered in the workplace; </section><section prefix="11">"Secondary area technology center" or "secondary area center" means a school facility dedicated to the primary purpose of offering five (5) or more technical preparation programs that lead to skill development focused on specific occupational areas. An area center may be called a "magnet technology center" or "career center" or may be assigned another working title by the parent agency. An area center may be either state or locally operated; and </section><section prefix="12">"Career and technical education department" means a portion of a school facility that has five (5) or more technical preparation programs that lead to skill development focused on specific occupational areas. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 2, effective April 19, 2012. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> April 19, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40071</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>