<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.31-020</section_number><catch_line>Annual incentive cap established -- Requirements for qualification for incentives -- Maximum incentives available to an approved company. </catch_line><order_by>31-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The maximum amount of sales and use tax incentives that may be committed in each fiscal year by the authority shall be capped at twenty million dollars ($20,000,000) for building and construction materials, and five million dollars ($5,000,000) for equipment used for research and development or electronic processing. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">To qualify for the sales and use tax incentives available under this subchapter, an eligible company shall make a minimum investment of at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) in an economic development project, including the cost of land, but excluding the cost of labor. </section><section prefix="b">To qualify for the sales and use tax incentive available under this subchapter for electronic processing equipment, in addition to the requirements of paragraph (a) of this subsection, the eligible company shall spend an aggregate amount of at least fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) on electronic processing equipment installed as part of the economic development project. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The maximum sales and use tax incentive available to an approved company under this subchapter is the total amount of sales and use tax paid on purchases made on the following items, up to the approved recovery amount after approval by the authority: <section prefix="1">Building and construction materials; </section><section prefix="2">Research and development equipment; and </section><section prefix="3">Electronic processing equipment. </section></section><section prefix="b">An approved company may qualify for a sales and use tax incentive in more than one (1) category listed in paragraph (a) of this subsection for the same economic development project. If the authority approves an eligible company to receive the sales and use tax incentives in more than one (1) category, the authority shall allocate the incentives to the appropriate cap established by subsection (2) of this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 21, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>