<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.706</section_number><catch_line>Ethics education manual for legislators. </catch_line><order_by>706</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The ethics education manual shall include, but not be limited to, ethics statutes, administrative regulations, explanations of purposes and principles underlying the laws, explanations of technical and specific legal requirements, examples of practical applications of the laws and principles, a questions-and-answers section regarding common problems and situations, summaries of advisory opinions, and any other information which would inform legislators about the required standards of conduct and assist them in applying those standards to specific situations. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall provide for the distribution of the manual to legislators. The commission shall distribute the first manual no later than one hundred twenty (120) days after appointment of the commission. On or before January 1, 1995, the commission shall distribute a supplement including, but not limited to, updates, additions, and revisions. Thereafter, the commission shall distribute revised and updated versions of the manual on or before January 1 of each odd-numbered year. </section><section prefix="3">Copies of the manual shall be made available to the public for a reasonable fee, not to exceed the actual cost, but not including the cost of staff required. </section></text><history>Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 34, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>