<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.655</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees -- Conflict of interest. </catch_line><order_by>655</order_by><text>No trustee or employee of the Kentucky Retirement Systems board shall: <section prefix="1">Have any interest, direct or indirect, in the gains or profits of any investment or transaction made by the board, save insofar as any such trustee or employee may be a member, employee, or beneficiary of the retirement system; </section><section prefix="2">Directly or indirectly, for himself or as an agent, use the assets of the retirement system, except to make current and necessary payments authorized by the board; </section><section prefix="3">Become an indorser or surety or in any manner an obligor for moneys loaned by or borrowed from the board; </section><section prefix="4">Have a contract or agreement with the retirement system, individually or through a business owned by the trustee or the employee; </section><section prefix="5">Use his or her official position with the retirement system to obtain a financial gain or benefit or advantage for himself or herself or a family member; </section><section prefix="6">Use confidential information acquired during his or her tenure with the retirement system to further his or her own economic interests or that of another person; or </section><section prefix="7">Hold outside employment with, or accept compensation from, any person or business with which he or she has involvement as part of his or her official position with the retirement system. The provisions of this subsection shall not prohibit a trustee from serving as an employee of an agency participating in one (1) of the systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 9, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 50. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 30. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40001</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>