<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.550</section_number><catch_line>Hemophilia treatment program. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs shall establish a Hemophilia Treatment Program within the commission for the detection, diagnosis and treatment of persons suffering from hemophilia. The Hemophilia Treatment Program shall assist those persons who require continuing treatment with blood, blood derivatives, or a manufactured pharmaceutical product to avoid crippling, hospitalization, or other effects associated with hemophilia, but who are unable to pay for the entire cost of such services on a continuing basis. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall also initiate activities with the advice of the Hemophilia Advisory Committee to: <section prefix="a">Develop standards for determining eligibility for the care and treatment of persons suffering from hemophilia; </section><section prefix="b">Assist in the development and expansion of programs for the diagnosis and treatment of hemophilia and related diseases including but not limited to home care and medical and dental procedures designed to provide maximum control over bleeding; </section><section prefix="c">Provide financial assistance either directly or indirectly to persons suffering from hemophilia for the purpose of obtaining blood, blood derivatives and concentrates, and other efficacious agents for use in hospital, medical and dental facilities as well as in the home; </section><section prefix="d">Provide for community educational programs for the detection of hemophilia and for the counseling of individuals and families suffering from hemophilia; and </section><section prefix="e">Conduct educational programs for physicians, dentists, hospitals, health departments, and the public concerning the methods of detection, diagnosis and treatment of persons who have hemophilia. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted and amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 211.750. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7312</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>