<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 17.500 to 17.580. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>As used in KRS 17.500 to 17.580: <section prefix="1">"Approved provider" means a mental health professional licensed or certified in Kentucky whose scope of practice includes providing mental health treatment services and who is approved by the Sex Offender Risk Assessment Advisory Board, under administrative regulations promulgated by the board, to provide comprehensive sex offender presentence evaluations or treatment to adults and youthful offenders, as defined in KRS 600.020; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, "criminal offense against a victim who is a minor" means any of the following offenses if the victim is under the age of eighteen (18) at the time of the commission of the offense: <section prefix="1">Kidnapping, as set forth in KRS 509.040, except by a parent; </section><section prefix="2">Unlawful imprisonment, as set forth in KRS 509.020, except by a parent; </section><section prefix="3">Sex crime; </section><section prefix="4">Promoting a sexual performance of a minor, as set forth in KRS 531.320; </section><section prefix="5">Human trafficking involving commercial sexual activity, as set forth in KRS 529.100; </section><section prefix="6">Promoting prostitution, as set forth in KRS 529.040, when the defendant advances or profits from the prostitution of a person under the age of eighteen (18); </section><section prefix="7">Use of a minor in a sexual performance, as set forth in KRS 531.310; </section><section prefix="8">Sexual abuse, as set forth in KRS 510.120 and 510.130; </section><section prefix="9">Unlawful transaction with a minor in the first degree, as set forth in KRS 530.064(1)(a); </section><section prefix="10">Any offense involving a minor or depictions of a minor, as set forth in KRS Chapter 531; </section><section prefix="11">Any attempt to commit any of the offenses described in subparagraphs 1. to 10. of this paragraph; and </section><section prefix="12">Solicitation to commit any of the offenses described in subparagraphs 1. to 10. of this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="b">Conduct which is criminal only because of the age of the victim shall not be considered a criminal offense against a victim who is a minor if the perpetrator was under the age of eighteen (18) at the time of the commission of the offense; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Law enforcement agency" means any lawfully organized investigative agency, sheriff's office, police unit, or police force of federal, state, county, urban-county government, charter county, city, consolidated local government, or a combination of these, responsible for the detection of crime and the enforcement of the general criminal federal or state laws; </section><section prefix="5">"Registrant" means: <section prefix="a">Any person eighteen (18) years of age or older at the time of the offense or any youthful offender, as defined in KRS 600.020, who has committed: <section prefix="1">A sex crime; or </section><section prefix="2">A criminal offense against a victim who is a minor; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Any person required to register under KRS 17.510; or </section><section prefix="c">Any sexually violent predator; or </section><section prefix="d">Any person whose sexual offense has been diverted pursuant to KRS 533.250, until the diversionary period is successfully completed; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Registrant information" means the name, including any lawful name change together with the previous name, Social Security number, age, race, sex, date of birth, height, weight, hair and eye color, fingerprints, DNA sample, a photograph, aliases used, residence, electronic mail address and any instant messaging, chat, or other Internet communication name identities, a brief description of the crime or crimes committed, and other information the cabinet determines, by administrative regulation, may be useful in the identification of registrants; </section><section prefix="7">"Residence" means any place where a person sleeps. For the purposes of this statute, a registrant may have more than one (1) residence. A registrant is required to register each residence address; </section><section prefix="8">"Sex crime" means: <section prefix="a">A felony offense defined in KRS Chapter 510, or KRS 530.020, 530.064(1)(a), 531.310, 531.320, or 531.335; </section><section prefix="b">A felony attempt to commit a felony offense specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection; or </section><section prefix="c">A federal felony offense, a felony offense subject to a court-martial of the United States Armed Forces, or a felony offense from another state or a territory where the felony offense is similar to a felony offense specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Sexual offender" means any person convicted of, pleading guilty to, or entering an Alford plea to a sex crime as defined in this section, as of the date the verdict is entered by the court; </section><section prefix="10">"Sexually violent predator" means any person who has been subjected to involuntary civil commitment as a sexually violent predator, or a similar designation, under a state, territory, or federal statutory scheme; </section><section prefix="11">"The board" means the Sex Offender Risk Assessment Advisory Board created under KRS 17.554; </section><section prefix="12">"Victim" has the same meaning as in KRS 421.500; </section><section prefix="13">"DNA sample" or "deoxyribonucleic acid sample" means a blood or swab specimen from a person, as prescribed by administrative regulation, that is required to provide a DNA sample pursuant to KRS 17.170 or 17.510, that shall be submitted to the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory for law enforcement identification purposes and inclusion in law enforcement identification databases; and </section><section prefix="14">"Authorized personnel" means an agent of state government who is properly trained in DNA sample collection pursuant to administrative regulation. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 4, effective March 27, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 12, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 8, effective June 26, 2007; ch. 29, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 99, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 15, effective April 11, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43380</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>