<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.430</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility of applicants -- Contract to practice. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be eligible for a scholarship made available under KRS 211.405 to 211.460, an applicant must: <section prefix="a">Have been a resident of this Commonwealth for not less than five (5) years immediately preceding the date of application; </section><section prefix="b">Be acceptable for enrollment in a dental school accredited by the Council on Dental Education of the American Dental Association, and approved by the board; and </section><section prefix="c">Furnish satisfactory evidence to the board that he does not have sufficient financial resources to enable him to study dentistry without assistance. </section></section><section prefix="2">Before a scholarship is granted, the applicant shall contract in writing with the board, that he will, within six (6) months from the date he completes his term of study, engage in the practice of dentistry in a locality or localities within this Commonwealth to be designated by the Dental Health Program of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, at the rate of one (1) year for each annual scholarship received, or proportional time for partial scholarships. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 358, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 302, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 231, sec. 2; and ch. 365, sec. 2. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 4, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8402</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>