<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.330</section_number><catch_line>Functions and powers of council. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The council is vested with the following functions and powers: <section prefix="a">To prescribe standards for the approval and continuation of approval of schools at which law enforcement and telecommunications training courses required under KRS 15.310 to 15.510, 15.530 to 15.590, and 15.990 to 15.992 shall be conducted, including but not limited to minimum standards for facilities, faculty, curriculum, and hours of attendance related thereto; </section><section prefix="b">To prescribe minimum qualifications for instructors at such schools, except that institutions of higher education shall be exempt from council requirements; </section><section prefix="c">To prescribe qualifications for attendance and conditions for expulsion from such schools; </section><section prefix="d">To prescribe minimum standards and qualifications for voluntary career development programs for certified peace officers and telecommunicators, including minimum standards for experience, education, and training, and to issue certificates to those meeting the minimum standards; </section><section prefix="e">To approve, to issue, and to revoke for cause certificates to schools and instructors as having met requirements under KRS 15.310 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="f">To approve law enforcement officers, telecommunicators, and other persons as having met requirements under KRS 15.310 to 15.510, 15.530 to 15.590, and 15.990 to 15.992; </section><section prefix="g">To inspect and evaluate schools at any time and to require of schools, instructors, and persons approved or to be approved under the provisions of KRS 15.310 to 15.510, 15.530 to 15.590, and 15.990 to 15.992, any information or documents; </section><section prefix="h">To promulgate reasonable rules and administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to accomplish the purposes of KRS 15.310 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="i">To monitor the Law Enforcement Foundation Program as prescribed in KRS 15.410 to 15.510; </section><section prefix="j">To adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business not otherwise provided for; and </section><section prefix="k">The council shall have the authority to certify police officers as set out in this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 15.310 to 15.510, 15.530 to 15.590, and 15.990 to 15.992 do not apply to the Department of Kentucky State Police except for the certification requirement established by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 19, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 139, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 117, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 32. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> ((6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 139, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>