<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.050</section_number><catch_line>General election laws to govern election of city officers unless changed by ordinance.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Election of city officers shall be governed by general election laws as provided in KRS Chapters 116 through 121 unless the city legislative body prescribes by ordinance that election of city officers shall be under nonpartisan city election laws as provided in KRS 83A.045, 83A.170, 83A.175 and 83A.047. The ordinance shall become effective not later than twenty-three (23) days prior to the date prescribed by the election law generally for filing notification and declaration forms with the county clerk in a year in which a regular election is to be held in which any city office is to be filled. Immediately subsequent to publication of any ordinance prescribing that election of city officers be under nonpartisan city election laws, a copy of that ordinance shall be filed with the county clerk of the county in which the city is located. </section><section prefix="2">A city may change the manner of election of city officers within the provisions of subsection (1) of this section by ordinance, except that no change shall be made earlier than five (5) years from the last change. </section><section prefix="3">The city shall pay the costs of city elections only if city elections are held at a time other than prescribed by KRS Chapters 116 to 121. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 15, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective March 2, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>