<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.800</section_number><catch_line>Courts of inquiry.   </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Courts of inquiry to investigate any matter of concern to the state military forces may be convened by any person authorized to convene a general court-martial, whether or not the persons involved have requested an inquiry. </section><section prefix="2">A court of inquiry consists of three (3) or more commissioned officers. For each court of inquiry the convening authority shall also appoint counsel for the court. </section><section prefix="3">Any person subject to this code whose conduct is subject to inquiry shall be designated as a party. Any person subject to this code who has a direct interest in the subject of inquiry has the right to be designated as a party upon request to the court. Any person designated as a party shall be given due notice and shall have the right to be present, to be represented by counsel, to cross-examine witnesses, and to introduce evidence. </section><section prefix="4">Members of a court of inquiry may be challenged by a party, but only for cause stated to the court. </section><section prefix="5">The members, counsel, the reporter, and interpreters of courts of inquiry shall take an oath or affirmation to faithfully perform their duties. </section><section prefix="6">Witnesses may be summoned to appear and testify and be examined before courts of inquiry, as provided for courts-martial. </section><section prefix="7">Courts of inquiry shall make findings of fact but shall not express opinions or make recommendations unless required to do so by the convening authority. </section><section prefix="8">Each court of inquiry shall keep a record of its proceedings, which shall be authenticated by the signatures of the president and counsel for the court and forwarded to the convening authority. If the record cannot be authenticated by the president it shall be signed by a member in lieu of the president. If the record cannot be authenticated by the counsel for the court it shall be signed by a member in lieu of the counsel. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 139, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 52. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 74, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 35.375. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>