<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-042</section_number><catch_line>Termination or refusal to issue insurance due to credit history prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>20-042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No insurer shall decline to issue, cancel, nonrenew, or otherwise terminate property and casualty insurance contracts covering personal risks solely because of credit history, lack of credit history, or the following extraordinary life circumstances that directly influence the credit history of the applicant or insured: <section prefix="a">Catastrophic event, as declared by the federal or state government; </section><section prefix="b">Serious illness or injury, or serious illness or injury to an immediate family member; </section><section prefix="c">Death of a spouse, child, or parent; </section><section prefix="d">Divorce or involuntary interruption of legally owed alimony or support payments; </section><section prefix="e">Identity theft; </section><section prefix="f">Temporary loss of employment for a period of three (3) months or more, if it results from involuntary termination; </section><section prefix="g">Military deployment overseas; or </section><section prefix="h">Other events, as determined by the insurer. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section, "personal risks" shall have the meaning as defined in KRS 304.13-011. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 540, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>