<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="405" order_by="405">PARENT AND CHILD </unit></structure><section_number>405.490</section_number><catch_line>Answer to order to withhold -- Procedure for obligor to contest amount of delinquent support withheld. </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person, including the obligor, who has been served with an order to withhold and deliver the obligor's property shall answer the order within twenty (20) days. </section><section prefix="2">The person in possession of any obligor's property shall withhold it and deliver it to the cabinet in accordance with the secretary's directions; or the obligor may offer a bond which is satisfactory to the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The person in possession of obligor's property shall have no liability or further responsibility after fulfilling the duties under this section. </section><section prefix="4">The obligor may dispute the amount of delinquent support by requesting a dispute hearing with twenty (20) days. </section><section prefix="5">If the obligor does not request a hearing, acknowledgment of the obligation is presumed and the secretary may apply the withheld property to the delinquent child support obligation. </section><section prefix="6">If a hearing is requested, when property or a bond is released to the secretary pursuant to an order to withhold and deliver property, the secretary shall hold the property or bond, pending determination of the obligor's liability by a hearing officer, pursuant to KRS 405.450. </section><section prefix="7">Upon a decision adverse to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services by a hearing officer, of the Circuit Court on appeal, the cabinet shall return the property together with interest at the legal rate for judgments. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 635, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 586, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>