<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.800</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 365.800 to 365.840.   </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text>As used in KRS 365.800 to 365.840, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Current net price on parts" means the price listed by a supplier in a price list or catalogue in effect at the time a retail agreement contract is terminated, less any applicable trade and cash discounts; </section><section prefix="2">"Retailer" means any person, firm, or corporation, including heirs, personal representatives, guardians, trustees, assignees, or receivers of the person, firm, or corporation, engaged in the business of selling and retailing inventory, but shall not include retailers of petroleum or motor vehicle and related automotive care and replacement products; </section><section prefix="3">"Inventory" means farm implements, tractors, farm machinery, consumer products, utility and industrial equipment, construction and excavating equipment, and any attachments, repair parts, or superseded parts for the equipment; </section><section prefix="4">"Net cost" means the price a retailer paid for the inventory to a supplier, less all discounts allowed; </section><section prefix="5">"Consumer products" means machines designed for or adapted and used for horticulture, floriculture, landscaping, grounds maintenance, or turf maintenance, including but not limited to lawnmowers, rototillers, trimmers, blowers, and other equipment used in both residential and commercial lawn, gardening, or turf maintenance, installation, or other applications; </section><section prefix="6">"Superseded parts" means any part that will provide the same function as a currently available part as of the date of termination of a retail agreement contract;  </section><section prefix="7">"Supplier" means any wholesaler, manufacturer, or distributor of inventory, or any purchaser of assets or stock of any surviving corporation resulting from a merger or liquidation, or any receiver, assignee, or trustee of the original wholesaler, manufacturer, distributor, or corporation; and </section><section prefix="8">"Terminate" or "termination" means cancel, fail to renew, or otherwise terminate a retail agreement contract. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 1, effective April 21, 2004. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective February 28, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42578</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>