<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.410</section_number><catch_line>How fee-bills made out -- Provisions concerning. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fee-bills of every officer shall be made out at length, in figures and in plain English, and signed by the officer in his official capacity.  </section><section prefix="2">No officer shall demand or receive for his services:  <section prefix="a">Any other or greater fee than is allowed by law;  </section><section prefix="b">Any fee for services rendered when the law has not fixed a compensation therefor;  </section><section prefix="c">Any fee for services not actually rendered.  </section></section><section prefix="3">Where there are more plaintiffs or defendants than one (1) in an action and they sever in their pleadings or otherwise, so that part of them cause an officer to render separate services for him or them, for which the others ought not to be liable, the fees for such services shall be charged separately to those for whom the service is rendered.  </section><section prefix="4">No officer in making out his fee-bill shall omit the name of any person properly chargeable therewith, or insert the name of a person not properly chargeable.  </section><section prefix="5">Fees against a person acting in a trust capacity shall be made out against him in such capacity and he shall only be liable therefor to the extent of the trust funds in his hands liable to the payment thereof.  </section><section prefix="6">No fee-bill shall be made out, or compensation allowed hereafter, for any ex officio services rendered by any officer.  </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1749. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23244</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>