<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.11-029</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance of records. </catch_line><order_by>11-029</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each licensee shall make, keep, and preserve the following books, accounts, and other records for a period of five (5) years, and these records shall be open to inspection by the commissioner: <section prefix="a">A record or records of each payment instrument sold; </section><section prefix="b">A general ledger containing all assets, liability, capital, income, and expense accounts, which general ledger shall be posted at least monthly; </section><section prefix="c">Bank statements and bank reconciliation records; </section><section prefix="d">Records of outstanding payment instruments; </section><section prefix="e">Records of each payment instrument paid within the five (5) year period; </section><section prefix="f">A list of the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of all of the licensee's agents; </section><section prefix="g">Copies of all currency transaction reports and suspicious activity reports filed in compliance with KRS 286.11-031; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other record the commissioner may reasonably require by order or regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">Records required to be maintained in this subtitle may be kept in an electronic retrievable format or other similar form of medium. </section><section prefix="3">Records may be maintained by a licensee or agent at a location other than within this state so long as they are made accessible to the commissioner upon seven (7) business days' written notice. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 843, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 15, effective April 24, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was created in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 as a new section of KRS Chapter 366A. Sec. 38 of that same bill also required that all sections of KRS Chapters 287, 288, 290, 291, 294, 366, 366A, and 368 be renumbered as sections of a single KRS chapter entitled the "Kentucky Financial Services Code." Therefore, the Statute Reviser, acting under KRS 7.136(1), has codified this section as a new section of KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>