<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="333" order_by="333">MEDICAL LABORATORIES </unit></structure><section_number>333.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>As used in this chapter unless the context clearly indicates otherwise, the following terms shall have the meanings set forth below: <section prefix="1">"Person" means any individual, firm, partnership, association, corporation, municipality, political subdivision, or any other entity whether organized for profit or not; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Medical laboratory" means any institution, building, place, or any other facility in which operations and procedures for the microbiological, serological, chemical, hematological, immunohematological, biophysical, cytological, pathological, or other methods of examination of tissues including blood, secretions, and excretions of the human body are performed to obtain information in diagnosing, preventing, or treating disease, or in which the results of any examination, determination, or test are used as a basis for health advice. These activities include the diagnosis and identification of disease by the examination of tissues removed by surgery and also the determination of cause of death by the examination of tissues removed at autopsy. The term "clinical laboratory" shall be deemed synonymous with the term "medical laboratory," and includes laboratories operated and maintained exclusively for teaching purposes; </section><section prefix="4">"Medical laboratory director" means the individual who is responsible for the administrative, scientific, and technical operation of the medical laboratory, including supervision of laboratory procedures, reporting of findings, and active participation to such extent as may be necessary to assure compliance with the law. He shall be responsible for the proper performance of all work in the laboratory and shall direct, supervise, and be responsible for the work of subordinates; </section><section prefix="5">"Medical laboratory supervisor" means an individual who, under the general supervision of a medical laboratory director, supervises technical personnel, performs tests requiring special scientific skills, experience, and educational background, and, in the absence of the director, is held responsible for the proper performance of all medical laboratory procedures and the reporting of results; </section><section prefix="6">"Medical laboratory technologist" means an individual who performs tests which require the exercise of independent judgment and responsibility, with minimal supervision by the director or supervisor, in only those specialties or subspecialties in which they are qualified by education, training, and experience; </section><section prefix="7">"Medical laboratory technician" means any individual other than the medical laboratory director, supervisor, technologist, or trainee who functions under the supervision of a medical laboratory director, supervisor, or technologist and performs only those medical laboratory procedures which require limited skill, responsibility, and a minimal exercise of independent judgment; </section><section prefix="8">"Medical laboratory trainee" means any individual in a medical laboratory who is seeking training and experience which, combined with the appropriate educational background, will qualify that person for employment as a "medical technologist" or "medical laboratory technician." Trainees may perform procedures under the direct supervision of the laboratory director, supervisor, or medical technologist; </section><section prefix="9">"Medical laboratory personnel" includes the medical laboratory director, supervisor, technologist, or technician, but does not include medical laboratory assistants, trainees, or other individuals employed by a medical laboratory to perform clerical or other administrative responsibilities; </section><section prefix="10">"Medical laboratory evaluation program" means a program for evaluating the proficiency of medical laboratories by the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="11">"Medical laboratory advisory committee" shall mean a group of consultants appointed by the secretary for health and family services or his designee to advise the cabinet on matters relating to the regulation of medical laboratories. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 602, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 553, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 93; and ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(2). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31841</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>