<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="68" order_by="68">COUNTY FINANCE AND COUNTY TREASURER </unit></structure><section_number>68.606</section_number><catch_line>Administration of district -- Board of trustees. </catch_line><order_by>606</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A district shall be administered by the fiscal court of the county creating it, which shall control and manage the affairs of the district. The fiscal court may, by a majority vote of its members, establish a board of trustees to control and manage the affairs of the district. </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees created under subsection (1) of this section shall operate in accordance with the following: <section prefix="a">The term of office of each trustee shall be four (4) years except as specified. The board shall consist of four (4) members who shall be appointed by the county judge/executive, with the approval of the fiscal court. Initial appointments shall be for terms of one (1), two (2), three (3), and four (4) years, as designated by the county judge/executive. Thereafter, each successor shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. No more than three (3) members of the board shall be members of the same political party. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall elect its chairman from among its members. The board may appoint a secretary, an executive director, and other officials and employees who need not be members of the board. Members of the board shall not receive compensation for their services, but shall be reimbursed for their actual expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. A quorum for the transacting of the business of the board shall consist of three (3) members. </section><section prefix="c">A member of the board may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </section></section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24117</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>