<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.265</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Equine Drug Research Council. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">There is hereby created a panel, to be known as the Kentucky Equine Drug Research Council, to advise the racing commission on the conduct of equine drug research and testing commissioned by the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission. </section><section prefix="b">The council shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor. It is recommended that the Governor appoint one (1) person from each of the following groups, organizations, or professions: <section prefix="1">A veterinarian, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Association of Equine Veterinarians; </section><section prefix="2">A horseman, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky division of the Horsemen's Benevolent and Protective Association; </section><section prefix="3">A pharmacologist, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">A Thoroughbred breeder, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Thoroughbred Owners and Breeders, Inc.; </section><section prefix="5">A legislator, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Legislative Research Commission; </section><section prefix="6">A representative of a licensed racing association, chosen by the Governor; </section><section prefix="7">A member of the harness racing industry, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the chairman of the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission; </section><section prefix="8">A member selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Harness Horsemen's Association; and </section><section prefix="9">A member of the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission, selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the chairman of the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission, to serve as chairman. </section></section><section prefix="c">The council shall meet at the call of the chairman, a majority of the council, or at the request of the racing commission. Members shall serve at the pleasure of their respective sponsoring organizations and shall receive no compensation for serving. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Equine Drug Research Council shall: <section prefix="a">Review equine drug research and testing research being conducted at the University of Kentucky, or with state funds; </section><section prefix="b">Review and report to the racing commission on drug research and testing research being conducted elsewhere; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the racing commission and make recommendations for establishing an effective drug regulatory policy for Kentucky racing; and </section><section prefix="d">Report to the General Assembly any needed changes regarding the regulation of drugs in horse racing in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The funds received by the racing commission pursuant to KRS 138.510 shall be used for financing: <section prefix="1">Drug research; </section><section prefix="2">Testing research; </section><section prefix="3">Equine medical research; </section><section prefix="4">Equine health research issues; and </section><section prefix="5">Any regulatory or administrative activity of the racing commission that is related to the research and issues described in subparagraphs 1. to 4. of this paragraph. Any expenditure under this subsection shall relate to the racing industry in Kentucky.  </section></section><section prefix="b">In authorizing expenditures, the council and the racing commission shall give funding priority to the activities described in this subsection which will take place, or are proposed to take place, in Kentucky over similar activities taking place outside Kentucky. However, expenditures under this subsection in furtherance of activities taking place outside Kentucky may be approved if the council and the racing commission determine that those expenditures will contribute to improvement in Kentucky's racing industry and to the development of a useful knowledge base relating to the subjects expressed in paragraph (a)1. to 5. of this subsection. </section><section prefix="c">The money received under this subsection shall be in addition to any funds appropriated to the racing commission for these purposes in the executive budget. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 451, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 110, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 42, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 17, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 7, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>