<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVII" order_by="37">SPECIAL PROCEEDINGS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="416" order_by="416">EMINENT DOMAIN </unit></structure><section_number>416.560</section_number><catch_line>Initiation of condemnation proceedings -- Costs -- Right of entry -- Damages. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of the law, a department, instrumentality or agency of a consolidated local government, city, county, or urban-county government, other than a waterworks corporation the capital stock of which is wholly owned by a city of the first class or a consolidated local government, having a right of eminent domain under other statutes shall exercise such right only by requesting the governing body of the consolidated local government, city, county, or urban-county to institute condemnation proceedings on its behalf. If the governing body of the consolidated local government, city, county, or urban-county agrees, it shall institute such proceedings under KRS 416.570, and all costs involved in the condemnation shall be borne by the department, instrumentality, or agency requesting the condemnation. </section><section prefix="2">If any department, instrumentality, or agency of a consolidated local government, city, county, or urban-county government, other than a waterworks corporation the capital stock of which is wholly owned by a city of the first class or a consolidated local government, operates in more than one (1) governmental unit, it shall request the governing body of the consolidated local government, city, county, or urban-county government wherein the largest part of the individual tract of the property sought to be condemned lies, to institute condemnation proceedings on its behalf. </section><section prefix="3">A department, instrumentality, or agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, other than the Transportation Cabinet and local boards of education, having a right of eminent domain under other statutes shall exercise such right only by requesting the Finance and Administration Cabinet to institute condemnation proceedings on its behalf. If the Finance and Administration Cabinet agrees, it shall institute such proceedings under KRS 416.570, and all costs involved in the condemnation shall be borne by the department, instrumentality, or agency requesting the condemnation. </section><section prefix="4">Prior to the filing of the petition to condemn, the condemnor or its employees or agents shall have the right to enter upon any land or improvement which it has the power to condemn, in order to make studies, surveys, tests, sounding, and appraisals, provided that the owner of the land or the party in whose name the property is assessed has been notified ten (10) days prior to entry on the property. Any actual damages sustained by the owner of a property interest in the property entered upon by the condemnor shall be paid by the condemnor and shall be assessed by the court or the court may refer the matter to commissioners to ascertain and assess the damages sustained by the condemnee, which award shall be subject to appeal. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 230, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>