<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.220</section_number><catch_line>Payments, to whom made -- Accounting -- Exemption from assignment, levy or execution. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Payments of public assistance grants for eligible individuals shall be made at the time and in the manner prescribed by regulation to: <section prefix="a">The needy aged or needy blind or needy permanently and totally disabled person or recipient; or </section><section prefix="b">The parent or relative with whom a needy child lives; or </section><section prefix="c">The parent or legal guardian of a blind minor; or </section><section prefix="d">The legal guardian of (a) or (b) above; or </section><section prefix="e">Such other persons on behalf of an eligible person as may be prescribed by regulation; or </section><section prefix="f">Committees appointed by the court and approved for payment purposes by the secretary according to prescribed regulations. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person who is receiving and disbursing public assistance grants on behalf of another individual eligible under this chapter shall upon request make an accounting of such funds to the cabinet in accordance with regulations. If a public assistance grant made on behalf of a needy individual is not used for the benefit of such individual, such payment shall be suspended pending reasonable assurance that future grants will benefit the individual on whose behalf such payments are made. </section><section prefix="3">Public assistance shall not be assignable and shall be exempt from levy or execution. Furthermore, no assignment, pledge or encumbrance of any right to benefits due or payable under this chapter shall be valid. Public assistance benefits, as long as they are not mingled with other funds of the recipient, shall be exempt from any remedy for the collection of all debts, liens and encumbrances. No waiver of any exemption provided for in this subsection shall be valid. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 193, effective July 15, 1980. --Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21) and (29). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 7. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 5. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 3. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7661</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>