<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.125</section_number><catch_line>University programs. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The University of Kentucky shall provide: <section prefix="a">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, associate and baccalaureate programs of instruction; </section><section prefix="b">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, master degree programs, specialist degree programs above the master's-degree level, and joint doctoral programs in cooperation with other public postsecondary educational institutions in the state; </section><section prefix="c">Upon approval of the Council on Postsecondary Education, doctoral and post-doctoral programs and professional instruction including law, medicine, dentistry, education, architecture, engineering, and social professions. </section></section><section prefix="2">The University of Kentucky shall be the principal state institution for the conduct of statewide research and statewide service programs and shall be the primary institution authorized to expend state general fund appropriations on research and service programs of a statewide nature financed principally by state funds. As applied in this section, research and service programs of a statewide nature shall be programs requiring the establishment and operation of facilities or centers outside of the primary service area of the institution. In carrying out its statewide mission, the University of Kentucky shall conduct statewide research and provide statewide services including, but not limited to, agricultural research and extension services, industrial and scientific research, industrial technology extension services to Kentucky employers, and research related to the doctoral, professional, and post-doctoral programs offered within the university. The university may establish and operate centers and utilize state appropriations and other resources to carry out the necessary research and service activities throughout the state. The university may enter into joint research and service activities with other universities in order to accomplish its statewide mission. Nothing contained in this subsection shall limit the authority of the Council on Postsecondary Education to establish instructional programs that are consistent with the strategic agenda. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 85, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 108, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 3. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>