<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.355</section_number><catch_line>Information form for person who leaves infant -- Media campaign. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall make available standardized health, medical, and background information forms for use in gathering voluntary, nonidentifying information from a person who leaves an infant in accordance with KRS 405.075 and as required by KRS 216B.190 and 311.6526. The materials shall clearly state on each page that the information requested is designed to facilitate medical care for the infant. The material shall include information on family services, termination of parental rights, and adoption. The material shall also include: <section prefix="a">Information on the importance of medical and health information regarding the infant; and </section><section prefix="b">Written notification that failure to contact the Department for Community Based Services and assert a claim of parental rights within thirty (30) days of the receipt of the material shall result in the commencement of proceedings for involuntary termination of parental rights and placement of the child for adoption. </section></section><section prefix="2">Subject to available funding, the cabinet shall produce and distribute a media campaign to promote safe placement alternatives for newborn infants, the confidentiality offered to birth parents, and information regarding adoption procedures. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 6, effective April 9, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>