<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-874</section_number><catch_line>Recordkeeping system -- Receipt. </catch_line><order_by>50-874</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A recordkeeping system shall be implemented for a waste tire from the time it becomes a waste tire to the time it is disposed, recycled, or used as tire-derived fuel. </section><section prefix="2">A retailer, an automotive recycling dealer, and a person required to register as an accumulator, transporter, or processor who transfers waste tires to another person shall obtain a receipt for the waste tires. The final processor or a transporter who arranges for disposal or recycling out-of-state shall return a copy of the receipt for disposal or recycling to the retailer within thirty (30) days of receiving the waste tires. If the retailer does not receive the receipt from the final processor or transporter showing proof of who took final custody of the waste tires and disposed of the tires in accordance with KRS 224.50-856(1) and (2), the retailer shall notify the Division of Waste Management. </section><section prefix="3">A person filling out a receipt shall provide the following information: <section prefix="a">That person's name, address, company and signature; </section><section prefix="b">The number of waste tires or their passenger tire equivalents accepted; </section><section prefix="c">The date the waste tires were transferred; and </section><section prefix="d">The name and address of the person transferring the waste tires. </section></section><section prefix="4">A person who fills out a receipt shall keep a copy for three (3) years. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>