<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who, by himself or herself or acting through another, directly or indirectly, violates any of the provisions of KRS 243.020 to 243.670, for which no other penalty is provided, shall, for the first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; and for the second and each subsequent violation, he or she shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. The penalties provided for in this subsection shall be in addition to the revocation of the offender's license. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who, by himself or herself or through another, directly or indirectly, violates subsection (1) of KRS 243.020 shall, for the first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; for the second offense, he or she shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor; and for the third and each subsequent offense, he or she shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates subsection (3) of KRS 243.020 shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates KRS 243.620 with respect to a license issued under KRS 243.050 or 243.082 shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 243.720 or 243.730 or any regulation issued thereunder shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 243.710 to 243.850 shall be subject to the uniform civil penalties imposed pursuant to KRS 131.180. </section><section prefix="7">In every case, any tax imposed by KRS 243.710 to 243.720 which is not paid on or before the due date shall bear interest at the tax interest rate as defined in KRS 131.010(6) from the due date until the date of payment. </section><section prefix="8">Any person who, by himself or herself or acting through another, directly or indirectly, violates KRS 243.502(1) shall, for the first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor, and for the second and each subsequent violation, he or she shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. The penalties provided for in this subsection shall be in addition to the suspension or revocation of the offender's license. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 243.897 shall be subject to a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 80, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008; and ch. 83, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 24, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 463, sec. 31, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 30, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 24, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 186, Art. V, sec. 3, effective March 25, 1960. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 24; and ch. 173, sec. 14. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-150, 2554b-153, 2554b-195, 2554b-196, 2554b-219, 4214a-21, 4214a-22, 4281c-22, 4281c-27. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(9/1/92).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has changed an incorrect reference to KRS 243.030 contained in subsection (2) of this statute back to KRS 243.020. Apparently, a typographical error occurred in this reference in 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 24; however, the text as originally found in 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1 (KRS ch. 243, p. 24) referenced KRS 243.020, and subsequent amendments of the statute have not changed that reference. Cf. KRS 446.270 and 446.280. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42515</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>