<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="438" order_by="438">OFFENSES AGAINST PUBLIC HEALTH AND SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>438.280</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 438.280 to 438.290 </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text>As used in KRS 438.280 to 438.290: <section prefix="1">"Alarm system" means electronic equipment and devices designed to act as a personal emergency response system; </section><section prefix="2">"Personal emergency response system" means an alarm system that is: <section prefix="a">Installed in the residence of a customer; </section><section prefix="b">Monitored by an alarm systems company; </section><section prefix="c">Designed only to permit the customer to signal the occurrence of a medical or personal emergency on the part of the customer so that the personal emergency response system provider may dispatch appropriate aid; and </section><section prefix="d">Not part of a combination of alarm systems that includes a burglar alarm or fire alarm; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Personal emergency response system provider" means a person who sells, installs, services, monitors, or responds to a personal emergency response system, but shall not include: <section prefix="a">A 911 center, public safety answering point, or communications center; </section><section prefix="b">A public or private agency called by the 911 center, public safety answering point, or communications center to render aid or services to the customer who sent the alarm to the personal emergency response system provider; or </section><section prefix="c">Any person on the customer's contact list; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Customer" means both: <section prefix="a">The person in whose residence the personal emergency response system is installed; and </section><section prefix="b">The person with whom a personal emergency response system provider has contracted for the provision of personal emergency response services; and </section></section><section prefix="5">"Responder" means: <section prefix="a">A person, if any, designated by the customer; and </section><section prefix="b">The 911 center, public safety answering point, or communications center in the jurisdiction from which an alarm was received, that is to be called by the personal emergency response system provider in the event the customer requires aid from a responder. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, provides that KRS 438.280 to 438.290 "...shall be known and may be cited as the Christine Talley Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19098</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>