<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.180</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter. The cabinet may also promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to the requirements of Public Law 96-272 as to the maximum number of children who at any time during a fiscal year, will remain in foster care after having been in such care for a period in excess of twenty-four (24) months, together with the steps to be taken to achieve such goal. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to provide the following: <section prefix="a">The method used to periodically review the status of children placed in foster family homes which shall include, but not be limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Within five (5) days, exclusive of weekends and holidays, of the temporary removal hearing provided for in this chapter, a case conference shall be held on all children placed with the cabinet for the purpose of establishing a specific treatment plan which may include preventive and reunification services for the child and his parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision. Additional case conferences and reviews shall be held as appropriate, but shall be held at least every six (6) months. The parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision and his counsel, if any, shall have the right to be present at and participate in such conferences. The child; the child's attorney, if any; the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision and his attorney of record, if any; and the county attorney shall be notified of, and may be present at and participate in such conferences; </section><section prefix="2">On-going case work and supportive services shall be provided as indicated to best meet the needs of the child as established by the review and planning process; and </section><section prefix="3">There may be procedures for providing for appropriate visitation between the parents and the child based on the needs of the child; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The procedures for reporting to a committing court the status and plans for children committed to the cabinet as dependent, neglected or abused and placed in foster family homes. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 55, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 79, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20207</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>