<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.150</section_number><catch_line>Preference points for active or honorably or generally discharged members of the active military, military reserves, or National Guard -- Conditions under which spouses, surviving spouses, and dependent parents may receive preference points -- Identification on register certificate -- Required interviews. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who has served in the active military, military reserves, or National Guard and was discharged or released therefrom with an honorable discharge, discharge under honorable conditions, or a general discharge shall have five (5) points added to the veteran's entrance examination score for classified positions. Any current member of the active military, military reserves, or National Guard shall be entitled to the same number of points. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has served in the active military, military reserves, or National Guard and was discharged or released therefrom with an honorable discharge, discharge under honorable conditions, or a general discharge, whom the Veterans Administration or any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States determines has service-connected disabilities, shall have ten (10) points added to the veteran's entrance examination score for a classified position. </section><section prefix="3">The spouse of a person who has served in the active military, military reserves, or National Guard, was discharged or released therefrom with an honorable discharge, discharge under honorable conditions, or a general discharge, would be eligible for a ten (10) point preference, and whose service-connected disability disqualifies the veteran for positions along the general line of the veteran's usual occupation shall have ten (10) preference points added to the spouse's entrance examination score for a classified position. In such a case, the spouse loses the right to preference if the disabled veteran recovers. </section><section prefix="4">Until remarriage, the surviving spouse of a person who has served in the active military, military reserves, or National Guard and was discharged or released therefrom with an honorable discharge, discharge under honorable conditions, or a general discharge shall have ten (10) preference points added to the spouse's entrance examination score for a classified position. This includes the surviving spouse of any military personnel who died while in the Armed Forces, unless circumstances surrounding the death would have been cause for other than honorable or general discharge separation. </section><section prefix="5">A parent totally or partially dependent on a person who has served in the active military, military reserves, or National Guard and lost his or her life under honorable conditions while on active duty or active duty for training purposes or became permanently and totally disabled as a result of a service-connected disability shall have ten (10) preference points added to the parent's examination score for a classified position. </section><section prefix="6">The preference points granted by subsections (1) to (5) of this section shall be added to entrance examination scores for classified positions only if the score is determined by the secretary to be a passing score and after verification of the required service. The total of the entrance examination score and the preference points may exceed one hundred (100). </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">When a register certificate is transmitted to a state agency for employment consideration, that certificate shall clearly identify all individuals entitled to preference points under subsections (1) to (6) of this section, whether or not an examination is actually a part of the selection method. Regardless of the selection method used to fill a vacancy, these individuals shall be clearly identified. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">If the number of individuals identified in paragraph (a) of this subsection is less than five (5), the employing agency shall offer an interview to all individuals identified in paragraph (a) of this subsection, including individuals presently employed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky and applying for another classified position within state government. </section><section prefix="2">If the number of individuals identified in paragraph (a) of this subsection equals or exceeds five (5), the employing agency shall offer an interview to no fewer than five (5). </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.150, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 6, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 6; and ch. 386, sec. 1. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.212. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1378</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>