<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.050</section_number><catch_line>Area development districts created. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>There is hereby created and established in the Commonwealth fifteen (15) area development districts consisting of the following counties: <section prefix="1">Purchase Area Development District which shall include the counties of Ballard, Carlisle, Hickman, Fulton, McCracken, Graves, Marshall, and Calloway; </section><section prefix="2">Pennyrile Area Development District which shall include the counties of Livingston, Crittenden, Lyon, Caldwell, Hopkins, Muhlenberg, Trigg, Christian and Todd; </section><section prefix="3">Green River Area Development District which shall include the counties of Union, Henderson, Webster, McLean, Daviess, Ohio and Hancock; </section><section prefix="4">Barren River Area Development District which shall include the counties of Logan, Simpson, Butler, Warren, Edmonson, Hart, Barren, Allen, Metcalfe and Monroe; </section><section prefix="5">Lincoln Trail Area Development District which shall include the counties of Breckinridge, Meade, Grayson, Hardin, Larue, Nelson, Washington, and Marion; </section><section prefix="6">Jefferson Area Development District which shall include the counties of Bullitt, Henry, Jefferson, Oldham, Shelby, Spencer and Trimble; </section><section prefix="7">Northern Kentucky Area Development District which shall include the counties of Boone, Kenton, Campbell, Carroll, Gallatin, Owen, Grant and Pendleton; </section><section prefix="8">Buffalo Trace Area Development District which shall include the counties of Bracken, Mason, Robertson, Fleming and Lewis; </section><section prefix="9">Gateway Area Development District which shall include the counties of Rowan, Bath, Montgomery, Menifee, and Morgan; </section><section prefix="10">Fivco Area Development District which shall include the counties of Greenup, Boyd, Carter, Elliott, and Lawrence; </section><section prefix="11">Big Sandy Area Development District which shall include the counties of Johnson, Magoffin, Martin, Floyd, and Pike; </section><section prefix="12">Kentucky River Area Development District which shall include the counties of Wolfe, Owsley, Lee, Breathitt, Leslie, Perry, Knott, and Letcher; </section><section prefix="13">Cumberland Valley Area Development District which shall include the counties of Jackson, Rockcastle, Laurel, Clay, Knox, Whitley, Bell, and Harlan; </section><section prefix="14">Lake Cumberland Area Development District which shall include the counties of Taylor, Adair, Green, Casey, Russell, Pulaski, Clinton, Cumberland, Wayne, and McCreary; and </section><section prefix="15">Bluegrass Area Development District which shall include the counties of Anderson, Franklin, Woodford, Mercer, Boyle, Lincoln, Garrard, Jessamine, Fayette, Scott, Harrison, Bourbon, Nicholas, Clark, Madison, Powell, and Estill. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1652</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>