<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.540</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for law enforcement telecommunicator -- Information not subject to disclosure. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An agency hiring a telecommunicator after July 15, 2006, shall certify to the Department of Criminal Justice Training before admission to the telecommunicator training program that the telecommunicator: <section prefix="a">Is a citizen of the United States and has reached the age of majority; </section><section prefix="b">Is a high school graduate or has received a general equivalency diploma (GED); </section><section prefix="c">Has not been convicted of a felony or other crimes involving moral turpitude as determined by submission of each applicant's fingerprints to the information systems section of the Department of Kentucky State Police and to the Federal Bureau of Investigation identification division, and by such other investigations as required by the hiring agency; </section><section prefix="d">Has taken a psychological suitability screening administered or approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council to determine his or her suitability to perform the duties of a telecommunicator. Any agency that administers its own suitability screening shall certify the results to the department; </section><section prefix="e">Has taken a polygraph examination administered or approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council to determine his or her suitability to perform the duties of a telecommunicator. Any agency that administers its own polygraph examination shall certify the results to the department; and </section><section prefix="f">Has passed a drug screening administered or approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. A person shall be deemed to have passed a drug screening if the results are negative for the use of an illegal controlled substance or prescription drug abuse. Any agency that administers its own screening shall certify passing results to the department. </section></section><section prefix="2">Provisions of the Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884, to the contrary notwithstanding, the applicant's home address, telephone number, date of birth, Social Security number, and results of any background investigation, psychological suitability screening, and polygraph examination conducted under this section shall not be subject to disclosure. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 30, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=969</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>