<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">C RESTRUCTURE OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT IN COUNTY CONTAINING CITY OF FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>67C.143</section_number><catch_line>Removal of elected officers of consolidated local government -- Hearing -- Vote of council -- Appeal -- Vacancy. </catch_line><order_by>143</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless otherwise provided by law, any elected officer of a consolidated local government in case of misconduct, incapacity, or willful neglect in the performance of the duties of his or her office may be removed from office by the legislative council, sitting as a court, under oath, upon charges preferred by the mayor or by any five (5) members of the legislative council, or, in case of charges against the mayor, upon charges preferred by not less than ten (10) members of the legislative council. No legislative council member preferring a charge shall sit as a member of the legislative council when it tries that charge. </section><section prefix="2">No elected officer shall be removed without having been given the right to a full public hearing. </section><section prefix="3">A decision to remove a mayor or legislative council member shall require a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the total number of legislative council members sitting as a court. </section><section prefix="4">Any elected officer removed from office under the provisions of this section may appeal to the Circuit Court and from there to the Court of Appeals. The appeal to the Circuit Court shall be taken and tried in the same manner as civil cases are tried. </section><section prefix="5">No elected officer removed from office under this section shall be eligible to fill the office vacated before the expiration of the term to which the elected member was originally elected. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24023</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>