<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">A LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE </unit></structure><section_number>323A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Landscape Architects; </section><section prefix="2">"Landscape architect" means a person who engages in the practice of landscape architecture as defined in subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="3">The "practice of landscape architecture" means to render or offer to render any professional service in connection with the planning of outdoor space involving the relationships of people, flora and fauna, and facilities, with emphasis on the function, preservation, conservation, restoration, and enhancement of the physical environment, by arranging land and water and the elements thereon, including the alignment of roadways and the location of buildings, service areas, parking areas, walkways, steps, ramps, pools, and other structures, and the grading of the land, surface and sub-soil drainage, erosion control, planting, reforestation, and the preservation of the natural landscape ecology and environment, in accordance with the accepted professional standard of public health, welfare, and safety. The practice of landscape architecture shall include the location and arrangement of such tangible objects and features as are incidental and necessary to the purposes outlined in this subsection. The practice of landscape architecture shall not include the design of structures of facilities with separate and self-contained purposes for habitation or industry, public streets or streets intended for public dedication, highways, utilities, storm and sanitary sewers, or sewage treatment facilities, if ordinarily included in the practice of engineering or architecture. Nothing contained in this subsection shall preclude a duly licensed landscape architect from performing any of the services described in the first sentence of this subsection in connection with the setting, approaches, or environment for buildings, structures, or facilities; and </section><section prefix="4">"Professional services" means the providing of professional landscape architectural services for compensation. "Professional services" may include consultation, investigation, reconnaissance, research, planning, design, or responsible supervision. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>