<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.323</section_number><catch_line>District board -- Membership -- Number, how determined -- Removal of members. </catch_line><order_by>323</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Where there is only one (1) participating county in the district, the county judge/executive, with the approval of the fiscal court of the participating county shall appoint five (5) members of the district board. Where there are two (2) or more counties participating in the district the board shall consist of at least one (1) but not more than four (4) persons from each participating county, the total membership of the board to consist of not less than five (5) persons. Where a participating county in a district in which more than one (1) county is participating has a population of seventy-five thousand (75,000) or less, that county shall be allowed one (1) board member. Where a participating county in a district in which one (1) or more county is participating has a population in excess of seventy-five thousand (75,000) the county shall be allowed a board member for each forty thousand (40,000) or a portion thereof, of population in excess of seventy-five thousand (75,000) of population, but not to exceed four (4) members in all. </section><section prefix="2">Where, after each county in the district has appointed the number of board members that it is allowed to appoint, the board consists of fewer than five (5) members the secretary shall recommend a number of persons from the district at large suitable for appointment to the board equal to twice the difference between the number already appointed and five (5). The board members appointed by the county judges/executive shall elect to the membership on the board one-half (1/2) of those recommended by the secretary. The length of the term of no member shall be determined as required by KRS 216.325 until the full membership of the board has been appointed. The successors of the members from the district at large shall be appointed in the same manner as the original members from the district at large. Population shall be determined by the most recent decennial report of the United States Census Bureau. </section><section prefix="3">A member of the board may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 6, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>