<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">JUDICIAL RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>21.410</section_number><catch_line>Disability retirement -- Computation.   </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If upon examination of a member under his normal retirement age by one (1) or more qualified physicians employed by the retirement board, it is certified to the satisfaction of the board that such member is so physically or mentally disabled as to be incapacitated for further performance of duty, and that such incapacity is likely to be permanent, the member may retire for disability. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">A member who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014, who retires for disability as provided by this subsection shall be entitled to receive commencing immediately a disability retirement allowance, payable monthly during his disability, in an amount equal to one-half (1/2) of the monthly service retirement allowance he would have received commencing at his normal retirement date if he had continued in service until that date and had then retired, computed however on the basis of his final compensation at time of actual retirement. </section><section prefix="2">A member who begins participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, who retires for disability as provided by this subsection shall be entitled to a disability retirement allowance equal to the higher of twenty percent (20%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay or the retirement allowance determined in the same manner as for retirement at his or her normal retirement date under KRS 21.402. </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A member who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014, need not have completed eight (8) years of service in order to be eligible for benefits under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">A member who begins participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, must have completed at least five (5) years of service in order to apply and be eligible for the disability benefits provided by this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">The retirement board shall cause a member who has been retired for disability and who is still under his normal retirement age to undergo periodic examination by one (1) or more qualified physicians employed by the board, to determine whether he continues to be incapacitated for service of the character required of a judge or commissioner. If upon any such examination it is certified to the satisfaction of the board that the member is no longer so incapacitated, or if the member refuses to submit to examination, the board shall terminate his disability retirement allowance. He shall then be entitled to such rights, if any, under subsection (2) or (3) of KRS 21.400 or under KRS 21.402 as he would have been entitled to had he voluntarily retired on the date he was retired for disability. </section><section prefix="4">Upon reaching his normal retirement age, a member who has been receiving a disability retirement allowance may apply for and receive, in lieu thereof, the service retirement allowance he would have been entitled to receive at normal retirement age had he voluntarily retired on the date he was retired for disability. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 26, effective July 1, 2013. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Art. III, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 01, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42654</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>