<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="82" order_by="82">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>82.615</section_number><catch_line>Response to notice. </catch_line><order_by>615</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who receives notice of a parking violation shall respond to such notice as provided in this section within seven (7) days of the date of the notice, by either paying the fine set forth in the notice or requesting a hearing pursuant to KRS 82.620. </section><section prefix="2">If the owner of a vehicle cited for a parking violation has not responded to the notice within seven (7) days as provided in subsection (1) of this section, the local government shall send a second notice by regular, first-class mail of the United States Postal Service to the last known address of the registered owner of the vehicle as listed on the certificate of title. Such notice shall state that if the owner of the vehicle does not respond to the notice by either paying the fine or by requesting in writing a hearing pursuant to KRS 82.620, within seven (7) days of the receipt of the notice, the owner shall be deemed to have waived his right to a hearing and the determination that a violation was committed shall be considered final. Any person who fails to request a hearing or pay the fine within the seven (7) days shall be deemed to have refused to pay the fine levied by the citation. </section><section prefix="3">The registered owner of a vehicle at the time the violation occurred shall be liable for all fines, fees and penalties which he has refused to pay. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39865</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>