<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.542</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 148.542 to 148.546.   </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text>As used in KRS 148.542 to 148.546: <section prefix="1">"Above-the-line production crew" means employees involved with the production of a motion picture or entertainment production whose salaries are negotiated prior to commencement of production, such as actors, directors, producers, and writers; </section><section prefix="2">"Animated production" means a nationally distributed feature-length film created with the rapid display of a sequence of images using 2-D or 3-D graphics of artwork or model positions in order to create an illusion of movement; </section><section prefix="3">"Approved company" means an eligible company approved for incentives provided under KRS 141.383 and 148.544; </section><section prefix="4">"Below-the-line production crew" means employees involved with the production of a motion picture or entertainment production except above-the-line production crew. "Below-the-line production crew" includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">Casting assistants; </section><section prefix="b">Costume design; </section><section prefix="c">Extras; </section><section prefix="d">Gaffers; </section><section prefix="e">Grips; </section><section prefix="f">Location managers; </section><section prefix="g">Production assistants; </section><section prefix="h">Set construction staff; and </section><section prefix="i">Set design staff; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Cabinet" means the Finance and Administration Cabinet; </section><section prefix="6">"Commercial" means an individual production or series of live-action or animated productions, music videos, infomercials, or interstitials that are: <section prefix="a">Less than thirty-one (31) minutes in length; </section><section prefix="b">Made for the purpose of promoting a product, service, or idea; and </section><section prefix="c">Produced for regional or national distribution via broadcast, cable, or any digital format, including but not limited to cable, satellite, Internet, or mobile electronic devices; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="8">"Compensation" means compensation included in adjusted gross income as defined in KRS 141.010(10); </section><section prefix="9">"Documentary" means a production based upon factual information and not subjective interjections; </section><section prefix="10">"Eligible company" means any person that intends to film or produce a motion picture or entertainment production in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="11">"Employee" means the same as defined in KRS 141.010(20); </section><section prefix="12">"Enhanced incentive county" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.32-010; </section><section prefix="13">"Feature-length film" means a live-action or animated production that is: <section prefix="a">More than thirty (30) minutes in length; and </section><section prefix="b">Produced for distribution in theaters or via digital format, including but not limited to DVD, Internet, or mobile electronic devices; </section></section><section prefix="14">"Industrial film" means a business-to-business film that may be viewed by the public, including but not limited to videos used for training or for viewing at a trade show; </section><section prefix="15">"Kentucky-based company" has the same meaning as in KRS 164.6011; </section><section prefix="16"><section prefix="a">"Motion picture or entertainment production" means: <section prefix="1">The following if filmed in whole or in part, or produced in whole or in part, in the Commonwealth: <section prefix="a">A feature-length film; </section><section prefix="b">A television program; </section><section prefix="c">An industrial film; </section><section prefix="d">A documentary; or </section><section prefix="e">A commercial; or </section></section><section prefix="2">A national touring production of a Broadway show produced in Kentucky; </section></section><section prefix="b">"Motion picture or entertainment production" does not include the filming or production of obscene material or television coverage of news or athletic events; </section></section><section prefix="17">"Obscene" means the same as defined in KRS 531.010; </section><section prefix="18">"Office" means the Kentucky Film Office in the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; </section><section prefix="19">"Person" means the same as defined in KRS 141.010(15); </section><section prefix="20"><section prefix="a">"Qualifying expenditure" means expenditures made in the Commonwealth for the following if directly used in or for a motion picture or entertainment production: <section prefix="1">The production script and synopsis; </section><section prefix="2">Set construction and operations, wardrobe, accessories, and related services; </section><section prefix="3">Lease or rental of real property in Kentucky as a set location; </section><section prefix="4">Photography, sound synchronization, lighting, and related services; </section><section prefix="5">Editing and related services; </section><section prefix="6">Rental of facilities and equipment; </section><section prefix="7">Vehicle leases; </section><section prefix="8">Food; and </section><section prefix="9">Accommodations. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Qualifying expenditure" does not include Kentucky sales and use tax paid by the approved company on the qualifying expenditure; </section></section><section prefix="21">"Qualifying payroll expenditure" means compensation paid to above-the-line crew and below-the line crew while working on a motion picture or entertainment production in the Commonwealth if the compensation is for services performed in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="22">"Resident" has the same meaning as in KRS 141.010; </section><section prefix="23">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; </section><section prefix="24">"Tax incentive agreement" means the agreement entered into pursuant to KRS 148.546 between the office and the approved company; and </section><section prefix="25">"Television program" means any live-action or animated production or documentary, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">An episodic series; </section><section prefix="b">A miniseries; </section><section prefix="c">A television movie; or </section><section prefix="d">A television pilot; </section></section> that is produced for distribution on television via broadcast, cable, or any digital format, including but not limited to cable, satellite, Internet, or mobile electronic devices. </text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 43, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 4 provides that the amendments made to this statute in that Act apply to taxable periods beginning on or after January 1, 2015. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44506</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>