<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">B METROPOLITAN CORRECTIONAL SERVICES DEPARTMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67B.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, the following words or terms shall have the respective meanings indicated, unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context: <section prefix="1">"Department" means a metropolitan correctional services department created or maintained by a consolidated local government or the fiscal court of a county containing a city of the first class, where the constitutional offices of sheriff and jailer have been consolidated, pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">"Fiscal court" means the county judge/executive and justices of the peace of a county, or the county judge/executive and three (3) county commissioners elected pursuant to KRS 67.050 and 67.060, which exercises the legislative functions of a county as provided by the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="3">"Correctional facility" means the county jail and all other detention and penal facilities of a county or consolidated local government, whether for juvenile or adult offenders and public wards, together with all rehabilitative facilities of such a county or consolidated local government for juvenile or adult offenders and for public wards, including facilities operated by private agencies under contract with the consolidated local government or fiscal court, as such facilities may be designated from time to time by the consolidated local government or fiscal court. </section><section prefix="4">"Sheriff" means the sheriff of a county or the sheriff in a county containing a consolidated local government who has been duly elected by the qualified voters as provided in Section 99 of the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">"Jailer" means the jailer of a county or the jailer in a county containing a consolidated local government who has been duly elected by the qualified voters of a county as provided in Section 99 of the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="6">"Governmental agency" means any incorporated city, division of a city, or consolidated local government, including the United States of America, and its agencies and instrumentalities, situated within, or conducting public operations within, a county in which a metropolitan correctional services department has been duly established. </section><section prefix="7">"Consolidated local government" means a local government established pursuant to KRS Chapter 67C. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 47, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective February 29, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23990</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>