<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.1-120</section_number><catch_line>Insurable interest of trustee. </catch_line><order_by>1-120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "settlor" means a person that executes a trust instrument. The term includes a person for which a fiduciary or agent is acting. </section><section prefix="2">A trustee of a trust has an insurable interest in the life of an individual insured under a life insurance policy that is owned by the trustee of the trust acting in a fiduciary capacity or that designates the trust itself as the owner if, on the date the policy is issued: <section prefix="a">The insured is: <section prefix="1">A settlor of the trust; or </section><section prefix="2">An individual in whom a settlor of the trust has, or would have had if living at the time the policy was issued, an insurable interest; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The life insurance proceeds are primarily for the benefit of one (1) or more trust beneficiaries that have: <section prefix="1">An insurable interest in the life of the insured; or </section><section prefix="2">A substantial interest engendered by love and affection in the continuation of the life of the insured and, if not already included under subparagraph 1. of this paragraph, who are: <section prefix="a">Related within the third degree or closer, as measured by the civil law system of determining degrees of relation, either by blood or law, to the insured; or </section><section prefix="b">Stepchildren of the insured. </section></section></section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43075</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>