<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.474</section_number><catch_line>Multiple textbook adoptions. </catch_line><order_by>474</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall have the authority to prescribe the conditions whereby a school district may make multiple textbook adoptions for the different school subjects by grades. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall have the authority to prescribe the administrative regulations to govern the purchase of the multiple-adopted textbooks for the school district. The chief state school officer, subject to the approval of the Kentucky Board of Education, may purchase the textbooks from the publishers whose books have been adopted by the school district for grades kindergarten through twelve (12) and distribute them without cost to the pupils attending the public schools in the school district. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 163, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 3, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 12, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3197</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>