<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="38" order_by="38">NATIONAL GUARD </unit></structure><section_number>38.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who makes a false oath as to any statement contained in the enlistment papers mentioned in subsection (3) of KRS 38.090 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="2">Any civil officer who fails to execute process and sentences when required to do so under KRS 38.400 shall be fined not more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense. </section><section prefix="3">Any master, keeper, or other person in charge of a tollgate, toll bridge, or ferry who willfully hinders or delays any member of the Kentucky National Guard or Kentucky active militia going to or returning from any parade, encampment, drill, or meeting which he is required by proper authority to attend, or who refuses free passage to any member, conveyance, or other property in violation of KRS 38.430 shall be fined not more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 38.440 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 38.450 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (1) of KRS 38.460 or who aids in enforcing any provision prohibited by subsection (2) of KRS 38.460 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) or more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisoned in the county jail not less than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="7">Any person who trespasses upon property occupied by the Kentucky National Guard or Kentucky active militia contrary to the orders of the officer in charge of such property shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisoned in the county jail for six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="8">Any witness who refuses to appear in answer to a subpoena, to answer questions before a military court or board is guilty of contempt and may be fined not more than fifty dollars ($50) by such court or board. </section><section prefix="9">Any employer failing to meet any requirements of KRS 38.238 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 14. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 27. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2711a-175, 2711a-184, 2711a-185, 2711a-199, 2711a-203, 2711a-205, 2711a-210, 2711a-213, 2711a-222, 2711a-223. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>