<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.38A-110</section_number><catch_line>Conversion of single service organization -- Net worth and capital requirements. </catch_line><order_by>38A-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person issued a single service organization certificate of authority in accordance with KRS 304.38-065 and holding the certificate of authority on July 15, 2002, shall be converted to a limited health service organization as defined in KRS 304.38A-010. At the next renewal of the certificate of authority, the person shall be issued a certificate of authority to act as a limited health service organization if it meets the requirements for continuance of the certificate of authority. No certificate of authority to act as a single service organization shall be issued or renewed after July 15, 2002. </section><section prefix="2">A single service organization holding a certificate of authority immediately prior to July 15, 2002, that is converted to a limited health service organization according to subsection (1) of this section shall continue to be required to meet the minimum net worth requirement of one hundred twenty-five thousand dollars ($125,000) and shall comply with the risk-based capital requirements for health organizations in administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner for health maintenance organizations and other health organizations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1524, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30023</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>