<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29">A JURIES </unit></structure><section_number>29A.180</section_number><catch_line>Responsibility for needs of jurors, transportation to view scene, security personnel, equipment, and services. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The sheriff, city police, or city marshal, as appropriate, shall be responsible for meals, housing, and other incidental needs of grand jurors and petit jurors in Circuit Court and in District Court when the jurors are kept overnight or otherwise sequestered when ordered to do so by the judge of the court for which the jurors were summoned. The expenses for these services shall be borne by the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the officer shall be reimbursed in accordance with administrative regulations issued by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">The sheriff, city police, or city marshal, as appropriate, shall be responsible for the transportation of jurors and other authorized persons to views of the scene or other locations authorized by the court pursuant to KRS 29A.310. In criminal cases the expenses for these services shall be borne by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the sheriff shall be reimbursed in accordance with administrative regulations issued by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. Excepting views conducted under the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky, in civil cases these expenses shall be paid by the party requesting the viewing. </section><section prefix="3">The sheriff, city police, or city marshal, as appropriate, shall be responsible for providing any specialized security personnel, equipment, and services which the judge, with the consent of the Chief Justice, shall deem necessary for the conduct of a trial in which the judge believes that special security precautions are necessary or desirable. The expenses for these services shall be borne by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the officer shall be reimbursed in accordance with administrative regulations issued by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. In such cases, the judge may also request the Chief Justice to provide the services of the Department of Kentucky State Police to ensure proper security precautions relating to the case. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 114, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 29, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>