<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.652</section_number><catch_line>Wrongful use, possession, etc., of controlled substances.   </catch_line><order_by>652</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person subject to this code who wrongfully uses, possesses, manufactures, distributes, or imports into the customs territory of the United States, exports from the United States, or introduces into an installation, vessel, vehicle, or aircraft used by or under the control of the Armed Forces of the United States, state military forces, or the state military forces of any other state a substance described in subsection (2) of this section shall be punished as a court-martial may direct. </section><section prefix="2">The substances referred to in subsection (1) of this section are the following: <section prefix="a">Opium, heroin, cocaine, amphetamine, lysergic acid diethylamide, methamphetamine, phencyclidine, barbituric acid, and marijuana and any compound or derivative of any of these substances; </section><section prefix="b">Any substance not specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection that is listed on a schedule of controlled substances prescribed by the President for the purposes of the Uniform Code of Military Justice of the Armed Forces of the United States, 10 U.S.C. secs. 801 et seq.; and  </section><section prefix="c">Any other substance not specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection or contained on a list prescribed by the President under paragraph (b) of this subsection that is listed in schedules I through V of Article 202 of the Controlled Substances Act, 21 U.S.C. sec. 812. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 116, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41997</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>