<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.670</section_number><catch_line>Annual report of guardian. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A guardian shall file with the court at least annually a verified report stating:  <section prefix="a">The ward's current mental, physical, and social condition;  </section><section prefix="b">The address of every residence of the ward during the reporting period and length of stay at each residence;  </section><section prefix="c">A summary of the medical, social, educational, vocational, and other professional services received by the ward during the reporting period;  </section><section prefix="d">An outline of the guardian's visits with and activities on behalf of the ward;  </section><section prefix="e">A recommendation as to the need for continued guardianship;  </section><section prefix="f">A statement signed by the standby guardian, if one has been appointed, that the standby guardian continues to be willing to serve in the event of the death, resignation, removal, or incapacity of the guardian; and  </section><section prefix="g">Other information requested by the court or useful in the opinion of the guardian.  </section></section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of filing the report required by subsection (1) of this section, the guardian shall be given access to records pertaining to the ward held by public or private agencies which contain information necessary for the guardian to perform his duties.  </section><section prefix="3">The court shall review the report required in subsection (1) of this section and take whatever action it considers necessary to enhance the well-being of the ward.  </section><section prefix="4">In addition to the requirements of this section, a guardian shall comply with the reporting requirements of KRS 387.710 unless a separate conservator has been appointed.  </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 18, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>