<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.003Codes</section_number><catch_line>of ethics for city, county, charter county, urban-county government, and consolidated local government officials and employees -- Codes of ethics for boards, officers, and employees of special purpose governmental entities -- Interlocal agreements.   </catch_line><order_by>003Codes</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The governing body of each city, county, urban-county, consolidated local government, and charter county, shall adopt, by ordinance, a code of ethics which shall apply to all elected officials of the city, county, urban-county, consolidated local government, or charter county, and to appointed officials and employees of the city, county, urban-county, consolidated local government, or charter county government, or agencies created jointly, as specified in the code of ethics. The elected officials of a city, county, or consolidated local government to which a code of ethics shall apply include the mayor, county judge/executive, members of the governing body, county clerk, county attorney, sheriff, jailer, coroner, surveyor, and constable but do not include members of any school board. Agencies created jointly may include planning or administrative commissions or boards. Candidates for the local government elective offices specified in this subsection shall comply with the annual financial disclosure statement filing requirements contained in the code of ethics. </section><section prefix="b">The boards, officers, and employees of special purpose governmental entities shall be subject to a code of ethics as provided in KRS 65A.070. As used in this section, special purpose governmental entity has the same meaning as in KRS 65A.010. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any city, county, or consolidated local government may enter into a memorandum of agreement or an interlocal agreement with one (1) or more other cities, counties, or consolidated local governments for joint adoption of a code of ethics which shall apply to all elected officials of the cities, counties, or consolidated local governments, and to appointed officials and employees as specified by each of the cities, counties, or consolidated local governments which enters into the agreement. Interlocal agreements shall be executed pursuant to the Interlocal Cooperation Act in KRS 65.210 to 65.300. The interlocal agreement or memorandum of agreement may provide for but shall not be limited to: <section prefix="a">The provision of administrative services relating to the implementation of a code of ethics; </section><section prefix="b">The creation of a regional ethics board which serves independently to provide advice to member governments and their officials and provides for the enforcement of locally adopted codes of ethics; and </section><section prefix="c">Contracting by a memorandum of agreement with an area development district for the provision of administrative services relating to the implementation of a code of ethics. </section></section> Candidates for the city, county, or consolidated local government elective offices specified in this subsection shall comply with the annual financial disclosure statement filing requirements contained in the code of ethics. <section prefix="3">Each code of ethics adopted as provided by subsection (1) or (2) of this section, or amended as provided by subsection (4) of this section, shall include but not be limited to provisions which set forth: <section prefix="a">Standards of conduct for elected and appointed officials and employees; </section><section prefix="b">Requirements for creation of financial disclosure statements, which shall be filed annually by all candidates for the city, county, or consolidated local government elective offices specified in subsection (1) of this section, elected officials of each city, county, or consolidated local government, and other officials or employees of the city, county, or consolidated local government, as specified in the code of ethics, and which shall be filed with the person or group responsible for enforcement of the code of ethics; </section><section prefix="c">A policy on the employment of members of the families of officials or employees of the city, county, or consolidated local government, as specified in the code of ethics; </section><section prefix="d">The designation of a person or group who shall be responsible for enforcement of the code of ethics, including maintenance of financial disclosure statements, all of which shall be available for public inspection, receipt of complaints alleging possible violations of the code of ethics, issuance of opinions in response to inquiries relating to the code of ethics, investigation of possible violations of the code of ethics, and imposition of penalties provided in the code of ethics. </section></section><section prefix="4">The code of ethics ordinance adopted by a city, county, or consolidated local government may be amended but shall not be repealed. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Within twenty-one (21) days of the adoption of the code of ethics required by this section, each city, county, or consolidated local government shall deliver a copy of the ordinance by which the code was adopted and proof of publication in accordance with KRS Chapter 424 to the Department for Local Government. The Department for Local Government shall maintain the ordinances as public records and shall maintain a list of city, county, or consolidated local governments which have adopted a code of ethics and a list of those which have not adopted a code of ethics. </section><section prefix="b">Within twenty-one (21) days of the amendment of a code of ethics required by this section, each city, county, or consolidated local government shall: <section prefix="1">Deliver a copy of the ordinance by which the code was amended and proof of publication in accordance with KRS Chapter 424 to the Department for Local Government, which shall maintain the amendment with the ordinance by which the code was adopted; and </section><section prefix="2">Deliver a copy of the ordinance by which the code was amended to the governing body of each special purpose governmental entity that follows that establishing entity's code of ethics pursuant to KRS 65A.070. </section></section><section prefix="c">For ordinances adopting or amending a code of ethics under this section, cities of the first class and consolidated local governments shall comply with the publication requirements of KRS 83A.060(9), notwithstanding the exception contained in that statute. </section></section><section prefix="6">If a city, county, or consolidated local government fails to comply with the requirements of this section, the Department for Local Government shall notify all state agencies, including area development districts, which deliver services or payments of money from the Commonwealth to the city, county, or consolidated local government. Those agencies shall suspend delivery of all services or payments to the city, county, or consolidated local government which fails to comply with the requirements of this section. The Department for Local Government shall immediately notify those same agencies when the city, county, or consolidated local government is in compliance with the requirements of this section, and those agencies shall reinstate the delivery of services or payments to the city, county, or consolidated local government. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 10, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 46, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 40, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 346, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(3/21/2013). Under the authority of KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or technical error in this statute. In subsection (1)(b), the word "have" has been changed to read "has." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44076</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>