<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-578</section_number><catch_line>Notice to health care provider of material change to managed care plan. </catch_line><order_by>17A-578</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Material change" means a change to a contract, the occurrence and timing of which is not otherwise clearly identified in the contract, that decreases the health care provider's payment or compensation or changes the administrative procedures in a way that may reasonably be expected to significantly increase the provider's administrative expense; and </section><section prefix="b">"Participating provider" means a physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311, an advanced practice registered nurse licensed under KRS Chapter 314, a psychologist licensed under KRS Chapter 319, or an optometrist licensed under KRS Chapter 320 that has entered into an agreement with an insurer to provide health care services. </section></section><section prefix="2">If an insurer issuing a managed care plan makes a material change to an agreement it has entered into with a participating provider for the provision of health care services, the insurer shall provide the participating provider with at least ninety (90) days' written notice of the material change. The notice shall include a description of the material change and a statement that the participating provider has the option to withdraw from the agreement prior to the material change becoming effective pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">A participating provider who opts to withdraw following notice of a material change pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall send written notice of withdrawal to the insurer no later than forty-five (45) days prior to the effective date of the material change. </section><section prefix="4">If an insurer issuing a managed care plan makes a change to an agreement that changes an existing prior authorization, precertification, notification, or referral program, or changes an edit program or specific edits, the insurer shall provide notice of the change to the participating provider at least fifteen (15) days prior to the change. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 48, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17447</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>