<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.856</section_number><catch_line>Forfeiture of right to grow hemp following revocation of industrial hemp grower license -- Failure to comply with administrative regulations -- Plea to or conviction of felony -- Administrative hearings and appeals.   </catch_line><order_by>856</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An industrial hemp grower licensee who does not comply with the requirements of KRS 260.850 to 260.869, or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder, shall have his or her license revoked and shall forfeit the right to grow industrial hemp in this state for a period of up to five (5) years as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">A license revocation or forfeiture shall occur pursuant to this section only after the licensee has had an opportunity, upon due notice, for an informal hearing before the chair of the commission, to show cause why the license should not be revoked and the licensee's right to grow forfeited. </section><section prefix="3">The chair of the commission may revoke any license of a person who has pled guilty to, or been convicted of, a felony. </section><section prefix="4">If a license is revoked and a licensee's right to grow is forfeited as the result of an informal hearing, the decision may be appealed, and upon appeal an administrative hearing shall be conducted before the commission in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="5">The licensee may appeal the final order of the commission by filing a petition in the Fayette Circuit Court, or the Circuit Court in which the licensee resides, in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>