<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.587</section_number><catch_line>Medical and accident insurance program for students. </catch_line><order_by>587</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of regents may provide medical and accident insurance for students enrolled in the Kentucky Community and Technical College System institutions. The president, on behalf of the system, may enter into a contract or contracts with one (1) or more sureties or insurance companies or their agents to provide appropriate medical and accident insurance coverage and to provide group coverage to all students enrolled in institutions within the system. The appropriate group coverage shall be issued by one (1) or more sureties or insurance companies authorized to transact business in this state, and the coverage shall be approved by the commissioner of insurance. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall approve policies upon recommendation of the president to implement the medical and accident insurance program. The board may fix the rate of fees for all postsecondary and adult students as it deems necessary to meet the expense in whole or in part for appropriate student medical and accident insurance. </section><section prefix="3">The limits of liability and other appropriate provisions for student medical and accident insurance authorized by this section shall be set by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 213, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 21, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4335</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>