<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="378" order_by="378">A KENTUCKY UNIFORM VOIDABLE TRANSACTIONS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>378A.110</section_number><catch_line>Application to series organization.  </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>(1)In this section:(a)"Protected series" means an arrangement, however denominated,created by a series organization that, pursuant to the law under which theseries organization is organized, has the characteristics set forth inparagraph (b) of this subsection; and(b)"Series organization" means an organization that, pursuant to the lawunder which it is organized, has the following characteristics:1.The organic record of the organization provides for creation by theorganization of one (1) or more protected series, howeverdenominated, with respect to specified property of the organization,and for records to be maintained for each protected series thatidentify the property of, or associated with, the protected series;2.Debt incurred or existing with respect to the activities of, or propertyof, or associated with, a particular protected series is enforceableagainst the property of, or associated with, the protected series only,and not against the property of, or associated with, the organizationor other protected series of the organization; and3.Debt incurred or existing with respect to the activities or property ofthe organization is enforceable against the property of theorganization only, and not against the property of, or associatedwith, a protected series of the organization.(2)A series organization and each protected series of the organization is aseparate person for purposes of this chapter, even if for other purposes aprotected series is not a person separate from the organization or otherprotected series of the organization.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 11, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44731</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>