<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.480</section_number><catch_line>Examination of applicants by Department of Kentucky State Police -- Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall examine every applicant for an operator's license as identified in KRS 186.6401, except as otherwise provided in this section. The examination shall be held in the county where the applicant resides unless: <section prefix="a">The applicant is granted written permission by the circuit clerk of the county in which he or she resides to take the examination in another county, and the Department of Kentucky State Police agree to arrange for the examination in the other county; or </section><section prefix="b">The applicant is tested using a bioptic telescopic device. </section></section><section prefix="2">The examination shall include a test of the applicant's eyesight to ensure compliance with the visual acuity standards set forth in KRS 186.577. The examination shall also include a test of the applicant's ability to read and understand highway signs regulating, warning and directing traffic, the applicant's knowledge of traffic laws and an actual demonstration of the applicant's ability to exercise ordinary and reasonable control in the operation of a motor vehicle. An applicant for a motorcycle operator's license shall be required to show his or her ability to operate a motorcycle, in addition to other requirements of this section. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">At the time of application, holds a valid operator's license from another state, provided that state affords a reciprocal exemption to a Kentucky resident; or </section><section prefix="b">Is a citizen of the Commonwealth who has been serving in the United States military and has allowed his or her operator's license to expire. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person whose intermediate license or operator's license is denied, suspended, or revoked for cause shall apply for reinstatement at the termination of the period for which the license was denied, suspended, or revoked by submitting to the examination. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any person whose license was suspended for failure to meet the conditions described in KRS 186.411 when, within one (1) year of suspension, the driving privileges of such individuals are reinstated. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 195, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 123, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 6. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 5. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 8, effective June 13, 1968. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-33, 2739m-67. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>