<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.133</section_number><catch_line>Purpose, duties and powers of the board -- Rules and regulations, publication -- Enforcement -- Promotion of facilities. </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of the board shall be to establish, maintain, operate, and expand necessary, desirable or appropriate airport and air navigation facilities. It shall have the duty and such powers as may be necessary, or desirable to promote and develop aviation, including air transportation, airports and air navigation facilities. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall establish and fix reasonable rates, charges and fees for the use of the landing area, ramps and other common aviation facilities. In fixing such rates, charges or fees the board may take into consideration, among other factors, the total capital investment by the board or other local or state governmental authority, the revenue needed properly to maintain such facilities, the revenue needed properly to expand the airport and its facilities, the portion of the facilities utilized by the licensee or contracting party and its customers and the volume and type of business conducted. Any party aggrieved by the rates, charges or fees may appeal from the action of the board to the Circuit Court of the county within which the board operates, within ninety (90) days from the date that the board finally publishes such rates, charges or fees and gives notice of same to the contracting party or licensee. The Circuit Court may hear evidence and determine whether or not the rates, charges or fees are, or are not, reasonable in amount. Appeal from the judgment of the Circuit Court may be prosecuted as any other civil appeal. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall likewise have power, from time to time, to fix rates, charges or fees by contract, or by publishing general rates, charges or fees for commercial vendors, concessionaires or other persons for the use or occupancy of terminal or other ground use facilities, under such terms or conditions as it may deem to be in the best interest of maintaining, operating or expanding necessary airport or air navigation facilities, and the public use thereof. </section><section prefix="4">The board may acquire by contract, lease, purchase, gift, condemnation or otherwise any real or personal property, or rights therein, necessary for establishing, operating or expanding airports and air navigation facilities. The board may erect, equip, operate and maintain on such property, buildings and equipment necessary, desirable or appropriate for airport or air navigation facilities. The board may dispose of any real or personal property, or rights therein, which, in the opinion of the board are no longer needed for operating or expanding the airport or air navigation facilities. </section><section prefix="5">The board or any other governmental unit may by resolution reciting that the property is needed for airport or air navigation purposes direct the condemnation of any property, including navigation or other easements. The procedure for condemnation shall conform to the procedures set out in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="6">The board or any other governmental unit may from time to time make, adopt and enforce such rules, regulations and ordinances as it may find necessary, desirable or appropriate for carrying into effect the purposes of this chapter, including those relating to the operation and control of the airport, airport facilities or air navigation facilities owned or operated by such board or such other governmental unit. All rules, regulations and ordinances adopted pursuant to this section shall be published according to the provisions of KRS 424.130, and the board or other governmental unit adopting them shall keep a permanent record of such rules, regulations and ordinances available for public inspection, on the airport premises. Prosecution for a violation of any rule, regulation or ordinance adopted pursuant to this section shall be in the District Court of any county within which the airport is located. </section><section prefix="7">Any board may engage in activities to promote, encourage or develop the use of airports or air navigation facilities under its control and any board which has members thereof appointed by the Governor shall be assisted in such activities by the state Cabinet for Economic Development if it requests such assistance from the cabinet. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 171, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 86. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 33. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5736</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>