<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.400</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Lieutenant Governor. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the duties prescribed for the office by the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the duties of the Lieutenant Governor shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">To serve as vice chairman of the State Property and Buildings Commission as prescribed by KRS 56.450; </section><section prefix="b">To serve as vice chairman of the Kentucky Turnpike Authority as prescribed in KRS 175.430; </section><section prefix="c">To serve as a member of the Kentucky Council on Agriculture in accordance with KRS 247.417; </section><section prefix="d">To appoint one (1) member of the Public Officials' Compensation Commission as provided in KRS 64.742; </section><section prefix="e">To serve as a member of the Board of the Kentucky Housing Corporation in accordance with KRS 198A.030; and </section><section prefix="f">To serve as a member of Kentucky delegations on the following interstate compact commissions or boards: <section prefix="1">The Southern Growth Policies Board as prescribed by KRS 147.585; </section><section prefix="2">The Breaks Interstate Park Commission as provided in KRS 148.225; </section><section prefix="3">The Falls of the Ohio Interstate Park Commission pursuant to KRS 148.242; </section><section prefix="4">The Tennessee-Tombigbee Waterway Development Authority pursuant to KRS 182.305; </section><section prefix="5">The Interstate Water Sanitation Control Commissions as prescribed by KRS 224.18-710; and </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Mining Advisory Council for the Interstate Mining Compact as provided by KRS 350.310. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Governor and Lieutenant Governor from agreeing upon additional duties within the executive branch of the state government to be performed by the Lieutenant Governor. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 74, effective September 16, 1993. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 70, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 18, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 13, effective April 12, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>