<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.080</section_number><catch_line>License, certified social worker -- Requirements -- Issuance.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue a license as "certified social worker" to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Is a person of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">Has received a master's degree or doctorate degree in social work from an educational institution approved by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Has paid to the board an examination fee established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="e">Has passed an examination prepared by the board; </section><section prefix="f">Has not within the preceding three (3) months failed to pass an examination given by the board; and </section><section prefix="g">Has paid an initial license fee established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The license shall be displayed in the licensee's principal place of practice, and shall entitle the licensee to hold himself forth to the public as providing services as authorized by KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and 335.990. </section><section prefix="3">A certified social worker may engage in the practice of clinical social work by contracting, in writing, with a licensed clinical social worker who shall assume responsibility for and supervise the certified social worker's practice as directed by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. The certified social worker shall, for purposes of this section, be an employee of an institution or organization in which the certified social worker has no direct or indirect interest other than employment. No certified social worker shall enter into a practice of clinical social work until this contract has been approved by the board, and shall cease the practice of clinical social work immediately upon the termination of the contract. At the termination of the contract, the certified social worker shall apply for licensure as a licensed clinical social worker or request an extension of the contract from the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 25, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 27, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 2. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>