<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.775</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 230.775 to 230.785. </catch_line><order_by>775</order_by><text>As used in KRS 230.775 to 230.785, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Hub" means an international wagering hub, a business which, through a qualified subscriber-based service, conducts pari-mutuel wagering on the horse races that it simulcasts and other races that it carries in its wagering menu; </section><section prefix="2">"Qualified subscriber-based service" means any information service or system, including but not limited to a closed-loop system, that uses: <section prefix="a">A device or combination of devices authorized and operated exclusively for placing, receiving, or otherwise making pari-mutuel wagers on horse races by a customer subscriber base through accounts established with the operator of the hub; </section><section prefix="b">An effective customer verification and age verification system; and </section><section prefix="c">Appropriate data security standards to prevent unauthorized access by nonsubscribers or minors; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Foreign jurisdiction" means states other than Kentucky, a territory of the United States, a foreign country, or any political subdivision thereof; </section><section prefix="4">"Racing commission" means the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission or its successor; and </section><section prefix="5">"Call center" means that portion of a qualified subscriber-based service that is physically located in the Commonwealth, where wagers are placed, received, or otherwise made by a customer subscriber base through accounts established with the operator of the hub. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 488, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10928</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>