<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.900</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Motor Carrier Advisory Committee -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Motor Carrier Advisory Committee is created as an agency of the Commonwealth to carry out the functions and duties conferred upon it by KRS 281.905. </section><section prefix="2">The committee shall consist of the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Speaker of the House, the President of the Senate, or their respective designated representatives, and nine (9) representatives of the motor carrier industry engaged in operations in the Commonwealth in the transportation of persons or property. </section><section prefix="3">On July 15, 1990, the Governor shall appoint the motor carrier industry representative to the committee. Members shall be appointed by the Governor for three (3) years, except that initial appointments to the board shall be staggered in the following manner: <section prefix="a">Three (3) members shall serve for a period of one (1) year; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members shall serve for a period of two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall serve for a period of three (3) years. </section></section><section prefix="4">Motor carrier industry representatives of the committee shall qualify for membership by taking the constitutional oath of office and shall be provided with certificates of appointments. The members of the committee shall serve without per diem or compensation. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 674, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 62, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14452</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>