<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="37" order_by="37">ACTIVE MILITIA </unit></structure><section_number>37.170</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky State Defense Force -- Organization -- Reorganization. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor is hereby authorized to enlist, organize, maintain, equip, discipline and pay when called into active field service a volunteer state defense force other than the National Guard, which shall constitute the active militia and shall be known as the Kentucky State Defense Force, which shall consist of able-bodied citizens who are residents of the State of Kentucky between the ages of eighteen (18) and sixty-four (64) who are not active members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever the President of the United States shall call any part of the National Guard of this state into active federal service, the Governor is hereby authorized to organize the Kentucky State Defense Force under such regulations as may be promulgated by the Governor or adjutant general. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor shall have the power to alter, divide, annex, disband or reorganize any organization of the Kentucky State Defense Force whenever in his judgment the efficiency of the state forces will thereby be increased, and he shall have power to change the organization so as to conform to the regulations now or hereafter prescribed by the laws of the United States for the organization of the National Guard or militia. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414,sec. 47, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 10; and ch. 386, sec. 9. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 3. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 4, secs. 1, 4, and 8. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21507</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>