<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="339" order_by="339">CHILD LABOR </unit></structure><section_number>339.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text>Anyone who employs or permits or suffers any minor to be employed or to work in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450, or of any order or ruling issued under the provisions thereof, or obstructs the Department of Workplace Standards, its officers, or agents, or any other person authorized to inspect places of employment under KRS 339.210 to 339.450, or anyone who, having under his or her control or custody any minor, permits or suffers him or her to be employed or to work in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450, or who sells to a minor any article with the knowledge that the minor intends to sell the article in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450, shall be assessed a civil penalty, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 336.985, of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). Every employer who continues to employ a minor in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450 after he has been notified by the Department of Workplace Standards, its officers or agents, shall be assessed a civil penalty, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 336.985, of one hundred dollars ($100) for each day the violation continues and the employment of any minor in violation of KRS 339.210 to 339.450 shall with respect to each minor so employed constitute a separate and distinct offense. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1776, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 414, sec. 33, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>