<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.360</section_number><catch_line>Duty of mine foreman as to breakthroughs, measurement of air current, designation of escapeways, and installation of man doors. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The mine foreman shall see that breakthroughs are made as required by law, and shall see that ventilation is conducted by means of the breakthroughs and through the rooms by means of check doors or curtains placed on the entries or other suitable places, and shall not permit any room to be opened in advance of the ventilating current. </section><section prefix="2">At least once each week while the mine is in operation the mine foreman, or some certified person designated by the mine foreman, with an anemometer furnished by the licensee, shall measure the air current at the inlet and outlet and at or near the faces of the advanced headings, and shall keep a record of the measurements in a book approved by the commissioner for the purpose. </section><section prefix="3">The mine foreman shall see that signboards directing the way to outlets or escapeways are conspicuously placed throughout the mine. </section><section prefix="4">Hinged man doors, installed after June 16, 1976, shall be at least thirty (30) inches square or the height of the coal seam, and shall be installed on the intake and the return air course at intervals not to exceed three hundred (300) feet when the height of the coal is below forty-eight (48) inches and at intervals not to exceed five hundred (500) feet when the height of the coal is above forty-eight (48) inches. </section><section prefix="5">Where it is necessary to cross a conveyer belt to reach an escapeway man door, unless another safe means is provided, there shall be a stop-start switch controlling the conveyer belt. The switch shall be located in such a manner that it may be reached from each side of the belt. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 43, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 19. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 33. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 33, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-42. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>