<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.180</section_number><catch_line>Duplicate receipts and plates -- Clerk's fees -- Cancellation of registration and issuance of new plates upon loss of plate -- Reporting of lost plates -- Issuance of plates upon removal from one county to another -- Reinstatement after revocation under KRS 186A.040 -- Proof of insurance. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If the owner loses his or her copy of a registration or transfer receipt, he or she may obtain a duplicate from the county clerk who issued the present owner's copy of the receipt by presenting the clerk proof of insurance on the motor vehicle in compliance with KRS 304.39-080, and by filing an affidavit, upon a form furnished by the cabinet. The owner shall pay to the clerk a fee of three dollars ($3), except proof of insurance shall not be required for duplicates applied for by motor vehicle dealers as defined in KRS 190.010. </section><section prefix="b">When the owner's copy of any registration or transfer receipt shows that the spaces provided thereon for noting and discharging security interests have been exhausted, the owner may apply to the county clerk who issued the receipt in order to obtain a duplicate thereof. The owner shall surrender his or her copy of the current receipt to the clerk and provide proof of insurance on the motor vehicle in compliance with KRS 304.39-080, before a duplicate may be issued. The owner shall pay the clerk a fee of three dollars ($3), except proof of insurance shall not be required for duplicates applied for by motor vehicle dealers as defined in KRS 190.010. </section><section prefix="c">Any security interest which has been discharged as shown by the records of the clerk or upon the owner's copy of the current receipt shall be omitted from the duplicate receipt to be issued by the clerk. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the owner loses a registration plate, he or she shall surrender his or her registration receipt to the county clerk from whom it was obtained and file a written statement as to the loss of the plate. Upon presenting the clerk proof of insurance on the motor vehicle in compliance with KRS 304.39-080, and upon the payment of the sum of three dollars ($3) for each plate and a fee of three dollars ($3) to the clerk for his or her services, the owner shall be issued another registration receipt and a plate or plates which shall bear a different number from that of the lost plate. The clerk shall retain the owner's statement and a copy of the owner's proof of insurance, and shall make a notation on the triplicate copy of the surrendered registration receipt stating the number of the registration receipt replacing it. The original copy of the surrendered receipt shall be forwarded to the cabinet. The cabinet shall forthwith cancel the registration corresponding to the number of the lost plate. The cancellation shall be reported by the cabinet to the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police. Any person finding a lost registration plate shall deliver it to the Transportation Cabinet or to any county clerk for forwarding it to the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">If the owner moves from one (1) county into another county of the Commonwealth, he or she may obtain a registration plate bearing the name of the county of residence. In order to obtain a new registration plate, the owner shall surrender his or her current registration receipt and current registration plate to the county clerk. Upon being provided with proof of insurance on the motor vehicle in compliance with KRS 304.39-080, the clerk shall provide the owner with a new registration receipt and plate bearing the county name. The surrendered receipt and plate shall be forwarded to the Transportation Cabinet. The fee for this registration shall be five dollars ($5) of which the clerk shall be entitled to three dollars ($3) and the cabinet shall be entitled to two dollars ($2). </section><section prefix="4">If the owner's registration is revoked as a result of the provisions set forth in KRS 186A.040, the owner may have his or her registration reinstated by the county clerk who issued the present owner's copy of the receipt by presenting the clerk proof of: <section prefix="a">Insurance on the motor vehicle in compliance with KRS 304.39-080 and by filing an affidavit upon a form furnished by the cabinet; or </section><section prefix="b">A valid compliance or exemption certificate in compliance with KRS 224.20-720 or issued under the authority of an air pollution control district under KRS 224.20-760. </section></section><section prefix="5">The owner of a motor vehicle that has the vehicle's registration revoked under KRS 186.290 shall pay to the clerk a fee of twenty dollars ($20), which shall be equally divided between the county clerk and the cabinet. </section><section prefix="6">On and after January 1, 2006, if the motor vehicle is a personal motor vehicle as defined in KRS 304.39-087, proof of insurance required under this section shall be determined by the county clerk as provided in KRS 186A.042. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 190, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 442, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 2. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 333, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(9). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 208. sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-12. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5995</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>