<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="57" order_by="57">PUBLIC PRINTING AND DISTRIBUTION OF PUBLIC DOCUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>57.310</section_number><catch_line>House and Senate journals, who entitled to copies -- Affirmative response required prior to receipt. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the following officers and libraries are entitled free of charge to copies of the journals of each house of the General Assembly, as they are published: each member of the General Assembly, one (1) copy for the session in which he served; the law library of each county, one (1) copy; the Governor and Secretary of State, one (1) copy each; the State Law Library, two (2) copies; the Legislative Research Commission, five (5) copies for the use of the Senate and five (5) copies for the use of the House of Representatives; the law library of the University of Kentucky, the law library of the University of Louisville, the Library of Congress, the Kentucky Historical Society, the Department for Libraries and Archives, and each of the state universities in Kentucky, two (2) copies each. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to printing the journals, the Legislative Research Commission shall inquire of those entitled to a free copy of the journals under subsection (1) of this section: <section prefix="a">Whether the officer or library wishes to receive the free copy or copies to which entitled; and </section><section prefix="b">If the officer or library desires to receive a free copy, whether the officer or library prefers to receive it in print or electronic format. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless those entitled to a free copy of the journals respond affirmatively to the inquiry required by subsection (2) of this section, they shall not receive a free copy or copies of the journals. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 24. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 16. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2425, 2426a, 2426b. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22797</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>