<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.240</section_number><catch_line>Additional employees for regulation of race meetings -- Administrative regulations as to duties, qualifications, and training -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the employees referred to in KRS 230.230, the executive director of the racing commission may employ, dismiss, or take other personnel action and determine the reasonable compensation of stewards, supervisors of mutuels, veterinarians, inspectors, accountants, security officers, and other employees deemed by the executive director to be essential at or in connection with any horse race meeting and in the best interest of racing. Three (3) Thoroughbred stewards shall be employed at each Thoroughbred race meeting. Two (2) stewards shall be employed and compensated by the Commonwealth, subject to reimbursement by the racing associations pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. One (1) Thoroughbred steward shall be employed and compensated by the racing association hosting the race meeting. Three (3) standardbred judges shall be employed at each standardbred race meeting. Two (2) standardbred judges shall be employed and compensated by the Commonwealth, subject to reimbursement by the racing associations pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. One (1) standardbred judge shall be employed and compensated by the racing association hosting the race meeting. The security officers shall be peace officers and conservators of the peace on racing commission property and at all race tracks and grounds in the Commonwealth and shall possess all the common law and statutory powers and privileges now available or hereafter made available to sheriffs, constables, and police officers for the purpose of enforcing all laws relating directly or indirectly to the conduct of horse racing and pari-mutuel wagering thereon, or the enforcement of laws relating to the protection of persons or property on premises licensed by the racing commission. The racing commission, for the purpose of maintaining integrity and honesty in racing, shall prescribe by administrative regulation the powers and duties of the persons employed under this section and qualifications necessary to competently perform their duties. In addition, the racing commission shall be responsible for seeing that racing officials employed under the provisions of this section have adequate training to perform their duties in a competent manner. </section><section prefix="2">The racing commission shall promulgate administrative regulations for effectively preventing the use of improper devices, and restricting or prohibiting the use and administration of drugs or stimulants or other improper acts to horses prior to the horse participating in a race. The racing commission may acquire, operate, and maintain, or contract for the maintenance and operation of, a testing laboratory and related facilities, for the purpose of saliva, urine, or other tests, and to purchase supplies and equipment for and in connection with the laboratory or testing processes. The expense of the laboratory or other testing processes, whether furnished by contract or otherwise, together with all supplies and equipment used in connection therewith, shall be paid by the various associations licensed under this chapter in the manner and in proportions as the racing commission shall by administrative regulation provide. </section><section prefix="3">The compensation of the employees referred to in this section shall be paid by the licensee conducting the horse race meeting in connection with which the employees are utilized or employed. The salary of the executive director to the racing commission shall be prorated among and paid by the various associations licensed under this chapter in the manner as the racing commission shall, by administrative regulation, provide. Except for the Thoroughbred steward and the standardbred judge authorized in subsection (1) of this section, the employees referred to in this section shall be deemed employees of the racing commission, and are paid by the licensee or association for convenience only. </section><section prefix="4">Each person, as a condition precedent to the privilege of receiving a license under this chapter to conduct a horse race meeting, shall be deemed to have agreed to pay expenses and compensation as provided in this section and as may be actually and reasonably incurred. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 448, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 15, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10835</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>