<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.067</section_number><catch_line>Publicly owned vehicles, how marked -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>067</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All publicly owned vehicles shall be properly identified by an insignia on one (1) door on each side of every such vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">Such insignia shall not be less than twelve (12) inches in width and not less than twenty-one (21) inches in length, of a design so chosen by the legislative body of the state, county, or city in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">The legislative body may designate a separate insignia for each division, department, agency, bureau or any other authority as may come under their jurisdiction within the state, county or city within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">Publicly owned vehicle, as used in this section, means any vehicle paid for with public funds and used by an elected or appointed official or employee of the state, county or city within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate the provisions of KRS 44.045 and 186.065. </section><section prefix="6">The legislative body of any county or city may exempt from the provisions of this section any vehicle used for investigatory purposes. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1972. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1972</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5947</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>