<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.6-065</section_number><catch_line>Out-of-state credit unions. </catch_line><order_by>6-065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A credit union organized in another state may conduct business as a credit union in this state with the approval of the commissioner. The commissioner shall find that the out-of-state credit union: <section prefix="a">Is a credit union organized under laws similar to this subtitle; </section><section prefix="b">Is financially solvent; </section><section prefix="c">Has account insurance comparable to that required for credit unions incorporated under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="d">Is effectively examined and supervised by the supervisory authority of the state in which it is organized; and </section><section prefix="e">Needs to conduct business in this state to adequately serve its members in this state. </section></section><section prefix="2">The out-of-state credit union shall agree to: <section prefix="a">Grant loans at rates not in excess of the rates permitted for credit unions incorporated under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="b">Comply with the same consumer protection provisions that credit unions incorporated under this subtitle must obey; </section><section prefix="c">Designate and maintain an agent for the service of process in this state; and </section><section prefix="d">Submit copies of reports to the commissioner when requested. </section></section><section prefix="3">The commissioner may examine the out-of-state credit union or enter into cooperative or reciprocal agreements with the out-of-state credit union's regulatory authority for periodic examinations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 720, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 290.065. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>