<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.060</section_number><catch_line>Petition for intervention. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The hearing officer shall grant a petition for intervention if: <section prefix="a">The petitioner has a statutory right to initiate the proceeding in which he wishes to intervene; or </section><section prefix="b">The petitioner has an interest which is or may be adversely affected by the outcome of the proceeding. </section></section><section prefix="2">The hearing officer may grant intervention after consideration of the following factors and a determination that intervention is in the interests of justice: <section prefix="a">The nature of the issues; </section><section prefix="b">The adequacy of representation of the petitioner's interest which is provided by the existing parties to the proceeding; </section><section prefix="c">The ability of the petitioner to present relevant evidence and argument; and </section><section prefix="d">The effect of intervention on the agency's ability to implement its statutory mandate. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless otherwise required by federal law, a petition for intervention shall be filed and copies mailed to all parties named in the notice of the hearing, at least fourteen (14) days before the hearing. The parties to the hearing shall have seven (7) days within which to file any response they may have to the petition to intervene. If a petitioner qualifies for intervention under subsection (2) of this section, the hearing officer may impose conditions upon the intervenor's participation in the proceedings, either at the time that intervention is granted or at any subsequent time. Conditions may include: <section prefix="a">Limiting the intervenor's participation to designated issues in which the intervenor has a particular interest demonstrated by the petition; </section><section prefix="b">Limiting the intervenor's use of discovery, cross-examination, and other procedures so as to promote the orderly and prompt conduct of the proceedings; and </section><section prefix="c">Requiring two (2) or more intervenors to combine their presentations of evidence and argument, cross-examination, discovery, and other participation in the proceedings. </section></section><section prefix="4">The hearing officer, at least three (3) days before the hearing, shall issue an order granting or denying each pending petition for intervention, specifying any conditions, and briefly stating the reasons for the order. The hearing officer shall promptly give notice of an order granting, denying, or modifying intervention to the petitioner for intervention and to all parties. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=790</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>