<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.120</section_number><catch_line>Notification of failure to renew license -- Procedure for renewal of expired license -- Renewal after lapse of five or more years -- Inactive license. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within thirty (30) days after the renewal period, the executive director shall notify all pharmacists who have failed to comply with license renewal requirements. </section><section prefix="2">Any pharmacist who has failed to timely renew his license for any consecutive period up to five (5) years may renew his license only upon satisfying the continuing education regulations of the board and paying the cumulative penalty and renewal fees provided for in KRS 315.110. </section><section prefix="3">Any pharmacist who has failed to timely renew his license for five (5) or more consecutive years may renew his license only upon satisfying the continuing education regulations of the board, passing a satisfactory examination before the board and paying the renewal and penalty fees provided for in KRS 315.110. </section><section prefix="4">Any pharmacist not currently holding an active pharmacist's license in another jurisdiction who does not desire to meet the qualifications for active license renewal shall, upon application, be issued an inactive license. Such license shall entitle the license holder to use the term "pharmacist" but the license holder shall not be permitted to engage in the practice of pharmacy. An inactive license holder may apply for an active license as provided for by the regulations of the board. The inactive license renewal fee shall be set by administrative regulation of the board, not to exceed fifty dollars ($50) annually. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2627. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31006</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>