<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.241</section_number><catch_line>Counterfeiting intellectual property -- Penalties -- Disposition of property. </catch_line><order_by>241</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Counterfeit mark" means: <section prefix="1">Any unauthorized reproduction or copy of intellectual property; or </section><section prefix="2">Intellectual property knowingly affixed to any item without the authority of the owner of the intellectual property. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Intellectual property" means any trademark, service mark, trade name, label, term, device, design, or word adopted or used by a person to identify the person's goods or services. </section><section prefix="c">"Person" includes, in addition to its meaning under KRS 446.010, any association, organization, or entity amenable to suit in a court of law. </section><section prefix="d">"Retail value" means the counterfeiter's regular selling price for the item or service bearing or identified by the counterfeit mark. In the case of items bearing a counterfeit mark which are components of a finished product, the retail value shall be the counterfeiter's regular selling price of the finished product on or in which the component would be utilized. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person who willfully manufactures, uses, displays, advertises, distributes, offers for sale, sells, or possesses with intent to sell or distribute any item or service that the person knows bears or is identified by a counterfeit mark shall be guilty of counterfeiting. </section><section prefix="3">A person having possession, custody, or control of more than twenty-five (25) items that the person knows bear or are identified by a counterfeit mark shall be presumed to possess the items with the intent to sell or distribute. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, except where the person has been previously convicted of a violation of this section or the violation involves more than one hundred (100) items bearing a counterfeit mark or the total retail value of all items bearing, or services identified by, a counterfeit mark is more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), in which case the person shall be guilty of a Class D felony. Unless reduced by the court for extenuating circumstances and notwithstanding KRS Chapter 534, upon conviction the offender shall, in addition to any other allowable disposition, be fined an amount equal to the greater of: <section prefix="a">Three (3) times the retail value of the items bearing, or services identified by, the counterfeit mark; </section><section prefix="b">Double the amount of the defendant's gain from commission of the offense; or </section><section prefix="c">As otherwise allowed in KRS Chapter 534 for felonies and misdemeanors. </section></section><section prefix="5">For purposes of this section, the quantity or retail value of items or services shall include the aggregate quantity or retail value of all items bearing, or services identified by, every counterfeit mark the defendant manufactures, uses, displays, advertises, distributes, offers for sale, sells, or possesses. </section><section prefix="6">Except for items in the possession of a person not in violation of this section, any items bearing a counterfeit mark, and all personal property, including but not limited to, any items, objects, tools, machines, equipment, instrumentalities, or vehicles of any kind, employed or used in connection with a violation of this section shall be seized by any law enforcement officer. <section prefix="a">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, all personal property seized under this subsection shall be forfeited in accordance with KRS 431.100. </section><section prefix="b">Upon request of the intellectual property owner, all seized items bearing a counterfeit mark shall be released to the intellectual property owner. </section><section prefix="c">If the intellectual property owner does not request release of seized items bearing a counterfeit mark, the items shall be destroyed unless the intellectual property owner consents to another disposition. </section></section><section prefix="7">Any state or federal certificate of registration of any intellectual property shall be prima facie evidence of the facts stated in the certificate. </section><section prefix="8">The remedies provided in this section shall be cumulative to other civil and criminal remedies provided by law. </section><section prefix="9">Notwithstanding any statute to the contrary, fines imposed under this section shall be paid into the crime victims' compensation fund established in KRS 346.185. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>