<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.14-060</section_number><catch_line>Known claims against dissolved corporation. </catch_line><order_by>14-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dissolved corporation may dispose of the known claims against it by following the procedure described in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The dissolved corporation shall notify its known claimants in writing of the dissolution at any time after its effective date. The written notice shall: <section prefix="a">Describe information that must be included in a claim; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a mailing address where a claim may be sent; </section><section prefix="c">State the deadline, which may not be fewer than one hundred twenty (120) days from the effective date of the written notice, by which the dissolved corporation must receive the claim; and </section><section prefix="d">State that the claim will be barred if not received by the deadline. </section></section><section prefix="3">A claim against the dissolved corporation shall be barred: <section prefix="a">If a claimant who was given written notice under subsection (2) of this section does not deliver the claim to the dissolved corporation by the deadline; </section><section prefix="b">If a claimant whose claim was rejected by the dissolved corporation does not commence a proceeding to enforce the claim within ninety (90) days from the effective date of the rejection notice. </section></section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this section, "claim" shall not include a contingent liability, a claim based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution or any liability to the Commonwealth or the United States for any state or federal tax liability. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 142, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13452</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>