<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.660</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of commission. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Multidisciplinary Commission on Child Sexual Abuse shall: <section prefix="a">Prepare and issue a model protocol for local multidisciplinary teams regarding investigation and prosecution of child sexual abuse and the role of children's advocacy centers on multidisciplinary teams. </section><section prefix="b">Review and approve protocols prepared by local multidisciplinary teams. </section><section prefix="c">Advise local multidisciplinary teams on the investigation and prosecution of child sexual abuse. </section><section prefix="d">Receive data on child sexual abuse cases collected by the Prosecutors Advisory Council and issue annual reports. </section><section prefix="e">Collect data on the operation of local multidisciplinary teams. </section><section prefix="f">Seek funding to support special projects relating to the operation of local multidisciplinary teams. </section><section prefix="g">Receive and review complaints regarding local multidisciplinary teams, and make appropriate recommendations. </section><section prefix="h">Recommend to the Governor, Legislative Research Commission, and Supreme Court changes in state programs, legislation, administrative regulations, policies, budgets, and treatment and service standards which may facilitate effective intervention of child sexual abuse cases and the investigation and prosecution of perpetrators of child sexual abuse, and which may improve the opportunity for victims of child sexual abuse to receive treatment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Multidisciplinary Commission on Child Sexual Abuse may, within budget limitations, establish and maintain necessary offices, appoint employees, and prescribe the duties and compensation for the appointed employees. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>