<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-100</section_number><catch_line>Loss reserves -- Casualty insurance. </catch_line><order_by>6-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As to casualty insurance transacted by it, each insurer shall maintain at all times reserves in an amount estimated in the aggregate to provide for payment of all losses and claims incurred, whether reported or unreported, which are unpaid and for which the insurer may be liable, and to provide for the expenses of adjustment or settlement of losses and claims. The reserves shall be computed in accordance with regulations from time to time made by the commissioner, after due notice and hearing, upon reasonable consideration of the ascertained experience and the character of such kind of business for the purpose of adequately protecting the insured and the solvency of the insurer. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever the loss and loss expense experience of the insurer show that reserves, calculated in accordance with such regulations, are inadequate, the commissioner may require the insurer to maintain additional reserves. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner may, by regulation, prescribe the manner and form of reporting pertinent information concerning the reserves provided for in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1001, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 16, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 6, sec. 10, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>