<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.8-420</section_number><catch_line>Standards of conduct for officers. </catch_line><order_by>8-420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An officer with discretionary authority shall discharge his duties under that authority: <section prefix="a">In good faith; </section><section prefix="b">On an informed basis; and </section><section prefix="c">In a manner he honestly believes to be in the best interests of the corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">An officer shall be considered to discharge his duties on an informed basis if he makes, with the care an ordinarily prudent person in a like position would exercise under similar circumstances, inquiry into the business and affairs of the corporation, or into a particular action to be taken or decision to be made. </section><section prefix="3">In discharging his duties an officer shall be entitled to rely on information, opinions, reports, or statements, including financial statements and other financial data, if prepared or presented by: <section prefix="a">One (1) or more officers or employees of the corporation whom the officer honestly believes to be reliable and competent in the matters presented; or </section><section prefix="b">Legal counsel, public accountants, or other persons as to matters the officer honestly believes are within the person's professional or expert competence. </section></section><section prefix="4">An officer shall not be considered to be acting in good faith if he has knowledge concerning the matter in question that makes reliance otherwise permitted by subsection (3) of this section unwarranted. </section><section prefix="5">Any action taken as an officer, or any failure to take any action as an officer, shall not be the basis for monetary damages or injunctive relief unless: <section prefix="a">The officer has breached or failed to perform his duties in compliance with this section; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of an action for monetary damages, the breach or failure to perform constitutes willful misconduct or wanton or reckless disregard for the best interests of the corporation or its shareholders. </section></section><section prefix="6">A person bringing an action or monetary damages under this section shall have the burden of proving by clear and convincing evidence the provisions of subsection (5)(a) and (b) of this section, and the burden of proving that the breach or failure to perform was the legal cause of damages suffered by the corporation. </section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this section shall eliminate or limit the liability of any officer for any act or omission occurring prior to July 15, 1988. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 91, effective January 1, 1989 and ch. 224, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><former-codification> KRS 271A.257. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>