<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.035</section_number><catch_line>Scope of administrative regulations -- Specialties -- Limitation of liability -- Power to prescribe -- Exceptions from requirements of chapter. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to dentists. The administrative regulations shall include the classification of and licensure of dentists, by examination or credentials, the licensure of specialists, student limited licenses, faculty limited licenses, reciprocity, retirement of a license, reinstatement of a license, charity licenses, and conscious sedation and anesthesia permits. </section><section prefix="2">Renewal programs shall be organized to include continuing education approved by the board. </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of licensure of specialists the board shall only recognize fields of specialty duly recognized and approved by the American Dental Association. Individuals licensed as specialists shall not practice outside of that specialty except as provided for in charitable dentistry as defined by administrative regulation, during a declared disaster by order of the Governor, or when the special needs of the patient require they be followed past the age of eighteen (18) by a pediatric dentist. </section><section prefix="4">No person licensed under this chapter, who in good faith renders emergency care at the scene of an emergency, shall be liable for any civil damages as a result of any acts or omissions by such person in rendering the emergency care. </section><section prefix="5">Any dentist who serves on any committee, board, commission, or other entity which is duly constituted by any licensed hospital, dental society or association affiliated with the American Dental Association, dental care foundation affiliated with such dental society or association or governmental or quasi-governmental agency for the purpose of reviewing and evaluating the dental acts of other dentists, or dental auxiliary personnel, shall not be required to respond in damages for any action taken by him or her in good faith as a member of such committee, board, commission, or other entity. </section><section prefix="6">Licensed dentists may prescribe any drug necessary within the scope of their practice. </section><section prefix="7">Dentists may sign death certificates the same as physicians, when necessary in the line of their profession. </section><section prefix="8">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to a legally licensed doctor of medicine unless he or she practices dentistry as a specialty. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in this chapter shall apply to a practitioner of dentistry duly licensed by another state or the District of Columbia while making a clinical demonstration before a dental society, convention, association of dentists, or a dental school. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>