<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.150</section_number><catch_line>Policing of fairgrounds and exhibition center. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>The State Fair Board may arrange with the county judge/executive or the officer that has charge of the police force of any county or city in which the state fair is held, for the proper policing of the state fairgrounds, and may arrange with the state for the policing of the state fairgrounds by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The State Fair Board may arrange with the mayor or the officer that has charge of the police force of any county or city in which the exhibition center is located for the proper policing of the exhibition center, and may arrange with the state for the policing of the exhibition center by the Department of Kentucky State Police. If the State Fair Board is unable to arrange with a city, county, or state authority for police protection, it may appoint, or may delegate to any agent or employee the power to appoint, subject to the approval of the State Fair Board, necessary special police to properly police the state fairgrounds and exhibition center. Such police officers are vested with the powers and charged with the duties of peace officers. </text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 275, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618i-6. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11594</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>