<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.24-615</section_number><catch_line>Consideration distributed to eligible members. </catch_line><order_by>24-615</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The total aggregate consideration to be distributed to the eligible members shall be determined under a fair formula. The total aggregate consideration shall not be less than the converting mutual's total surplus or surplus as regards policyholders; plus the value of all nonadmitted assets; plus a reasonable present equity in reserves, if any; minus any adjustments for contributed or borrowed surplus. </section><section prefix="2">The consideration to be distributed to the eligible members shall be cash, stock, or other securities of the former mutual or of an affiliate, additional paid up insurance or annuity benefits, or any combination of these forms of consideration or other forms of consideration described in the plan of conversion and approved by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">The form of consideration to be distributed to a class, category, or group of eligible members may differ from the form of consideration to be distributed to another class, category, or group of eligible members. The choice of the form of consideration may take into account such factors as the type of policies with respect to which the consideration is being distributed, the country or state of residence or tax status of the eligible members, the length of time that eligible members have been members of the converting mutual, or other appropriate factors or circumstances described in the plan of conversion. </section><section prefix="4">Distribution of all or part of the consideration to some or all of the eligible members may be delayed, or restrictions on sale or transfer of any stock or other securities to be distributed to eligible members may be required, for a reasonable period of time following the effective date of the conversion. That period of time shall not exceed six (6) months, unless approved by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1356, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29587</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>