<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.363</section_number><catch_line>Board approval of massage therapy program of instruction -- Requirements -- Continuing education guidelines.   </catch_line><order_by>363</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person, institution, or business entity offering a massage therapy program of instruction shall file a completed application for a certificate of good standing with the board on a form prescribed by the board and pay a fee as specified in KRS 309.357. The completed application shall provide proof acceptable to the board that the following criteria have been met: <section prefix="a">The school is licensed to operate by the Kentucky Commission on Proprietary Education, the Council on Postsecondary Education, or their equivalent in another state; </section><section prefix="b">A curriculum statement showing clock hours devoted to each subject with the following minimums: <section prefix="1">One hundred twenty-five (125) hours of anatomy, physiology, or kinesiology; </section><section prefix="2">A two hundred (200) hour course to include massage theory, technique, and practice focusing on gliding strokes, kneading, direct pressure, deep friction, joint movement, superficial warming techniques, percussion, compression, vibration, jostling, shaking, and rocking; </section><section prefix="3">Two hundred (200) hours of approach to the business of massage, specifically including contraindications, benefits, business, history, ethics, client documentation, legalities of massage, and modality courses designed to meet the school's specific program objectives; </section><section prefix="4">Forty (40) hours of pathology; and </section><section prefix="5">The school may use its discretion in allotting the additional thirty-five (35) curricular hours that are required under KRS 309.358; </section></section><section prefix="c">A listing of instructional staff and their qualifications as follows: <section prefix="1">Instructors of the practical courses shall be licensed massage therapists and shall have three (3) years of experience in the practice of massage therapy; </section><section prefix="2">Instructors of science courses shall be either licensed massage therapists with three (3) years of experience in the practice of massage therapy or have certification or specific higher education in the subject they are teaching; and </section><section prefix="3">Instructors in adjunctive courses shall have subject-specific education and experience. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall accept National Certification Board for Therapeutic Massage and Bodywork guidelines in approving continuing education. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 24, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2003; and ch. 70, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2003).  2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 14, and 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 14, are substantially identical and have been codified together. The phrase "joint movement" in subparagraph (b) 2. of subsection (1) of ch. 70, sec. 14, which passed the General Assembly last, prevails over "joint mobilization" in the same subparagraph of ch. 45, sec. 14. See KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40336</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>