<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.070</section_number><catch_line>Payments for insurance coverage of firefighters permanently and totally disabled in line of duty -- Documentation -- Reduction in payments if firefighter has other coverage -- Procedure upon termination of disability or coverage -- Administrative regulations -- Penalty for providing false information -- Proration if funds insufficient.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a firefighter as defined in KRS 61.315 is, before, on, or after July 15, 2002, permanently and totally disabled as defined in KRS 342.0011 as a direct result of activities in the line of duty, then the firefighter shall be entitled to receive a monthly payment to be paid by the State Treasurer from the general fund appropriation to the police and firefighter-life insurance category contained in miscellaneous appropriations of the state/executive branch budget of: <section prefix="a">Three hundred dollars ($300) to help defray the costs of life insurance; and </section><section prefix="b">Three hundred dollars ($300) to help defray the costs of health insurance. </section></section><section prefix="2">In order to receive the monthly payment, the firefighter must present to the Commission on Fire Protection Personnel Standards and Education: <section prefix="a">A written statement from the fire chief of the fire department under whose command the firefighter was at the time of injury stating the fact that the firefighter was on active duty and on assignment with that fire department when the injury occurred; and </section><section prefix="b">A written statement from at least two (2) licensed and practicing physicians stating that the member is totally and likely to be permanently disabled as defined in KRS 342.0011; and </section><section prefix="c">Proof, in a form satisfactory to the commission, that the firefighter has either or both active life and health insurance policies. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">If a firefighter, either through a settlement of any kind or through any other source, has life insurance provided at no cost, then the firefighter shall not be eligible to receive the life insurance payment described in subsection (1)(a) of this section. If a firefighter receives partial payment of life insurance, and the portion of the payment that the firefighter is responsible for is less than the amount stated in subsection (1) of this section, then the firefighter shall only receive that portion of the payment to pay for the cost of the insurance. </section><section prefix="b">If a firefighter, either through a settlement of any kind or through any other source, has health insurance provided at no cost, then the firefighter shall not be eligible to receive the health insurance payment described in subsection (1)(b) of this section. If a firefighter receives partial payment of health insurance, and the portion of the payment that the firefighter is responsible for is less than the amount stated in subsection (1) of this section, then the firefighter shall only receive that portion of the payment to pay for the cost of the insurance. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the firefighter should no longer be considered permanently and totally disabled as defined in KRS 342.0011, or if either or both life and health insurance policies are terminated, then the firefighter shall within thirty (30) days of that determination notify the Commission on Fire Protection Personnel Standards and Education, in writing, of that fact or facts. The commission shall then terminate the appropriate subsequent payments to that firefighter. A firefighter may continue to receive payments for one (1) type of insurance as long as the firefighter is still permanently and totally disabled and the insurance policy is active. If the firefighter fails to notify the commission within thirty (30) days and receives subsequent payments under this section, the firefighter shall be responsible for repaying any payments provided to the firefighter under this section from the date that the firefighter was no longer considered permanently and totally disabled. </section><section prefix="5">The Commission on Fire Protection Personnel Standards and Education shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A establishing procedures and criteria applicable to the administration of this section by December 31, 2002. </section><section prefix="6">Any firefighter convicted of knowingly providing false information to receive the benefits in subsection (1) of this section shall be guilty of a Class D felony and shall be responsible for repaying the total amount paid to the firefighter, plus interest, under the provisions of this section within a time to be determined by the commission. The firefighter shall also no longer be eligible to receive any payments provided under this section. </section><section prefix="7">In the event sufficient funds do not exist to cover all the financial obligations of this section, then the payments shall be prorated among the participants evenly. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40340</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>