<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.055</section_number><catch_line>State purchasing regulations. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Prior to January 1, 1979, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall publish the initial state purchasing regulations in accordance with current Finance and Administration Cabinet policies and procedures. The initial regulations may be promulgated on an interim basis, without regard to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A, provided, however, that final regulations shall be promulgated pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A within two hundred forty (240) days following the promulgation of the initial regulations. </section><section prefix="2">All additions, deletions, or other modifications of the final purchasing regulations issued pursuant to subsection (1) of this section shall be promulgated by the secretary in accordance with any applicable provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall not delegate his power to issue the state purchasing regulations under subsections (1) and (2) of this section to any other person or agency, and no state purchasing regulations shall be issued except as approved by the secretary. </section><section prefix="4">No state purchasing regulation shall change in any way a contract commitment by the Commonwealth nor of a contractor to the Commonwealth, which was in existence on the effective date of the regulation. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of state purchasing regulations promulgated as authorized herein shall be considered to be incorporated by operation of law in all state contracts. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 12, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1979 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22336</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>