<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.591</section_number><catch_line>Nomination of candidate by petition -- Qualification of candidate through filing of notice of candidacy. </catch_line><order_by>591</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person seeking the endorsement by a political party for the office of President of the United States, or any group organized in this state on behalf of, and with the consent of, the person, may file with the Secretary of State certified petitions signed by five thousand (5,000) persons who, at the time they sign, are registered and qualified voters in the Commonwealth and are affiliated, by registration, with the same political party as the candidate for whom petitions are filed. </section><section prefix="2">The petitions shall be filed by the petitioners with the Secretary of State no later than the last Tuesday in January preceding a presidential preference primary. </section><section prefix="3">The petitions shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the candidate for nomination and the party of which he is a member; and </section><section prefix="b">The name and address of the chairman of the group circulating such petition. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Secretary of State shall determine the sufficiency of petitions filed with him and shall immediately communicate his determination to the chairman of the group which has filed the petitions. </section><section prefix="5">In lieu of the petition requirements of subsections (1) to (4) of this section, a candidate may qualify to appear on the presidential preference primary ballot of his political party by filing with the Secretary of State, no later than the last Tuesday in January preceding a presidential preference primary, a notice of candidacy signed by the candidate and either of the following: <section prefix="a">A certification by the Federal Election Commission that, by the filing deadline, the candidate has qualified for matching federal campaign funds; or </section><section prefix="b">Evidence that, by the filing deadline, the candidate's name is qualified to appear on the presidential preference primary ballot of his political party in at least twenty (20) other states. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Secretary of State shall determine the sufficiency of the documentation provided pursuant to subsection (5) of this section and shall immediately communicate his determination to the candidate or his agent. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective January 29, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 16, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 53, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 431, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> January 29, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27664</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>