<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.280</section_number><catch_line>Examination of mine by properly certified person -- Duties -- Frequency of examinations. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In all mines the licensee, mine manager, or superintendent shall employ one (1) or more properly certified persons. </section><section prefix="2">A properly certified person shall examine carefully, within three (3) hours before each shift enters the mine: <section prefix="a">Every working place; </section><section prefix="b">All places adjacent to live workings; </section><section prefix="c">Every roadway where persons are required to work or travel; </section><section prefix="d">All abandoned panels on the intake; </section><section prefix="e">Every set of seals on the intake; and </section><section prefix="f">All roof falls near active workings on the intake and on the working sections. </section></section><section prefix="3">Before proceeding with the examination he shall see that the air current is traveling its proper course. </section><section prefix="4">A properly certified person shall use approved gas detection devices in the performance of the required examination and shall examine the entrances to all worked-out and abandoned portions adjacent to the intake roadways and working places under his charge where explosive gas is likely to accumulate. </section><section prefix="5">After examination, the properly certified person shall leave at or as close as possible to the face of every place examined the date and time of the examination and his initials as evidence that he has performed his duty. </section><section prefix="6">If an explosive mixture of gas is discovered, the properly certified person shall place a danger signal across the entrance to every place where explosive gas is discovered or where immediate danger is found to exist from any other cause. The signal shall be sufficient warning to ensure that persons do not enter the area. </section><section prefix="7">When the mine is idle and workmen are required to go into the mine, the section, portion, or part of the mine entered must be inspected by a properly certified person within three (3) hours before the workmen enter. </section><section prefix="8">Each week, a properly certified person designated by the mine foreman shall examine each set of seals on the return, all designated intake and return entries, and all escapeways. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 38, effective April 9, 1996. --Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 27. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 16. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 26. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 30, effective March 5, 1952. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 8. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-38. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33008</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>