<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.312</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for license and temporary license. </catch_line><order_by>312</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be eligible for licensure by the board as an interpreter, the applicant shall submit an application which includes: <section prefix="a">An application fee; and </section><section prefix="b">Current certification from a nationally recognized organization at the requisite level for sign language interpreters, oral interpreters, or cued speech transliterators as determined by the board and promulgated by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall issue an interpreter license to an applicant who fulfills these requirements. The front of the license shall clearly list all certifications held by the licensee. </section><section prefix="3">The board may issue a temporary license as an interpreter to an applicant who is certified at a level below that required for licensure in subsection (1) of this section. A temporary license shall be available for a person who is training under the supervision of a licensed interpreter under circumstances defined by the board in administrative regulation. A temporary license is valid for only a certain period until the licensee achieves the minimum level of certification required for licensure under subsection (1) of this section. A temporary license is not renewable although extensions may be granted under circumstances defined by administrative regulation. <section prefix="a">For graduates of a baccalaureate interpreter training program, a temporary license shall be valid for up to one (1) year. </section><section prefix="b">For graduates of an associate of arts interpreter training program, a temporary license shall be valid for up to two (2) years. </section><section prefix="c">For nondegree applicants, a temporary license shall be valid for up to two (2) years. </section></section><section prefix="4">Upon payment of the application fee, the board shall grant licensure to an applicant holding a valid license, certificate, or equivalent issued by another state if it is based upon standards equivalent to or exceeding the standards required by KRS 309.300 to 309.319. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30357</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>