<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">C RESTRUCTURE OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT IN COUNTY CONTAINING CITY OF FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>67C.313</section_number><catch_line>Police officers deemed qualified to continue duties and to be permanent employees -- Probationary officers. </catch_line><order_by>313</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All police officers of whatever rank and title of a consolidated local government police force shall be covered by the provisions of this section, except probationary officers. All officers of a consolidated local government police force on active duty or service as of the effective date of an ordinance creating a consolidated local government police merit system and board, shall be deemed fit and qualified to continue their respective duties of employment on or for the consolidated local government police force without examination or further qualification. </section><section prefix="2">All personnel covered by the provisions of this section, except probationary officers, shall be deemed to be permanent employees subject to their ability to satisfactorily perform their respective duties and further subject to their good behavior. </section><section prefix="3">A probationary officer shall not be included in the merit system until that officer has satisfactorily completed his or her initial probationary period which shall be one (1) year from his or her sworn date. The one (1) year probationary period may be extended for up to six (6) months upon showing of just cause by the chief and approved by the board. </section><section prefix="4">Officers covered by the provisions of KRS 67C.303 and serving promotional probationary periods shall not be deemed excluded from the merit system during the promotional probationary periods. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 5, effective March 18, 2003. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> March 18, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24032</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>