<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="510" order_by="510">SEXUAL OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>510.090</section_number><catch_line>Sodomy in the third degree.   </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of sodomy in the third degree when: <section prefix="a">He or she engages in deviate sexual intercourse with another person who is incapable of consent because he or she is an individual with an intellectual disability; </section><section prefix="b">Being twenty-one (21) years old or more, he or she engages in deviate sexual intercourse with another person less than sixteen (16) years old; or </section><section prefix="c">Being twenty-one (21) years old or more, he or she engages in deviate sexual intercourse with another person less than eighteen (18) years old and for whom he or she provides a foster family home as defined in KRS 600.020; </section><section prefix="d">Being a person in a position of authority or position of special trust, as defined in KRS 532.045, he or she engages in deviate sexual intercourse with a minor less than eighteen (18) years old with whom he or she comes into contact as a result of that position; or </section><section prefix="e">Being a jailer, or an employee, contractor, vendor, or volunteer of the Department of Corrections, Department of Juvenile Justice, or a detention facility as defined in KRS 520.010, or of an entity under contract with either department or a detention facility for the custody, supervision, evaluation, or treatment of offenders, he or she subjects a person who he or she knows is incarcerated, supervised, evaluated, or treated by the Department of Corrections, Department of Juvenile Justice, detention facility, or contracting entity, to deviate sexual intercourse. </section></section><section prefix="2">Sodomy in the third degree is a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 128, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 148, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 32, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 282, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 89, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 148, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40870</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>