<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.517</section_number><catch_line>Mini-truck -- Definition -- Criteria for operation -- Permitted and prohibited uses.   </catch_line><order_by>517</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "mini-truck" means a lightweight Japanese kei class utility vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (5) of this section, a person shall not operate a mini-truck upon any public highway or roadway or upon the right-of-way of any public highway or roadway. </section><section prefix="3">A person shall not operate a mini-truck on private property without the consent of the landowner, tenant, or individual responsible for the property. </section><section prefix="4">A person shall not operate a mini-truck on public property unless the governmental agency responsible for the property has approved the use of mini-trucks. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A person may operate a mini-truck on any two (2) lane public highway in order to cross the highway. In crossing the highway under this paragraph, the operator shall cross the highway at as close to a ninety (90) degree angle as is practical and safe, and shall not travel on the highway for more than two-tenths (2/10) of a mile. </section><section prefix="b">A person may operate a mini-truck on any two (2) lane public highway if the operator is engaged in farm or agricultural-related activities, construction, road maintenance, or snow removal. </section><section prefix="c">The Transportation Cabinet may designate, and a city or county government may designate, those public highways, segments of public highways, and adjoining rights-of-way of public highways under its jurisdiction where mini-trucks that are prohibited may be operated. </section><section prefix="d">A person operating a mini-truck on a public highway under this subsection shall possess a valid operator's license. </section><section prefix="e">A person operating a mini-truck on a public highway under this subsection shall comply with all applicable traffic regulations. </section><section prefix="f">A person shall not operate a mini-truck under this subsection unless the mini-truck has at least two (2) headlights and two (2) taillights, which shall be illuminated at all times the mini-truck is in operation. </section><section prefix="g">A person operating a mini-truck under this subsection shall restrict the operation to daylight hours, except when engaged in snow removal or emergency road maintenance. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42229</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>