<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.010</section_number><catch_line>Purpose and application of chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of this chapter is: <section prefix="a">To provide for the protection of adults who may be suffering from abuse, neglect, or exploitation, and to bring said cases under the purview of the Circuit or District Court; </section><section prefix="b">To provide that any person who becomes aware of such cases shall report them to a representative of the cabinet, thereby causing the protective services of the state to be brought to bear in an effort to protect the health and welfare of these adults in need of protective services and to prevent abuse, neglect, or exploitation; and </section><section prefix="c">To promote coordination and efficiency among agencies and entities that have a responsibility to respond to the abuse, neglect, or exploitation of adults. </section></section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall apply to the protection of adults who are the victims of abuse, neglect, or exploitation inflicted by a person or caretaker. It shall not apply to victims of domestic violence unless the victim is also an adult as defined in KRS 209.020(4). </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 200, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(11/9/93).  A prior reference to the "department" in this statute was changed to "cabinet" pursuant to 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 50(5), and KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8180</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>