<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">A SPECIAL PURPOSE GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES </unit></structure><section_number>65A.020Duties</section_number><catch_line>of Department for Local Government relating to forms, reporting, and online access -- Information to be submitted by special purpose governmental entities -- Failure to submit information -- Administrative regulations -- Registry -- Registration fee -- Annual report.   </catch_line><order_by>020Duties</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The DLG shall: <section prefix="a">On or before March 1, 2014, make the necessary reporting and certification forms, online reporting portal, and online central registry available for reporting by special purpose governmental entities. The portal and registry shall serve as a unified location for the reporting of and access to administrative and financial information by special purpose governmental entities; and </section><section prefix="b">On or before October 1, 2014, make available online public access to administrative and financial information reported by special purpose governmental entities. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">For each fiscal period beginning on or after July 1, 2014, all special purpose governmental entities shall annually submit to the DLG the information required by this section. The information shall be submitted in accordance with this section, at the time, and in the form and format required by the DLG. The information submitted shall include at a minimum the following: <section prefix="1">Administrative information: <section prefix="a">The name, address, and, if applicable, the term and appointing authority for each board member of the governing body of the entity; </section><section prefix="b">The fiscal year of the entity; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Revised Statute and, if applicable, the local government ordinance and interlocal agreement under which the entity was established; the date of establishment; the establishing entity; and the statute or statutes, local government ordinance, or interlocal agreement under which the entity operates, if different from the statute or statutes, ordinance, or agreement under which it was established; </section><section prefix="d">The mailing address and telephone number and, if applicable, the Web site uniform resource locator (URL) of the entity; </section><section prefix="e">The operational boundaries and service area of the entity and the services provided by the entity; </section><section prefix="f">i. A listing of all the most significant taxes or fees imposed and collected by the entity, including the rates or amounts charged for the reporting period and the statutory or other source of authority for the levy of the tax or fee. ii. As used in this subdivision, "most significant taxes or fees" means the five (5) taxes or fees levied by the entity that produce the most tax and fee revenue for the entity, provided that if the top five (5) revenue-producing taxes and fees do not produce at least eighty-five percent (85%) of all tax and fee revenues received by the entity, additional taxes and fees shall be listed until the taxes and fees listed produce at least eighty-five percent (85%) of all tax and fee revenues of the entity. If an entity levies fewer than five (5) taxes and fees, the entity shall list all taxes and fees levied; </section><section prefix="g">The primary contact for the entity for purposes of communication from the DLG; </section><section prefix="h">The code of ethics that applies to the entity, and whether the entity has adopted additional ethics provisions; </section><section prefix="i">A listing of all federal, state, and local governmental entities that have oversight authority over the special purpose governmental entity or to which the special purpose governmental entity submits reports, data, or information; and </section><section prefix="j">Any other related administrative information required by the DLG; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Financial information: <section prefix="a">i. The most recent adopted budget of the entity for the upcoming fiscal year; ii. After the close of each fiscal year, a comparison of the budget to actual revenues and expenditures for each fiscal year, including any amendments made throughout the fiscal year to the budget originally submitted; iii. Completed audits or attestation engagements as provided in KRS 65A.030; and iv. Other financial oversight reports or information required by the DLG. </section><section prefix="b">In lieu of the submissions required by subdivision a.i., ii., and iv. of this subparagraph: i. A federally regulated municipal utility shall submit, after the close of each fiscal year, the monthly balance, revenue, and expense report required by the federal regulator, which constitutes year-end data; and ii. A public utility established pursuant to KRS 96.740 that is not a federally regulated municipal utility shall submit after the close of each fiscal year a report that includes the same information, in the same format as is required for federally regulated municipal utilities under subpart i. of this subdivision. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">The provisions of KRS 65A.040 shall apply when a special purpose governmental entity fails to submit the information required by this section in a timely manner, or submits information that does not comply with the requirements and standards established by this section and the DLG. To facilitate the enforcement of these provisions, the DLG shall establish and maintain an online list of due dates for the filing of reports, audit certifications, and information for each special purpose governmental entity. </section><section prefix="c">The provisions of this subsection shall be in addition to, and shall not supplant or replace any reporting or filing requirements established by other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The DLG shall, by administrative regulation adopted pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, develop standard forms, protocols, timeframes, and due dates for the submission of information by special purpose governmental entities. All information shall be submitted electronically; however, the DLG may allow submission by alternative means, with the understanding that the DLG shall be responsible for converting the information to a format that will make it accessible through the registry. </section><section prefix="b">In an effort to reduce duplicative submissions to different governmental entities and agencies, during the development of the forms, protocols, timeframes, and due dates, the DLG shall consult with other governmental entities and agencies that may use the information submitted by special purpose governmental entities, and may include the information those agencies and entities need to the extent possible. </section><section prefix="c">As an alternative to completing and submitting any standard form developed by the DLG for the reporting of financial information, federally regulated municipal utilities and public utilities established pursuant to KRS 96.740 that are not federally regulated municipal utilities may elect to satisfy the reporting requirements established by subsection (2)(a)2. of this section for the public power components of their operations by reporting the financial information related to their electric system accounts in accordance with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission's Uniform System of Accounts. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Beginning October 1, 2014, all information submitted by special purpose governmental entities under this section shall be publicly available through the registry. The registry shall be updated at least monthly, but may be updated more frequently at the discretion of the DLG. The registry shall include a notation indicating the date of the most recent update. </section><section prefix="b">The registry shall be in a searchable format and shall, at a minimum, allow a search by county, by special purpose governmental entity name, and by type of entity. </section><section prefix="c">To the extent possible, the registry shall be linked to or accessed through the Web site established pursuant to KRS 42.032 to provide public access to expenditure records of the executive branch of state government. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">To offset the costs incurred by the DLG in maintaining and administering the registry, the costs incurred in providing education for the governing bodies and employees of special purpose governmental entities as required by KRS 65A.060, and the costs incurred by the DLG and the Auditor of Public Accounts in responding to and acting upon noncompliant special purpose governmental entities under KRS 65A.040, excluding costs associated with conducting audits or special examinations, each special purpose governmental entity shall pay a registration fee to the DLG on an annual basis at the time of registration under this section. </section><section prefix="b">The initial annual fee shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">For special purpose governmental entities with annual revenue from all sources of less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), twenty-five dollars ($25); </section><section prefix="2">For special purpose governmental entities with annual revenues from all sources of at least one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) but less than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000), two hundred fifty dollars ($250); and </section><section prefix="3">For special purpose governmental entities with annual revenues of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) or greater, five hundred dollars ($500). </section></section><section prefix="c">If the costs of administering and maintaining the registry, providing education, and enforcing compliance change over time, the fee and tiered structure established by paragraph (b) of this subsection may be adjusted one (1) time by the DLG through the promulgation of an administrative regulation under KRS Chapter 13A. The rate, if adjusted, shall be set at a level no greater than a level that is expected to generate sufficient revenue to offset the actual cost of maintaining and administering the registry, providing education for the governing bodies and employees of special purpose governmental entities, and enforcing compliance. </section><section prefix="d">The portion of the registration fee attributable to expenses incurred by the Auditor of Public Accounts for duties and services other than conducting audits or special examinations shall be collected by the DLG and transferred to the Auditor of Public Accounts on a quarterly basis. Prior to the transfer of funds, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall submit an invoice detailing the actual costs incurred, which shall be the amount transferred; however, the amount transferred to the Auditor of Public Accounts under the initial fee established by paragraph (b) of this section shall not exceed the annual amount agreed to between the DLG and the Auditor of Public Accounts. </section><section prefix="e"><section prefix="1">In determining the annual fee due from a special purpose governmental entity, the DLG may exclude revenues received by the special purpose governmental entity if: <section prefix="a">The revenues constitute nonrecurring, nonoperating grants for the purpose of capital asset acquisition, capital construction, disaster recovery efforts, or other one (1) time purposes as determined by the DLG; and </section><section prefix="b">The special purpose governmental entity requests, in writing to the DLG and for each fiscal year it receives the revenue in question, that the revenues in question not be included in determining its annual revenues. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any receipts excluded under this paragraph shall still be reported as required under subsection (2)(a)2. of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">By October 1, 2014, and on or before each October 1 thereafter, the DLG shall file an annual report with the Legislative Research Commission detailing the compliance of special purpose governmental entities with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. The Legislative Research Commission shall refer the report to the Interim Joint Committee on Local Government for review. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective March 19, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, effective March 21, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/19/2014). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 11 provides that the amendments to this statute made in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, shall apply retroactively beginning January 1, 2014. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>