<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 136.500 to 136.575. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>As used in KRS 136.500 to 136.575, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Billing address" means the location indicated in the books and records of the financial institution, on the first day of the taxable year or the date in the taxable year when the customer relationship began, as the address where any notice, statement, or bill relating to a customer's account is mailed; </section><section prefix="2">"Borrower located in this state" means a borrower, other than a credit card holder, that is engaged in a trade or business that maintains its commercial domicile in this state or a borrower that is not engaged in a trade or business; </section><section prefix="3">"Credit card holder located in this state" means a credit card holder whose billing address is in this state; </section><section prefix="4">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="5">"Commercial domicile" means: <section prefix="a">The location from which the trade or business is principally managed and directed; or </section><section prefix="b">The state of the United States or the District of Columbia from which the financial institution's trade or business in the United States is principally managed and directed, if a financial institution is organized under the laws of a foreign country, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any territory or possession of the United States. </section></section> It shall be presumed, subject to rebuttal, that the location from which the financial institution's trade or business is principally managed and directed is the state of the United States or the District of Columbia to which the greatest number of employees are regularly connected or out of which they are working, irrespective of where the services of the employees are performed, as of the last day of the taxable year; <section prefix="6">"Compensation" means wages, salaries, commissions, and any other form of remuneration paid to employees for personal services that are included in the employee's gross income under the Internal Revenue Code. In the case of employees not subject to the Internal Revenue Code, the determination of whether the payments would constitute gross income to the employees under the Internal Revenue Code shall be made as though the employees were subject to the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="7">"Credit card" means credit, travel, or entertainment card; </section><section prefix="8">"Credit card issuer's reimbursement fee" means the fee a financial institution receives from a merchant's bank because one (1) of the persons to whom the financial institution has issued a credit card has charged merchandise or services to the credit card; </section><section prefix="9">"Employee" means, with respect to a particular financial institution, "employee" as defined in Section 3121(d) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="10">"Financial institution" means: <section prefix="a">A national bank organized as a body corporate and existing or in the process of organizing as a national bank association pursuant to the provisions of the National Bank Act, 12 U.S.C. secs. 21 et seq., in effect on December 31, 1997, exclusive of any amendments made subsequent to that date; </section><section prefix="b">Any bank or trust company incorporated or organized under the laws of any state, except a banker's bank organized under KRS 286.3-135; </section><section prefix="c">Any corporation organized under the provisions of 12 U.S.C. secs. 611 to 631, in effect on December 31, 1997, exclusive of any amendments made subsequent to that date, or any corporation organized after December 31, 1997, that meets the requirements of 12 U.S.C. secs. 611 to 631, in effect on December 31, 1997; or </section><section prefix="d">Any agency or branch of a foreign depository as defined in 12 U.S.C. sec. 3101, in effect on December 31, 1997, exclusive of any amendments made subsequent to that date, or any agency or branch of a foreign depository established after December 31, 1997, that meets the requirements of 12 U.S.C. sec. 3101 in effect on December 31, 1997; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Gross rents" means the actual sum of money or other consideration payable for the use or possession of property. <section prefix="a">"Gross rents" includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">Any amount payable for the use or possession of real property or tangible property, whether designated as a fixed sum of money or as a percentage of receipts, profits, or otherwise; </section><section prefix="2">Any amount payable as additional rent or in lieu of rent, such as interest, taxes, insurance, repairs, or any other amount required to be paid by the terms of a lease or other arrangement; and </section><section prefix="3">A proportionate part of the cost of any improvement to real property made by or on behalf of the financial institution which reverts to the owner or lessor upon termination of a lease or other arrangement. The amount to be included in gross rents is the amount of amortization or depreciation allowed in computing the taxable income base for the taxable year. However, where a building is erected on leased land by or on behalf of the financial institution, the value of the land is determined by multiplying the gross rent by eight (8) and the value of the building is determined in the same manner as if owned by the financial institution; </section></section><section prefix="b">The following are not included in the term "gross rents": <section prefix="1">Reasonable amounts payable as separate charges for water and electric service furnished by the lessor; </section><section prefix="2">Reasonable amounts payable as service charges for janitorial services furnished by the lessor; </section><section prefix="3">Reasonable amounts payable for storage, if these amounts are payable for space not designated and not under the control of the financial institution; and </section><section prefix="4">That portion of any rental payment which is applicable to the space subleased from the financial institution and not used by it; </section></section></section><section prefix="12">"Internal Revenue Code" means the Internal Revenue Code, Title 26 U.S.C., in effect on December 31, 2001, exclusive of any amendments made subsequent to that date; </section><section prefix="13">"Loan" means any extension of credit resulting from direct negotiations between the financial institution and its customer, and the purchase, in whole or in part, of the extension of credit from another. Loans include participations, syndications, and leases treated as loans for federal income tax purposes. Loans shall not include properties treated as loans under Section 595 of the Internal Revenue Code, futures or forward contracts, options, notional principal contracts such as swaps, credit card receivables, including purchased credit card relationships, noninterest-bearing balances due from depository institutions, cash items in the process of collection, federal funds sold, securities purchased under agreements to resell, assets held in a trading account, securities, interests in a real estate mortgage investment company, or other mortgage-backed or asset-backed security, and other similar items; </section><section prefix="14">"Loan secured by real property" means a loan or other obligation for which fifty percent (50%) or more of the aggregate value of the collateral used to secure the loan or other obligation, when valued at fair market value as of the time the original loan or obligation was incurred, was real property; </section><section prefix="15">"Merchant discount" means the fee or negotiated discount charged to a merchant by the financial institution for the privilege of participating in a program where a credit card is accepted in payment for merchandise or services sold to the card holder; </section><section prefix="16">"Person" means an individual, estate, trust, partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or any other business entity; </section><section prefix="17">"Principal base of operations" means: <section prefix="a">With respect to transportation property, the place from which the property is regularly directed or controlled; and </section><section prefix="b">With respect to an employee: <section prefix="1">The place the employee regularly starts work and to which the employee customarily returns in order to receive instructions from his or her employer; or </section><section prefix="2">If the place referred to in subparagraph 1. of this paragraph does not exist, the place the employee regularly communicates with customers or other persons; or </section><section prefix="3">If the place referred to in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph does not exist, the place the employee regularly performs any other functions necessary to the exercise of the employee's trade or profession at some other point or points; </section></section></section><section prefix="18">"Real property owned" and "tangible personal property owned" mean real and tangible personal property, respectively, on which the financial institution may claim depreciation for federal income tax purposes, or property to which the financial institution holds legal title and on which no other person may claim depreciation for federal income tax purposes or could claim depreciation if subject to federal income tax. Real and tangible personal property do not include coin, currency, or property acquired in lieu of or pursuant to a foreclosure; </section><section prefix="19">"Regular place of business" means an office at which the financial institution carries on its business in a regular and systematic manner and which is continuously maintained, occupied, and used by employees of the financial institution; </section><section prefix="20">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, or any foreign country; </section><section prefix="21">"Syndication" means an extension of credit in which two (2) or more persons fund and each person is at risk only up to a specified percentage of the total extension of credit or up to a specified dollar amount; </section><section prefix="22">"Taxable year" means calendar year 1996 and every calendar year thereafter; </section><section prefix="23">"Transportation property" means vehicles and vessels capable of moving under their own power, such as aircraft, trains, water vessels, and motor vehicles, as well as any equipment or containers attached to the property, such as rolling stock, barges, or trailers; </section><section prefix="24">"United States obligations" means all obligations of the United States exempt from taxation under 31 U.S.C. sec. 3124(a) or exempt under the United States Constitution or any federal statute, including the obligations of any instrumentality or agency of the United States that are exempt from state or local taxation under the United States Constitution or any statute of the United States; and </section><section prefix="25">"Kentucky obligations" means all obligations of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, its counties, municipalities, taxing districts, and school districts, exempt from taxation under the Kentucky Revised Statutes and the Constitution of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 330, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 1, effective April 7, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 instructs the Reviser of Statutes to adjust KRS references throughout the statutes to conform with the 2006 renumbering of the Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. Such an adjustment has been made in this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28565</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>