<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.725</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 150.725 to 150.735. </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text>As used in KRS 150.725 to 150.735: <section prefix="1">"Permit" means a permit to hold captive cervids; </section><section prefix="2">"Applicant" means a person or entity who has applied to the department for a permit to hold captive cervids; </section><section prefix="3">"Application" means an application to obtain a permit to hold captive cervids; </section><section prefix="4">"Hold" means to confine to a facility regulated under KRS 150.725 to 150.735; </section><section prefix="5">"Import" means to knowingly bring a captive cervid into the state for the purpose of that captive cervid remaining in the state or being slaughtered in the state. "Import" shall not include transporting a captive cervid into the state for the purpose of transporting that captive cervid through the state to a location out of the state. A captive cervid specified in this subsection shall be deemed to be in transit; and </section><section prefix="6">"In transit" means to transport a captive cervid through this Commonwealth by a direct route and in a continuous manner from a location out of state to another location out of state. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal numbering system in this statute, inserting subsection numbers [(1), (2), and (3)] in place of paragraph designations [(a), (b), and (c)] and deleting the subsection number at the beginning of the statute. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2062</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>