<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.330</section_number><catch_line>Turning and right-of-way at intersections. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When two (2) vehicles approach or enter an intersection from different roadways at approximately the same time, the operator of the vehicle on the left shall yield the right-of-way to the vehicle on the right. </section><section prefix="2">The right-of-way rule declared in subsection (1) is modified at highways and through intersections and as otherwise stated in this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">Preferential right-of-way may be indicated by stop signs or yield signs. The state highway commissioner, with reference to state highways, and local authorities, with reference to other highways under their jurisdiction, may designate any intersection as a stop intersection or as a yield intersection and erect stop signs or yield signs at one (1) or more entrances to such intersections. </section><section prefix="4">Except when directed to proceed by a police officer, every operator of a vehicle approaching a stop sign shall stop at a clearly marked stop line but, if none, before entering the crosswalk on the near side of the intersection or, if none, then at the point nearest the intersecting roadway where the operator has view of approaching traffic on the intersecting roadway before entering it. After having stopped, the operator shall yield the right-of-way to any vehicle in the intersection or approaching on another roadway so closely as to constitute an immediate hazard during the time when such operator is moving across or within the intersection or junction of roadways. </section><section prefix="5">The operator of a vehicle approaching a yield sign shall, in obedience to such sign, slow down to a speed reasonable for the existing conditions and, if required for safety to stop, shall stop at a clearly marked stop line but, if none, before entering the crosswalk on the near side of the intersection or, if none, then at the point nearest the intersecting roadway where the operator has a view of approaching traffic on the intersecting roadway before entering it. After slowing and stopping, the operator shall yield the right-of-way to any vehicle in the intersection or approaching on another roadway so closely as to constitute an immediate hazard during the time such operator is moving across or within the intersection or junction of roadways; provided, however, that if such an operator is involved in a collision with a vehicle in the intersection or junction of roadways after driving past a yield sign without stopping, such collision shall be deemed prima facie evidence of his failure to yield right-of-way. </section><section prefix="6">The operator of a vehicle intending to turn shall do so as follows: <section prefix="a">Right turns - both the approach for a right turn and a right turn shall be made as close as practicable to the right-hand curb or edge of the roadway; </section><section prefix="b">Left turns - the operator of a vehicle intending to turn left shall approach the turn in the extreme left-hand lane lawfully available to traffic moving in the direction of travel of such vehicle. Whenever practicable, the left turn shall be made to the left of the center of the intersection and so as to leave the intersection or other location in the extreme right-hand lane lawfully available to traffic moving in the same direction as such vehicle on the roadway being entered. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Transportation Cabinet and local authorities in their respective jurisdictions may cause official traffic control devices to be placed and thereby require and direct that a different course from that specified in this section be traveled by turning vehicles and, when such devices are so placed, no operator shall turn a vehicle other than as directed and required by such devices. </section><section prefix="8">The operator of any vehicle shall not turn such vehicle so as to proceed in the opposite direction unless such movement can be made in safety without interfering with other traffic. </section><section prefix="9">The operator of a vehicle intending to turn to the left within an intersection or into an alley, private road, or driveway shall yield the right-of-way to any vehicle approaching from the opposite direction which is within the intersection or so close thereto as to constitute an immediate hazard. </section><section prefix="10">The operator of a vehicle about to enter or cross a roadway from any place other than another roadway shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles approaching on the roadway to be entered or crossed. </section><section prefix="11">On highways with a center lane restricted for left turns off the highway by vehicles proceeding in both directions: <section prefix="a">A left turn shall not be made from any other lane; and </section><section prefix="b">A vehicle shall not be driven in a center lane as described in this subsection except when preparing for or making a left turn off the highway or merging onto the highway after making a left turn from a side road or other entrance. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 144, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-37, 2739g-42. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6370</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>