<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-650</section_number><catch_line>Source separation and collection program for waste materials -- Use of funds received -- Resource conservation and recovery fund. </catch_line><order_by>10-650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall assume the primary responsibility in state government for implementing a source separation and collection program for waste materials generated as a result of state agency operations, including, at a minimum, aluminum, high grade office paper, and corrugated paper. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall establish procedures for collection and storage of recovered material and contractual or other arrangements for transportation and purchase of recovered materials. Every state agency of the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of state government and all state-supported institutions of higher education, in cooperation with the cabinet, shall develop a plan to conduct source separation and collection activities for recovered materials. </section><section prefix="3">A state agency or institution may elect to operate its own source separation program upon review and approval by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall take or cause to be taken such actions as may be necessary to: <section prefix="a">Identify the geographical location of existing or potential markets for recovered materials and energy generated; </section><section prefix="b">Identify the economic and technical barriers to the use of recovered materials and energy generated; </section><section prefix="c">Identify sound technologies, techniques, and processes for resource recovery and energy generated applicable to both urban and rural areas of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Encourage the development of new uses for recovered materials; and </section><section prefix="e">Encourage and promote the development of new markets for recovered materials. </section></section><section prefix="5">Funds received by the Energy and Environment Cabinet from the source separation and collection program as described in this section shall be utilized by the cabinet to defray the cost of conducting the activities outlined in this section. Funds received by any other state agency or institution from an approved source separation collection program may be used to offset costs of the program. Any moneys generated by the cabinet or other state agencies or institutions in excess of the amounts needed to conduct these activities shall be placed in the resource conservation and recovery fund and be used for other litter abatement activities. </section><section prefix="6">There is created within the State Treasury a trust and agency fund, which shall not lapse, to be known as the resource conservation and recovery fund. Any appropriations, gifts, grants or program revenues received by the cabinet relating to resource recovery and litter abatement shall be deposited in the fund. Moneys in the fund shall be used for resource recovery and litter abatement activities. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 357, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 61, effective February 26, 1991. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 186, sec. 22, effective March 29, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.902, and also previously codified as KRS 224.217. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10332</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>