<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.350</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45.351 to 45.359 unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Block grant" means any federal block grant authorized by the federal Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 (P.L. 97-35) and any subsequent amendments thereto and any federal block grant authorized by the United States Congress after July 1, 1983. </section><section prefix="2">"Commission" means the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="3">"Designated review body" means either: <section prefix="a">Any interim joint committee, as designated by the Commission at any time when the General Assembly is not in session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review; or </section><section prefix="b">Any interim joint committee, as designated by the Commission at any time when the General Assembly is not in session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review plus the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue; or </section><section prefix="c">Any standing committee, as designated by the Committee on Committees during any legislative session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review; or </section><section prefix="d">Any standing committee, as designated by the Committee on Committees during any legislative session, whose subject jurisdiction  relates to the block grant under review plus the Senate and House standing committees on appropriations and revenue. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Federal administering agency" means any agency of the United States government administering any block grant. </section><section prefix="5">"State administering agency" means any agency of the Commonwealth submitting an application for block grant funding to the secretary or chief public official of the federal administering agency. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>