<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-725</section_number><catch_line>Minimum contract provisions. </catch_line><order_by>9-725</order_by><text>Transactions between a reinsurance intermediary manager and the reinsurer it represents in such capacity shall only be entered into pursuant to a written contract, specifying the responsibilities of each party, which shall be approved by the reinsurer's board of directors. At least thirty (30) days before the reinsurer assumes or cedes business through such producer, a true copy of the contract approved by the reinsurer's board of directors shall be filed with the commissioner for approval. The contract shall, at a minimum, contain provisions that: <section prefix="1">The reinsurer may terminate the contract for cause upon written notice to the reinsurance intermediary manager. The reinsurer may suspend the authority of the reinsurance intermediary manager to assume or cede business during the pendency of any dispute regarding the cause for termination; </section><section prefix="2">The reinsurance intermediary manager shall render accounts to the reinsurer accurately detailing all material transactions, including information necessary to support all commissions, charges, and other fees received by, or owing to, the reinsurance intermediary manager, and remit all funds due under the contract to the reinsurer on not less than a monthly basis; </section><section prefix="3">All funds collected for the reinsurer's account shall be held by the reinsurance intermediary manager in a fiduciary capacity in a bank which is a qualified United States financial institution. The reinsurance intermediary manager may retain no more than three (3) months estimated claims payment and allocated loss adjustment expenses. The reinsurance intermediary manager shall maintain a separate bank account for each reinsurer that it represents; </section><section prefix="4">For at least ten (10) years after expiration of each contract of reinsurance transacted by the reinsurance intermediary manager, the reinsurance intermediary manager shall keep a complete record for each transaction showing: <section prefix="a">The type of contract, limits, underwriting restrictions, classes or risks, and territory; </section><section prefix="b">Period of coverage, including effective and expiration dates, cancellation provisions and notice required for cancellation; and disposition of outstanding reserves on covered risks; </section><section prefix="c">Reporting and settlement requirements of balances; </section><section prefix="d">Rate used to compute the reinsurance premium; </section><section prefix="e">Names and addresses of reinsurers; </section><section prefix="f">Rates of all reinsurance commissions, including the commissions on any retrocessions handled by the reinsurance intermediary manager; </section><section prefix="g">Related correspondence and memoranda; </section><section prefix="h">Proof of placement; </section><section prefix="i">Details regarding retrocessions handled by the reinsurance intermediary manager, as permitted by KRS 304.9-735(4), including the identity of retrocessionaires and percentage of each contract assumed or ceded; </section><section prefix="j">Financial records, including, but not limited to, premium and loss accounts; and </section><section prefix="k">When the reinsurance intermediary manager places a reinsurance contract on behalf of a ceding insurer: <section prefix="1">Directly from any assuming reinsurer, written evidence that the assuming reinsurer has agreed to assume the risk; and </section><section prefix="2">If placed through a representative of the assuming reinsurer, other than an employee, written evidence that the reinsurer has delegated binding authority to the representative; </section></section></section><section prefix="5">The reinsurer shall have access to and the right to copy all accounts and records maintained by the reinsurance intermediary manager related to its business in a form usable by the reinsurer; </section><section prefix="6">The contract shall not be assigned in whole or in part by the reinsurance intermediary manager; </section><section prefix="7">The reinsurance intermediary manager shall comply with the written underwriting and rating standards established by the insurer for the acceptance, rejection, or cession of all risks; </section><section prefix="8">Set forth the rates, terms, and purposes of commissions, charges, and other fees which the reinsurance intermediary manager may levy against the reinsurer; </section><section prefix="9">If the contract permits the reinsurance intermediary manager to settle claims on behalf of the reinsurer: <section prefix="a">All claims shall be reported to the reinsurer in a timely manner; </section><section prefix="b">A copy of the claim file shall be sent to the reinsurer at its request or as soon as it becomes known that the claim: <section prefix="1">Has the potential to exceed the lesser of an amount determined by the commissioner or the limit set by the reinsurer; </section><section prefix="2">Involves a coverage dispute; </section><section prefix="3">May exceed the reinsurance intermediary manager's claims settlement authority; </section><section prefix="4">Is open for more than six (6) months; or </section><section prefix="5">Is closed by payment of the lesser of an amount set by the commissioner or an amount set by the reinsurer; </section></section><section prefix="c">All claim files shall be the joint property of the reinsurer and the reinsurance intermediary manager. However, upon an order of liquidation of the reinsurer, the files shall become the sole property of the reinsurer or its estate, but the reinsurance intermediary manager shall have reasonable access to and the right to copy the files; and </section><section prefix="d">Any settlement authority granted to the reinsurance intermediary manager may be terminated for cause upon the reinsurer's written notice to the reinsurance intermediary manager or upon the termination of the contract. The reinsurer may suspend the settlement authority during the pendency of the dispute regarding the cause of termination; </section></section><section prefix="10">If the contract provides for a sharing of interim profits by the reinsurance intermediary manager, that the interim profits shall not be paid until one (1) year after the end of each underwriting period for property business and five (5) years after the end of each underwriting period for casualty business, or a later period set by the commissioner for specified lines of insurance, and not until the adequacy of reserves on remaining claims has been verified pursuant to KRS 304.9-735(3); </section><section prefix="11">The reinsurance intermediary manager shall annually provide the reinsurer with a statement of its financial condition prepared by an independent certified accountant; </section><section prefix="12">The reinsurer shall at least semiannually conduct an on-site review of the underwriting and claims processing operations of the reinsurance intermediary manager; </section><section prefix="13">The reinsurance intermediary manager shall disclose to the reinsurer any relationship it has with any insurer prior to ceding or assuming any business with such reinsurer pursuant to this contract; and </section><section prefix="14">The acts of the reinsurance intermediary manager shall be deemed to be the acts of the reinsurer on whose behalf it is acting. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1086, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16974</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>