<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.415</section_number><catch_line>Constitutional amendments. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly may state the substance of the amendment proposed to the Constitution of Kentucky in the form of a question in a manner calculated to inform the electorate of the substance of the amendment. When an amendment to the Constitution has been proposed by the General Assembly, the Secretary of State shall cause the question calculated to inform the electorate of the substance of the amendment which is prepared by the General Assembly or the Attorney General to be published at least one (1) time in a newspaper of general circulation published in this state, and shall also cause to be published at the same time and in the same manner the fact that the amendment will be submitted to the voters for their acceptance or rejection at the next regular election at which members of the General Assembly are to be voted for. The publication shall be made not later than the first Tuesday in August preceding the election at which the amendment is to be voted on. </section><section prefix="2">The Attorney General shall, if the General Assembly has not already done so, state the substance of an amendment to the Constitution of Kentucky which has been proposed by the General Assembly in the form of a question in a manner calculated to inform the electorate of the substance of the amendment, and, not later than fourteen (14) days preceding the first Tuesday in August preceding the next regular election at which members of the General Assembly are to be chosen, shall certify the question to the Secretary of State to be placed on the voting machine. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State, not later than the second Monday after the second Tuesday in August preceding the next regular election at which members of the General Assembly are to be chosen in a year in which there is not an election for President and Vice President of the United States, or not later than the Thursday after the first Tuesday in September preceding a regular election in a year in which there is an election for President and Vice President of the United States, shall certify the substance of the amendment, as stated and certified by the General Assembly or by the Attorney General, to the county clerk of each county, and the county clerk shall have the substance of the amendment, as so certified, indicated on the voting machines. </section><section prefix="4">The votes cast for and against the amendment shall be counted, canvassed, and certified to the Secretary of State in the same manner as the votes cast for any officer elective by the votes of the whole state. If a majority of the votes cast on the question are for the amendment, it shall become a part of the Constitution. </section><section prefix="5">The expenses of the publications provided for in this section shall be paid as are the expenses of other publications that the Secretary of State is required to make in connection with elections. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 461, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 23, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 127, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27641</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>