<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.160</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for issuance of license -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No manufacturer's or wholesaler's license shall be issued pursuant to this chapter unless the applicant therefor has furnished satisfactory proof: <section prefix="a">That the applicant is in compliance with all applicable federal and state laws and regulations relating to controlled substances and is of good moral character or, if the applicant be an association or corporation that the managing officers are of good moral character; </section><section prefix="b">That the applicant is equipped as to land, buildings, and security to properly carry on the business described in his application. </section></section><section prefix="2">No license shall be granted to any person who has been convicted of a misdemeanor involving any controlled substance or who has been convicted of any felony. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may suspend or revoke any license for cause. </section><section prefix="4">Upon appeal of any action taken under authority of this section, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 540, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 483, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 129, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 17. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>