<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.655</section_number><catch_line>Application of KRS 365.650 to 365.695. </catch_line><order_by>655</order_by><text>The provisions of KRS 365.650 to 365.695 shall not apply to: <section prefix="1">Sales at wholesale to retail merchants by commercial selling agents in the usual course of business; </section><section prefix="2">Wholesale trade shows or conventions; </section><section prefix="3">Sales of goods, wares or merchandise by sample catalogue or brochure for future delivery; </section><section prefix="4">Participants in fairs and convention center activities when the participants' businesses are conducted primarily for amusement or entertainment; </section><section prefix="5">Any general sale, fair, auction or bazaar sponsored by any religious, educational, public service or charitable organization; </section><section prefix="6">Garage sales held on premises devoted to residential use; </section><section prefix="7">Sales of crafts or items made by hand and sold or offered for sale by the person making such crafts or handmade items; </section><section prefix="8">Sales of locally grown agricultural products; </section><section prefix="9">Sales made by a seller at residential premises pursuant to an invitation issued by the owner or legal occupant of such premises; </section><section prefix="10">Sheriffs, constables, or other public or court officers, or any other person or persons acting under the direction or authority of any court, state or federal, selling goods, wares or merchandise in the course of their official duties; </section><section prefix="11">Flea market vendors who can demonstrate compliance with KRS 139.550; </section><section prefix="12">Professions and occupations licensed and regulated by the state when the activities are performed within the scope of their respective statutory and regulatory authority; and </section><section prefix="13">Temporary sales at another location by businesses with a permanent business location within the State of Kentucky. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34831</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>