<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.215</section_number><catch_line>Malt beverage supplier's license authorizing importation of malt beverages -- Nonresident entities eligible for license -- Licenses and limited licenses -- Exemption from notice requirements of KRS 243.360.   </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An out-of-state brewer, distributor, importer for a brewer, or importer of a non-United States brand of malt beverage may obtain a malt beverage supplier's license for importing a malt beverage product into Kentucky if it is: <section prefix="a">Licensed to do business in the state in which it is located; and </section><section prefix="b">Registered with the Kentucky Department of Revenue. </section></section><section prefix="2">An entity listed in subsection (1) of this section who wishes to import more than twenty-five thousand (25,000) barrels or seven hundred seventy-five thousand (775,000) gallons of malt beverage shall: <section prefix="a">Apply for an out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license on an application provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Submit documentation required by the application; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay the annual fee required by KRS 243.040. </section></section><section prefix="3">An entity listed in subsection (1) of this section who wishes to import less than twenty-five thousand (25,000) barrels or seven hundred seventy-five thousand (775,000) gallons of malt beverage shall: <section prefix="a">Apply for a limited out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license on an application provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Submit documentation required by the application; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay an annual fee required by KRS 243.040. </section></section><section prefix="4">An out-of-state applicant shall be exempt from the notice requirements of KRS 243.360. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 34, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>