<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.110</section_number><catch_line>Concurrent and consecutive terms of imprisonment. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When multiple sentences of imprisonment are imposed on a defendant for more than one (1) crime, including a crime for which a previous sentence of probation or conditional discharge has been revoked, the multiple sentences shall run concurrently or consecutively as the court shall determine at the time of sentence, except that: <section prefix="a">A definite and an indeterminate term shall run concurrently and both sentences shall be satisfied by service of the indeterminate term; </section><section prefix="b">The aggregate of consecutive definite terms shall not exceed one (1) year; </section><section prefix="c">The aggregate of consecutive indeterminate terms shall not exceed in maximum length the longest extended term which would be authorized by KRS 532.080 for the highest class of crime for which any of the sentences is imposed. In no event shall the aggregate of consecutive indeterminate terms exceed seventy (70) years; and </section><section prefix="d">The sentences of a defendant convicted of two (2) or more felony sex crimes, as defined in KRS 17.500, involving two (2) or more victims shall run consecutively. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the court does not specify the manner in which a sentence imposed by it is to run, the sentence shall run concurrently with any other sentence which the defendant must serve unless the sentence is required by subsection (3) of this section or KRS 533.060 to run consecutively. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any provision in this section to the contrary, if a person is convicted of an offense that is committed while he is imprisoned in a penal or reformatory institution, during an escape from imprisonment, or while he awaits imprisonment, the sentence imposed for that offense may be added to the portion of the term which remained unserved at the time of the commission of the offense. The sentence imposed upon any person convicted of an escape or attempted escape offense shall run consecutively with any other sentence which the defendant must serve. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any provision in this chapter to the contrary, if a person is convicted of an offense that is committed while he is imprisoned in a penal or reformatory institution, the sentence imposed for that offense may, upon order of the trial court, be served in that institution. The person may be transferred to another institution pursuant to administrative regulations of the Department of Corrections. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 47, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 114, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 135, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 283, effective January 1, 1975; and ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20048</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>