<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.190</section_number><catch_line>Exempt codeine preparations. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nonprescription medicinal preparations that contain in one hundred (100) milliliters, or as a solid or semisolid preparation, in one hundred (100) grams, not more than two hundred (200) milligrams of codeine or its salts may be sold over the counter subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">That the medicinal preparation shall contain in addition to the codeine in it, some drug or drugs conferring upon it medicinal qualities other than those possessed by the codeine alone; </section><section prefix="b">That such preparation shall be dispensed or sold in good faith as a medicine, and not for the purpose of evading the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="c">That such preparation shall only be sold at retail without a prescription to a person at least eighteen (18) years of age and only by a pharmacist. An employee may complete the actual cash or credit transaction or delivery; </section><section prefix="d">That such preparations shall not be displayed in areas of the pharmacy open to the public; and </section><section prefix="e">That no person shall purchase and no pharmacist or practitioner shall sell to the same person within a forty-eight (48) hour period more than one hundred twenty (120) milliliters of an exempt codeine preparation. Any person purchasing in excess of this limitation shall be deemed to be in illegal possession. </section></section><section prefix="2">All wholesalers, manufacturers, and repackers shall keep a separate exempt codeine registry showing the following: <section prefix="a">Date; </section><section prefix="b">Registration number of recipient; </section><section prefix="c">Name of recipient; </section><section prefix="d">Address; </section><section prefix="e">Name of preparation; and </section><section prefix="f">Quantity. </section></section><section prefix="3">All pharmacists and practitioners shall keep a separate exempt codeine registry showing the following: <section prefix="a">Date; </section><section prefix="b">Name of recipient; </section><section prefix="c">Address; </section><section prefix="d">Name of preparation; </section><section prefix="e">Quantity; and </section><section prefix="f">Pharmacist's or practitioner's name. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services may by regulation specifically prohibit any such codeine preparation from being sold over the counter due to actual or potential abuse. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 541, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 484, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9675</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>