<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.007</section_number><catch_line>Removal of appointed member of special district governing body -- Hearing -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>007</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless otherwise provided by state law, an appointed member of the governing body of a special district may be removed from office by the appointing authority after a hearing with notice as required by KRS Chapter 424 for inefficiency, neglect of duty, malfeasance or conflict of interest. The hearing shall be initiated and chaired by the appointing authority, who shall prepare a written statement setting forth the reasons for removal. The member to be removed shall be notified of his proposed removal and the reasons therefor by registered mail sent to his last known address at least ten (10) days prior to the hearing. The person to be removed may employ counsel to represent him. A record of the hearing shall be made by the appointing authority. </section><section prefix="2">Where the removal of an appointed member of a special district governing body is by the county judge/executive pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, the removal shall be subject to the approval of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="3">A member removed pursuant to this section may appeal, within ten (10) days of the rendering of the decision or the approval of the fiscal court if required, to the Circuit Court of the county of the appointing authority. The scope of the appeal shall be limited to whether the appointing authority or the fiscal court abused their discretion in removing the member. </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>