<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.050</section_number><catch_line>Computation of bonus. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person determined by the administrator to be a qualified veteran shall be paid the sum of nine dollars ($9) for each month and major fraction of a month of active duty, in the Armed Forces in the continental United States, not to exceed in all the sum of three hundred dollars ($300), and the sum of fifteen dollars ($15) for each month and major fraction of a month of such service outside the continental United States, subject to an aggregate limit for all service in the sum of five hundred dollars ($500). A veteran who served in one or more of the conflict periods defined in subsections (15), (16), (17), and (18) of KRS 40.010 shall be limited to a maximum payment of three hundred dollars ($300) if no part of his total service during the periods specified was served outside the continental United States, or five hundred dollars ($500) if a part of his total service during the periods specified was served outside the continental United States. </section><section prefix="2">If a person determined to have been a qualified veteran shall be deceased at the time payment of the veterans' bonus would otherwise be made to him, the amount of his bonus shall be paid to the first surviving beneficiary, if any, according to the order of priority defined in subsection (8) of KRS 40.010 and if there be no surviving beneficiary, the bonus of such veteran shall lapse, and no payment thereof shall be made. </section><section prefix="3">A beneficiary (as defined in subsections (8), (9), (10), (11), and (12) of KRS 40.010) of a person killed in the line of duty while on active duty in the Armed Forces during the periods defined in subsections (15), (16), (17), and (18) of KRS 40.010 or person who died of service-connected injury sustained while on active duty in the Armed Forces during the conflict periods defined above shall be paid three hundred dollars ($300) if no part of his total service during these periods was served outside the continental United States or five hundred dollars ($500) if any part of his total service during these periods was served outside the continental United States. The provisions of subsection (1) and the minimum period of service for entitlement to a bonus as established by subsection (2) of KRS 40.010 shall not apply to these beneficiaries. However, this exception does not waive the respective maximums of three hundred dollars ($300) or five hundred dollars ($500) for each veteran, person killed in the line of duty while on active duty in the Armed Forces, or person who died as a result of service-connected injury sustained while on active duty in the Armed Forces. </section></text><history>Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 5, effective February 20, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>: February 20, 1960</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21825</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>