<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">HUMAN RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>194.245</section_number><catch_line>Construction and operation of new facilities, beginning August 1, 1990 -- Transfer of ownership and administration.   </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No later than August 1, 1990, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall begin contracting to construct and operate, or lease and operate the following: <section prefix="a">A one hundred (100) bed inpatient mental health facility in eastern Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Twelve (12) child-care centers with a minimum of one (1) center in each of the six (6) Kentucky congressional districts; </section><section prefix="c">Four (4) eight (8) bed group homes for individuals with an intellectual disability; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) one hundred (100) bed personal care homes; and </section><section prefix="e">Twelve (12) senior citizens centers with a minimum of one (1) center in each of the six (6) Kentucky congressional districts. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may transfer the ownership of all real property relating to any child-care center, with the approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and all operational and administrative responsibility over any child-care center, and any contract, agreement, or lease that the Cabinet for Health and Family Services has assumed or executed for the operation of any child-care center to the city, county, or urban-county government in which the center is located. </section><section prefix="b">Any transfer made under this section shall provide for the continued operation of a center in accordance with the public purpose set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">In the event the Cabinet for Health and Family Services cannot locate an entity to continue operations of a real property for the purpose specified in this subsection, it may, with approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, transfer property or designate the property as surplus with no stipulation for further use. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may transfer the ownership of all real property relating to any senior citizens center, with the approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and all operational and administrative responsibility over any senior citizens center, and any contract, agreement, or lease that the Cabinet for Health and Family Services has assumed or executed for the operation of any senior citizens center, to the city, county, or urban-county government in which the center is located. </section><section prefix="b">Any transfer made under this section shall provide for the continued operation of a center in accordance with the public purpose set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">In the event the Cabinet for Health and Family Services cannot locate an entity to continue operations of a real property for the purpose specified in this subsection, it may, with approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, transfer property or designate the property as surplus with no stipulation for further use. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 149, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 29, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40934</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>