<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3">GRANTS TO UNITED STATES OF LANDS AND RIGHTS TO ACQUIRE </unit></structure><section_number>3.260</section_number><catch_line>Application by United States for concurrent legislative jurisdiction -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the United States shall desire to acquire concurrent legislative jurisdiction for purposes of criminal law enforcement over any lands within this Commonwealth which the United States has or shall have acquired for purposes of the establishment or extension of a unit of the National Park System of the United States Department of the Interior and shall make application for that purpose, Kentucky cedes such measure of legislative jurisdiction, not exceeding that requested by the United States, as may be necessary to enable the United States and the Commonwealth of Kentucky to exercise concurrent legislative jurisdiction for purposes of criminal law enforcement over such lands. The Governor is directed to negotiate with the United States, on behalf of the General Assembly, the administrative details of any such cession, which details shall be included in the instrument of cession. </section><section prefix="2">Said application on behalf of the United States shall be accompanied by an accurate description of the lands over which such concurrent legislative jurisdiction for purposes of criminal law enforcement is desired. </section><section prefix="3">Said cession of legislative jurisdiction shall become effective when the instrument of cession is signed by the Governor and the acceptance of jurisdiction by the United States is indicated in writing upon the instrument of cession by the United States Secretary of the Interior or his designee and entered upon the executive journal. In the event the Governor is of the opinion that the cession of legislative jurisdiction embodied in any proposed instrument of cession exceeds the measure of legislative jurisdiction necessary to enable the United States and the Commonwealth of Kentucky to exercise concurrent legislative jurisdiction for purposes of criminal law enforcement over the lands in question, he shall not sign the instrument of cession, and the cession shall not become effective until the General Assembly, at its next session, shall approve same. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978  </history><metadata><effective> June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=96</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>