<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23">A CIRCUIT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>23A.070</section_number><catch_line>Thirtieth Judicial Circuit -- Family court -- Funds from previously created campaign accounts. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Thirtieth Judicial Circuit is entitled to twenty-three (23) judges and shall have twenty-three (23) numbered divisions of the Circuit Court. The Circuit Court divisions designated for family court shall be consecutively numbered beginning with the Thirtieth Judicial Circuit, First Division, Family Court. All other Circuit Court divisions shall be consecutively numbered beginning with the Thirtieth Judicial Circuit, First Division, and shall appear on the ballot prior to the designated family court divisions. These designations shall apply for election purposes and all other purposes. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any provision of KRS 121.180(10) to the contrary, a judicial candidate whose division number is altered pursuant to subsection (1) of this section subsequent to the establishment of a campaign account with the Kentucky Registry of Election Finance may expend the funds contained in the established account for election to the judicial division to which they were elected or appointed. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1996. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 481. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20623</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>