<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.350</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Authority" means the land bank authority established pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300 and KRS 65.350 to 65.375; </section><section prefix="2">"Agreement" means the interlocal cooperation agreement entered into by the parties pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300 and KRS 65.350 to 65.375; </section><section prefix="3">"Local government" means every city, regardless of classification, every county, and every consolidated local government and urban-county government; </section><section prefix="4">"Parties" means the parties to the agreement, that shall include any local government, the local school district, which may include county and independent school districts, within the county and the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Property" means real property, including any improvements thereon; and </section><section prefix="6">"Tax delinquent property" means any property on which the taxes levied and assessed by any party remain in whole or in part unpaid on the date due and payable. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><former-codification> KRS 91.800. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23394</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>