<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.031</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for solid waste management conflict resolution. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Local Government, in cooperation with cities, counties, waste management districts, waste industries, the Energy and Environment Cabinet, and the Environmental Quality Commission, shall develop procedures designed to resolve conflicts resulting from municipal solid waste management facility siting and operation. The procedures shall address: <section prefix="a">Resolution of conflicts associated with multijurisdictional municipal solid waste management facilities, including the use of such techniques as negotiation, mediation, or arbitration to address issues, including but not limited to host community compensation and collection and disposal fees; and </section><section prefix="b">Resolution of issues, except those relating to permit conditions imposed by the cabinet, resulting from municipal solid waste management facility siting and operation, including the use of such techniques as negotiation, mediation, or arbitration to address concerns of those persons and landowners who are directly affected by the facility's location and operation. Issues which may be addressed include but are not limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Operational issues, such as hours of operation; </section><section prefix="2">Recycling and composting efforts that may be implemented; </section><section prefix="3">Protection of property values; </section><section prefix="4">Traffic routing and road maintenance; and </section><section prefix="5">Establishment of local advisory committees. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Local Government shall adopt administrative regulations to implement the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed to abridge any rights or remedies provided by KRS Chapters 109 and 224, or at common law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 136, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 72, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 57, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 10, effective February 26, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1650</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>