<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.618</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure of records by commissioner and Attorney General -- Authority to require submission of additional information.   </catch_line><order_by>618</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding KRS 131.190, the commissioner is authorized to disclose to the Attorney General the name and address of a stamping agent or distributor and the number of sticks by brand name that have been purchased from a nonparticipating manufacturer and have been stamped with Kentucky stamps by that agent or distributor. The Attorney General may share this information with federal, other state, or local agencies only for the purposes of enforcement of KRS 131.600 to 131.630 or corresponding laws of other states. The Attorney General is further authorized to disclose to a nonparticipating manufacturer or its importers this information that has been provided by a stamping agent regarding the purchases from that nonparticipating manufacturer or its importers. This information provided by a stamping agent may be used in any enforcement action against the nonparticipating manufacturer or its importers by the Attorney General. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to the information required to be submitted pursuant to KRS 131.608, 131.614, and 131.620, the Attorney General or the commissioner may require a stamping agent, distributor, participating manufacturer, nonparticipating manufacturer, or a nonparticipating manufacturer's importers to submit any additional information including but not limited to samples of the packaging or labeling of each brand family as is necessary to enable the Attorney General to determine whether the participating manufacturer or the nonparticipating manufacturer and its importers are in compliance with KRS 131.600 to 131.630. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 7, effective July 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 159, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 8, effective April 6, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44706</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>