<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.710</section_number><catch_line>Local system merged with state system. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local retirement systems merged with the state retirement system under the provisions of 1938 Ky. Acts (1st Ex. Sess.), ch. 1, sec. 49, shall be discontinued. The payment of all benefits to members on the retired roll at the time of discontinuance shall become the obligation of the school district in which the local system was operated prior to its discontinuance. The method of determining and paying refundable deposits due members of the local system shall be as provided in 1938 Ky. Acts (1st Ex. Sess.), ch. 1, sec. 49. </section><section prefix="2">Payments to annuitants in cities of the first class or in areas formerly constituting a city of the first class which have been consolidated with their county shall not exceed the amount being received by them at the time the local retirement system is discontinued. The sum that remains after the death of all annuitants shall be used by the local board of education for general school purposes. </section><section prefix="3">The local board of education shall continue to invest the funds transferred to it for the benefit of the existing annuitants as long as such annuitants live. Such investment shall be governed by 1934 Ky. Acts, ch. 65, Art. IX, except that the local board of education is substituted for the board of trustees of the local retirement system. The local board of education shall keep all funds transferred to it by the local retirement system and all income from the investment of such funds in a separate fund to be known as the annuity fund. The local board of education may pay from the fund any reasonable expenses necessary for the fund's administration and general management. The local board of education shall safeguard the fund by requiring such additional surety bond of the treasurer as it deems necessary, by providing for an annual audit by a reputable auditing firm, by spreading on the minutes of the board of education at least annually a report of investments, assets, and liabilities, and the names, addresses, and annuities of annuitants, and by making such an appropriation to the fund from local school revenues as will guarantee the full and complete discharge of all obligations to annuitants. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 175, effective July 15, 2002. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 543, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4506b-49. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3986</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>