<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.910</section_number><catch_line>Declaration of public need and legislative policy. </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby found and declared that there now exists in urban counties in this Commonwealth a lack of parking space for automobiles in main business and professional areas including but not limited to those areas commonly referred to as "downtown".  It is further found that persons commonly referred to as "shoppers", are induced to transact business in areas providing free parking facilities for reasonable lengths of time.  It is further found that many "downtown" or main business areas have deteriorated as a consequence of inadequate or too costly parking facilities and that the tax base has often decreased while the need for governmental services, such as police, fire, and accident protection and street maintenance has often increased all to the detriment of the entire community.  </section><section prefix="2">It is hereby declared that it is the policy of this Commonwealth to protect and promote the safety, comfort, convenience, and welfare of the people of the Commonwealth and particularly of the communities in which there exists inadequate or too costly parking in "downtown" or main business areas and in which the tax base is decreasing or is threatened.  It is further declared that adequate and reasonably priced parking facilities promote the safety, comfort, convenience and welfare of the people living and working in all sections of any community but that the greatest benefit falls upon property owners, businesses, and professional persons owning property or offering their goods and services in close proximity to such parking facilities. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 9, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1976</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23978</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>