<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.060</section_number><catch_line>Actions to collect and recover money due Commonwealth upon request of Department of Revenue. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>Upon written request of the Department of Revenue, the Attorney General shall: <section prefix="1">With the assistance of the Auditor of Public Accounts and the Department of Revenue, investigate the condition of any unsatisfied claim, demand, account, and judgment in favor of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">When he believes that any fraudulent, erroneous or illegal fee bill, account, credit, charge or claim has been erroneously or improperly approved, allowed or paid out of the Treasury to any person, institute the necessary actions to recover the same. To this end he may employ assistants and experts to assist in examining the fee bills, accounts, settlements, credits and claims, and the books, records and papers of any of the officers of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Institute the necessary actions to collect and cause the payment into the Treasury of all unsatisfied claims, demands, accounts and judgments in favor of the Commonwealth, except where specific statutory authority is given the Department of Revenue to do so. </section><section prefix="4">Comply with KRS 48.005, if any funds of any kind or nature whatsoever are recovered by or on behalf of the Commonwealth, in any legal action, including an ex rel. action in which the Attorney General has entered an appearance or is a party under statutory or common law authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 38, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 6, effective April 21, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 3, effective April 21, 2000. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 112-1, 340a-3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=880</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>