<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.055</section_number><catch_line>Disorderly conduct in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of disorderly conduct in the first degree when he or she: <section prefix="a">In a public place and with intent to cause public inconvenience, annoyance, or alarm, or wantonly creating a risk thereof: <section prefix="1">Engages in fighting or in violent, tumultuous, or threatening behavior; </section><section prefix="2">Makes unreasonable noise; or </section><section prefix="3">Creates a hazardous or physically offensive condition by any act that serves no legitimate purpose; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Acts in a way described in paragraph (a) of this subsection within three hundred (300) feet of a: <section prefix="1">Cemetery during a funeral or burial; </section><section prefix="2">Funeral home during the viewing of a deceased person; </section><section prefix="3">Funeral procession; </section><section prefix="4">Funeral or memorial service; or </section><section prefix="5">Building in which a funeral or memorial service is being conducted; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Acts in a way described in paragraph (a) of this subsection at any point in time between one (1) hour prior to the commencement of an event specified in paragraph (b) of this subsection and one (1) hour following its conclusion; and </section><section prefix="d">Knows that he or she is within three hundred (300) feet of an occasion described in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">Disorderly conduct in the first degree is a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective March 27, 2006; and ch. 51, sec. 1, effective March 27, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (3/27/2006).  This section was created by 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, and 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, which are substantially identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>