<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.350</section_number><catch_line>Organization of board -- Meetings -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of trustees shall constitute a corporate body with perpetual succession. Within ten (10) days after their appointment, the appointive officer shall call a meeting of the library board to organize by the election of such officers as they deem necessary and meet on a regularly scheduled basis thereafter once each month. If the appointive officer does not call a meeting, the trustees may do so on their own initiative. </section><section prefix="2">They shall adopt such bylaws and policies for their own guidance and for the government of the library as they deem expedient; have the supervision, care and custody of all property of the library including its quarters or buildings; employ a library director and upon that person's recommendation employ such other staff as may be necessary, who shall be certified in accordance with KRS 171.240 to 171.300, fix the compensation of the library director and staff; adopt personnel policies which shall include dismissal of employees; submit annually to the legislative body a budget containing estimates in detail of the amount of money necessary for the library for the ensuing year; allot funds for the purchase of library materials and supplies for the library; and do all other acts necessary for the orderly and efficient management and control of the library. </section><section prefix="3">They may accept such gifts of money or property for library purposes as they deem expedient; lease or purchase land for library buildings; lease, purchase or erect an appropriate building or buildings for library purposes and acquire such other property and equipment as may be needed therefor; and may enter into contracts for library service with other library boards as provided for in KRS 65.210 to 65.300 and with other units of government as provided for in KRS 173.310(4). </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 5. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>