<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-604</section_number><catch_line>Person's power to dissociate as general partner -- Wrongful dissociation. </catch_line><order_by>2-604</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person has the power to dissociate as a general partner at any time, rightfully or wrongfully, by express will pursuant to KRS 362.2-603(1). </section><section prefix="2">A person's dissociation as a general partner is wrongful only if: <section prefix="a">It is in breach of an express provision of the partnership agreement; or </section><section prefix="b">It occurs before the termination of the limited partnership and: <section prefix="1">The person withdraws as a general partner by express will; </section><section prefix="2">The person is expelled as a general partner by judicial determination under KRS 362.2-603(5); </section><section prefix="3">The person is dissociated as a general partner by becoming a debtor in bankruptcy; or </section><section prefix="4">In the case of a person that is not an individual, trust other than a business trust, or estate, the person is expelled or otherwise dissociated as a general partner because it willfully dissolved or terminated. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">A person that wrongfully dissociates as a general partner is liable to the limited partnership and, subject to KRS 362.2-931, to the other partners for damages caused by the dissociation. The liability is in addition to any other obligation of the general partner to the limited partnership or to the other partners. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 141, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>