<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.125</section_number><catch_line>Working of prisoners at community-service-related projects -- Written policy -- Prisoner's status not employment. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">As used in this section, "community-service-related project" means a project involving work for: <section prefix="1">The Commonwealth or an agency of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">A county, urban-county, charter county, city, special district, or an agency of any of these entities; or </section><section prefix="3">A nonreligious-sponsored nonprofit, charitable, or service organization. </section></section><section prefix="b">Work on a community-service-related project shall not confer private benefit on a person except as may be incidental to the public benefit. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each jailer shall write a policy governing prisoners working on community-service-related projects, which shall be submitted to the fiscal court for approval. The written policy shall state at a minimum: <section prefix="a">Which type of prisoner, if any, shall be assigned to which type of work, taking into account the physical and mental abilities of prisoners and security of the jail and the general public; </section><section prefix="b">That no prisoner shall be assigned to unduly hazardous work that would endanger the life or health of the prisoner or others; and </section><section prefix="c">That any prisoner may, for a valid medical reason, decline to work on community-service-related projects. No prisoner shall be punished or otherwise penalized for this refusal. </section></section><section prefix="3">A prisoner shall not begin work on a particular community-service-related project without the approval of the director of the relevant entity referred to in subsection (1)(a) of this section, or the director's designee. </section><section prefix="4">Participation in community-service-related projects shall not be deemed employment for any purpose, and a prisoner shall not be deemed an employee or agent of the entity for which he or she performs the community service work. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.068. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>