<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.450</section_number><catch_line>Causes for refusal of license. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A license to be issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 shall be refused: <section prefix="a">If the applicant or the premises for which the license is sought does not comply fully with all alcoholic beverage control statutes and the regulations of the board; </section><section prefix="b">If the applicant or the premises for which the license is sought does not comply with all regulations of a city administrator or county administrator; </section><section prefix="c">If the applicant has done any act for which a revocation of license would be authorized; or </section><section prefix="d">If the applicant has made any false material statement in his application. </section></section><section prefix="2">A license that might be issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 may be refused by a state director for any reason which the director, in the exercise of his or her sound discretion, deems sufficient. Among those factors that the director shall consider in the exercise of his or her discretion are: public sentiment in the area; number of licensed outlets in the area; potential for future growth; type of area involved; type of transportation available; and financial potential of the area. </section></text><history>Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-134, 2554b-139. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>