<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.209Issuance</section_number><catch_line>of bonds or notes to finance energy projects -- Security -- Lien.   </catch_line><order_by>209Issuance</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local government may issue bonds or notes to finance energy projects through assessments imposed pursuant to KRS 65.205 to 65.209. </section><section prefix="2">Bonds or notes issued under this section shall not be general obligations of the local government. The bonds or notes shall be secured solely by one (1) or more of the following, as provided by the governing body of the local government in the resolution or ordinance approving the issuance of the bonds or notes: <section prefix="a">Payments of assessments on relevant real properties in one (1) or more specified energy project assessment districts; </section><section prefix="b">Reserves established by the local government from grants, bonds, or other available funds; </section><section prefix="c">Municipal bond insurance, lines of credit, public or private guaranties, standby bond purchase agreements, collateral assignments, mortgages, or other available means of providing credit support or liquidity; and </section><section prefix="d">Any other funds available for the purposes of KRS 65.205 to 65.209. </section></section><section prefix="3">A local government pledge of assessments, funds, or contractual rights in connection with the issuance of bonds or notes by the local government under this section constitutes a first lien on the assessments, funds, or contractual rights pledged in favor of the person to whom the pledge is given, without further action by the local government. The lien is valid and binding against any other person, with or without notice. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>