<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.846</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings concerning academic achievement in STEM disciplines. </catch_line><order_by>846</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds that: <section prefix="1">The future of Kentucky depends upon the ability to develop intellectual capital that can drive the research and development activities that will allow the Commonwealth to successfully compete in the global knowledge-based economy; </section><section prefix="2">Kentucky's natural resources, the nation's need for energy independence, and the worldwide movement toward the creation of cleaner and more sustainable energy technologies afford Kentucky the opportunity to become an international leader in energy diversification; </section><section prefix="3">Strengthening Kentucky's position in key areas of the knowledge-based economy, including energy and environmental technology, biosciences, materials science, advanced manufacturing, information technology, human health and development, and other fields, requires a strong and steady stream of researchers, workers, policymakers, and entrepreneurs trained in the STEM disciplines; </section><section prefix="4">The number of Kentucky's elementary and secondary students interested in pursuing, and adequately prepared for success in, the STEM disciplines in college and the workforce is insufficient to meet the challenges and opportunities with which Kentucky is confronted; </section><section prefix="5">The number of Kentucky's elementary, middle, and secondary school teachers who are highly qualified to provide instruction in the STEM disciplines is insufficient to adequately prepare students for careers in the knowledge-based economy; and </section><section prefix="6">Bold, collaborative, and strategic action is needed by all stakeholders in Kentucky's P-20 education system, business sector, and government to improve Kentucky's position for success in the knowledge-based economy by expanding and strengthening STEM educational opportunities from prekindergarten through the doctoral degree level, inspiring more Kentuckians to pursue those opportunities, and linking those opportunities with a coherent set of statewide economic and workforce development strategies. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3617</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>