<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.83805</section_number><catch_line>Department of Law to establish minimum standards for mold remediation companies -- Complaints to Attorney General. </catch_line><order_by>83805</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall, after consultation with the Public Protection Cabinet and the Department for Public Health, establish minimum standards for mold remediation companies that operate in the Commonwealth. The minimum standards shall be based on the five (5) general principles of mold remediation created by the Institute of Inspection, Cleaning and Restoration Certification (IICRC) in its publication, IICRC S520, Second Edition, Standard and Reference Guide for Professional Mold Remediation, or its successor publication. The five (5) general principles of mold remediation are as follows: <section prefix="a">Safety and health; </section><section prefix="b">Project documentation; </section><section prefix="c">Contaminant control; </section><section prefix="d">Contaminant removal; and </section><section prefix="e">Contamination prevention. </section></section> All mold remediation companies operating in the Commonwealth shall adhere to the minimum standards established by the department. <section prefix="2">Any customer complaints regarding adherence by mold remediation companies to the administrative regulations promulgated under this section shall be directed to the Attorney General. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Environmental and Public Protection Cabinet" in subsection (1) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 3, has been changed in codification to the "Public Protection Cabinet" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35084</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>