<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="514" order_by="514">THEFT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>514.110</section_number><catch_line>Receiving stolen property. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of receiving stolen property when he receives, retains, or disposes of movable property of another knowing that it has been stolen, or having reason to believe that it has been stolen, unless the property is received, retained, or disposed of with intent to restore it to the owner. </section><section prefix="2">The possession by any person of any recently stolen movable property shall be prima facie evidence that such person knew such property was stolen. </section><section prefix="3">Receiving stolen property is a Class A misdemeanor unless: <section prefix="a">The value of the property is five hundred dollars ($500) or more but less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), in which case it is a Class D felony; </section><section prefix="b">The value of the property is ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more, in which case it is a Class C felony; </section><section prefix="c">The property is a firearm, regardless of the value of the firearm, in which case it is a Class D felony; or </section><section prefix="d">The property is anhydrous ammonia, regardless of the value of the ammonia, in which case it is a Class D felony unless it is proven that the person violated this section with the intent to manufacture methamphetamine in violation of KRS 218A.1432, in which case it is a Class B felony for the first offense and a Class A felony for each subsequent offense. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 490, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 314, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 396, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 127, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19813</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>