<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.140</section_number><catch_line>Dispositional alternatives.  </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text>(1)In determining the disposition of all cases brought on behalf of dependent,neglected, or abused children, the juvenile session of the District Court, in thebest interest of the child, shall have but shall not be limited to the followingdispositional alternatives:(a)Informal adjustment of the case;(b)Protective orders, such as the following:1.Requiring the parent or any other person to abstain from anyconduct abusing, neglecting, or making the child dependent;2.Placing the child in his own home under supervision of the cabinetor its designee with services as determined to be appropriate by thecabinet; and3.Orders authorized by KRS 403.715 to 403.785 and by KRS Chapter456;(c)Removal of the child to the custody of an adult relative, other person, orchild-caring facility or child-placing agency, taking into consideration thewishes of the parent or other person exercising custodial control orsupervision. Before any child is committed to the cabinet or placed out ofhis home under the supervision of the cabinet, the court shall determinethat reasonable efforts have been made by the court or the cabinet toprevent or eliminate the need for removal and that continuation in thehome would be contrary to the welfare of the child;(d)Commitment of the child to the custody of the cabinet for placement foran indeterminate period of time not to exceed his or her attainment of theage eighteen (18), unless the youth elects to extend his or hercommitment beyond the age of eighteen (18) under paragraph (e) of thissubsection. Beginning at least six (6) months prior to an eligible youthattaining the age of eighteen (18), the cabinet shall provide the eligibleyouth with education, encouragement, assistance, and support regardingthe development of a transition plan, and inform the eligible youth of his orher right to extend commitment beyond the age of eighteen (18); or(e)Extend or reinstate an eligible youth's commitment up to the age oftwenty-one (21) to receive transitional living support. The request shall bemade by the youth prior to attaining nineteen (19) years of age. Uponreceipt of the request and with the concurrence of the cabinet, the courtmay authorize commitment up to the age of twenty-one (21).(2)An order of temporary custody to the cabinet shall not be considered as apermissible dispositional alternative.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 50, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended1990 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky.Acts ch. 350, sec. 51, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423,sec. 75, effective July 1, 1987.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44798</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>