<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.995</section_number><catch_line>Violations for which additional restitution shall be paid to department.   </catch_line><order_by>995</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "gross score" means the Boone and Crockett score derived by calculating the measurements of the antlers of a white-tailed deer or elk in accordance with subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The gross score of an antlered white-tailed deer or elk shall be calculated in accordance with the Boone and Crockett Club's "Measuring and Scoring North American Big Game Trophies, Third Edition, 2009" and shall be taken by an official Boone and Crockett Club scorer. Measurements taken for the purpose of calculating the gross score may be taken at any time, with no drying time being required. </section><section prefix="3">A person found guilty of a violation of the provisions of this chapter regarding the taking, buying, selling, transporting, or possessing of an antlered white-tailed deer with a gross score of more than one hundred twenty-five (125) inches shall pay to the department an additional restitution value calculated by squaring the difference between the gross score and one hundred (100) and multiplying the resulting number by one dollar and sixty-five cents ($1.65). </section><section prefix="4">A person found guilty of a violation of the provisions of this chapter regarding the taking, buying, selling, transporting, or possessing of an antlered elk with a gross score of more than two hundred eighty (280) inches shall pay to the department an additional restitution value calculated by squaring the difference between the gross score and two hundred fifty-five (255) and multiplying the resulting number by one dollar and sixty-five cents ($1.65). </section><section prefix="5">A person found guilty of a violation of the provisions of this chapter regarding the taking, buying, selling, transporting, or possessing of a bear shall pay to the department an additional restitution value of one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="6">A person found guilty of a violation of the provisions of this chapter regarding the taking, buying, selling, transporting, or possessing of a turkey shall pay to the department an additional restitution value of five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="7">A person found guilty of a violation of the provisions of this chapter regarding the taking, buying, selling, transporting, or possessing of a bobcat shall pay to the department an additional restitution value of five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner or designee may bring a civil action to recover the restitution value owed to the department under subsection (3), (4), (5), (6), or (7) of this section. A person who owes restitution to the department under subsection (3), (4), (5), (6), or (7) of this section shall forfeit his or her hunting license or, if license-exempt, the privilege to perform the hunting acts authorized by the license until the restitution owed has been paid. </section><section prefix="9">The restitution required by this section shall be in addition to all other restitution, replacement costs, and civil or criminal penalties authorized by this chapter and the administrative regulations promulgated hereunder. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>