<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.375</section_number><catch_line>Independent, political organization, or political group candidates filing to fill vacancy -- Ineligibility of Senior Status Special Judge.   </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a vacancy occurs in any elective office less than one hundred thirty-four (134) days before the primary or at any time after the primary, but not less than three (3) months before the regular election, independent, or political organization, or political group candidates may file their petitions at the time and place provided in KRS 118.365, subject to the restrictions concerning party registration and candidacy provided in KRS 118.315(1). </section><section prefix="2">A judge who elected to retire as a Senior Status Special Judge in accordance with KRS 21.580 shall not become a candidate or a nominee for any elected office during the five (5) year term prescribed in KRS 21.580(1)(a)1., regardless of the number of days served by the judge acting as a Senior Status Special Judge. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 48, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 22, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 123, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42255</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>