<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.202</section_number><catch_line>Electronic system for monitoring controlled substances -- Required registration and reporting -- Penalty for illegal use of system -- Pilot or continuing project -- Continuing education programs -- Reports of failure to comply with section -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>202</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish an electronic system for monitoring Schedules II, III, IV, and V controlled substances that are dispensed within the Commonwealth by a practitioner or pharmacist or dispensed to an address within the Commonwealth by a pharmacy that has obtained a license, permit, or other authorization to operate from the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. The cabinet may contract for the design, upgrade, or operation of this system if the contract preserves all of the rights, privileges, and protections guaranteed to Kentucky citizens under this chapter and the contract requires that all other aspects of the system be operated in conformity with the requirements of this or any other applicable state or federal law. </section><section prefix="2">A practitioner or a pharmacist authorized to prescribe or dispense controlled substances to humans shall register with the cabinet to use the system provided for in this section and shall maintain such registration continuously during the practitioner's or pharmacist's term of licensure and shall not have to pay a fee or tax specifically dedicated to the operation of the system. </section><section prefix="3">Every dispenser within the Commonwealth who is licensed, permitted, or otherwise authorized to prescribe or dispense a controlled substance to a person in Kentucky shall report to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services the data required by this section, except that reporting shall not be required for: <section prefix="a">A drug administered directly to a patient in a hospital, a resident of a health care facility licensed under KRS Chapter 216B, a resident of a child-caring facility as defined by KRS 199.011, or an individual in a jail, correctional facility, or juvenile detention facility; </section><section prefix="b">A drug, other than any Schedule II controlled substance or a Schedule III controlled substance containing hydrocodone, dispensed by a practitioner at a facility licensed by the cabinet, provided that the quantity dispensed is limited to an amount adequate to treat the patient for a maximum of forty-eight (48) hours; or </section><section prefix="c">A drug administered or dispensed to a research subject enrolled in a research protocol approved by an institutional review board that has an active federalwide assurance number from the United States Department of Health and Human Services, Office for Human Research Protections, where the research involves single, double, or triple blind drug administration or is additionally covered by a certificate of confidentiality from the National Institutes of Health. </section></section><section prefix="4">Data for each controlled substance that is dispensed shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Patient identifier; </section><section prefix="b">National drug code of the drug dispensed; </section><section prefix="c">Date of dispensing; </section><section prefix="d">Quantity dispensed; </section><section prefix="e">Prescriber; and </section><section prefix="f">Dispenser. </section></section><section prefix="5">The data shall be provided in the electronic format specified by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services unless a waiver has been granted by the cabinet to an individual dispenser. The cabinet shall establish acceptable error tolerance rates for data. Dispensers shall ensure that reports fall within these tolerances. Incomplete or inaccurate data shall be corrected upon notification by the cabinet if the dispenser exceeds these error tolerance rates. </section><section prefix="6">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall only disclose data to persons and entities authorized to receive that data under this section. Disclosure to any other person or entity, including disclosure in the context of a civil action where the disclosure is sought either for the purpose of discovery or for evidence, is prohibited unless specifically authorized by this section. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall be authorized to provide data to: <section prefix="a">A designated representative of a board responsible for the licensure, regulation, or discipline of practitioners, pharmacists, or other person who is authorized to prescribe, administer, or dispense controlled substances and who is involved in a bona fide specific investigation involving a designated person; </section><section prefix="b">Employees of the Office of the Inspector General of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services who have successfully completed training for the electronic system and who have been approved to use the system, Kentucky Commonwealth's attorneys and assistant Commonwealth's attorneys, county attorneys and assistant county attorneys, a peace officer certified pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404, a certified or full-time peace officer of another state, or a federal peace officer whose duty is to enforce the laws of this Commonwealth, of another state, or of the United States relating to drugs and who is engaged in a bona fide specific investigation involving a designated person; </section><section prefix="c">A state-operated Medicaid program in conformity with subsection (7) of this section; </section><section prefix="d">A properly convened grand jury pursuant to a subpoena properly issued for the records; </section><section prefix="e">A practitioner or pharmacist, or employee of the practitioner's or pharmacist's practice acting under the specific direction of the practitioner or pharmacist, who requests information and certifies that the requested information is for the purpose of: <section prefix="1">Providing medical or pharmaceutical treatment to a bona fide current or prospective patient; or </section><section prefix="2">Reviewing and assessing the individual prescribing or dispensing patterns of the practitioner or pharmacist or to determine the accuracy and completeness of information contained in the monitoring system; </section></section><section prefix="f">The chief medical officer of a hospital or long-term-care facility, an employee of the hospital or long-term-care facility as designated by the chief medical officer and who is working under his or her specific direction, or a physician designee if the hospital or facility has no chief medical officer, if the officer, employee, or designee certifies that the requested information is for the purpose of providing medical or pharmaceutical treatment to a bona fide current or prospective patient or resident in the hospital or facility; </section><section prefix="g">In addition to the purposes authorized under paragraph (a) of this subsection, the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, for any physician who is: <section prefix="1">Associated in a partnership or other business entity with a physician who is already under investigation by the Board of Medical Licensure for improper prescribing or dispensing practices; </section><section prefix="2">In a designated geographic area for which a trend report indicates a substantial likelihood that inappropriate prescribing or dispensing may be occurring; or </section><section prefix="3">In a designated geographic area for which a report on another physician in that area indicates a substantial likelihood that inappropriate prescribing or dispensing may be occurring in that area; </section></section><section prefix="h">In addition to the purposes authorized under paragraph (a) of this subsection, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, for any advanced practice registered nurse who is: <section prefix="1">Associated in a partnership or other business entity with a physician who is already under investigation by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure for improper prescribing or dispensing practices; </section><section prefix="2">Associated in a partnership or other business entity with an advanced practice registered nurse who is already under investigation by the Board of Nursing for improper prescribing practices; </section><section prefix="3">In a designated geographic area for which a trend report indicates a substantial likelihood that inappropriate prescribing or dispensing may be occurring; or </section><section prefix="4">In a designated geographic area for which a report on a physician or another advanced practice registered nurse in that area indicates a substantial likelihood that inappropriate prescribing or dispensing may be occurring in that area; </section></section><section prefix="i">A judge or a probation or parole officer administering a diversion or probation program of a criminal defendant arising out of a violation of this chapter or of a criminal defendant who is documented by the court as a substance abuser who is eligible to participate in a court-ordered drug diversion or probation program; or </section><section prefix="j">A medical examiner engaged in a death investigation pursuant to KRS 72.026. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Department for Medicaid Services shall use any data or reports from the system for the purpose of identifying Medicaid providers or recipients whose prescribing, dispensing, or usage of controlled substances may be: <section prefix="a">Appropriately managed by a single outpatient pharmacy or primary care physician; or </section><section prefix="b">Indicative of improper, inappropriate, or illegal prescribing or dispensing practices by a practitioner or drug seeking by a Medicaid recipient. </section></section><section prefix="8">A person who receives data or any report of the system from the cabinet shall not provide it to any other person or entity except as provided in this section, in another statute, or by order of a court of competent jurisdiction and only to a person or entity authorized to receive the data or the report under this section, except that: <section prefix="a">A person specified in subsection (6)(b) of this section who is authorized to receive data or a report may share that information with any other persons specified in subsection (6)(b) of this section authorized to receive data or a report if the persons specified in subsection (6)(b) of this section are working on a bona fide specific investigation involving a designated person. Both the person providing and the person receiving the data or report under this paragraph shall document in writing each person to whom the data or report has been given or received and the day, month, and year that the data or report has been given or received. This document shall be maintained in a file by each agency engaged in the investigation; </section><section prefix="b">A representative of the Department for Medicaid Services may share data or reports regarding overutilization by Medicaid recipients with a board designated in subsection (6)(a) of this section, or with a law enforcement officer designated in subsection (6)(b) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">The Department for Medicaid Services may submit the data as evidence in an administrative hearing held in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B; </section><section prefix="d">If a state licensing board as defined in KRS 218A.205 initiates formal disciplinary proceedings against a licensee, and data obtained by the board is relevant to the charges, the board may provide the data to the licensee and his or her counsel, as part of the notice process required by KRS 13B.050, and admit the data as evidence in an administrative hearing conducted pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, with the board and licensee taking all necessary steps to prevent further disclosure of the data; and </section><section prefix="e">A practitioner, pharmacist, or employee who obtains data under subsection (6)(e) of this section may share the report with the patient or person authorized to act on the patient's behalf and place the report in the patient's medical record, with that individual report then being deemed a medical record subject to disclosure on the same terms and conditions as an ordinary medical record in lieu of the disclosure restrictions otherwise imposed by this section. </section></section><section prefix="9">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services, all peace officers specified in subsection (6)(b) of this section, all officers of the court, and all regulatory agencies and officers, in using the data for investigative or prosecution purposes, shall consider the nature of the prescriber's and dispenser's practice and the condition for which the patient is being treated. </section><section prefix="10">The data and any report obtained therefrom shall not be a public record, except that the Department for Medicaid Services may submit the data as evidence in an administrative hearing held in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="11">Intentional failure by a dispenser to transmit data to the cabinet as required by subsection (3), (4), or (5) of this section shall be a Class B misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class A misdemeanor for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="12">Intentional disclosure of transmitted data to a person not authorized by subsection (6) to subsection (8) of this section or authorized by KRS 315.121, or obtaining information under this section not relating to a bona fide specific investigation, shall be a Class B misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class A misdemeanor for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="13"><section prefix="a">The Commonwealth Office of Technology, in consultation with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, may submit an application to the United States Department of Justice for a drug diversion grant to fund a pilot or continuing project to study, create, or maintain a real-time electronic monitoring system for Schedules II, III, IV, and V controlled substances. </section><section prefix="b">The pilot project shall: <section prefix="1">Be conducted in two (2) rural counties that have an interactive real-time electronic information system in place for monitoring patient utilization of health and social services through a federally funded community access program; and </section><section prefix="2">Study the use of an interactive system that includes a relational data base with query capability. </section></section><section prefix="c">Funding to create or maintain a real-time electronic monitoring system for Schedules II, III, IV, and V controlled substances may be sought for a statewide system or for a system covering any geographic portion or portions of the state. </section></section><section prefix="14">Provisions in this section that relate to data collection, disclosure, access, and penalties shall apply to the pilot project authorized under subsection (13) of this section. </section><section prefix="15">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may, by promulgating an administrative regulation, limit the length of time that data remain in the electronic system. Any data removed from the system shall be archived and subject to retrieval within a reasonable time after a request from a person authorized to review data under this section. </section><section prefix="16"><section prefix="a">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall work with each board responsible for the licensure, regulation, or discipline of practitioners, pharmacists, or other persons who are authorized to prescribe, administer, or dispense controlled substances for the development of a continuing education program about the purposes and uses of the electronic system for monitoring established in this section. </section><section prefix="b">The cabinet shall work with the Kentucky Bar Association for the development of a continuing education program for attorneys about the purposes and uses of the electronic system for monitoring established in this section. </section><section prefix="c">The cabinet shall work with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet for the development of a continuing education program for law enforcement officers about the purposes and uses of the electronic system for monitoring established in this section. </section></section><section prefix="17">If the cabinet becomes aware of a prescriber's or dispenser's failure to comply with this section, the cabinet shall notify the licensing board or agency responsible for licensing the prescriber or dispenser. The licensing board shall treat the notification as a complaint against the licensee. </section><section prefix="18">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. Included in these administrative regulations shall be: <section prefix="a">An error resolution process allowing a patient to whom a report had been disclosed under subsection (8) of this section to request the correction of inaccurate information contained in the system relating to that patient; and </section><section prefix="b">Beginning July 1, 2013, a requirement that data be reported to the system under subsection (3) of this section within one (1) day of dispensing. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective March 4, 2013. -- Amended 2012 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 4, effective July 20, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 43, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 252, effective June 26, 2007; and ch.124, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 627, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 99, sec. 543, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004; and ch. 107, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 1, effective April 9, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective>March 4, 2013</effective><lrc-note> (7/13/2004).  This section was amended by 2004 Ky. Acts chs. 68 and 107. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 107, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>