<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.195</section_number><catch_line>Financial information on salaries and on filing fees and costs to be submitted as part of the judicial branch budget recommendation -- Treatment of salaries in judicial branch budget bill. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly shall set the salaries of the justices and judges of the Court of Justice in the judicial branch budget bill. The Chief Justice shall include in the judicial branch budget recommendation the salaries of the justices and the judges. If the General Assembly concurs with the recommended judicial salaries contained in the judicial branch budget recommendation, then the judicial salaries shall be set in the judicial branch budget bill by incorporating by reference the judicial branch budget recommendation. If the General Assembly sets judicial salaries different from the judicial branch budget recommendation, then the General Assembly shall set forth the salaries of the justices and judges or the incremental changes in the judicial branch budget bill. </section><section prefix="2">The Chief Justice shall include in the judicial branch budget recommendation: <section prefix="a">The filing fees and costs, and any changes in the fees and costs, set under KRS 23A.200 or 24A.170 during the fiscal biennium immediately preceding the biennium for which the recommendation is submitted; and </section><section prefix="b">A statement of whether, and to what extent, the Supreme Court intends to raise or anticipates raising the fees and costs set under KRS 23A.200 or 24A.170 during the biennium for which the recommendation is submitted. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 9, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective April 1, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>