<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.005</section_number><catch_line>Policy on regulation and registration of vehicles -- License plates. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is declared to be the policy of this Commonwealth that all commercial vehicles should be regulated, registered, and the laws pertaining thereto be administered by the Transportation Cabinet. Motor vehicles other than commercial vehicles should be registered, regulated, and controlled by the Transportation Cabinet and the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">All motor vehicles registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(1) shall be on an annual basis and evidenced by a license plate whose registration designation is a combination of three (3) letters of the alphabet and three (3) Arabic numerical digits. These registration plates shall be issued for use during a multiyear period and validated for continued use the following year, or years, by affixing an appropriate insignia of plastic or adhesive material bearing the date of the new year. </section><section prefix="3">All motor vehicles registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(3)(a), (4)(a), (5), (6), or (11) shall have registration plates issued for use during a multiyear period and validated for continued use the following year, by affixing an appropriate insignia of plastic or adhesive material bearing the date of the new year. </section><section prefix="4">The Transportation Cabinet may promulgate regulations and prepare the proper insignia and forms, which forms shall include information required by the Transportation Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 189, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976; and ch. 133, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1976; Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art IV, sec. 20(9); and ch. 226, sec. 1; and ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(9). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 168. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>