<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.066</section_number><catch_line>Ability of precinct with small number of voters to use voting facilities and election officers of larger precinct. </catch_line><order_by>066</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the case of a precinct comprised of a small number of registered voters, the county board of elections may, pursuant to KRS 117.055, utilize the facilities of another precinct as a voting location. Additionally, the county board of elections may petition the State Board of Elections to allow the precinct election officers of the larger precinct to serve as precinct election officers for the precinct that is the subject of the petition. The petition shall designate both the smaller precinct and the larger precinct with which it is to be included, the type of voting machine or machines to be used, and whether supplemental paper ballots are to be used. The petition shall contain a full explanation of the reasons why inclusion is desirable. </section><section prefix="2">If the petition submitted pursuant to subsection (1) of this section is approved by the State Board of Elections, the election shall be conducted according to the following provisions: <section prefix="a">One voting machine may be utilized for both precincts if the State Board of Elections certifies that separate ballots may be placed upon the voting machine to be used without endangering the integrity of the ballots or without violating any other election law. Otherwise, separate voting machines shall be used for each precinct. In the instance of a precinct which has a small number of voters such that the use of a separate voting machine would be cost-prohibitive, the county clerk may make application to the State Board of Elections to use supplemental paper ballots under KRS 118.215 to conduct the voting for the small precinct on election day. If the use of supplemental paper ballots is approved by the State Board of Elections, at the close of voting on election day, the locked ballot box shall be transported to the county board of elections and ballots shall be counted by the county board of elections as provided by KRS 117.275(10) to (13); </section><section prefix="b">Separate precinct voter rosters shall be maintained for each precinct, and steps shall be taken to insure that voters cast their ballot in their duly authorized precinct; and </section><section prefix="c">A separate set of elections forms and reports required by this chapter and the State Board of Elections shall be maintained for each precinct. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective April 2, 2002. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 10, effective April 13, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to "KRS 117.275(7)" in subsection (2)(a) of this statute has been changed in codification to "KRS 117.275(10) to (13)." 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 8, renumbered and subdivided the former subsection (7) of KRS 117.275 as subsections (10), (11), (12), and (13), but failed to include a conforming amendment to the reference in subsection (2)(a) of this statute. This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27365</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>