<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.19-020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>19-020</order_by><text>For the purpose of this subtitle: <section prefix="1">"Credit life insurance" means insurance on the life of a debtor pursuant to or in connection with a specific loan or other credit transaction; </section><section prefix="2">"Credit health insurance" means insurance on a debtor to provide indemnity for payments becoming due on a specific loan or other credit transaction while the debtor is disabled as defined in the policy; </section><section prefix="3">"Creditor" means the lender of money or vendor or lessor of goods, services, or property, rights or privileges, for which payment is arranged through a credit transaction, or any successor to the right, title or interest of any such lender, vendor, or lessor, and an affiliate, associate or subsidiary of any of them, or any director, officer or employee of any of them, or any other person in any way associated with any of them; </section><section prefix="4">"Debtor" means a borrower of money or a purchaser or lessee of goods, services, property, rights or privileges for which payment is arranged through a credit transaction; </section><section prefix="5">"Indebtedness" means the total amount payable by a debtor to a creditor in connection with a loan or other credit transaction; </section><section prefix="6">"Joint credit life or credit health" shall mean insurance on the life of the debtor and the spouse of the debtor, partners, or any other legal cosigner. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 19, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29459</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>