<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 41.070, 41.110, 41.120, 41.130, 41.150, 41.160, 41.290, 41.300, and 41.990 -- Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 41.070, 41.110, 41.120, 41.130, 41.150, 41.160, 41.290, 41.300, or 41.990, unless the context requires otherwise, the terms "appropriation," "budget unit," "disbursements,""expenditures," "expenses," and "receipts" have the meaning given them by KRS 43.010 and 48.010. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this chapter: <section prefix="a">"Bank" and "depository" include any qualified financial intermediary and savings and loan associations chartered by the State of Kentucky or the United States government designated to take custody of state funds on deposit, for periods greater than overnight, with the intent to honor presentments against those deposits; </section><section prefix="b">"Warrant" means a printed or electronic authorization from the Finance and Administration Cabinet for the Treasurer to issue a check; </section><section prefix="c">"Form" or "report" means any written method of transporting data; and </section><section prefix="d">"Writing" or "written" means letters, words, or numbers, or their equivalent, set down by handwriting, typewriting, printing, photostating, photographing, magnetic impulse, mechanical or electronic recording, or other form of data compilation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 26, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 120, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 450, sec. 55, effective July 1, 1983. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1992b-2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21883</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>