<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.370</section_number><catch_line>Conversion of partnership or limited partnership to limited liability company. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A partnership or limited partnership may be converted to a limited liability company pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="2">The terms and conditions of a conversion of a partnership or limited partnership to a limited liability company shall, in the case of a partnership, be approved by all the partners or by a number or percentage specified for conversion in the partnership agreement or, in the case of a limited partnership, by all the partners, notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in the limited partnership agreement. </section><section prefix="3">After the conversion is approved under subsection (2) of this section, the partnership or limited partnership shall file articles of organization with the office of the Secretary of State which satisfy the requirements of KRS 275.025 and include: <section prefix="a">A statement that the partnership or limited partnership was converted to a limited liability company from a partnership or limited partnership, as the case may be; </section><section prefix="b">Its former name; </section><section prefix="c">In the case of a partnership, a statement of the number of votes cast by the partners entitled to vote for and against the conversion and, if the vote is less than unanimous, the number or percentage required to approve the conversion under the partnership agreement; and </section><section prefix="d">If the converting partnership has filed a statement of registration as a limited liability partnership in accordance with KRS 362.555, a statement of qualification in accordance with KRS 362.1-931, or a statement of partnership authority, each shall be deemed canceled as of the effective date and time of the articles of organization as determined in accordance with KRS 275.020; and </section><section prefix="e">In the case of a limited partnership, the converting limited partnership's certificate of limited partnership shall be deemed canceled as of the effective date and time of the articles of organization as determined in accordance with KRS 275.020. </section></section><section prefix="4">The conversion shall take effect when the articles of organization are filed with the office of the Secretary of State or, as provided in KRS 275.020, at a later date specified in the articles of organization. </section><section prefix="5">A partner or, in the case of a limited partnership, a general partner who becomes a member of a limited liability company as a result of a conversion shall remain liable as a partner or general partner for an obligation incurred by the partnership or limited partnership before the conversion takes effect. If the other party to a transaction with the limited liability company reasonably believes when entering the transaction that the member undertaking the transaction is a partner in a partnership or a general partner in a limited partnership, the member shall be liable for an obligation incurred by the limited liability company within ninety (90) days after the conversion takes effect. The partner's or general partner's liability for all other obligations of the limited liability company incurred after the conversion takes effect shall be that of a member as provided in this chapter. A limited partner who becomes a member as a result of a conversion shall remain liable only as a limited partner for an obligation incurred by the limited partnership before the conversion takes effect. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 124, effective July 15, 2010; and amended ch. 133, sec. 43, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 124, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 74, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 133, and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intent of the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment not serve to void the amendment, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict; therefore, they have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section."  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 124, subsection (3)(d) cited "Section 146 of this Act." It is apparent from context that the section referred to should have been Section 145 of the Act, KRS 362.555. The Reviser of Statutes has made this change under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>