<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.12-230</section_number><catch_line>Unfair claims settlement practices. </catch_line><order_by>12-230</order_by><text>It is an unfair claims settlement practice for any person to commit or perform any of the following acts or omissions: <section prefix="1">Misrepresenting pertinent facts or insurance policy provisions relating to coverages at issue; </section><section prefix="2">Failing to acknowledge and act reasonably promptly upon communications with respect to claims arising under insurance policies; </section><section prefix="3">Failing to adopt and implement reasonable standards for the prompt investigation of claims arising under insurance policies; </section><section prefix="4">Refusing to pay claims without conducting a reasonable investigation based upon all available information; </section><section prefix="5">Failing to affirm or deny coverage of claims within a reasonable time after proof of loss statements have been completed; </section><section prefix="6">Not attempting in good faith to effectuate prompt, fair and equitable settlements of claims in which liability has become reasonably clear; </section><section prefix="7">Compelling insureds to institute litigation to recover amounts due under an insurance policy by offering substantially less than the amounts ultimately recovered in actions brought by such insureds; </section><section prefix="8">Attempting to settle a claim for less than the amount to which a reasonable man would have believed he was entitled by reference to written or printed advertising material accompanying or made part of an application; </section><section prefix="9">Attempting to settle claims on the basis of an application which was altered without notice to, or knowledge or consent of the insured; </section><section prefix="10">Making claims payments to insureds or beneficiaries not accompanied by statement setting forth the coverage under which the payments are being made; </section><section prefix="11">Making known to insureds or claimants a policy of appealing from arbitration awards in favor of insureds or claimants for the purpose of compelling them to accept settlements or compromises less than the amount awarded in arbitration; </section><section prefix="12">Delaying the investigation or payment of claims by requiring an insured, claimant, or the physician of either to submit a preliminary claim report and then requiring the subsequent submission of formal proof of loss forms, both of which submissions contain substantially the same information; </section><section prefix="13">Failing to promptly settle claims, where liability has become reasonably clear, under one (1) portion of the insurance policy coverage in order to influence settlements under other portions of the insurance policy coverage; </section><section prefix="14">Failing to promptly provide a reasonable explanation of the basis in the insurance policy in relation to the facts or applicable law for denial of a claim or for the offer of a compromise settlement; </section><section prefix="15">Failing to comply with the decision of an independent review entity to provide coverage for a covered person as a result of an external review in accordance with KRS 304.17A-621, 304.17A-623, and 304.17A-625; </section><section prefix="16">Knowingly and willfully failing to comply with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-714 when collecting claim overpayments from providers; or </section><section prefix="17">Knowingly and willfully failing to comply with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-708 on resolution of payment errors and retroactive denial of claims. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17037</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>