<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-854</section_number><catch_line>Closing of bank by commissioner -- Written statement of grounds -- Appointment of receiver. </catch_line><order_by>3-854</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may take possession and close a bank for purposes of liquidation in any case in which the commissioner finds that the bank: <section prefix="a">Is insolvent; </section><section prefix="b">Has permitted capital to become impaired to a level which does not permit the bank to operate in a safe and sound manner; </section><section prefix="c">Has had insurance of depositors' accounts terminated by the FDIC; or </section><section prefix="d">Has requested through its board of directors that the commissioner take possession for the benefit of depositors, other creditors and shareholders. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the commissioner has taken possession of and closed a bank for purpose of liquidation, the commissioner shall forthwith issue a written finding of one (1) or more of the grounds for closing provided in this section and shall appoint a receiver for the bank. The commissioner shall immediately thereafter apply to the receivership court for confirmation of the appointment of a receiver. The court shall act upon the application forthwith and may proceed without notice to any person. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 648, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 43, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.854. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>