<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.937</section_number><catch_line>Center of Excellence in Rural Health. </catch_line><order_by>937</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The University of Kentucky shall maintain a Center of Excellence in Rural Health. </section><section prefix="2">The mission of the Center of Excellence in Rural Health shall be the improvement of the health of all rural Kentuckians and the improvement of rural health care systems through education, research, and service. </section><section prefix="3">The Center of Excellence in Rural Health shall: <section prefix="a">Support a site-based director, core faculty, and staff; </section><section prefix="b">Collect and maintain statistical and other information relating to rural health status, rural health care systems, rural health policy, and other issues affecting the health and well-being of rural populations; </section><section prefix="c">Collect, analyze, interpret, disseminate, and make recommendations regarding the availability, distribution, and sufficiency of the health professions workforce; </section><section prefix="d">Provide educational opportunities for students committed to rural health care: <section prefix="1">To obtain education in needed health professions as determined by the workforce analyses, rotating these programs as necessary; </section><section prefix="2">By testing and developing innovative models for learning; and </section><section prefix="3">By reserving funds budgeted for specific educational programs that in the future are deemed no longer necessary for use for educational programs for other health professions; </section></section><section prefix="e">Maintain site-based family practice residencies; </section><section prefix="f">Serve as the federally designated Office of Rural Health and perform the duties prescribed by the United States Health Resources and Services Administration; </section><section prefix="g">Demonstrate or provide innovative programs that improve the health of rural Kentuckians and strengthen rural health care systems; and </section><section prefix="h">Advocate for rural health care. </section></section><section prefix="4">To the extent additional funds are appropriated, the Center of Excellence in Rural Health shall establish additional sites throughout the Commonwealth as necessary to achieve the mission of the center. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the study of rural health policies, workforce analyses, or the training of health professionals in or for rural or medically underserved areas by other state universities. </section><section prefix="6">The University of Kentucky shall report to the Council on Postsecondary Education and the Legislative Research Commission a detailed, audited statement of expenditures for each program function in the Center of Excellence for Rural Health Care by September 1 of each year which enumerates expenditures for the preceding fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 131, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>