<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.200</section_number><catch_line>Water Transportation Advisory Board -- Members -- Officers -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Water Transportation Advisory Board is established as an advisory body to the executive and legislative branches of government on matters pertaining to water transportation. </section><section prefix="2">The Water Transportation Advisory Board shall be composed of seven (7) members, to be appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">Four (4) members representing the Commonwealth's public riverports, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of eight (8) nominees supplied by the Kentucky Association of Riverports. The Governor shall give consideration to including a representative from each river containing an operating public riverport; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) at-large members, to be appointed by the Governor from the private sector associated with the waterways industry; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member representing Kentuckians for Better Transportation, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees supplied by that organization. </section></section><section prefix="3">After the initial appointments, members of the Water Transportation Advisory Board shall serve terms of four (4) years. Members shall be eligible to succeed themselves and shall serve until their successor is appointed. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the Water Transportation Advisory Board shall not be paid for their service as board members, and shall not be reimbursed for any expenses involved in attending board meetings. </section><section prefix="5">The Water Transportation Advisory Board shall elect a chair and a vice chair from its members who shall serve in those capacities until replaced. A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum for the purposes of conducting business. The board shall be subject to the provisions of the Kentucky Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="6">The Water Transportation Advisory Board shall meet biennially, or when called by the chair, or at the request of the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet. The board shall receive assistance in carrying out its administrative functions from the Transportation Cabinet and shall be attached to the Transportation Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 5, sets forth the initial terms for members of the Water Transportation Advisory Board established by this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5018</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>