<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="383" order_by="383">LANDLORD AND TENANT </unit></structure><section_number>383.200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions of forcible entry and detainer. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The words "possession," "entry," "detainer," in KRS 383.200 to 383.285, refer to lands and tenants.  </section><section prefix="2">A forcible entry is:  <section prefix="a">An entry without the consent of the person having the actual possession;  </section><section prefix="b">As to landlord, an entry upon the possession of his tenant at will or by sufferance, whether with or without the tenant's consent.  </section></section><section prefix="3">A forcible detainer is:  <section prefix="a">The refusal of a tenant to give possession to his landlord after the expiration of his term; or of a tenant at will or by sufferance to give possession to the landlord after the determination of his will;  </section><section prefix="b">The refusal of a tenant of a person who has made a forcible entry to give possession, on demand, to the person upon whose possession the forcible entry was made;  </section><section prefix="c">The refusal of a person who has made a forcible entry upon the possession of one who acquired it by a forcible entry to give possession, on demand, to him upon whose possession the first forcible entry was made;  </section><section prefix="d">The refusal of a person who has made a forcible entry upon the possession of a tenant for a term to deliver possession to the landlord, upon demand, after the term expires; and, if the term expires whilst a writ of forcible entry sued out by the tenant is pending, the landlord may, at his cost and for his benefit, prosecute it in the name of the tenant.  </section></section></text><history>Transferred 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1953, from C.C. sec. 452. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1953</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35699</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>