<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.680</section_number><catch_line>Records required to be kept. </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every licensee shall maintain complete records on all motor vehicles, by type, operating on Kentucky highways, weight and number of axles, mileage records and records of all purchases, use, and other dispositions of gasoline and special fuels. Such records, together with manifests of lading, invoices and other papers pertaining to gasoline or special fuels consumption, shall be retained for a period of five (5) years, and shall be made available to the Transportation Cabinet upon request for examination. </section><section prefix="2">If any licensee fails or refuses upon written request to furnish any information to the Transportation Cabinet concerning an audit, assessment, or verification of tax information, the cabinet may make an estimate of the licensee's tax due and issue an assessment against the licensee based upon the estimated tax due. Such assessment may be used by the cabinet in any legal proceeding for collection of the tax. The cabinet may at any subsequent proceeding require the taxpayer to file any reports or additional information it deems necessary. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 17. -- Amended 1956 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 20. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective>April 1, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28799</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>