<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.8-304</section_number><catch_line>Indorsement. </catch_line><order_by>8-304</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An indorsement may be in blank or special. An indorsement in blank includes an indorsement to bearer. A special indorsement specifies to whom a security is to be transferred or who has power to transfer it. A holder may convert a blank indorsement to a special indorsement. </section><section prefix="2">An indorsement purporting to be only of part of a security certificate representing units intended by the issuer to be separately transferable is effective to the extent of the indorsement. </section><section prefix="3">An indorsement, whether special or in blank, does not constitute a transfer until delivery of the certificate on which it appears or, if the indorsement is on a separate document, until delivery of both the document and the certificate. </section><section prefix="4">If a security certificate in registered form has been delivered to a purchaser without a necessary indorsement, the purchaser may become a protected purchaser only when the indorsement is supplied. However, against a transferor, a transfer is complete upon delivery and the purchaser has a specifically enforceable right to have any necessary indorsement supplied. </section><section prefix="5">An indorsement of a security certificate in bearer form may give notice of an adverse claim to the certificate, but it does not otherwise affect a right to registration that the holder possesses. </section><section prefix="6">Unless otherwise agreed, a person making an indorsement assumes only the obligations provided in KRS 355.8-108 and not an obligation that the security will be honored by the issuer. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 143, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 8-304. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>