<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.350</section_number><catch_line>Mine foreman to notify licensee or superintendent of dangers -- Duties as to reports -- Compliance with inspector's recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The mine foreman shall notify, in writing, the licensee or superintendent of the mine of his inability to comply with any of the requirements of the mining laws, and the licensee or superintendent shall at once attend to the matter complained of by the mine foreman so as to enable him to comply with the mining laws. </section><section prefix="2">The mine foreman shall each day enter and sign plainly with ink, in a book provided for that purpose, a report of the condition of the mine. The report shall clearly state any danger that comes under his observation during the day or is reported to him by his assistants or by the fire bosses, and shall state what action was taken to correct such danger, whether or not there is a proper supply of material on hand for the safe working of the mine, and whether or not the mining laws are being complied with. The mine foreman shall each day read carefully, and countersign with ink, all reports entered in the record book of the fire bosses. </section><section prefix="3">The mine superintendent, mine manager, mine foreman, and assistant foreman shall be held jointly responsible for the immediate compliance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 351 and this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 18. --Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 32, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-42. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>