<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.510</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person to engage in the business of bail bondsman as defined in subsection (3) of this section, or to otherwise for compensation or other consideration: <section prefix="a">Furnish bail or funds or property to serve as bail; or </section><section prefix="b">Make bonds or enter into undertakings as surety; </section></section> for the appearance of persons charged with any criminal offense or violation of law or ordinance punishable by fine, imprisonment or death, before any of the courts of this state, including city courts, or to secure the payment of fines imposed and of costs assessed by such courts upon a final disposition. <section prefix="2">Nothing contained herein shall serve to release any bail bondsman heretofore licensed by this state from the obligation of undischarged bail bond liability existing on June 19, 1976. </section><section prefix="3">"Bail bondsman" shall mean any person, partnership, or corporation engaged for profit in the business of furnishing bail, making bonds or entering into undertakings, as surety, for the appearance of persons charged with any criminal offense or violation of law or ordinance punishable by fine, imprisonment, or death, before any of the courts of this state, or securing the payment of fines imposed and of costs assessed by such courts upon final disposition thereof, and the business of a bail bondsman shall be limited to the acts, transactions, and undertakings described in this subsection and to no other. </section><section prefix="4">KRS 431.510 to 431.550 shall not be construed to limit or repeal KRS 431.021 or to prevent licensed insurers providing security required by Subtitle 39 of KRS Chapter 304 and nonprofit associations from posting or causing to be posted by licensed insurers security or acting as surety for their insureds or members for an offense arising from the operation of a motor vehicle, provided that such posting of security or acting as surety is merely incidental to the terms and conditions of an insurance contract or a membership agreement and provided further that no separate premium or charge therefor is required from the insureds or members. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 47, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18627</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>