<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.278</section_number><catch_line>Pilot program to analyze outcomes and effectiveness of substance abuse treatment programs. </catch_line><order_by>278</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Analyze" means to apply scientific and mathematical measures to determine meaningful patterns and associations in data. "Analyze" includes descriptive analysis to examine historical data, predictive analysis to examine future probabilities and trends, and prescriptive analysis to examine how future decisions may impact the population and trends; and </section><section prefix="b">"Pilot program" means a program in a county or set of counties, or a subset or subsets of the population, as designated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Office of Drug Control Policy for analyzing the effectiveness of substance abuse treatment services in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">The general purpose of this section is to assist in the development of a pilot program to analyze the outcomes and effectiveness of substance abuse treatment programs in order to ensure that the Commonwealth is: <section prefix="a">Addressing appropriate risk and protective factors for substance abuse in a defined population; </section><section prefix="b">Using approaches that have been shown to be effective; </section><section prefix="c">Intervening early at important stages and transitions; </section><section prefix="d">Intervening in appropriate settings and domains; and </section><section prefix="e">Managing programs effectively. </section></section><section prefix="3">Sources of data for the pilot program shall include, at a minimum, claims under the Kentucky Department for Medicaid Services, the electronic monitoring system for controlled substances established under KRS 218A.202, and the Department of Workers' Claims within the Labor Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">As funds are available, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Office of Drug Control Policy shall initiate a pilot program to determine, collect, and analyze performance measurement data for substance abuse treatment services to determine practices that reduce frequency of relapse, provide better outcomes for patients, hold patients accountable, and control health costs related to substance abuse. </section><section prefix="5">By December 31, 2016, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Office of Drug Control Policy shall issue a joint report to the Legislative Research Commission and the Office of the Governor that: <section prefix="a">Details the findings of the pilot program; </section><section prefix="b">Includes recommendations based on the pilot program's results for optimizing substance abuse treatment services; and </section><section prefix="c">Includes recommendations for the continued application of analytics to further augment Kentucky’s approach to fighting substance abuse in the future. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 9, effective March 25, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44005</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>