<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">A LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE </unit></structure><section_number>323A.210</section_number><catch_line>Functions of board -- Authority to promulgate administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Adopt and provide itself with a seal with a band inscribed, "Kentucky Board of Landscape Architects" with the coat of arms of the state in the center; </section><section prefix="b">Keep a complete record of its proceedings and an accurate list of all applications made, licenses issued, inactive and retired licenses, and licenses disciplined; </section><section prefix="c">Make a general report including finances to the Governor annually; and </section><section prefix="d">Employ legal counsel or contract for legal services it considers necessary. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board may: <section prefix="a">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary to maintain a program of continuing education for licensees. Continuing education requirements shall be determined by administrative regulation of the board. No requirement for continuing education shall exceed fifteen (15) hours per year; and </section><section prefix="b">Adopt all reasonable administrative regulations consistent with this chapter that are necessary to carry into effect the purposes of this chapter. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 21. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43366</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>