<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.621</section_number><catch_line>Extraterritorial application. </catch_line><order_by>621</order_by><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person may be convicted under this code of an offense committed by his own conduct or the conduct of another for which he is legally accountable when: <section prefix="1">Either the conduct or the result which is an element of the offense occurs within this state; </section><section prefix="2">Conduct occurring outside the state is sufficient to constitute an attempt to commit an offense within the state; </section><section prefix="3">Conduct occurring outside the state is sufficient to constitute a conspiracy to commit an offense within the state and an overt act in furtherance of the conspiracy occurs within the state; </section><section prefix="4">Conduct occurring within this state establishes complicity in the commission of, or an attempt, solicitation, or conspiracy to commit, an offense in another jurisdiction which is also an offense under this code; </section><section prefix="5">The offense consists of the omission to perform a legal duty imposed by this code regardless of where that person is when the omission occurs; or </section><section prefix="6">The offense is a violation of this code that expressly prohibits conduct outside the state. </section></text><history>Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 3, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=335</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>