<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.390</section_number><catch_line>Record book of boarding or lodging home. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text>Every person who boards or lodges children under the age of sixteen (16) years or conducts a boarding house or boarding home for such children, shall keep a book, securely bound, in which shall be entered the name, sex and race of every child boarded or lodged in the house or home conducted by him or her, together with the names and post office addresses of the parents of such child, the date such child was placed in such house or home, the date of such child's birth and the amount charged each week or month as compensation for boarding or lodging such child. Such facts shall be entered in said book at the time said child is placed in said house or home and shall be signed by the person or persons placing said child therein before leaving the premises upon which said house or home is conducted. Such book shall always be available for inspection by the health officer of the county in which said house or home is situated, or the judge of the juvenile session of District Court of said county, or any probation officer of said court. Failure to comply with the provisions of this section shall constitute an offense, punishable as provided in subsection (3) of KRS 199.990. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 153, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 63. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><note>This section was amended by 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 142, which was to have become effective July 1, 1982. Thereafter, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284 changed the effective date of that act to July 15, 1984. Then, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 184 repealed both 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, and 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7156</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>