<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.410</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>As used in KRS 273.405 to 273.453, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commission" means the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="2">"Community action agency" means a corporation organized for the purpose of alleviating poverty within a community or area by developing employment opportunities; by bettering the conditions under which people live, learn, and work; and by conducting, administering, and coordinating similar programs. </section><section prefix="3">"Designated review body" means either: <section prefix="a">Any interim joint committee, as designated by the Commission at any time when the General Assembly is not in session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review; or </section><section prefix="b">Any interim joint committee, as designated by the Commission at any time when the General Assembly is not in session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review plus the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue; or </section><section prefix="c">Any standing committee, as designated by the Committee on Committees during any legislative session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review; or </section><section prefix="d">Any standing committee, as designated by the Committee on Committees during any legislative session, whose subject jurisdiction relates to the block grant under review plus the Senate and House Standing Committees on Appropriations and Revenue. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Federal administering agency" means any agency of the United States government administering any block grant. </section><section prefix="5">"Federal act" means the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, P.L. 97-35, and any amendments thereto, as the federal act relates to community services block grants. </section><section prefix="6">"State administering agency" means any agency of the Commonwealth designated by the Governor to apply for and administer funds made available under the federal act. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13734</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>