<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.164</section_number><catch_line>Duties of council -- Staff support. </catch_line><order_by>164</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The council shall function as an advisory agent of state government and provide leadership and assistance for labor and management in this state, and shall serve to effect improved labor-management relations within the state, and to thereby attract and encourage new and existing industry in this state. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall not infringe upon or assume the responsibilities, duties or functions of the Labor Cabinet or Cabinet for Economic Development. The council may make recommendations to the Governor and the Legislature on matters relating to labor-management problems in this state and any other matter it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="3">Meetings of the council may be held at any location in this state; however the principal office of the council will be located in Frankfort, Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Labor Cabinet shall supply necessary staff and supplies to the council as well as funds for reimbursing each member for reasonable and necessary expenses incurred as a result of attending council meetings, and he or she shall act as the executive secretary of the council. The director of the Division of Employment Standards, Apprenticeship and Mediation shall be responsible for the coordination of such staff and supplies. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1718, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 36, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>