<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0287</section_number><catch_line>Duties of STEM Initiative Task Force -- Strategic plan -- Business plan. </catch_line><order_by>0287</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The STEM Initiative Task Force shall explore the critical relationship between STEM degree production and the knowledge-based economy of Kentucky and make recommendations to accelerate Kentucky's performance in the STEM disciplines. The task force shall develop a comprehensive, statewide strategic plan and a business plan to improve STEM performance in government, business, elementary and secondary education, and postsecondary education. </section><section prefix="2">The strategic plan shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Energizing a statewide public awareness campaign to help Kentuckians understand the critical importance of STEM to their own economic competitiveness and that of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Creating incentives and a supportive environment for students, teachers, and institutions that pursue, succeed, and excel in the STEM disciplines throughout the P-20 educational pipeline; </section><section prefix="c">Implementing international best practices in professional development programs for P-16 STEM teachers to increase the intensity, duration, and rigor of professional development; </section><section prefix="d">Improving teacher preparation programs and encouraging people with undergraduate and graduate degrees in the STEM disciplines to enter the teaching profession; </section><section prefix="e">Revolutionizing how STEM subjects are taught, learned, and assessed and implementing a statewide, research-based STEM curriculum that is aligned with global workforce and academic standards; </section><section prefix="f">Engaging business, industry, and civic leaders to improve STEM education and skills in the Commonwealth and creating incentives for Kentucky businesses that employ and invest in STEM-educated students; </section><section prefix="g">Developing an ongoing, coordinated, statewide STEM initiative that maximizes the impact of resources among government agencies, schools, colleges and universities, and businesses, and which is focused on developing and attracting STEM-related jobs in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="h">Targeting energy sustainability problems and opportunities in Kentucky and the nation as a primary objective of statewide STEM enhancements; </section><section prefix="i">Developing STEM mentoring programs that partner students in grades five (5) through twelve (12), their teachers, or both, with engineers, business professionals, college or university professors, university students, or others with expertise in the STEM disciplines to link academic coursework with the real world, underscoring the importance of rigorous academic preparation and encouraging pursuit of careers in the STEM disciplines; and </section><section prefix="j">Creating recognition awards and activities and financial support for individuals, businesses, or organizations that exhibit excellence in mentoring within the STEM disciplines. </section></section><section prefix="3">The STEM Task Force shall develop a business plan aligned with the strategic plan which includes measurable benchmarks for progress in achieving the goals within the strategic plan for one (1) year, three (3) year, and five (5) year time periods. The initial business plan shall be presented to the Interim Joint Committees on Appropriations and Revenue and Education by December 30, 2008. In subsequent years, the task force shall review and revise the business plan as needed to further the purposes of the STEM Initiative. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4186</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>