<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5319Receipt</section_number><catch_line>and disbursement of payments.   </catch_line><order_by>5319Receipt</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A support enforcement agency or tribunal of this state shall disburse promptly any amounts received pursuant to a support order, as directed by the order. The agency or tribunal shall furnish to a requesting party or tribunal of another state or a foreign country a certified statement by the custodian of the record of the amounts and dates of all payments received. </section><section prefix="2">If neither the obligor, nor the obligee who is an individual, nor the child resides in this state, upon request from the support enforcement agency of this state or another state, the child support enforcement agency of this state or a tribunal of this state shall: <section prefix="a">Direct that the support payment be made to the support enforcement agency in the state in which the obligee is receiving services; and </section><section prefix="b">Issue and send to the obligor's employer a conforming income-withholding order or an administrative notice of change of payee, reflecting the redirected payments. </section></section><section prefix="3">The support enforcement agency of this state receiving redirected payments from another state pursuant to a law similar to subsection (2) of this section shall furnish to a requesting party or tribunal of the other state a certified statement by the custodian of the record of the amount and dates of all payments received. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 30, effective June 24, 2015. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 42, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44106</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>