<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.250</section_number><catch_line>Chief engineer -- Powers and duties -- Report -- Compensation of engineers. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the board undertakes to establish or construct any improvement, it shall appoint a competent civil engineer as chief engineer, who may be an individual or a corporation, and who shall engage such assistants as the board approves. The chief engineer shall have control of the engineering work in the district. He may, with the consent of the board, consult any eminent engineer and obtain his opinion and advice concerning the plans for the district. He shall make all necessary surveys of the property within the district, and of any adjacent property that may be affected. </section><section prefix="2">The engineer shall make a written report to the board, with maps and profiles of the surveys, containing a plan for draining, leveeing and reclaiming the property from overflow or damage by water. These maps and profiles shall also indicate, so far as necessary, the physical characteristics of the land and the location of any cities, public roads, streets, railroads, drains and other property located on the land. The report shall also contain an accurate description of each tract of land within the district, giving the name of the owner and his post office address, and a statement showing the quantity of land. The report shall also include a property map, showing the boundary of each tract of land, the quantity of land in each tract, the name of the owner, and all streams, roads, railroads, and the location of all proposed improvements. Everything filed by the engineer shall be made in triplicate by him, one (1) marked original and the others duplicates. The original shall not be withdrawn from the custody of the secretary of the board, but the duplicates may be withdrawn for use by the viewers, the board, or for use on the work by the engineer or contractor, receipted for by the person withdrawing it and returned in due time. </section><section prefix="3">The compensation to engineers for making the preliminary survey and plan shall not exceed ten dollars ($10) per day and actual expenses. The compensation of any consulting engineer shall not exceed thirty dollars ($30) per day, nor shall a consulting engineer in any district be employed for more than ten (10) days. All engineering fees in the organization of a district under employment by the board shall not exceed five percent (5%) of the gross cost of the improvement made.  When any fees are sought to be allowed in excess of the above schedule and entered into the total costs as the basis for making the levy of assessments, permission shall first be obtained from the fiscal court. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 235, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2380b-14, 2380b-55. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12948</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>