<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.450</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 214.452 to 214.466. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>As used in KRS 214.452 to 214.466, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Blood" means any blood, blood product, blood component, or blood derivative including plasma. </section><section prefix="2">"Blood establishment" means a place of business under one (1) management at one (1) general physical location which engages in the collection, preparation, processing, labeling, packaging, and dispensing of blood to any health care facility, health service, or health care provider and which is licensed by the United States Food and Drug Administration. Blood establishment does not include autologous blood donation programs permitted under KRS 214.456. </section><section prefix="3">"Blood-borne communicable disease" means any of those diseases which are specifically so defined and set forth in administrative regulation promulgated by the United States Food and Drug Administration. </section><section prefix="4">"Health facility" means any health facility set forth under KRS 216B.015 which provides for the transfusion of blood into a living human body. </section><section prefix="5">"Health care provider" means any person licensed or certified under the laws of the Commonwealth as a dentist, physician, osteopath, registered nurse, practical nurse, paramedic, emergency medical technician, or physician assistant. </section><section prefix="6">"Health service" means any health service as set forth under KRS 216B.015 and which provides for the transfusion of blood into a living human body. </section><section prefix="7">"Transfuse" means to transfer blood from one (1) person to another. </section><section prefix="8">"Donor" means either a paid or volunteer donor of blood. </section><section prefix="9">"Untested blood" means blood that has not been tested or blood for which test results have not yet been returned. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 582, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 512, Part 12, sec. 86, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>