<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.3-620</section_number><catch_line>Own Risk and Solvency Assessment Summary Report or combination of reports -- When required -- Contents -- Signature.   </catch_line><order_by>3-620</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Upon the commissioner's request, and no more than once each year, an insurer shall submit to the commissioner an ORSA Summary Report or any combination of reports that together contain the information described in the ORSA Guidance Manual applicable to the insurer or the insurance group of which the insurer is a member. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding any request from the commissioner, if the insurer is a member of an insurance group, the insurer shall submit the report required by paragraph (a) of this subsection if the commissioner is the lead state commissioner of the insurance group, as determined by the procedures within the Financial Analysis Handbook adopted by the NAIC. </section></section><section prefix="2">The report shall include the signature of the insurer's or insurance group's chief risk officer or other executive having responsibility for the oversight of the insurer's enterprise risk management process, attesting to the best of his or her belief and knowledge that the insurer applies the enterprise risk management process described in the ORSA Summary Report and that a copy of the report has been provided to the insurer's board of directors or the appropriate committee thereof. </section><section prefix="3">An insurer may comply with subsection (1) of this section by providing the most recent and substantially similar report, provided by the insurer or another member of an insurance group of which the insurer is a member, to the commissioner of insurance of another state or to a supervisor or regulator of a foreign jurisdiction, if the report provides information that is comparable to the information described in the ORSA Guidance Manual. Any such report in a language other than English shall be accompanied by a translation of the report into the English language. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43952</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>