<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="401" order_by="401">CHANGE OF NAME </unit></structure><section_number>401.020</section_number><catch_line>Parents or guardian may have child's name changed in District, Family, or Circuit Court. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>Both parents, provided both are living, or one (1) parent if one (1) is deceased, or if no parent is living, the guardian, may have the name of a child under the age of eighteen (18) changed by the District Court, or if the Family Court or Circuit Court has a case before it involving the family, the Family Court of a county with a Family Court, or the Circuit Court of a county without a Family Court of the county in which the child resides. However, if one (1) parent refuses or is unavailable to execute the petition, proper notice of filing the petition shall be served in accordance with the Rules of Civil Procedure. If the child resides on a United States Army post, military reservation, or fort, his or her name may be changed by the District Court, or the Family Court of a county with a Family Court, or the Circuit Court of a county without a Family Court of any county adjacent thereto. </text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 2, effective March 22, 2013. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 396, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 89. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 13. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3718. </history><metadata><effective>March 22, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>