<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.430</section_number><catch_line>Rejection of application for license -- Time frame for issuance of license. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state director may reject any application for a license issued under KRS 243.030 and 243.040 if the application is incomplete or the correct fee has not been remitted with the application. In rejecting an application, the state director shall provide a written statement of the deficiencies contained in the application. </section><section prefix="2">A license shall not be issued until the thirty (30) day period in which a protest is permissible has expired. Any license for which public notice under KRS 243.360 is required may conditionally be issued in less than thirty (30) days from the date the application is received if the premises has previously operated under the same type of license within the last twelve (12) months. All remaining licenses provided for in KRS 243.030 or 243.040 shall be issued when, in the sound discretion of the director, all of the information necessary has been obtained. </section></text><history>Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 18. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, secs. 3 and 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-131, 2554b-204. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11365</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>