<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.221</section_number><catch_line>Meetings of board -- Quorum -- Minutes -- Bylaws -- Hearing examiner. </catch_line><order_by>221</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each board of adjustment shall conduct meetings at the call of the chairman who shall give written or oral notice to all members of the board at least seven (7) days prior to the meeting, which notice shall contain the date, time and place for the meeting, and the subject or subjects which will be discussed. </section><section prefix="2">A simple majority of the total membership of a board of adjustment as established by agreement shall constitute a quorum. Any member of a board of adjustment who has any direct or indirect financial interest in the outcome of any question before the body shall disclose the nature of the interest and shall disqualify himself from voting on the question. </section><section prefix="3">All boards of adjustment shall adopt bylaws for the transaction of business and shall keep minutes and records of all proceedings, including regulations, transactions, findings, and determinations, and the number of votes for and against each question, and if any member is absent or abstains from voting, indicating the fact, all of which shall, immediately after adoption, be filed in the office of the board. If the board has no office, such records may be kept in custody of an officer of the board and shall be available to the general public. A transcript of the minutes of a board of adjustment shall be provided if requested by a party, at the expense of the requesting party, and the transcript shall constitute the record. </section><section prefix="4">A board of adjustment may appoint one (1) or more of its members to act as hearing examiner to preside over a public hearing or public meeting and make recommendations to the board based upon a transcript or record of the hearing. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, secs. 44 to 46. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>