<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-140</section_number><catch_line>Optional additional benefits. </catch_line><order_by>39-140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On and after July 1, 1975, each reparation obligor of the owner of a vehicle required to be registered in this Commonwealth shall, upon the request of a reparation insured, be required to provide added reparation benefits for economic loss in units of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per person subject to the lesser of: <section prefix="a">Forty thousand dollars ($40,000) in added reparation benefits; or </section><section prefix="b">The limit of security provided for liability to any one (1) person in excess of the requirements of KRS 304.39-110(1)(a). </section></section><section prefix="2">Each basic reparation obligor shall be permitted to incorporate in added reparation benefits coverage such terms, conditions and exclusions as may be consistent with premiums charged. The amounts payable under added reparation benefits may be duplicative of benefits received from collateral source benefits, or may provide for reasonable waiting periods, deductibles or coinsurance provision. The added reparation obligor shall be subrogated, subject to KRS 304.39-070 and 304.39-300, to the injured person's right of recovery against any responsible third party. </section><section prefix="3">If the injured person, or injured persons, is entitled to damages under KRS 304.39-060 from the liability insurer of a second person, a self-insurer or an obligated government, collection of such damages shall have priority over the rights of the subrogee for its reimbursement of basic or added reparation benefits paid to or in behalf of such injured person or persons. </section><section prefix="4">Basic reparation insurers shall make available upon request deductibles in the amounts of two hundred fifty dollars ($250), five hundred dollars ($500) and one thousand dollars ($1,000) from all basic reparation benefits otherwise payable, except that if two (2) or more basic reparation insureds to whom the deductible is applicable under the contract of insurance are injured in the same accident, the aggregate amount of the deductible applicable to all of them shall not exceed the specified deductible, which amount where necessary shall be allocated equally among them. Any person who is a basic reparation insured under an insurance policy issued with no deductible or with a deductible of a lesser amount than that under which he receives basic reparation benefits payments, shall be entitled to be paid under such policy the difference between the benefits he is actually paid and the benefits which would have been paid had his benefits been payable under such policy. </section><section prefix="5">Reparation obligors shall make available upon request to those persons who have rejected their tort limitations, in accordance with KRS 304.39-060(4), basic reparation benefits coverage and added reparation benefits. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 14, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>