<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.641</section_number><catch_line>Distribution of authorized delegate vote among party candidates. </catch_line><order_by>641</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The political parties in distributing authorized delegate votes among party candidates shall select one (1) of the following methods of distribution: <section prefix="a">The candidates receiving the highest number of votes, provided each candidate receives at least fifteen percent (15%) of the total vote cast by his political party, shall be awarded a pro rata portion of the authorized delegate vote of his political party as follows: <section prefix="1">The total vote received by the candidates qualifying under the provisions of KRS 118.551 to 118.651 and subsections herein shall, when combined, be equal to one hundred percent (100%); </section><section prefix="2">Each such candidate shall share in the total percentage in direct proportion to the total vote received by him mathematically determined to be the percentage of the aggregate vote which represents one hundred percent (100%); </section><section prefix="3">Each political party shall appropriate such percentage, as is determined by this section, to the total number of delegate votes as are allotted by the national committee of each party; or </section></section><section prefix="b">The candidate receiving the highest number of votes cast by his political party shall be awarded a pro rata portion of the authorized delegate vote of his political party in compliance with the state party rules for that party. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each political party shall, on the first ballot at its national convention, cast this Commonwealth's vote for the candidates as determined by the primary or party caucus and calculated under this section or under party rules, whichever is applicable.  Provided, however, that in the event of the death or withdrawal of a candidate receiving votes under this section prior to the tabulation of the first ballot, any delegate votes allocated to such candidate shall be considered uncommitted.  Withdrawal shall mean notice in writing by the candidate to the chairman of the Kentucky delegation prior to the first ballot. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27674</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>