<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="524" order_by="524">INTERFERENCE WITH JUDICIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>524.040</section_number><catch_line>Intimidating a participant in the legal process. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of intimidating a participant in the legal process when, by use of physical force or a threat directed to a person he believes to be a participant in the legal process, he or she: <section prefix="a">Influences, or attempts to influence, the testimony, vote, decision, or opinion of that person; </section><section prefix="b">Induces, or attempts to induce, that person to avoid legal process summoning him or her to testify; </section><section prefix="c">Induces, or attempts to induce, that person to absent himself or herself from an official proceeding to which he has been legally summoned; </section><section prefix="d">Induces, or attempts to induce, that person to withhold a record, document, or other object from an official proceeding; </section><section prefix="e">Induces, or attempts to induce, that person to alter, destroy, mutilate, or conceal an object with intent to impair the object's integrity or availability for use in an official proceeding; or </section><section prefix="f">Hinders, delays, or prevents the communication to a law enforcement officer or judge of information relating to the possible commission of an offense or a violation of conditions of probation, parole or release pending judicial proceedings. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">An official proceeding need not be pending or about to be instituted at the time of the offense; and </section><section prefix="b">The testimony, record, document, or other object need not be admissible in evidence or free of a claim of privilege. </section></section><section prefix="3">Intimidating a participant in the legal process is a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="4">In order for a person to be convicted of a violation of this section, the act against a participant in the legal process or the immediate family of a participant in the legal process shall be related to the performance of a duty or role played by the participant in the legal process. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 203, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19906</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>