<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9133</section_number><catch_line>Contents of declaration.   </catch_line><order_by>9133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The declaration for a condominium shall contain: <section prefix="a">The name of the condominium which shall include the word "condominium" or be followed by the words "a condominium," and the association; </section><section prefix="b">The name of every county in which any part of the condominium is situated; </section><section prefix="c">A legally sufficient description of the real estate included in the condominium; </section><section prefix="d">A statement of the maximum number of units which the declarant reserves the right to create; </section><section prefix="e">A description of the boundaries of each unit created by the declaration, including the unit's identifying number; </section><section prefix="f">A description of any limited common elements as provided in KRS 381.9141(2)(h), except for those limited common elements specified in KRS 381.9127(2), (4), and (6); </section><section prefix="g">A description of any real estate, except real estate subject to development rights, which may be allocated subsequently as limited common elements, other than limited common elements specified in KRS 381.9127(2), (4), and (6), together with a statement that they may be so allocated; </section><section prefix="h">A description of any development rights and other special declarant rights reserved by the declarant, together with a legally sufficient description of the real estate to which each of those rights applies, and a time limit within which each of those rights must be exercised; </section><section prefix="i">If any development right may be exercised with respect to different parcels of real estate at different times, a statement to that effect together with: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A statement fixing the boundaries of those portions and identifying the proposed order in which those portions may be subjected to the exercise of each development right; or </section><section prefix="b">A statement that no assurances are made concerning the boundaries or order in which the exercise of development rights may occur; and </section></section><section prefix="2">A statement as to whether, if any development right is exercised in any portion of the real estate subject to that development right, that development right must be exercised in all or in any other portion of the remainder of that real estate; </section></section><section prefix="j">Any other conditions or limitations under which the rights described in paragraph (i) of this subsection may be exercised or will lapse; </section><section prefix="k">An allocation to each unit of the allocated interests in the manner described in KRS 381.9137; </section><section prefix="l">Any restrictions on use, occupancy, and alienation of the units; </section><section prefix="m">The recording data for recorded easements and licenses appurtenant to or included in the condominium or to which any portion of the condominium is or may become subject by virtue of a reservation in the declaration; and </section><section prefix="n">All matters required by KRS 381.9135, 381.9137, 381.9139, 381.9141, 381.9153, and 381.9169(4). </section></section><section prefix="2">The declaration may contain any other matters the declarant deems appropriate. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 17, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36832</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>