<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.280</section_number><catch_line>Conspiracy to violate chapter unlawful. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text>It shall be an unlawful practice for a person, or for two (2) or more persons to conspire: <section prefix="1">To retaliate or discriminate in any manner against a person because he has opposed a practice declared unlawful by this chapter, or because he has made a charge, filed a complaint, testified, assisted, or participated in any manner in any investigation, proceeding, or hearing under this chapter; or </section><section prefix="2">To aid, abet, incite, compel, or coerce a person to engage in any of the acts or practices declared unlawful by this chapter; or </section><section prefix="3">To obstruct or prevent a person from complying with the provisions of this chapter or any order issued thereunder; </section><section prefix="4">To resist, prevent, impede, or interfere with the commission, or any of its members or representatives, in the lawful performance of duty under this chapter; or </section><section prefix="5">To coerce, intimidate, threaten, or interfere with any person in the exercise or enjoyment of, or on account of his having exercised or enjoyed, or on account of his having aided or encouraged any other person in the exercise or enjoyment of, any right granted or protected by KRS 344.360, 344.367, 344.370, 344.380, or 344.680. </section></text><history>   Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 34, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 6, sec. 601. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32631</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>