<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.020</section_number><catch_line>Rescue squads -- Formation -- Authorization to operate within a jurisdiction -- Functions -- Public notification of lost or missing impaired persons.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Rescue squads may be formed and duly authorized to perform in the public interest. Authorization to operate within a jurisdiction may be granted by the chief elected official of each urban-county government, charter county government, county, or city which the squad proposes to serve. Rescue squads shall have a formal affiliation with the local disaster and emergency services organization. The statement of affiliation shall be renewed annually. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 39F.040, a rescue squad shall be composed of at least twelve (12) active members and shall maintain at least one (1) vehicle dedicated to rescue service. Squads may operate in conjunction with a fire division, or may operate as a separate unit. </section><section prefix="3">Each rescue squad shall develop and maintain bylaws and written procedures to specify, at a minimum, election or appointment, succession, and term of officers; financial accounting; property accountability; and rules of notification and response to emergencies. </section><section prefix="4">Rescue squads shall contribute to public safety and welfare by performing functions which may include but not be limited to: removal of victims trapped in vehicles or structures; search for lost or missing persons or missing impaired persons, except those sought for criminal acts; first aid; emergency evacuation; recovery of drowning victims; recovery of any corpse if not accessible by ambulance or hearse and if so authorized by the coroner; and traffic control at an accident scene when requested by law enforcement authorities. Rescue squads organized for the purpose of searching for lost or missing persons which are searching for an impaired person shall work in cooperation with local media outlets to notify the public that an impaired person is lost or missing. Rescue squads shall not engage in law enforcement activities other than traffic control. </section><section prefix="5">The division shall administer funds appropriated for rescue equipment and training and the division shall promulgate administrative regulations to be applied to all rescue squads that apply for financial assistance. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 84, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, provides that Sections 2 to 5 of the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Chase McMurray Act."  (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 4, provides that Sections 1 to 3 of this Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Golden Alert Bill." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>