<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.073</section_number><catch_line>Continuing competency requirements.   </catch_line><order_by>073</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As a prerequisite for license renewal, all individuals licensed under provisions of this chapter shall be required to document continuing competency during the immediate past licensure period as prescribed in regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The continuing competency requirement shall be documented and reported as set forth by the board in administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall approve providers of continuing education. The approval may include recognition of providers approved by national organizations and state boards of nursing with comparable standards. Standards for these approvals shall be set by the board in administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall work cooperatively with professional nursing organizations, approved nursing schools, and other potential sources of continuing education programs to ensure that adequate continuing education offerings are available statewide. The board may enter into contractual agreements to implement the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall be responsible for notifying applicants for licensure and licensees applying for license renewal, of continuing competency requirements. </section><section prefix="6">As a part of the continuing education requirements that the board adopts to ensure continuing competency of present and future licensees, the board shall ensure practitioners licensed under KRS Chapter 314 complete a one-time training course of at least one and one-half (1.5) hours covering the recognition and prevention of pediatric abusive head trauma, as defined in KRS 620.020. The one and one-half (1.5) hours required under this section shall be included in the current number of required continuing education hours. </section><section prefix="7">In order to offset administrative costs incurred in the implementation of the mandatory continuing competency requirements, the board may charge reasonable fees as established by regulation in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="8">The continuing competency requirements shall include at least five (5) contact hours in pharmacology continuing education for any person licensed as an advanced practice registered nurse. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 16, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 117, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 57, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 171, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 10, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 113 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44619</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>