<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.270</section_number><catch_line>Administration of system by Energy and Environment Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text>The Wild Rivers System shall be administered by the Energy and Environment Cabinet according to the policies and criteria set forth in KRS 146.200 to 146.360. The secretary for energy and environment shall adopt such rules or regulations necessary for the preservation and enhancement of the stream areas as set forth in KRS 146.250, and for control of recreational, educational, scientific, and other uses of these areas in a manner that shall not impair them. In such administration primary emphasis shall be given to protecting aesthetic, scenic, historic, archaeologic, and scientific features of the area. The secretary shall develop a management plan for a designated stream area and shall publicize and hold public hearings and record the views expressed on each plan developed. Management plans for a given stream area may establish varying degrees of intensity for its protection, based on special attributes of each area, but shall follow the concepts embodied in KRS 146.230. No public use of lands within the boundaries of a designated wild river area in which the state has acquired an interest shall be permitted prior to the development of a management plan. Any such management plan shall be developed jointly with the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources with respect to those aspects of such plan as relate to the jurisdiction of that department over fish and wildlife resources. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 127, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 7. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(1), (9). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1501</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>