<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="421" order_by="421">WITNESSES </unit></structure><section_number>421.500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 421.500 to 421.575 -- Applicability -- Required notifications -- Duties of public officers and agencies.   </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 421.500 to 421.575, "victim" means an individual who suffers direct or threatened physical, financial, or emotional harm as a result of the commission of a crime classified as stalking, unlawful imprisonment, use of a minor in a sexual performance, unlawful transaction with a minor in the first degree, terroristic threatening, menacing, harassing communications, intimidating a witness, criminal homicide, robbery, rape, assault, sodomy, kidnapping, burglary in the first or second degree, sexual abuse, wanton endangerment, criminal abuse, human trafficking, or incest. If the victim is a minor or legally incapacitated, "victim" means a parent, guardian, custodian or court-appointed special advocate. <section prefix="a">If the victim is deceased and the relation is not the defendant, the following relations shall be designated as "victim" for the purpose of exercising those rights contained in KRS 421.500 to 421.575: <section prefix="1">The spouse; </section><section prefix="2">An adult child if subparagraph 1. of this paragraph does not apply; </section><section prefix="3">A parent if subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph do not apply; </section><section prefix="4">A sibling if subparagraphs 1. to 3. of this paragraph do not apply; and </section><section prefix="5">A grandparent if subparagraphs 1. to 4. of this paragraph do not apply. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the victim is deceased and the relation is not the defendant, the following relations shall be designated as "victims" for the purpose of presenting victim impact testimony under KRS 532.055(2)(a)7.: <section prefix="1">A spouse; </section><section prefix="2">An adult child; </section><section prefix="3">A parent; </section><section prefix="4">A sibling; and </section><section prefix="5">A grandparent. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If any court believes that the health, safety, or welfare of a victim who is a minor or is legally incapacitated would not otherwise adequately be protected, the court may appoint a special advocate to represent the interest of the victim and to exercise those rights provided for by KRS 421.500 to 421.575. Communication between the victim and the special advocate shall be privileged. </section><section prefix="3">Law enforcement personnel shall ensure that victims receive information on available protective, emergency, social, and medical services upon initial contact with the victim and are given information on the following as soon as possible: <section prefix="a">Availability of crime victim compensation where applicable; </section><section prefix="b">Community based treatment programs; </section><section prefix="c">The criminal justice process as it involves the participation of the victim or witness; </section><section prefix="d">The arrest of the accused; and </section><section prefix="e">How to register to be notified when a person has been released from prison, jail, a juvenile detention facility, or a psychiatric facility or forensic psychiatric facility if the case involves a violent crime as defined in KRS 439.3401 and the person charged with or convicted of the offense has been involuntarily hospitalized pursuant to KRS Chapter 202A. </section></section><section prefix="4">Law enforcement officers and attorneys for the Commonwealth shall provide information to victims and witnesses on how they may be protected from intimidation, harassment, and retaliation as defined in KRS 524.040 or 524.055. </section><section prefix="5">Attorneys for the Commonwealth shall make a reasonable effort to insure that: <section prefix="a">All victims and witnesses who are required to attend criminal justice proceedings are notified promptly of any scheduling changes that affect their appearances; </section><section prefix="b">If victims so desire and if they provide the attorney for the Commonwealth with a current address and telephone number, they shall receive prompt notification, if possible, of judicial proceedings relating to their case, including, but not limited to, the defendant's release on bond and any special conditions of release; of the charges against the defendant, the defendant's pleading to the charges, and the date set for the trial; of notification of changes in the custody of the defendant and changes in trial dates; of the verdict, the victim's right to make an impact statement for consideration by the court at the time of sentencing of the defendant, the date of sentencing, the victim's right to receive notice of any parole board hearing held for the defendant, and that the office of Attorney General will notify the victim if an appeal of the conviction is pursued by the defendant; and of a scheduled hearing for shock probation or for bail pending appeal and any orders resulting from that hearing; and </section><section prefix="c">The victim knows how to register to be notified when a person has been released from a prison, jail, a juvenile detention facility, or a psychiatric facility or forensic psychiatric facility if the case involves a violent crime as defined in KRS 439.3401 and the person charged with or convicted of the offense has been involuntarily hospitalized pursuant to KRS Chapter 202A; </section><section prefix="d">The victim receives information on available: <section prefix="1">Protective, emergency, social, and medical services; </section><section prefix="2">Crime victim compensation, where applicable; </section><section prefix="3">Restitution, where applicable; </section><section prefix="4">Assistance from a victim advocate; and </section><section prefix="5">Community-based treatment programs; and </section></section><section prefix="e">The victim of crime may, pursuant to KRS 15.247, receive protection from harm and threats of harm arising out of cooperation with law enforcement and prosecution efforts. </section></section><section prefix="6">The victim shall be consulted by the attorney for the Commonwealth on the disposition of the case including dismissal, release of the defendant pending judicial proceedings, any conditions of release, a negotiated plea, and entry into a pretrial diversion program. </section><section prefix="7">In prosecution for offenses listed in this section for the purpose of defining "victim," law enforcement agencies and attorneys for the Commonwealth shall promptly return a victim's property held for evidentiary purposes unless there is a compelling reason for retaining it. Photographs of such property shall be received by the court as competent evidence in accordance with the provisions of KRS 422.350. </section><section prefix="8">A victim or witness who so requests shall be assisted by law enforcement agencies and attorneys for the Commonwealth in informing employers that the need for victim or witness cooperation in the prosecution of the case may necessitate absence of that victim or witness from work. </section><section prefix="9">The Attorney General, where possible, shall provide technical assistance to law enforcement agencies and attorneys for the Commonwealth if such assistance is requested for establishing a victim assistance program. </section><section prefix="10">If a defendant seeks appellate review of a conviction and the Commonwealth is represented by the Attorney General, the Attorney General shall make a reasonable effort to notify victims promptly of the appeal, the status of the case, and the decision of the appellate court. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  Subsection (4) of this statute contained a reference to KRS 524.045, which was repealed in 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. The reference to KRS 524.045 should have been deleted from this statute as a conforming amendment in that Act, or even when this statute was amended in 2008. The Reviser of Statutes has removed the reference during the codification of 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h) to correct manifest clerical or typographical errors. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41849</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>