<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.4477</section_number><catch_line>Assessment to be deducted from the purchase price of the commodity -- Use of funds. </catch_line><order_by>4477</order_by><text>In the event a majority of the producers eligible for participation in the referendum and voting therein shall vote in favor of the assessment, then, upon the written request of the duly certified commission, council, board, association, or other agency of producers of the agricultural commodity, the Commissioner shall notify forthwith, by certified mail, all persons engaged in the business of purchasing the agricultural commodities in this state, that on and after the date specified in the letter, the specified assessment shall be deducted from the producer's payment by the purchaser, or his agent or representative, from the purchase price of the agricultural commodity. The assessment so deducted shall be remitted by the purchaser to the duly certified commission, council, board, association, or other agency of the producers entitled to it on or before the final day of the month following the end of the month in which the commodity is sold to the purchaser. The funds, including donations from individuals, concerns, corporations, and grants from the state or governmental agencies, shall be used for the purpose of promoting and stimulating, through educational and applied research programs, the increased production of the agricultural commodity. The books and records of all the purchasers of the agricultural commodity shall at all times during regular business hours be open for inspection by the Commissioner of Agriculture or his duly authorized agents. </text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11667</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>