<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.0832</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for licensure as a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor.   </catch_line><order_by>0832</order_by><text>An applicant for licensure as a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor shall pay the board the initial fee for licensure, and shall: <section prefix="1">Be at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="2">Have obtained from a regionally accredited college or university or a college or university accredited by an agency recognized by the United States Department of Education: <section prefix="a">A sixty (60) hour master's degree in a behavioral science with clinical application; </section><section prefix="b">A thirty (30) hour advanced placement master's degree in a behavioral science with clinical application; or </section><section prefix="c">A doctoral degree in a behavioral science with clinical application; </section></section><section prefix="3">Have completed at least one hundred eighty (180) classroom hours of alcohol and drug counselor specific board-approved curriculum; </section><section prefix="4">Have passed a written examination as specified by the board in administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="5">Have signed an agreement to abide by the standards of practice and code of ethics approved by the board; </section><section prefix="6">Have completed at least six (6) hours of ethics training; three (3) hours of domestic violence training; and two (2) hours training in the transmission, control, treatment, and prevention of the human immunodeficiency virus, in addition to the educational requirements in subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="7">Have submitted two (2) letters of reference from certified alcohol and drug counselors or licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselors; </section><section prefix="8">Live or work at least a majority of the time in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="9">Have complied with the requirements for the training program in suicide assessment, treatment, and management in KRS 210.366 and any administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; and </section><section prefix="10">Have completed two thousand (2,000) hours of board-approved experience working with persons having a substance use disorder, three hundred (300) hours of which shall have been under the direct supervision of a licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44295</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>