<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.46967</section_number><catch_line>Violation as unfair or deceptive trade practice -- Powers of Attorney General. </catch_line><order_by>46967</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A violation by a telemarketing company, telemarketer, caller, or merchant of KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999 shall constitute an unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive act or practice in the conduct of trade or commerce in violation of KRS 367.170. </section><section prefix="2">All of the remedies, powers, and duties provided for the Attorney General by KRS 367.190 to 367.300 and the penalties provided in KRS 367.990, relating to acts and practices violating KRS 367.170 shall apply with equal force and effect to acts and practices declared unlawful by KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999 shall be construed to limit or restrict the exercise of powers or the performance of the duties of the Attorney General authorized under any other provision of law. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 463, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was created by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 302 and 463, which are substantively identical and have been codified together. Minor variations have been resolved by giving precedence to Acts ch. 463 which was enacted last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34975</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>