<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.350</section_number><catch_line>Fees. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In proceedings in the juvenile session of the District Court, no court fees shall be charged against, and no witness fees shall be allowed to, any party to a petition. No public officer shall be entitled to receive any fee from the service of process or for attendance in court in any such proceedings. All other persons acting under orders of the court may be paid for service of process and attendance as witnesses. The payments for fees provided by law for like services in civil cases in the Circuit Court are to be made out of the county treasury. The county or state may compensate any officer or person in the amount prescribed by law for the transportation of a child to a place where he will be detained or placed or the return of any child to the jurisdiction of the court, and funds for this purpose may be appropriated and paid by the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of paying salaries and expenses necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS Chapters 600 to 645, the fiscal court of any county, or urban-county council of an urban-county government, may levy taxes and make appropriations within constitutional limitations. The legislative body of any city also is authorized to appropriate funds to assist the county in carrying out the purposes of KRS Chapters 600 to 645, including providing facilities for custody and care of children coming within the purview of KRS Chapters 600 to 645. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 39, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 54, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20174</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>