<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.355</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of professional license or certification held by active duty member of Armed Forces. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, any member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty who, at the time of activation, was: <section prefix="a">A member in good standing with any administrative body of the state; and </section><section prefix="b">Duly licensed or certified to engage in his or her profession or vocation in the Commonwealth; </section></section> shall be kept in good standing by the administrative body with which he or she is licensed or certified. <section prefix="2">While a licensee or certificate holder is an active duty member of the Armed Forces of the United States, the license or certificate referenced in subsection (1) of this section shall be renewed without: <section prefix="a">The payment of dues or fees; </section><section prefix="b">Obtaining continuing education credits when: <section prefix="1">Circumstances associated with military duty prevent obtaining training and a waiver request has been submitted to the appropriate administrative body; or </section><section prefix="2">The active duty military member performs the licensed or certified occupation as part of his or her military duties as annotated in Defense Department form 214 (DD 214); or </section></section><section prefix="c">Performing any other act typically required for the renewal of the license or certificate. </section></section><section prefix="3">The license or certificate issued under this section shall be continued as long as the licensee or certificate holder is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States on active duty and for a period of at least six (6) months after discharge from active duty. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39918</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>