<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.849</section_number><catch_line>Long-term statewide goals concerning STEM disciplines and AP and IB course participation. </catch_line><order_by>849</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall establish long-term and annual statewide goals for increasing: <section prefix="a">The number of high schools providing rigorous curricula and making available accelerated classes and college credit for students; </section><section prefix="b">The number and percentage of students enrolled in and completing AP and IB courses by content area; </section><section prefix="c">The number and percentage of students taking the AP and IB examinations in advanced science and mathematics; </section><section prefix="d">The number and percentage of students receiving a score of three (3) or better on the AP examinations or five (5) or better on IB examinations in advanced science and mathematics; </section><section prefix="e">The number and percentage of students whose families are eligible for free or reduced-price lunch receiving a score of three (3) or better on AP examinations or five (5) or better on IB examinations; </section><section prefix="f">The number of teachers successfully completing a College Board-endorsed AP or IB summer training institute; </section><section prefix="g">The number of teachers with the knowledge and training needed to prepare students for high achievement on AP and IB examinations in advanced science and mathematics; and </section><section prefix="h">Other criteria determined by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Department of Education shall develop a program evaluation framework regarding the use of the science and mathematics advancement fund for the purposes set forth in KRS 158.847. The program evaluation framework shall address areas including but not limited to the use of funds, the number of grants and awards, student achievement outcomes, and trends over time on the indicators established to measure progress against the statewide goals under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Beginning in 2008, the department shall submit an annual report no later than December 1 to the Kentucky Board of Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Education. The report for 2008 shall provide a status report on the implementation of programs supported by the science and mathematics advancement fund. Subsequent reports shall incorporate information collected and analyzed based on the program evaluation framework under paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3620</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>