<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-040</section_number><catch_line>"Consultant" defined. </catch_line><order_by>9-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A "consultant" is a person, who as an independent contractor in relation to a client, for fee or compensation other than from an insurer, in any manner advises or purports to advise, any person actually or prospectively insured, or named or to be named as beneficiary, or having or to have any interest in or insured under, an insurance contract or annuity contract, existing or proposed, relative to coverage, advisability, rights, or interests under such contract, or relative to the retention, exchange, surrender, or exercise of rights thereunder. This subsection shall not apply as to an attorney while acting under a license to practice law in this state. </section><section prefix="2">A "property and casualty consultant" is a person licensed as a consultant as to property insurance contracts, casualty insurance contracts, health insurance contracts issued by property or casualty insurers, and surety contracts. </section><section prefix="3">A "life and health consultant" is a person licensed as a consultant as to life insurance contracts, annuity contracts, and health insurance contracts. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 4, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16888</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>