<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.460</section_number><catch_line>Utilities to pay interest on deposits required of patrons -- Commission to calculate interest rate annually -- Interest rates for water districts and water associations -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, a utility, including an electric cooperative organized under KRS Chapter 279, shall pay interest on amounts required to be deposited by patrons to secure utility service. The commission shall calculate the interest rate on an annual basis by averaging the one (1) year constant maturity treasury rate from September, October, and November, and shall notify utilities in December of each year of the interest rate to be paid by utilities for the following calendar year. </section><section prefix="2">No water district organized under KRS Chapter 74 nor water association organized under KRS Chapter 273 shall pay interest that exceeds the rate it receives in interest, nor shall the interest payable to the customer at any time exceed six percent (6%) annually on amounts required to be deposited by patrons to secure water accounts. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A to implement this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2223-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40132</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>