<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.380</section_number><catch_line>School employees -- Restrictions on appointment of relatives, violent offenders, and persons convicted of sex crimes -- Restriction on assignment to alternative education program as disciplinary action -- National and state criminal history background checks on applicants, new hires, and school-based decision-making council parent members -- Application and renewal forms -- Employees charged with felony offenses.   </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Alternative education program" means a program that exists to meet the needs of students that cannot be addressed in a traditional classroom setting but through the assignment of students to alternative classrooms, centers, or campuses that are designed to remediate academic performance, improve behavior, or provide an enhanced learning experience. Alternative education programs do not include career or technical centers or departments; </section><section prefix="b">"Contractor" means an adult who is permitted access to school grounds pursuant to a current or prospective contractual agreement with the school, school board, school district, or school-affiliated entity, at times when students are present. The term "contractor" includes an employee of a contractor; </section><section prefix="c">"Relative" means father, mother, brother, sister, husband, wife, son, daughter, aunt, uncle, son-in-law, and daughter-in-law; and </section><section prefix="d">"Vacancy" means any certified position opening created by the resignation, dismissal, nonrenewal of contract, transfer, or death of a certified staff member of a local school district, or a new position created in a local school district for which certification is required. However, if an employer-employee bargained contract contains procedures for filling certified position openings created by the resignation, dismissal, nonrenewal of contract, transfer, or death of a certified staff member, or creation of a new position for which certification is required, a vacancy shall not exist, unless certified positions remain open after compliance with those procedures. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 160.346: <section prefix="a">All appointments, promotions, and transfers of principals, supervisors, teachers, and other public school employees shall be made only by the superintendent of schools, who shall notify the board of the action taken. All employees of the local district shall have the qualifications prescribed by law and by the administrative regulations of the Kentucky Board of Education and of the employing board. Supervisors, principals, teachers, and other employees may be appointed by the superintendent for any school year at any time after February 1 preceding the beginning of the school year. No superintendent of schools shall appoint or transfer himself or herself to another position within the school district; </section><section prefix="b">When a vacancy occurs in a local school district, the superintendent shall notify the chief state school officer thirty (30) days before the position shall be filled. The chief state school officer shall keep a registry of local district vacancies which shall be made available to the public. The local school district shall post position openings in the local board office for public viewing; </section><section prefix="c">When a vacancy needs to be filled in less than thirty (30) days' time to prevent disruption of necessary instructional or support services of the school district, the superintendent may seek a waiver from the chief state school officer. If the waiver is approved, the appointment shall not be made until the person recommended for the position has been approved by the chief state school officer. The chief state school officer shall respond to a district's request for waiver or for approval of an appointment within two (2) working days; </section><section prefix="d">When a vacancy occurs in a local district, the superintendent shall conduct a search to locate minority teachers to be considered for the position. The superintendent shall, pursuant to administrative regulations of the Kentucky Board of Education, report annually the district's recruitment process and the activities used to increase the percentage of minority teachers in the district; </section><section prefix="e">No relative of a superintendent of schools shall be an employee of the school district. However, this shall not apply to a relative who is a classified or certified employee of the school district for at least thirty-six (36) months prior to the superintendent assuming office, or prior to marrying a relative of the superintendent, and who is qualified for the position the employee holds. A superintendent's spouse who has at least eight (8) years of service in school systems may be an employee of the school district. A superintendent's spouse who is employed under this provision shall not hold a position in which the spouse supervises certified or classified employees. A superintendent's spouse may supervise teacher aides and student teachers. However, the superintendent shall not promote a relative who continues employment under an exception of this subsection; </section><section prefix="f">No superintendent shall employ a relative of a school board member of the district, unless on July 13, 1990, the board member's relative is an employee of the district, the board member is holding office, and the relative was not initially hired by the district during the tenure of the board member. A relative employed in 1989-90 and initially hired during the tenure of a board member serving on July 13, 1990, may continue to be employed during the remainder of the board member's term. However, the superintendent shall not promote any relative of a school board member who continues employment under the exception of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="g"><section prefix="1">No principal's relative shall be employed in the principal's school, except a relative who is not the principal's spouse and who was employed in the principal's school during the 1989-90 school year. </section><section prefix="2">No spouse of a principal shall be employed in the principal's school, except: <section prefix="a">A principal's spouse who was employed in the principal's school during the 1989-90 school year for whom there is no position for which the spouse is certified to fill in another school operated in the district; or </section><section prefix="b">A principal's spouse who was employed in the 1989-90 school year and is in a school district containing no more than one (1) elementary school, one (1) middle school, and one (1) high school. </section></section><section prefix="3">A principal's spouse who is employed in the principal's school shall be evaluated by a school administrator other than the principal. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of KRS 161.760 shall not apply to any transfer made in order to comply with the provisions of this paragraph. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">No superintendent shall assign a certified or classified staff person to an alternative education program as part of any disciplinary action taken pursuant to KRS 161.011 or 161.790 as part of a corrective action plan established pursuant to the local district evaluation plan. </section><section prefix="4">No superintendent shall employ in any position in the district any person who is a violent offender or has been convicted of a sex crime as defined by KRS 17.165 which is classified as a felony. The superintendent may employ, at his discretion, persons convicted of sex crimes classified as a misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A superintendent shall require a national and state criminal background check on all new certified hires in the school district and student teachers assigned within the district. Excluded are certified individuals who were employed in another certified position in a Kentucky school district within six (6) months of the date of hire and who had previously submitted to a national and state criminal background check for the previous employment. </section><section prefix="b">The superintendent shall require that each new certified hire and student teacher, as set forth in paragraph (a) of this subsection, submit to a national and state criminal history background check by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. </section><section prefix="c">All fingerprints requested under this section shall be on an applicant fingerprint card provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The fingerprint cards shall be forwarded to the Federal Bureau of Investigation from the Department of Kentucky State Police after a state criminal background check is conducted. The results of the state and federal criminal background check shall be sent to the hiring superintendent. Any fee charged by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall be an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request and conducting the search. </section><section prefix="d">The Education Professional Standards Board may promulgate administrative regulations to impose additional qualifications to meet the requirements of Public Law 92-544. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A superintendent shall require a state criminal background check on all classified initial hires. </section><section prefix="b">The superintendent shall require that each classified initial hire submit to a state criminal history background check by the Department of Kentucky State Police. If an applicant has been a resident of Kentucky twelve (12) months or less, the superintendent may require a national criminal history background check as a condition of employment. </section><section prefix="c">Any request for records under this section shall be on an applicant fingerprint card provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The results of the state criminal background check and the results of the national criminal history background check, if requested under the provisions of paragraph (b) of this subsection, shall be sent to the hiring superintendent. Any fee charged by the Department of Kentucky State Police shall be an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request and conducting the search. </section></section><section prefix="7">The superintendent may require a contractor, volunteer, or visitor to submit to a national and state criminal history background check by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. Any request for records under this section shall be on an applicant fingerprint card provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The results of the state criminal background check and the results of the national criminal history background check, if requested, shall be sent to the hiring superintendent. Any fee charged by the Department of Kentucky State Police shall be an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request and conducting the search. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">If a school term has begun and a certified or classified position remains unfilled or if a vacancy occurs during a school term, a superintendent may employ an individual, who will have supervisory or disciplinary authority over minors, on probationary status pending receipt of the criminal history background check. Application for the criminal record of a probationary employee shall be made no later than the date probationary employment begins. </section><section prefix="b">Employment shall be contingent on the receipt of the criminal history background check documenting that the probationary employee has no record of a sex crime nor as a violent offender as defined in KRS 17.165. </section><section prefix="c">Notwithstanding KRS 161.720 to 161.800 or any other statute to the contrary, probationary employment under this section shall terminate on receipt by the school district of a criminal history background check documenting a record of a sex crime or as a violent offender as defined in KRS 17.165 and no further procedures shall be required. </section><section prefix="d">The provisions of KRS 161.790 shall apply to terminate employment of a certified employee on the basis of a criminal record other than a record of a sex crime or as a violent offender as defined in KRS 17.165. </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">Each application or renewal form, provided by the employer to an applicant for a classified position, shall conspicuously state the following: "FOR THIS TYPE OF EMPLOYMENT, STATE LAW REQUIRES A STATE CRIMINAL HISTORY BACKGROUND CHECK AS A CONDITION OF EMPLOYMENT. UNDER CERTAIN CIRCUMSTANCES, A NATIONAL CRIMINAL HISTORY BACKGROUND CHECK MAY BE REQUIRED AS A CONDITION OF EMPLOYMENT." </section><section prefix="b">Each application or renewal form, provided by the employer to an applicant for a certified position, shall conspicuously state the following: "FOR THIS TYPE OF EMPLOYMENT, STATE LAW REQUIRES A NATIONAL AND STATE CRIMINAL HISTORY BACKGROUND CHECK AS A CONDITION OF EMPLOYMENT." </section><section prefix="c">Each application form for a district position shall require the applicant to: <section prefix="1">Identify the states in which he or she has maintained residency, including the dates of residency; and </section><section prefix="2">Provide picture identification. </section></section></section><section prefix="10">The provisions of subsections (5), (6), (7), (8) and (9) of this section shall apply to a nonfaculty coach or nonfaculty assistant as defined under KRS 161.185. </section><section prefix="11">A school-based decision-making council parent member, as defined under KRS 160.345, shall submit to a state and national fingerprint-supported criminal history background check by the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation. The results of the state criminal history background check and the results of the national criminal history background check, if requested, shall be sent to the district superintendent. Any fee charged by the Department of Kentucky State Police shall be an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request and conducting the search. A parent member may serve prior to the receipt of the criminal history background check report but shall be removed from the council on receipt by the school district of a report documenting a record of a sex crime or criminal offense against a victim who is a minor as defined in KRS 17.500 or as a violent offender as defined in KRS 17.165, and no further procedures shall be required. </section><section prefix="12">Notwithstanding any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes to the contrary, when an employee of the school district is charged with any offense which is classified as a felony, the superintendent may transfer the employee to a second position until such time as the employee is found not guilty, the charges are dismissed, the employee is terminated, or the superintendent determines that further personnel action is not required. The employee shall continue to be paid at the same rate of pay he or she received prior to the transfer. If an employee is charged with an offense outside of the Commonwealth, this provision may also be applied if the charge would have been treated as a felony if committed within the Commonwealth. Transfers shall be made to prevent disruption of the educational process and district operations and in the interest of students and staff and shall not be construed as evidence of misconduct. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 85, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective January 14, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 169, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 221, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 467, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 489, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 483, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 78, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 518, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 11. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 18. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 13. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-34. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 61 and 85, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/12/2012). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes in codification has changed the internal numbering of subsection (6) of this statute. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40245</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>