<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.510</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text>The Pest Control Advisory Board shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="1">To review commercial structural pest control and commercial structural fumigation enforcement proceedings and to make written recommendations for further action to the department. </section><section prefix="2">To hold hearings on the denial of an application for a license pursuant to KRS 217B.540. </section><section prefix="3">To review commercial structural pest control and commercial structural fumigation applicator license applications to ensure that the applicants meet state pest control licensing requirements and to make recommendations to the department. </section><section prefix="4">To review the state pest control licensing examinations. </section><section prefix="5">To assist the department in administering the licensing examinations for commercial structural pest control applicators and commercial structural fumigation applicators and to make recommendations to the department. </section><section prefix="6">To serve as a resource group to keep the department informed of current technical advancements in the pest control industry. </section><section prefix="7">To recommend reasonable rules and regulations concerning the following matters: <section prefix="a">Standards of application and workmanship. </section><section prefix="b">Proper health and safety precautions. </section><section prefix="c">Requirements for standardized structural pest control contracts. </section><section prefix="d">Furnishing of reports and information necessary for the Pest Control Advisory Board to carry out the provisions of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585. </section></section><section prefix="8">To assist the department in administering the licensing examinations for the commercial structural pest control applicators and commercial structural fumigation applicators and to make recommendations to the department. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 67, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9563</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>