<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.440</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for participation in fund distribution. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each local unit of government which meets the following requirements shall be eligible to share in the distribution of funds from the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund: <section prefix="a">Employs one (1) or more police officers; </section><section prefix="b">Pays every police officer at least the minimum federal wage; </section><section prefix="c">Maintains the minimum educational requirement of a high school degree, or its equivalent as determined by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, for employment of police officers on or after July 1, 1972, and for all sheriffs appointed or elected on or after July 15, 1998, and all deputy sheriffs, and state or public university police officers employed after July 15, 1998; provided, however, that all police officers employed prior to July 1, 1972, shall be deemed to have met the requirements of this subsection, and that all sheriffs serving in office on July 15, 1998, all deputy sheriffs, and state or public university police, employed prior to July 15, 1998, shall be deemed to have met the requirements of this subsection; </section><section prefix="d">Requires all police officers employed on or after July 1, 1972, and all sheriffs appointed or elected on or after July 15, 1998, and deputy sheriffs, and state or public university police officers employed on or after January 1, 1998, to successfully complete a basic training course of at least six hundred forty (640) hours' duration within one (1) year of the date of employment at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. All sheriffs serving in office on July 15, 1998, all deputy sheriffs, and state or public university police, employed prior to January 1, 1998, shall be deemed to have met the requirements of this subsection. The council may, by the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A, set the number of hours for basic training at a number higher than six hundred forty (640) hours based upon a training curriculum approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council as determined by a validated job task analysis; </section><section prefix="e">Requires all police officers, whether originally employed before or after July 1, 1972, and all sheriffs appointed or elected before, on, or after July 15, 1998, and all deputy sheriffs and state or public police officers employed before, on, or after July 15, 1998, to successfully complete each calendar year an in-service training course, appropriate to the officer's rank and responsibility and the size and location of his department, of at least forty (40) hours' duration at a school certified or recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. This requirement shall be waived for the period of time that a peace officer is serving on active duty in the United States Armed Forces. This waiver shall be retroactive for peace officers from the date of September 11, 2001; </section><section prefix="f">Requires compliance with all provisions of law applicable to local police, state or public university police, or sheriffs and their deputies, including transmission of data to the centralized criminal history record information system as required by KRS 17.150; </section><section prefix="g">Requires compliance with all reasonable rules and regulations, appropriate to the size and location of the local police department, state or public university police department, or sheriff's office, issued by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet to facilitate the administration of the fund and further the purposes of KRS 15.410 to 15.510; and </section><section prefix="h">Possesses a written policy and procedures manual related to domestic violence for law enforcement agencies that meets the standards set forth by, and has been approved by, the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. The policy shall comply with the provisions of KRS 403.715 to 403.785. The policy shall include purpose statements; definitions; supervisory responsibilities; procedures for twenty-four (24) hour access to protective orders; procedures for enforcement of court orders or relief when protective orders are violated; procedures for timely and contemporaneous reporting of adult abuse and domestic violence to the Cabinet for Families and Children, Department for Community Based Services; victim rights, assistance, and service responsibilities; and duties related to timely completion of records. </section></section><section prefix="2">No local unit of government which meets the criteria of this section shall be eligible to continue sharing in the distribution of funds from the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund unless the local police department, state or public university police department, or sheriff's office actually begins and continues to comply with the requirements of this section; provided, further, that no local unit shall be eligible to share in the distribution of funds from the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund until the local police department, state or public university police department, or sheriff's office has substantially complied with subsection (1)(f) and (g) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">A sheriff's office shall not lose eligibility to share in the distribution of funds from the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund if the sheriff does not participate in the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 23, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 510, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 606, sec. 120, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(10). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 2, (3) at 648. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=956</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>