<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-703</section_number><catch_line>Dissociated partner's liability to other persons. </catch_line><order_by>1-703</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A partner's dissociation does not of itself discharge the partner's liability for a partnership obligation incurred before dissociation. A dissociated partner is not liable for a partnership obligation incurred after dissociation, except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A partner who dissociates without resulting in a dissolution and winding up of the partnership business is liable as a partner to the other party in a transaction entered into by the partnership, or a surviving partnership under KRS 362.1-901 to 362.1-908, within two (2) years after the partner's dissociation, only if the partner is liable for the obligation under KRS 362.1-306 and at the time of entering into the transaction the other party: <section prefix="a">Reasonably believed that the dissociated partner was then a partner; </section><section prefix="b">Did not have notice of the partner's dissociation; and </section><section prefix="c">Is not deemed to have knowledge under KRS 362.1-303(5) or notice under KRS 362.1-704(3). </section></section><section prefix="3">By agreement with the partnership creditor and the partners continuing the business, a dissociated partner may be released from liability for a partnership obligation. </section><section prefix="4">A dissociated partner is released from liability for a partnership obligation if a partnership creditor, with notice of the partner's dissociation but without the partner's consent, agrees to a material alteration in the nature or time of payment of a partnership obligation. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 51, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34500</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>