<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.648</section_number><catch_line>Gross revenues and excise tax fund and state baseline and local growth fund -- Creation and administration of funds. </catch_line><order_by>648</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established in the State Treasury a gross revenues and excise tax fund. The fund shall be held and administered by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The cabinet shall invest money in the fund in the same manner as money in the state general fund. </section><section prefix="2">There is established in the State Treasury a state baseline and local growth fund. The fund shall be held and administered by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The cabinet shall invest money in the fund in the same manner as money in the state general fund. </section><section prefix="3">All revenue from the tax imposed under KRS 136.604 and 136.616, including all penalties and interest attributable to the nonpayment of the tax or for noncompliance with KRS 132.825 and 136.600 to 136.660 shall be deposited into gross revenues and excise tax fund. Amounts deposited in the gross revenues and excise tax fund shall be allocated among the state, political subdivisions, school districts and special districts as provided in KRS 136.648, 136.650, 136.652, 136.654, and 136.656. </section><section prefix="4">All money in the gross revenues and excise tax fund designated for distribution to political subdivisions under KRS 136.648, 136.650, 136.652, 136.654, and 136.656: <section prefix="a">Shall not be withheld or reduced by the General Assembly or any state agency for any reason, except for adjustments provided for within KRS 132.825 and 136.600 to 136.660; and </section><section prefix="b">Shall be used solely and exclusively for the provision of services to the general public, including public protection, health services, education, libraries, transportation services, and economic development. No amount shall be used for purely local purposes affecting only the inhabitants of the particular political subdivision, such as the administration of local government. Neither the General Assembly nor any state agency shall mandate how the funds are to be used. </section></section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 112, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28607</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>