<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.0305</section_number><catch_line>Souvenir package sales by licensed distillers.   </catch_line><order_by>0305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any licensed Kentucky distiller that is located in wet territory and that has a gift shop or other retail outlet on its premises may conduct the activities permitted under this section as a part of its distiller's license. </section><section prefix="2">A wholesaler registered to distribute the brands of any distiller may permit the distiller to deliver a souvenir package directly from the distillery proper to the portion of the distillery premises operated by the licensee for the sale of souvenir packages. However, all direct shipments shall be invoiced from the distiller to the wholesaler and from the wholesaler to the distiller, and all products directly shipped shall be included in the wholesaler's inventory and depletions for purposes of tax collections imposed pursuant to KRS 243.710 to 243.895 and 243.990. </section><section prefix="3">A distiller may sell souvenir packages at retail to distillery visitors of legal drinking age, in quantities not to exceed an aggregate of three (3) liters per visitor per day, with the exception of a purchase by a partnership, limited liability partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or other business entity holding an event on the premises of the distillery, in which case the limitation shall be one (1) liter per visitor attending the event. These sales shall be permitted only through the gift shop or other retail outlet on the distiller's premises. </section><section prefix="4">Hours of sale for souvenir packages at retail shall be 9 a.m. until 9 p.m. prevailing time Monday through Saturday. The licensed premises may remain open if it has a separate department pursuant to KRS 244.290(1). </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in this section, souvenir package sales shall be governed by all the statutes and administrative regulations governing the retail sale of distilled spirits by the package. </section><section prefix="6">No wholesaler may restrict the sale of souvenir packages to the distiller of origin exclusively, but shall make souvenir packages available to any Kentucky retail licensee licensed for the sale of distilled spirits by the package. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 46, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42481</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>