<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">STATE AND AREA PLANNING -- REGIONAL DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147.670</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers and duties of commission. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text>The area planning commission shall have the power and duty to: <section prefix="1">Prepare an area-wide comprehensive plan of the entire area within its jurisdiction, which includes all territory incorporated and unincorporated within the counties signator thereto. The area-wide comprehensive plan shall include at least all comprehensive plan elements and research requirements prescribed in KRS Chapter 100, so that the planning commissions of local planning units as established under KRS Chapter 100 and their respective legislative bodies, may adopt all or parts of said area-wide comprehensive plan, as it applies to their respective areas of jurisdiction, as a means of fulfilling the applicable requirements of KRS Chapter 100. This area-wide comprehensive plan shall be reviewed and amended, if necessary, at least once every five (5) years; </section><section prefix="2">Appoint an executive director for the commission and fix his compensation. The director shall be qualified by training and experience in the field of planning and zoning; </section><section prefix="3">Upon written request of a city or county within the territory of the area planning commission, the area planning commission's staff may prepare and submit for consideration to the appropriate local planning unit, zoning ordinances based on the comprehensive plans of such local planning unit. The area planning commission staff assigned to perform such work shall consult with the appropriate local planning unit as established under KRS Chapter 100, the city or county legislative bodies, and all property owners who are directly affected by any change in the zoning ordinance applicable to such local planning unit; </section><section prefix="4">Prescribe the qualifications of, appoint, remove, and fix the compensation of employees of the commission; </section><section prefix="5">Prepare, publish, and distribute reports and other material relating to the business of the commission; </section><section prefix="6">Prepare and submit an annual budget to the area planning council for the operation of the commission; </section><section prefix="7">Exercise general supervision of and make regulations for the administration of the affairs of the commission; </section><section prefix="8">Establish policies, procedures, and priorities for assigning staff and providing services to planning units established under the provision of KRS Chapter 100, their respective cities and counties, and other public and private agencies and organizations, and may, irrespective of KRS 147.675, enter into agreements with cities, counties, and other public agencies and organizations in accordance with the provisions of KRS 65.210 to 65.300 for the administration of KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839 and KRS Chapters 99, 99A, 100, and 198B; and </section><section prefix="9">Keep an accurate and complete record of all commission proceedings, financial statements, and annually report to the various cities and counties signators to the agreement provided in KRS 147.620. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 2. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>