<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8821</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>8821</order_by><text>Each code enforcement board shall have the power to: <section prefix="1">Adopt rules and regulations to govern its operation and the conduct of its hearings that are consistent with the requirements of KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839 and ordinances of the local government or local governments creating the board. </section><section prefix="2">Conduct hearings, or assign a hearing officer to conduct a hearing, to determine whether there has been a violation of any local government ordinance that the board has jurisdiction to enforce. Any member of the code enforcement board, including the chairman, may be assigned to conduct hearings on behalf of the board. All hearing officers, including members of a code enforcement board who serve as hearing officers, shall receive training related to the conduct of administrative hearings in accordance with procedures set out in KRS 13B.080. </section><section prefix="3">Subpoena alleged violators, witnesses, and evidence to its hearings. Subpoenas issued by the board may be served by any code enforcement officer. </section><section prefix="4">Take testimony under oath. The chairman of the board, or an assigned hearing officer, shall have the authority to administer oaths to witnesses prior to their testimony before the board on any matter. </section><section prefix="5">Make findings and issue orders that are necessary to remedy any violation of a local government ordinance that the board has jurisdiction to enforce. </section><section prefix="6">Impose civil fines as authorized by ordinance on any person found to have violated any ordinance that the board has jurisdiction to enforce. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>