<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.110</section_number><catch_line>Registry of Election Finance -- Membership -- Terms -- Meetings -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created as an independent agency of state government a Kentucky Registry of Election Finance. The registry shall be composed of seven (7) members appointed as provided herein. The registry shall remain independent of any other agency or department of state government. Members shall be at least twenty-five (25) years of age, registered voters in Kentucky, not announced candidates for public office, not officers of a political party's state central executive committee, shall not have been convicted of an election offense, and shall be persons of high ethical standards who have an active interest in promoting fair elections. Appointees shall be subject to Senate confirmation at the next regular session of the General Assembly following appointment, or at the next special session if included in the Governor's call. Appointees shall have full power to serve until any vote of nonconfirmation. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the registry shall be selected as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the state central committee of the political party polling the largest vote at the last gubernatorial election. </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the state central committee of the political party polling the second largest vote at the last gubernatorial election. The members appointed pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall take office on August 15, 1990, for a term of one (1) year and their successors shall serve a term of four (4) years beginning August 15, 1991, or until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) other members shall be appointed by the Governor. Before making these appointments, the Governor shall solicit nominations from at least two (2) organizations which have demonstrated a nonpartisan interest in fair elections and informed voting. The Governor's solicitations and the replies shall be public records. The Governor shall give due consideration to such nominations. The two (2) members appointed pursuant to this subsection shall be one (1) from each of the two (2) political parties which polled the greatest number of votes at the last gubernatorial election. Members appointed pursuant to this subsection shall take office on August 15, 1988, for a term of four (4) years or until their successors are appointed and qualified and their successors shall serve a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be appointed by the Auditor of Public Accounts after soliciting nominations as provided by subsection (c) of this section. The appointee shall be a member of one (1) of the two (2) political parties which polled the greatest number of votes at the last gubernatorial election. The member appointed pursuant to this subsection shall take office on August 15, 1997, for a term of four (4) years or until his successor is appointed and qualified and his successors shall serve a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be appointed by the Attorney General after soliciting nominations as provided by subsection (c) of this section. The appointee shall not be a member of the same political party as the person appointed by the Auditor of Public Accounts pursuant to subsection (d) of this section. The member appointed pursuant to this subsection shall take office on August 15, 1990, for a term of four (4) years or until his successor is appointed and qualified and his successors shall serve a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member shall be appointed by the Secretary of State after soliciting nominations as provided by subsection (c) of this section. The Secretary of State's appointment shall be without regard to political affiliation. The member appointed pursuant to this subsection shall take office on August 15, 1990, for a term of three (3) years or until his successor is appointed and qualified and his successors shall serve a term of four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">The members of the registry shall select a chairman from among the appointed membership, effective August 15, 1990. The chairman shall serve in that capacity for one (1) year and shall be eligible for reelection. The chairman shall preside at all meetings and shall have all the powers and privileges of the other members. </section><section prefix="4">In the event of a vacancy in the office of any member, the vacancy shall be filled in the same manner as the vacating member's office was filled pursuant to subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The registry shall fix the place and time of its regular meetings by order duly recorded in its minutes. No action shall be taken without a quorum present. Special meetings shall be called by the chairman on his own initiative or on the written request of three (3) members. Members shall receive seven (7) days' written notice of a special meeting and the notice shall specify the purpose, time and place of the meeting, and no other matters may be considered, without a specific waiver by all the members. </section><section prefix="6">The members of the registry shall receive sixty-five dollars ($65) per diem, and shall be reimbursed for all reasonable and necessary expenses. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 185. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27860</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>