<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.536</section_number><catch_line>Investigation and establishment of territorial boundaries -- Inclusion of city -- Notice to residents of territory -- Annexation by multicounty district.   </catch_line><order_by>536</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a petition for annexation of territory to a district is filed with the commissioner, he shall investigate at once the boundary of the territory proposed to be annexed, and may, at the cost of the district, cause to be made surveys necessary to establish with reasonable accuracy a boundary that will, in his judgment, accomplish the purpose sought by annexation of the territory in a practicable and workable manner, and that will be sufficiently comprehensive to avoid confusion or interference with any other similar district then existing or that may be created. The boundary established by the commissioner need not follow the boundary proposed by the district. </section><section prefix="2">Should it be found desirable to include in the territory to be annexed by a district all or a portion of a city of the home rule class, the governing body of such city shall determine by ordinance whether the city or portion thereof shall be included in the district, or whether the city shall bind itself to pay the charges for the services of the district furnished in such area. </section><section prefix="3">When the boundaries of the territory proposed to be annexed have been fixed by the commissioner as prescribed in subsection (1) of this section, he shall give notice of the application for annexation of the territory by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="4">If a multicounty district proposes to annex the unincorporated territory of another contiguous county, and the fiscal court of the contiguous county expresses by resolution its approval of the annexation, then the commissioner shall accept the boundaries of the proposed annexation. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 279, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 169. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43864</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>