<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.070</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal courts having county commissioners, law governing -- Special sessions -- Tie vote. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, and as otherwise provided by law, all laws governing fiscal courts composed of the county judge/executive and the justices of the peace shall be applicable to fiscal courts composed of the county judge/executive and the county commissioners. </section><section prefix="2">When the county judge/executive is unable to call a special session, or refuses to do so on request of two (2) commissioners, two (2) commissioners may call it if, in their opinion, the necessity exists. </section><section prefix="3">When there is a tie vote in the fiscal court in the selection of any officer or employee to be selected by the fiscal court, and a deadlock results and continues for fifteen (15) days or longer, the county judge/executive shall cause to be entered upon the minutes of the fiscal court an order reciting the facts as to the deadlock, and the question upon which it has occurred and exists, and thereupon, unless an election is immediately made by the fiscal court, the county judge/executive shall appoint the officer or employee. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1850, 1851b-6. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23682</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>