<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="406" order_by="406">UNIFORM ACT ON PATERNITY </unit></structure><section_number>406.051</section_number><catch_line>Remedies -- District Court's concurrent jurisdiction for child custody and visitation in paternity cases. </catch_line><order_by>051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The District Court has jurisdiction of an action brought under this chapter and all remedies for the enforcement of judgments for expenses of pregnancy and confinement for a wife or for education, necessary support, or funeral expenses for children born out of wedlock. An appeal may be had to the Circuit Court if prosecuted within sixty (60) days from the date of judgment. The court has continuing jurisdiction to modify or revoke a judgment for future education. All remedies under the uniform reciprocal enforcement of support act are available for enforcement of duties of support under this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The District Court may exercise jurisdiction, concurrent with that of the Circuit Court, to determine matters of child custody and visitation in cases where paternity is established as set forth in this chapter. The District Court, in making these determinations, shall utilize the provisions of KRS Chapter 403 relating to child custody and visitation. The District Court may decline jurisdiction if it finds the circumstances of any case require a level of proceedings more appropriate to the Circuit Court. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 314, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 412, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17620</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>