<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-131</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180.   </catch_line><order_by>6-131</order_by><text>As used in KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180, unless the context requires otherwise, the following definitions shall apply on or after the operative date of the valuation manual, as defined in subsection (11) of this section: <section prefix="1">"Accident and health insurance" means contracts that incorporate morbidity risk and provide protection against economic loss resulting from accident, sickness, or medical conditions and as may be specified in the valuation manual; </section><section prefix="2">"Appointed actuary" means a qualified actuary who is appointed in accordance with the valuation manual to prepare the actuarial opinion required by KRS 304.6-171(6) to (10); </section><section prefix="3">"Company" means an entity which has written, issued, or reissued life insurance, accident and health insurance, or deposit-type contracts: <section prefix="a">In Kentucky and has at least one (1) policy in force or a claim; or </section><section prefix="b">In any state and is required to hold a certificate of authority to write life insurance, accident and health insurance, or deposit-type contracts in this state; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Deposit-type contract" means a contract that does not incorporate mortality or morbidity risks and as may be specified in the valuation manual; </section><section prefix="5">"Life insurance" means contracts that incorporate mortality risk, including annuity and pure endowment contracts, and as may be specified in the valuation manual; </section><section prefix="6">"NAIC" means the National Association of Insurance Commissioners; </section><section prefix="7">"Policyholder behavior" means any action a policyholder, contract holder, or any other person with the right to elect options may take under a policy or contract subject to KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180, excluding events of mortality that result in benefits prescribed in their essential aspects by the terms of the policy or contract, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Lapse; </section><section prefix="b">Withdrawal; </section><section prefix="c">Transfer; </section><section prefix="d">Deposit; </section><section prefix="e">Premium payment; </section><section prefix="f">Loan; </section><section prefix="g">Annuitization; or </section><section prefix="h">Benefit elections; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Principle-based valuation" means a reserve valuation that uses one (1) or more methods or one (1) or more assumptions determined by the company and is required to comply with KRS 304.6-151 as specified in the valuation manual; </section><section prefix="9">"Qualified actuary" means an individual who is qualified to sign the applicable statement of actuarial opinion in accordance with the American Academy of Actuaries qualification standards for actuaries signing the statements and who meets the requirements specified in the valuation manual; </section><section prefix="10">"Tail risk" means a risk that occurs either where the frequency of low-probability events is higher than expected under a normal probability distribution or when there are observed events of very significant size or magnitude; and </section><section prefix="11">"Valuation manual" means the manual of valuation instructions adopted by the NAIC and any subsequent amendments. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>