<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.33-510Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 154.33-501 to 154.33-585.   </catch_line><order_by>33-510Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 154.33-501 to 154.33-585, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Area" or "region" means the geographical area of Kentucky contained within the Appalachian region as defined by the federal Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965, as amended; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the executive board of Shaping Our Appalachian Region, Inc., a Kentucky nonprofit 501(c)(3) corporation created and organized, as of June 24, 2015, to advance and promote a resilient and diverse eastern Kentucky by providing leadership, vision, and collaborative partnerships to support innovative regional practices and enhance public and private investments in areas such as job creation, entrepreneurship, tourism, education and lifelong learning, health and wellness, arts and heritage, and sustainable agricultural practices and food systems; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department for Local Government; </section><section prefix="4">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Executive director" means the chief administrator of Shaping Our Appalachian Region, Inc. having responsibility for its day-to-day operations, and possessing all duties, responsibilities, and authorities as specified by the board; </section><section prefix="6">"Fund" means the Kentucky Appalachian regional development fund as provided by KRS 154.33-550. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 465, sec. 1, effective April 21, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective March 20, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 154B.100 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44441</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>