<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.119</section_number><catch_line>Inspection of legislative records by public -- Review of determination. </catch_line><order_by>119</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Records in the custody of the Legislative Research Commission or the General Assembly shall be available for distribution to the public, or open for inspection by any person. </section><section prefix="2">As used in subsection (1) of this section, "records" includes bills and amendments introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives, Senate and House Journals, Acts of the General Assembly, roll call votes, final reports of committees, Kentucky Administrative Regulations, documents showing salary and expenses paid to members of the General Assembly and all employees of the legislative branch, contracts, receipts and work orders for repairs or renovations to legislative offices or facilities, items cataloged in the legislative library, the Legislative Record, and informational and educational materials offered by the public information office, including legislative videotapes and photographs, calendars, and meeting notices. </section><section prefix="3">Requests for records or other documents in the custody of the Legislative Research Commission or the General Assembly shall be directed to the director of the Legislative Research Commission. Except for KRS 61.880(3), provisions of the Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884, shall apply to a request for inspection or copies of documents or other items not set forth in subsection (2) of this section, and except that a request for a review under KRS 61.880 of any determination by the director shall be made to the Legislative Research Commission, which shall issue its decision within thirty (30) days. If the Legislative Research Commission does not issue its decision on a review of the director's determination within thirty (30) days of submission to it of the matter, the director's determination may be appealed to the Franklin Circuit Court within sixty (60) days of its issuance. For purposes of this subsection, any reference to the Attorney General in KRS 61.880 and 61.882 shall be read as the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2003).  This section contains subsections (7) to (9) of 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1. Under the authority of KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has divided 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, into two KRS sections and has renumbered the subsections to conform with this division. The first six subsections of 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, have been codified as KRS 7.117. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>