<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.310</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensure of Marriage and Family Therapists. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Kentucky Board of Licensure of Marriage and Family Therapists. Effective January 1, 1999, it shall be composed of seven (7) members. Six (6) members shall be licensed marriage and family therapists. One (1) member shall be a citizen-at-large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business of marriage and family therapy. All members shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of names of qualified persons submitted by any interested parties. The Governor may request the submission of additional names. Each member of the board shall serve for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="2">All reappointments to the board and vacancies on the board shall be filled by the Governor as described in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Each member of the board shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day spent performing official duties as a board member and reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in carrying out official duties. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall annually elect a chair, a vice chair, and a secretary-treasurer. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall hold at least two (2) meetings annually and additional meetings as the board may deem necessary. The additional meetings may be held upon call of the chairperson or upon written request of two (2) board members. Four (4) board members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">Upon recommendation of the board, the Governor may remove any board member for a poor attendance record, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. </section><section prefix="7">No board member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive full terms. A person who has previously served two (2) consecutive terms may be reappointed to the board if that person has not served in the preceding four (4) years. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>