<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.355</section_number><catch_line>Examination and approval of projects -- Grants -- Administration -- Conditions. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Local Government shall examine each capital project selected by the area development districts, and when it finds that a proposed project conforms to the requirements of KRS 42.350 to 42.370; that the estimated costs of the project are reasonable; that the costs proposed to be paid from the fund are within the amount available; and that the proposed beneficiary agency will be reasonably able to finance the operation and maintain the capital project during its estimated useful life, the commissioner of the Department for Local Government shall approve it. If the Department for Local Government determines that a capital project proposal does not conform to the requirements of KRS 42.350 to 42.370, that the estimated costs of the project are excessive or unreasonable in light of the public benefit to be derived from the project, or the unencumbered balance in the fund available for expenditure in the area development district is insufficient to pay the costs of the project, or the part thereof proposed to be paid out of the fund, or the beneficiary agency cannot reasonably finance the operation of or maintain the capital project during its estimated useful life, the project proposal shall be disapproved by the Department for Local Government. The final decision to either approve or disapprove any project proposal shall be made no later than forty-five (45) days following official submittal of a complete proposal by the area development district, and the area development district shall be accordingly notified at that time. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of the Department for Local Government may make direct grants-in-aid of money out of the fund to any beneficiary agency for the construction or acquisition of any approved capital project. When a direct grant-in-aid has been made to a beneficiary agency, all contracts awarded for the purchase of materials, supplies, equipment, or services, except professional and technical services, required for the construction or acquisition of the project shall be awarded to the lowest and best bidder in the discretion of the beneficiary agency after public advertisement as required by KRS Chapter 424 or other applicable law. All contracts awarded under this section for the construction, reconstruction, or renovation of a building or other improvement to real estate shall be deemed contracts for public works within the meaning of KRS 341.317 and KRS Chapter 376 and other applicable statutes. All beneficiary agencies receiving a direct grant-in-aid under this subsection shall keep and maintain complete and accurate records of accounts of all expenditures of the grant moneys which shall be subject to audit by the Commonwealth for a period of five (5) years after completion of the capital project. Beneficiary agencies shall complete approved capital projects within a reasonable period of time as determined by the Department for Local Government. Upon completion of capital projects, beneficiary agencies shall submit project completion reports to the Department for Local Government as prescribed by the Department for Local Government and containing documents and information as may be necessary to determine compliance with KRS 42.350 to 42.360 and other applicable statutes and administrative regulations. Beneficiary agencies shall be liable to repay to the fund any granted funds for failure to submit full project completion reports within a reasonable period of time or for expenditure of granted funds in violation of statutes and regulations. No additional area development funds may be approved until compliance, except at the discretion of the commissioner of the Department for Local Government. Any grant moneys not required after all of the costs of the capital project have been paid by the beneficiary agency shall be promptly returned to the Commonwealth for reallocation for expenditure for other capital projects in the area development district to which the funds had been originally allocated. </section><section prefix="3">No capital project shall be constructed under KRS 42.350 to 42.370 except upon land to which (a) the Commonwealth, a political subdivision of the Commonwealth, or the beneficiary agency of the capital project has a good and marketable title, free of encumbrances, or (b) the beneficiary agency of the project has the right to the uninterrupted use, occupancy, and possession for a period longer than the estimated useful life of the capital project; provided nothing herein shall prohibit the construction or renovation of public buildings on land with an existing encumbrance to secure payment of funds obtained for the acquisition or improvement of said land. Each beneficiary agency shall execute and deliver to the Commonwealth its written assurances, which shall be binding on the agencies' successors and assigns, guaranteeing that during its estimated useful life, the capital project shall be operated and maintained for public purposes and pledging that no mortgage or other encumbrances shall be placed against any capital project wholly financed out of the fund, except industrial development projects, for the breach of which assurances the Commonwealth shall have right of entry to the capital project and the beneficiary agency, or its successors and assigns, shall forthwith convey the title to the capital project to the Commonwealth. Similar assurances shall be executed and delivered to the Commonwealth by the beneficiary agencies of capital projects financed in part out of the fund and in part from other sources, except that when additional funding is derived from the issuance and sale of revenue bonds or under other statutorily authorized financing methods, to secure the repayment of which funds a statutory mortgage lien is granted in favor of any person or group of persons, the capital project may be encumbered to the extent authorized or required by the law under which the financing method was undertaken; nor shall anything in this section prohibit the encumbrance of any real property located within an industrial park or constituting an industrial site, developed or improved as a capital project under KRS 42.350 and this section, by any person, firm, company, partnership, or corporation to which the property has been conveyed, to obtain financing for the construction upon the property of industrial and commercial buildings. The written assurances provided by beneficiary agencies under this section shall be lodged for recording and recorded in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the proposed project shall be located. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 16, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 43, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 187, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22023</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>