<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.882</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Department of Parks -- Management plan -- Administrative regulations -- Trail maintenance. </catch_line><order_by>882</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The trail shall be administered by the department according to the policies and criteria set forth in KRS 148.870 to 148.892. Within six (6) months of the designation of the trail boundary, the department shall consider the needs of local area citizens and develop a management plan for the trail and shall publicize and hold public hearings and record the views expressed on the management plan in the county in which the trail lies that is affected by the management plan. Within twelve (12) months of development of the management plan, the department shall promulgate administrative regulations that are necessary for the preservation and enhancement of the trail and to carry out the purposes of KRS 148.870 to 148.892, and for control of recreational, educational, scientific, and other uses of these areas in a manner that shall not impair them. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall be responsible for maintaining the trail, building bridges, campsites, shelters, and related public-use facilities where required, to the extent funds are available therefor. The department may enter into written agreements as it relates to any of these functions to one (1) or more nonprofit entities or other persons. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>