<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">E IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL HAZARDOUS MATERIALS PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39E.030</section_number><catch_line>Members -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall be composed of not more than twenty-five (25) members and shall be chaired by the director of the Division of Emergency Management of the Department of Military Affairs, who shall also be a member. Other members shall include, but not be limited to, the executive director of the Commission on Fire Protection Personnel Standards and Education or the executive director's designee, representatives of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the state fire marshal, the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Office of the Attorney General, affected industry, local government, health services, environmental interests, and other persons who have technical expertise in the emergency response field as the Governor deems appropriate. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the commission shall be appointed by the Governor. All appointments shall be for a term of two (2) years. Members shall serve until their successors are appointed and qualified and shall be eligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall meet not less than semi-annually, or as convened by the chairman. </section><section prefix="4">If a member misses three (3) consecutive meetings of the full commission or three (3) meetings in two (2) consecutive years, the position shall be declared vacant by the commission. In these cases, the Governor shall make an appointment to fill the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="5">The presence of thirteen (13) members shall constitute a quorum and actions taken at these meetings shall be considered as actions of the full commission. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the commission shall not receive a salary for serving on the commission, but travel and per diem may be paid if funds are appropriated or otherwise made available for these purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 31, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 121, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>