<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.865</section_number><catch_line>Designation of alternates by commission members -- Scope of authority -- Joint certificate concerning designation. </catch_line><order_by>865</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each member of the commission may designate, by an instrument in writing over the member's signature and filed with the commission as a public record, an alternate with full authority to: <section prefix="a">Attend, in the absence of the appointing member for any reason, any properly-convened meeting of the commission; and </section><section prefix="b">Participate in the consideration of, and voting upon, business and transactions of the commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any designation of an alternate may, at the appointing member's direction: <section prefix="a">Be limited upon the face of the appointing instrument to be effective only for a designated meeting or only for specified business; </section><section prefix="b">Be shown on the face of the appointing instrument to be on a continuing basis, but in no case for a period of more than four (4) years, whenever the appointing member is unable to attend; </section><section prefix="c">Be revoked by the appointing member in an instrument of like formality, similarly filed with the secretary as a public record of the commission. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any party transacting business with the commission or materially affected by the commission shall be entitled to accept and rely upon a joint certificate of the secretary of the commission and any member of the commission concerning the designation of any alternate, the time and scope of designation, and if of a continuing nature, whether the designation has been revoked, and when. The joint certificate shall be made and delivered to the party within a reasonable time after written request is made with acceptable identification of the business or transaction referred and of the requesting party's interest. </section><section prefix="4">Each alternate shall be a person on the staff of the appointing member or shall be in the employ of the appointing member's agency or department of the government of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 7, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22738</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>