<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.110</section_number><catch_line>License to carry concealed deadly weapon -- Criteria -- Training -- Paper or electronic application -- Issuance and denial of licenses -- Automated listing of license holders -- Suspension or revocation -- Renewal -- Prohibitions -- Reciprocity -- Reports -- Requirements for training classes.   </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police is authorized to issue and renew licenses to carry concealed firearms or other deadly weapons, or a combination thereof, to persons qualified as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">An original or renewal license issued pursuant to this section shall: <section prefix="a">Be valid throughout the Commonwealth and, except as provided in this section or other specific section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes or federal law, permit the holder of the license to carry firearms, ammunition, or other deadly weapons, or a combination thereof, at any location in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Unless revoked or suspended as provided by law, be valid for a period of five (5) years from the date of issuance; </section><section prefix="c">Authorize the holder of the license to carry a concealed firearm or other deadly weapon, or a combination thereof, on or about his or her person; and </section><section prefix="d">Authorize the holder of the license to carry ammunition for a firearm on or about his or her person. </section></section><section prefix="3">Prior to the issuance of an original or renewal license to carry a concealed deadly weapon, the Department of Kentucky State Police, upon receipt of a completed application, applicable fees, and any documentation required by this section or administrative regulation promulgated by the Department of Kentucky State Police, shall conduct a background check to ascertain whether the applicant is eligible under 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(g) and (n), any other applicable federal law, and state law to purchase, receive, or possess a firearm or ammunition, or both. The background check shall include: <section prefix="a">A state records check covering the items specified in this subsection, together with any other requirements of this section; </section><section prefix="b">A federal records check, which shall include a National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) check; </section><section prefix="c">A federal Immigration Alien Query if the person is an alien who has been lawfully admitted to the United States by the United States government or an agency thereof; and </section><section prefix="d">In addition to the Immigration Alien Query, if the applicant has not been lawfully admitted to the United States under permanent resident status, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall, if a doubt exists relating to an alien's eligibility to purchase a firearm, consult with the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Department of Justice, United States Department of State, or other federal agency to confirm whether the alien is eligible to purchase a firearm in the United States, bring a firearm into the United States, or possess a firearm in the United States under federal law. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall issue an original or renewal license if the applicant: <section prefix="a">Is not prohibited from the purchase, receipt, or possession of firearms, ammunition, or both pursuant to 18 U.S.C. 922(g), 18 U.S.C. 922(n), or applicable federal or state law; </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Is a citizen of the United States who is a resident of this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Is a citizen of the United States who is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States who is on active duty, who is at the time of application assigned to a military posting in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">Is lawfully admitted to the United States by the United States government or an agency thereof, is permitted by federal law to purchase a firearm, and is a resident of this Commonwealth; or </section><section prefix="4">Is lawfully admitted to the United States by the United States government or an agency thereof, is permitted by federal law to purchase a firearm, is, at the time of the application, assigned to a military posting in Kentucky, and has been assigned to a posting in the Commonwealth; </section></section><section prefix="c">Is twenty-one (21) years of age or older; </section><section prefix="d">Has not been committed to a state or federal facility for the abuse of a controlled substance or been convicted of a misdemeanor violation of KRS Chapter 218A or similar laws of any other state relating to controlled substances, within a three (3) year period immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted; </section><section prefix="e">Does not chronically and habitually use alcoholic beverages as evidenced by the applicant having two (2) or more convictions for violating KRS 189A.010 within the three (3) years immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted, or having been committed as an alcoholic pursuant to KRS Chapter 222 or similar laws of another state within the three (3) year period immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted; </section><section prefix="f">Does not owe a child support arrearage which equals or exceeds the cumulative amount which would be owed after one (1) year of nonpayment, if the Department of Kentucky State Police has been notified of the arrearage by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="g">Has complied with any subpoena or warrant relating to child support or paternity proceedings. If the Department of Kentucky State Police has not been notified by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services that the applicant has failed to meet this requirement, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall assume that paternity and child support proceedings are not an issue; </section><section prefix="h">Has not been convicted of a violation of KRS 508.030 or 508.080 within the three (3) years immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted. The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police may waive this requirement upon good cause shown and a determination that the applicant is not a danger and that a waiver would not violate federal law; </section><section prefix="i">Demonstrates competence with a firearm by successful completion of a firearms safety or training course that is conducted by a firearms instructor who is certified by a national organization that certifies firearms instructors and includes the use of written tests, in person instruction, and a component of live-fire training or a firearms safety course offered or approved by the Department of Criminal Justice Training. The firearms safety course offered or approved by the Department of Criminal Justice Training shall: <section prefix="1">Be not more than eight (8) hours in length; </section><section prefix="2">Include instruction on handguns, the safe use of handguns, the care and cleaning of handguns, and handgun marksmanship principles; </section><section prefix="3">Include actual range firing of a handgun in a safe manner, and the firing of not more than twenty (20) rounds at a full-size silhouette target, during which firing, not less than eleven (11) rounds must hit the silhouette portion of the target; and </section><section prefix="4">Include information on and a copy of laws relating to possession and carrying of firearms, as set forth in KRS Chapters 237 and 527, and the laws relating to the use of force, as set forth in KRS Chapter 503; and </section></section><section prefix="j">Demonstrates knowledge of the law regarding the justifiable use of force by including with the application a copy of the concealed carry deadly weapons legal handout made available by the Department of Criminal Justice Training and a signed statement that indicates that applicant has read and understands the handout. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A legible photocopy or electronic copy of a certificate of completion issued by a firearms instructor certified by a national organization or the Department of Criminal Justice Training shall constitute evidence of qualification under subsection (4)(i) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Persons qualifying under subsection (6)(d) of this section may submit with their application: <section prefix="1">At least one (1) of the following paper or electronic forms or their successor forms showing evidence of handgun training or handgun qualifications: <section prefix="a">Department of Defense Form DD 2586; </section><section prefix="b">Department of Defense Form DD 214; </section><section prefix="c">Coast Guard Form CG 3029; </section><section prefix="d">Department of the Army Form DA 88-R; </section><section prefix="e">Department of the Army Form DA 5704-R; </section><section prefix="f">Department of the Navy Form OPNAV 3591-1; or </section><section prefix="g">Department of the Air Force Form AF 522; or </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Documentary evidence of an honorable discharge; and </section><section prefix="b">A notarized affidavit on a form provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police, signed under penalty of perjury, stating the person has met the training requirements of subsection (6)(d) of this section. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Peace officers who are currently certified as peace officers by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404 and peace officers who are retired and are members of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System, State Police Retirement System, or County Employees Retirement System or other retirement system operated by or for a city, county, or urban-county in Kentucky shall be deemed to have met the training requirement. </section><section prefix="b">Current and retired peace officers of the following federal agencies shall be deemed to have met the training requirement: <section prefix="1">Any peace officer employed by a federal agency specified in KRS 61.365; </section><section prefix="2">Any peace officer employed by a federal civilian law enforcement agency not specified above who has successfully completed the basic law enforcement training course required by that agency; </section><section prefix="3">Any military peace officer of the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, or Air Force, or a reserve component thereof, or of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard who has successfully completed the military law enforcement training course required by that branch of the military; </section><section prefix="4">Any member of the United States Coast Guard serving in a peace officer role who has successfully completed the law enforcement training course specified by the United States Coast Guard. </section></section><section prefix="c">Corrections officers who are currently employed by a consolidated local government, an urban-county government, or the Department of Corrections who have successfully completed a basic firearms training course required for their employment, and corrections officers who were formerly employed by a consolidated local government, an urban-county government, or the Department of Corrections who are retired, and who successfully completed a basic firearms training course required for their employment, and are members of a state-administered retirement system or other retirement system operated by or for a city, county, or urban-county government in Kentucky shall be deemed to have met the training requirement. </section><section prefix="d">Active or honorably discharged service members in the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard, or a reserve component thereof, or of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard shall be deemed to have met the training requirement if these persons: <section prefix="1">Successfully completed handgun training which was conducted by the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard, or a reserve component thereof, or of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard; or </section><section prefix="2">Successfully completed handgun qualification within the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, or Coast Guard, or a reserve component thereof, or of the Army Guard or Air Force National Guard. </section></section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">A paper application for a license, or renewal of a license, to carry a concealed deadly weapon shall be obtained from and submitted to the office of the sheriff in the county in which the person resides. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant, in lieu of a paper application, may submit an electronic application for a license, or renewal of a license, to carry a concealed deadly weapon to the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="3">Persons qualifying under subsection (6)(d) of this section shall be supplied the information in subsection (4)(i)4. of this section upon obtaining an application. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The completed paper application and any documentation required by this section plus an application fee or renewal fee, as appropriate, of sixty dollars ($60) shall be presented to the office of the sheriff of the county in which the applicant resides. </section><section prefix="2">The sheriff shall transmit the paper application and accompanying material to the Department of Kentucky State Police within five (5) working days. </section><section prefix="3">Twenty dollars ($20) of the paper application fee shall be retained by the office of the sheriff for official expenses of the office. Twenty dollars ($20) shall be sent to the Department of Kentucky State Police with the application. Ten dollars ($10) shall be transmitted by the sheriff to the Administrative Office of the Courts to fund background checks for youth leaders, and ten dollars ($10) shall be transmitted to the Administrative Office of the Courts to fund background checks for applicants for concealed weapons. </section></section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">A completed electronic application submitted in lieu of a paper application, any documentation required by this section, and an application fee or renewal fee, as appropriate, of seventy dollars ($70) shall be presented to the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="2">If an electronic application is submitted in lieu of a paper application, thirty dollars ($30) of the electronic application fee shall be retained by the Department of Kentucky State Police. Twenty dollars ($20) shall be sent to the office of the sheriff of the applicant's county of residence for official expenses of the office. Ten dollars ($10) shall be transmitted to the Administrative Office of the Courts to fund background checks for youth leaders, and ten dollars ($10) shall be transmitted to the Administrative Office of the Courts to fund background checks for applicants for concealed weapon carry permits. </section></section><section prefix="d">A full-time or part-time peace officer who is currently certified as a peace officer by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council and who is authorized by his or her employer or government authority to carry a concealed deadly weapon at all times and all locations within the Commonwealth pursuant to KRS 527.020, or a retired peace officer who is a member of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System, State Police Retirement System, County Employees Retirement System, or other retirement system operated by or for a city, county, or urban-county government in Kentucky, shall be exempt from paying the paper or electronic application or renewal fees. </section><section prefix="e">The application, whether paper or electronic, shall be completed, under oath, on a form or in a manner promulgated by the Department of Kentucky State Police by administrative regulation which shall include: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The name, address, place and date of birth, citizenship, gender, Social Security number of the applicant; and </section><section prefix="b">If not a citizen of the United States, alien registration number if applicable, passport number, visa number, mother's maiden name, and other information necessary to determine the immigration status and eligibility to purchase a firearm under federal law of a person who is not a citizen of the United States; </section></section><section prefix="2">A statement that, to the best of his or her knowledge, the applicant is in compliance with criteria contained within subsections (3) and (4) of this section; </section><section prefix="3">A statement that the applicant, if qualifying under subsection (6)(c) of this section, has provided: <section prefix="a">At least one (1) of the forms listed in subsection (5) of this section; or </section><section prefix="b">i. Documentary evidence of an honorable discharge; and ii. A notarized affidavit on a form provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police stating the person has met the training requirements of subsection (6)(c) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="4">A statement that the applicant has been furnished a copy of this section and is knowledgeable about its provisions; </section><section prefix="5">A statement that the applicant has been furnished a copy of, has read, and understands KRS Chapter 503 as it pertains to the use of deadly force for self-defense in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="6">A conspicuous warning that the application is executed under oath and that a materially false answer to any question, or the submission of any materially false document by the applicant, subjects the applicant to criminal prosecution under KRS 523.030. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">The applicant shall submit to the sheriff of the applicant's county of residence or county of military posting if submitting a paper application, or to the Department of Kentucky State Police if submitting an electronic application: <section prefix="a">A completed application as described in subsection (7) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">A recent color photograph of the applicant, as prescribed by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">A paper or electronic certificate or an affidavit or document as described in subsection (5) of this section; </section><section prefix="d">A paper or electronic document establishing the training exemption as described in subsection (6) of this section; and </section><section prefix="e">For an applicant who is not a citizen of the United States and has been lawfully admitted to the United States by the United States government or an agency thereof, an affidavit as prescribed by administrative regulation concerning his or her immigration status and his or her United States government issued: <section prefix="1">Permanent Resident Card I-551 or its equivalent successor identification; </section><section prefix="2">Other United States government issued evidence of lawful admission to the United States which includes the category of admission, if admission has not been granted as a permanent resident; and </section><section prefix="3">Evidence of compliance with the provisions of 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(g)(5), 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(d)(5), or 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(y)(2), and 27 C.F.R. Part 178, including, as appropriate, but not limited to evidence of ninety (90) day residence in the Commonwealth, a valid current Kentucky hunting license if claiming exemption as a hunter, or other evidence of eligibility to purchase a firearm by an alien which is required by federal law or regulation. </section></section> If an applicant presents identification specified in this paragraph, the sheriff shall examine the identification, may record information from the identification presented, and shall return the identification to the applicant. </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall, within sixty (60) days after the date of receipt of the items listed in subsection (8) of this section if the applicant submitted a paper application, or within fifteen (15) business days after the date of receipt of the items listed in subsection (8) of this section if the applicant applied electronically, either: <section prefix="a">Issue the license; or </section><section prefix="b">Deny the application based solely on the grounds that the applicant fails to qualify under the criteria listed in subsection (3) or (4) of this section. If the Department of Kentucky State Police denies the application, it shall notify the applicant in writing, stating the grounds for denial and informing the applicant of a right to submit, within thirty (30) days, any additional documentation relating to the grounds of denial. Upon receiving any additional documentation, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall reconsider its decision and inform the applicant within twenty (20) days of the result of the reconsideration. The applicant shall further be informed of the right to seek de novo review of the denial in the District Court of his or her place of residence within ninety (90) days from the date of the letter advising the applicant of the denial. </section></section><section prefix="10">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall maintain an automated listing of license holders and pertinent information, and this information shall be available upon request, at all times to all Kentucky, federal, and other states' law enforcement agencies. A request for the entire list of licensees, or for all licensees in a geographic area, shall be denied. Only requests relating to a named licensee shall be honored or available to law enforcement agencies. Information on applications for licenses, names and addresses, or other identifying information relating to license holders shall be confidential and shall not be made available except to law enforcement agencies. No request for lists of local or statewide permit holders shall be made to any state or local law enforcement agency, peace officer, or other agency of government other than the Department of Kentucky State Police, and no state or local law enforcement agency, peace officer, or agency of government, other than the Department of Kentucky State Police, shall provide any information to any requester not entitled to it by law. </section><section prefix="11">Within thirty (30) days after the changing of a permanent address, or within thirty (30) days after the loss, theft, or destruction of a license, the licensee shall notify the Department of Kentucky State Police of the loss, theft, or destruction. Failure to notify the Department of Kentucky State Police shall constitute a noncriminal violation with a penalty of twenty-five dollars ($25) payable to the clerk of the District Court. No court costs shall be assessed for a violation of this subsection. When a licensee makes application to change his or her residence address or other information on the license, neither the sheriff nor the Department of Kentucky State Police shall require a surrender of the license until a new license is in the office of the applicable sheriff and available for issuance. Upon the issuance of a new license, the old license shall be destroyed by the sheriff. </section><section prefix="12">If a license is lost, stolen, or destroyed, the license shall be automatically invalid, and the person to whom the same was issued may, upon payment of fifteen dollars ($15) for a paper request, or twenty-five dollars ($25) for an electronic request submitted in lieu of a paper request, to the Department of Kentucky State Police, obtain a duplicate, upon furnishing a notarized statement to the Department of Kentucky State Police that the license has been lost, stolen, or destroyed. </section><section prefix="13"><section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, or his or her designee in writing, shall revoke the license of any person who becomes permanently ineligible to be issued a license or have a license renewed under the criteria set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, or his or her designee in writing, shall suspend the license of any person who becomes temporarily ineligible to be issued a license or have a license renewed under the criteria set forth in this section. The license shall remain suspended until the person is again eligible for the issuance or renewal of a license. </section><section prefix="c">Upon the suspension or revocation of a license, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, or his or her designee in writing, shall: <section prefix="1">Order any peace officer to seize the license from the person whose license was suspended or revoked; or </section><section prefix="2">Direct the person whose license was suspended or revoked to surrender the license to the sheriff of the person's county of residence within two (2) business days of the receipt of the notice. </section></section><section prefix="d">If the person whose license was suspended or revoked desires a hearing on the matter, the person shall surrender the license as provided in paragraph (c)2. of this subsection and petition the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police to hold a hearing on the issue of suspension or revocation of the license. </section><section prefix="e">Upon receipt of the petition, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police shall cause a hearing to be held in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B on the suspension or revocation of the license. If the license has not been surrendered, no hearing shall be scheduled or held. </section><section prefix="f">If the hearing officer determines that the licensee's license was wrongly suspended or revoked, the hearing officer shall order the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police to return the license and abrogate the suspension or revocation of the license. </section><section prefix="g">Any party may appeal a decision pursuant to this subsection to the District Court in the licensee's county of residence in the same manner as for the denial of a license. </section><section prefix="h">If the license is not surrendered as ordered, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police shall order a peace officer to seize the license and deliver it to the commissioner. </section><section prefix="i">Failure to surrender a suspended or revoked license as ordered is a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="j">The provisions of this subsection relating to surrender of a license shall not apply if a court of competent jurisdiction has enjoined its surrender. </section><section prefix="k">When a domestic violence order or emergency protective order is issued pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 403 against a person holding a license issued under this section, the holder of the permit shall surrender the license to the court or to the officer serving the order. The officer to whom the license is surrendered shall forthwith transmit the license to the court issuing the order. The license shall be suspended until the order is terminated, or until the judge who issued the order terminates the suspension prior to the termination of the underlying domestic violence order or emergency protective order, in writing and by return of the license, upon proper motion by the license holder. Subject to the same conditions as above, a peace officer against whom an emergency protective order or domestic violence order has been issued shall not be permitted to carry a concealed deadly weapon when not on duty, the provisions of KRS 527.020 to the contrary notwithstanding. </section></section><section prefix="14"><section prefix="a">Not less than one hundred twenty (120) days prior to the expiration date of the license, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall mail to each licensee a written notice of the expiration and a renewal form prescribed by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The outside of the envelope containing the license renewal notice shall bear only the name and address of the applicant. No other information relating to the applicant shall appear on the outside of the envelope sent to the applicant. The licensee may renew his or her license on or before the expiration date by filing with the sheriff of his or her county of residence the paper renewal form, or by filing with the Department of Kentucky State Police an electronic renewal form in lieu of a paper renewal form, stating that the licensee remains qualified pursuant to the criteria specified in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, and the required renewal fee set forth in subsection (7) of this section. The sheriff shall issue to the applicant a receipt for the paper application for renewal of the license and shall date the receipt. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall issue to the applicant a receipt for an electronic application for renewal of the license submitted in lieu of a paper application for renewal and shall date the receipt. </section><section prefix="b">A license which has expired shall be void and shall not be valid for any purpose other than surrender to the sheriff in exchange for a renewal license. </section><section prefix="c">The license shall be renewed to a qualified applicant upon receipt of the completed renewal application, records check as specified in subsection (3) of this section, determination that the renewal applicant is not ineligible for a license as specified in subsection (4), and appropriate payment of fees. Upon the issuance of a new license, the old license shall be destroyed by the sheriff. A licensee who fails to file a renewal application on or before its expiration date may renew his or her license by paying, in addition to the license fees, a late fee of fifteen dollars ($15). No license shall be renewed six (6) months or more after its expiration date, and the license shall be deemed to be permanently expired six (6) months after its expiration date. A person whose license has permanently expired may reapply for licensure pursuant to subsections (7), (8), and (9) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="15">The licensee shall carry the license at all times the licensee is carrying a concealed firearm or other deadly weapon and shall display the license upon request of a law enforcement officer. Violation of the provisions of this subsection shall constitute a noncriminal violation with a penalty of twenty-five dollars ($25), payable to the clerk of the District Court, but no court costs shall be assessed. </section><section prefix="16">Except as provided in KRS 527.020, no license issued pursuant to this section shall authorize any person to carry a concealed firearm into: <section prefix="a">Any police station or sheriff's office; </section><section prefix="b">Any detention facility, prison, or jail; </section><section prefix="c">Any courthouse, solely occupied by the Court of Justice courtroom, or court proceeding; </section><section prefix="d">Any meeting of the governing body of a county, municipality, or special district; or any meeting of the General Assembly or a committee of the General Assembly, except that nothing in this section shall preclude a member of the body, holding a concealed deadly weapon license, from carrying a concealed deadly weapon at a meeting of the body of which he or she is a member; </section><section prefix="e">Any portion of an establishment licensed to dispense beer or alcoholic beverages for consumption on the premises, which portion of the establishment is primarily devoted to that purpose; </section><section prefix="f">Any elementary or secondary school facility without the consent of school authorities as provided in KRS 527.070, any child-caring facility as defined in KRS 199.011, any day-care center as defined in KRS 199.894, or any certified family child-care home as defined in KRS 199.8982, except however, any owner of a certified child-care home may carry a concealed firearm into the owner's residence used as a certified child-care home; </section><section prefix="g">An area of an airport to which access is controlled by the inspection of persons and property; or </section><section prefix="h">Any place where the carrying of firearms is prohibited by federal law. </section></section><section prefix="17">The owner, business or commercial lessee, or manager of a private business enterprise, day-care center as defined in KRS 199.894 or certified or licensed family child-care home as defined in KRS 199.8982, or a health-care facility licensed under KRS Chapter 216B, except facilities renting or leasing housing, may prohibit persons holding concealed deadly weapon licenses from carrying concealed deadly weapons on the premises and may prohibit employees, not authorized by the employer, holding concealed deadly weapons licenses from carrying concealed deadly weapons on the property of the employer. If the building or the premises are open to the public, the employer or business enterprise shall post signs on or about the premises if carrying concealed weapons is prohibited. Possession of weapons, or ammunition, or both in a vehicle on the premises shall not be a criminal offense so long as the weapons, or ammunition, or both are not removed from the vehicle or brandished while the vehicle is on the premises. A private but not a public employer may prohibit employees or other persons holding a concealed deadly weapons license from carrying concealed deadly weapons, or ammunition, or both in vehicles owned by the employer, but may not prohibit employees or other persons holding a concealed deadly weapons license from carrying concealed deadly weapons, or ammunition, or both in vehicles owned by the employee, except that the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet may prohibit an employee from carrying any weapons, or ammunition, or both other than the weapons, or ammunition, or both issued or authorized to be used by the employee of the cabinet, in a vehicle while transporting persons under the employee's supervision or jurisdiction. Carrying of a concealed weapon, or ammunition, or both in a location specified in this subsection by a license holder shall not be a criminal act but may subject the person to denial from the premises or removal from the premises, and, if an employee of an employer, disciplinary measures by the employer. </section><section prefix="18">All moneys collected by the Department of Kentucky State Police pursuant to this section shall be used to administer the provisions of this section and KRS 237.138 to 237.142. By March 1 of each year, the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Administrative Office of the Courts shall submit reports to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, indicating the amounts of money collected and the expenditures related to this section, KRS 237.138 to 237.142, and KRS 237.115, 244.125, 527.020, and 527.070, and the administration of the provisions of this section, KRS 237.138 to 237.142, and KRS 237.115, 244.125, 527.020, and 527.070. </section><section prefix="19">The General Assembly finds as a matter of public policy that it is necessary to provide statewide uniform standards for issuing licenses to carry concealed firearms and to occupy the field of regulation of the bearing of concealed firearms to ensure that no person who qualifies under the provisions of this section is denied his rights. The General Assembly does not delegate to the Department of Kentucky State Police the authority to regulate or restrict the issuing of licenses provided for in this section beyond those provisions contained in this section. This section shall be liberally construed to carry out the constitutional right to bear arms for self-defense. </section><section prefix="20"><section prefix="a">A person who is not a resident of Kentucky and who has a valid license issued by another state of the United States to carry a concealed deadly weapon in that state may, subject to provisions of Kentucky law, carry a concealed deadly weapon in Kentucky, and his or her license shall be considered as valid in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="b">If a person with a valid license to carry a concealed deadly weapon issued from another state that has entered into a reciprocity agreement with the Department of Kentucky State Police becomes a resident of Kentucky, the license issued by the other state shall be considered as valid for the first one hundred twenty (120) days of the person's residence in Kentucky, if within sixty (60) days of moving to Kentucky, the person completes a form promulgated by the Department of Kentucky State Police which shall include: <section prefix="1">A signed and notarized statement averring that to the best of his or her knowledge the person's license to carry a concealed deadly weapon is valid and in compliance with applicable out-of-state law, and has not been revoked or suspended for any reason except for valid forfeiture due to departure from the issuing state; </section><section prefix="2">The person's name, date of birth, citizenship, gender, Social Security number if applicable, proof that he or she is a citizen of the United States, a permanent resident of the United States, or otherwise lawfully present in the United States, former out-of-state address, current address within the state of Kentucky, date on which Kentucky residence began, state which issued the concealed carry license, the issuing state's concealed carry license number, and the state of issuance of license; and </section><section prefix="3">A photocopy of the person's out-of-state license to carry a concealed deadly weapon. </section></section><section prefix="c">Within sixty (60) days of moving to Kentucky, the person shall deliver the form and accompanying documents by registered or certified mail, return receipt requested, to the address indicated on the form provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police pursuant to this subsection. </section><section prefix="d">The out-of-state concealed carry license shall become invalid in Kentucky upon the earlier of: <section prefix="1">The out-of-state person having resided in Kentucky for more than one hundred twenty (120) days; or </section><section prefix="2">The person being issued a Kentucky concealed deadly weapon license pursuant to this section. </section></section><section prefix="e">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall, not later than thirty (30) days after July 15, 1998, and not less than once every twelve (12) months thereafter, make written inquiry of the concealed deadly weapon carrying licensing authorities in each other state as to whether a Kentucky resident may carry a concealed deadly weapon in their state based upon having a valid Kentucky concealed deadly weapon license, or whether a Kentucky resident may apply for a concealed deadly weapon carrying license in that state based upon having a valid Kentucky concealed deadly weapon license. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall attempt to secure from each other state permission for Kentucky residents who hold a valid Kentucky concealed deadly weapon license to carry concealed deadly weapons in that state, either on the basis of the Kentucky license or on the basis that the Kentucky license is sufficient to permit the issuance of a similar license by the other state. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall enter into a written reciprocity agreement with the appropriate agency in each state that agrees to permit Kentucky residents to carry concealed deadly weapons in the other state on the basis of a Kentucky-issued concealed deadly weapon license or that will issue a license to carry concealed deadly weapons in the other state based upon a Kentucky concealed deadly weapon license. If a reciprocity agreement is reached, the requirement to recontact the other state each twelve (12) months shall be eliminated as long as the reciprocity agreement is in force. The information shall be a public record and shall be available to individual requesters free of charge for the first copy and at the normal rate for open records requests for additional copies. </section></section><section prefix="21">By March 1 of each year, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall submit a statistical report to the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, indicating the number of licenses issued, revoked, suspended, and denied since the previous report and in total and also the number of licenses currently valid. The report shall also include the number of arrests, convictions, and types of crimes committed since the previous report by individuals licensed to carry concealed weapons. </section><section prefix="22">The following provisions shall apply to concealed deadly weapon training classes conducted by the Department of Criminal Justice Training or any other agency pursuant to this section: <section prefix="a">No concealed deadly weapon instructor trainer shall have his or her certification as a concealed deadly weapon instructor trainer reduced to that of instructor or revoked except after a hearing conducted pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B in which the instructor is found to have committed an act in violation of the applicable statutes or administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="b">No concealed deadly weapon instructor shall have his or her certification as a concealed deadly weapon instructor license suspended or revoked except after a hearing conducted pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B in which the instructor is found to have committed an act in violation of the applicable statutes or administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="c">The department shall not require prior notification that an applicant class or instructor class will be conducted by a certified instructor or instructor trainer; </section><section prefix="d">Each concealed deadly weapon instructor or instructor trainer who teaches a concealed deadly weapon applicant or concealed deadly weapon instructor class shall supply the Department of Criminal Justice Training with a class roster indicating which students enrolled and successfully completed the class, and which contains the name and address of each student, within five (5) working days of the completion of the class. The information may be sent by mail, facsimile, e-mail, or other method which will result in the receipt of or production of a hard copy of the information. The postmark, facsimile date, or e-mail date shall be considered as the date on which the notice was sent. Concealed deadly weapon class applicant, instructor, and instructor trainer information and records shall be confidential. The department may release to any person or organization the name, address, and telephone number of a concealed deadly weapon instructor or instructor trainer if that instructor or instructor trainer authorizes the release of the information in writing. The department shall include on any application for an instructor or instructor trainer certification a statement that the applicant either does or does not desire the applicant's name, address, and telephone number to be made public; </section><section prefix="e">An instructor trainer who assists in the conduct of a concealed deadly weapon instructor class or concealed deadly weapon applicant class for more than two (2) hours shall be considered as to have taught a class for the purpose of maintaining his or her certification. All class record forms shall include spaces for assistant instructors to sign and certify that they have assisted in the conduct of a concealed deadly weapon instructor or concealed deadly weapon class; </section><section prefix="f">An instructor who assists in the conduct of a concealed deadly weapon applicant class for more than two (2) hours shall be considered as to have taught a class for the purpose of maintaining his or her license. All class record forms shall include spaces for assistant instructors to sign and certify that they have assisted in the conduct of a concealed deadly weapon class; </section><section prefix="g">If the Department of Criminal Justice Training believes that a firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor has not in fact complied with the requirements for teaching a certified firearms instructor or applicant class by not teaching the class as specified in KRS 237.126, or who has taught an insufficient class as specified in KRS 237.128, the department shall send to each person who has been listed as successfully completing the concealed deadly weapon applicant class or concealed deadly weapon instructor class a verification form on which the time, date, date of range firing if different from the date on which the class was conducted, location, and instructor of the class is listed by the department and which requires the person to answer "yes" or "no" to specific questions regarding the conduct of the training class. The form shall be completed under oath and shall be returned to the Department of Criminal Justice Training not later than forty-five (45) days after its receipt. A person who fails to complete the form, to sign the form, or to return the form to the Department of Criminal Justice Training within the time frame specified in this section or who, as a result of information on the returned form, is determined by the Department of Criminal Justice Training, following a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, to not have received the training required by law shall have his or her concealed deadly weapon license revoked by the Department of Kentucky State Police, following a hearing conducted by the Department of Criminal Justice Training pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, at which hearing the person is found to have violated the provisions of this section or who has been found not to have received the training required by law; </section><section prefix="h">The department shall annually, not later than December 31 of each year, report to the Legislative Research Commission: <section prefix="1">The number of firearms instructor trainers and certified firearms instructors whose certifications were suspended, revoked, denied, or who were otherwise disciplined; </section><section prefix="2">The reasons for the imposition of suspensions, revocations, denials, or other discipline; and </section><section prefix="3">Suggestions for improvement of the concealed deadly weapon applicant training program and instructor process; </section></section><section prefix="i">If a concealed deadly weapon license holder is convicted of, pleads guilty to, or enters an Alford plea to a felony offense, then his or her concealed deadly weapon license shall be forthwith revoked by the Department of Kentucky State Police as a matter of law; </section><section prefix="j">If a concealed deadly weapon instructor or instructor trainer is convicted of, pleads guilty to, or enters an Alford plea to a felony offense, then his or her concealed deadly weapon instructor certification or concealed deadly weapon instructor trainer certification shall be revoked by the Department of Criminal Justice Training as a matter of law; and </section><section prefix="k">The following shall be in effect: <section prefix="1">Action to eliminate the firearms instructor trainer program is prohibited. The program shall remain in effect, and no firearms instructor trainer shall have his or her certification reduced to that of certified firearms instructor; </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall revoke the concealed deadly weapon license of any person who received no firearms training as required by KRS 237.126 and administrative regulations, or who received insufficient training as required by KRS 237.128 and administrative regulations, if the person voluntarily admits nonreceipt of training or admits receipt of insufficient training, or if either nonreceipt of training or receipt of insufficient training is proven following a hearing conducted by the Department of Criminal Justice Training pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 126, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 73, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 266, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 565, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 182, sec. 15, effective March 31, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 494, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 606, sec. 136, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 60 and 126, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/15/2014). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has changed a reference in subsection (5)(b)2.b. of this statute from "training requirements of subsection (6)(c) of this section" as it appeared in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 5, to read "training requirements of subsection (6)(d) of this section." It is clear from the context that the training requirements referred to are the handgun training requirements of the Armed Forces referenced in subsection (6)(d) of this statute. The Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error under the authority of KRS 7.136(h). (7/15/2008).  2008 House Bill 639, sec. 2, which became 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, amended KRS 237.110. The Senate Committee Substitute for HB 639 changed all references except one, which was inadvertently omitted, in this section from "handgun" to "firearm." To achieve consistency, the Reviser of Statutes has changed the reference in KRS 237.110(4)(b)4. from "handgun" to "firearm" under the authority of KRS 7.136. (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 2, subsection (13), contains a reference in paragraph (d) to surrender of a license "as provided in paragraph (c)1. of this subsection. "Because only paragraph (c)2. of subsection (13) contains the provision setting forth surrender of a license, the reference has been changed in codification to "paragraph (c)2. of this subsection" under KRS 7.136(1)(h). (3/21/2005).  1996 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 6 provides, "With respect to the training requirements of [KRS 237.110], [KRS 237.110] shall be deemed to be retroactive, and training completed prior to [October 1, 1996] may be used and shall be deemed to satisfy the training requirements of [KRS 237.110]." </lrc-note><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 4, (3) at 649.</budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>