<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="167" order_by="167">EDUCATION OF THE PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED </unit></structure><section_number>167.037</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky School for the Deaf Advisory Board. </catch_line><order_by>037</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be established a Kentucky School for the Deaf Advisory Board, composed of nine (9) members appointed by the Kentucky Board of Education upon recommendation of the chief state school officer. At the first regular meeting in each fiscal year, the board shall elect a chairman and vice chairman. A member may serve no more than two (2) consecutive years as chairman. Members shall be appointed for regular terms of four (4) years. Members of the board shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="2">Advisory board members for the Kentucky School for the Deaf shall be selected from nominations submitted by the Kentucky Association of the Deaf Inc., the Parent-Teacher-Cottage Parent Association, the Kentucky School for the Deaf Alumni Association Inc., the Kentucky Association of School Administrators, and the chief state school officer. Membership on the board shall be statewide and shall consist of two (2) parents of deaf children, one (1) professional in education of the deaf, one (1) former student of the Kentucky School for the Deaf, one (1) member of the Kentucky Association for the Deaf, two (2) members who shall represent school districts, and two (2) members at large. A majority of the board's membership shall be persons who are deaf or hard of hearing. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall act in an advisory capacity to assist the school superintendent in conducting the activities of the school. The board shall also make recommendations to the chief state school officer concerning all areas relating to the effective operation of the school, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Goals and objectives, </section><section prefix="b">Budget requests, </section><section prefix="c">Student services, </section><section prefix="d">Public relations, </section><section prefix="e">Construction and maintenance, and </section><section prefix="f">Program evaluation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 276, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4702</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>