<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.711</section_number><catch_line>Deputy county judge/executive and office personnel -- Appointment -- Compensation -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>711</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 67.710(7), the county judge/executive of any county may appoint a deputy county judge/executive, and a reasonable number of other assistants, secretaries, and clerical workers within the office of the county judge/executive as determined by the fiscal court, who shall serve at his pleasure. The fiscal court, pursuant to KRS 64.530(4), shall fix reasonable compensation for the deputy county judge/executive and such other employees. </section><section prefix="2">The deputy county judge/executive may exercise all administrative powers, duties, and responsibilities of that office, and may assume such other responsibilities as shall be prescribed in the administrative code of the county, except that the deputy county judge/executive shall not act for the county judge/executive as a member or presiding officer of the fiscal court. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 1, effective March 5, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 15, effective June 17, 1978.</history><metadata><effective> March 5, 1986</effective><lrc-note>.  See Legislative Research Commission Note following KRS 67.705. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>