<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.070</section_number><catch_line>Duties of commissioner of Department of Corrections -- Training programs. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections shall: <section prefix="a">Supervise and administer the Kentucky State Reformatory, the Kentucky Correctional Institution for Women, the Kentucky State Penitentiary, Northpoint Training Center, the Luther Luckett Correctional Complex, the Eastern Kentucky Correctional Complex, the Green River Correctional Complex, the Western Kentucky Correctional Complex, the Roederer Correctional Complex, and any minimum security correctional institutions established and operated by the department, or any divisions of those institutions, the private prisons as provided by KRS 197.500, and the prison industry program within those institutions. </section><section prefix="b">Supervise the employment of prisoners who have not been paroled or conditionally released, either within or without the walls or enclosures of these institutions. </section><section prefix="c">Have the authority to transfer, with the approval of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, appropriated funds from the budget of one (1) penal institution to another. </section><section prefix="d">Determine minimum, maximum, and conditional release dates of prisoners in accordance with KRS 197.045. </section><section prefix="e">Authorize the transfer of prisoners between institutions. </section><section prefix="f">Create those positions and employ those personnel necessary to perform the functions of the department. </section><section prefix="g">Promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement KRS 196.700 to 196.735. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may organize and maintain a training division for employees of the department and others and in connection therewith promulgate administrative regulations covering the course and conduct of the training and the period of time for which any employee or applicant therefor shall attend the school. <section prefix="a">The Division of Corrections Training shall establish, supervise, and coordinate training programs and schools for corrections personnel, jail personnel, and any other justice or nonlaw-enforcement related personnel as prescribed by the secretary and shall issue certification to those employees having successfully met the requirements of the training program. </section><section prefix="b">The Division of Corrections Training shall make a continuing study of corrections training standards and design, develop, and deliver preservice and in-service training programs. </section><section prefix="c">The Division of Corrections Training shall, by administrative regulations, prescribe minimum qualifications for its instructors and shall approve, issue, or revoke the certification of instructors. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 5, effective April 10, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 418, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 21, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 445, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 497, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 344, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, secs. 41 and 119, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, secs. 24(15), (19); and ch. 308, sec. 37. -- Amended 1963 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 9, effective October 1, 1963. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. X, sec. 5. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618-106. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6788</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>