<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1430</section_number><catch_line>Trafficking in synthetic drugs -- Penalties -- Affirmative defense -- Possession of synthetic drugs -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>1430</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A person is guilty of trafficking in synthetic drugs when he or she knowingly and unlawfully traffics in synthetic drugs. </section><section prefix="b">Trafficking in synthetic drugs is a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="c">In lieu of the fine amounts otherwise allowed under KRS Chapter 534, for any offense under this subsection the court may impose a maximum fine of double the defendant's gain from the commission of the offense, in which case any fine money collected shall be divided between the same parties, in the same ratio, and for the same purposes as established for forfeited property under KRS 218A.420. </section><section prefix="d">It shall be an affirmative defense to an offense under this subsection that the defendant committed the offense during the course of the defendant's employment as an employee of a retail store and that the defendant did not know and should not have known that the trafficked substance was a synthetic drug. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A person is guilty of possession of synthetic drugs when he or she knowingly and unlawfully possesses synthetic drugs. </section><section prefix="b">Possession of synthetic drugs is a Class B misdemeanor, except that, KRS Chapter 532 to the contrary notwithstanding, the maximum term of incarceration shall be no greater than thirty (30) days. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 1, effective April 11, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>