<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.134</section_number><catch_line>Installation permits -- Requisites -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, firm, or corporation shall: <section prefix="a">Construct, install, or alter, or cause to be constructed, installed, or altered, any plumbing without first having procured a plumbing installation permit therefor from the department; </section><section prefix="b">Use or continue to use, or permit the use or continued use of, any plumbing constructed, installed, or altered under a plumbing installation permit issued therefor where the department through a duly authorized inspector, employee, or agent, finds that the plumbing was not constructed, installed, or altered in accordance with such permit and the Kentucky State Plumbing Code. </section></section><section prefix="2">All applications for plumbing installation permits shall be accompanied by plans and specifications of the proposed plumbing installation, location, and construction of the water supply system to be used. If an on-site sewage disposal system that does not have a surface discharge is proposed, a valid on-site sewage disposal permit issued by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or its designated agent shall accompany the application. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall fix a reasonable schedule of fees and charges to be paid for plumbing installation permits and the necessary inspections incident thereto. The department shall also fix a reasonable schedule of fees and charges to be paid for necessary inspections of the construction, installation, or alteration of plumbing in public buildings. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1686, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 600, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 551, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 71. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 8. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 8. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31205</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>