<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.580</section_number><catch_line>Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial Committee -- Purpose -- Members -- Duties -- Responsibilities of cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established an Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial Committee for the purpose of creating an Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial in the city of Frankfort, Kentucky, or another location within the Commonwealth deemed more appropriate by the committee. Members of the committee shall include: <section prefix="a">The Governor or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="d">The Adjutant General of the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs or his or her designee; and </section><section prefix="e">A member recommended by the Joint Executive Council of Veterans Organizations to be appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial Committee shall be charged with the following duties: <section prefix="a">Choosing a design for the memorial; </section><section prefix="b">Determining a location for the memorial; </section><section prefix="c">Collecting the names of fallen service men and women to be included on the memorial; </section><section prefix="d">Requesting proposals for the construction of the memorial; </section><section prefix="e">Making recommendations on an entity to oversee the installation of the memorial; </section><section prefix="f">Making recommendations on an entity that will be responsible for maintenance and day-to-day upkeep of the memorial; and </section><section prefix="g">Seeking appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and any other funds, both public and private, to assist with the costs associated with the establishment of the memorial, which shall be deposited in the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund established in KRS 148.582. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial Committee shall complete the requirements of subsection (2)(a) to (f) of this section no later than October 1, 2012. The committee shall produce a written report to be provided to the Governor, the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. The report shall include, at a minimum, the following information: <section prefix="a">The results of the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial Committee's work with regard to the requirements of subsection (2)(a) to (f) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">An update on the costs required to complete the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial; and </section><section prefix="c">The amount of money raised for the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial at the date the report is due. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall have the following responsibilities related to the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial and the committee established to create the memorial: <section prefix="a">Provision of staff and administrative resources, not including reimbursement for any expense related to the committee's work, for the committee; and </section><section prefix="b">Administration of the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund established in KRS 148.582. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40256</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>