<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.339</section_number><catch_line>Monitoring of establishment of nursing home beds -- Collection of data -- Secretary's report to General Assembly. </catch_line><order_by>339</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall monitor the establishment of continuing care retirement communities' nursing home beds closely. The cabinet shall collect the following data regarding continuing care retirement communities' nursing home beds: <section prefix="a">The number of applications for a certificate of need to convert nursing home beds to nursing facility beds, the number of beds included in each application, and the number of beds approved; </section><section prefix="b">The number of applications for Medicaid certification for continuing care retirement communities' nursing home beds, the number of beds included in each application, and the number of beds certified as Medicaid eligible; </section><section prefix="c">The payor sources for continuing care retirement communities' nursing home beds; and </section><section prefix="d">The number of each type of bed or living unit within each continuing care retirement community on July 14, 2000, and the number of each type of bed or living unit within each continuing care retirement community on October 31, 2003. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to the beginning of the 2004 Regular Session of the General Assembly, the secretary shall issue a report to the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the chair of the Senate Standing Committee on Health and Welfare, and the chair of the House Standing Committee on Health and Welfare addressing the impact of KRS 216B.015, 216B.020, 216B.330, and 216B.332 upon the state's Medicaid budget, consumer access issues, and providers of long-term care. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 2, effective March 28, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> March 28, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9251</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>