<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.2841</section_number><catch_line>Free tuition at state-supported school for survivor of police officer, firefighter, or volunteer firefighter killed in line of duty -- Free tuition at state-supported school for survivor of other state-administered retirement system participants who died as a result of duty-related injury -- Limitation. </catch_line><order_by>2841</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any person whose parent or any nonmarried widow or widower whose spouse was a resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon becoming a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or volunteer firefighter and who was killed while in active service or training for active service or who died as a result of a service-connected disability shall not be required to pay any matriculation or tuition fee upon admission to any state-supported university, community college, or vocational training institution. The provisions of this subsection shall apply to any firefighter or volunteer firefighter who is killed or dies under the conditions covered in this subsection on July 1, 1989, or thereafter. </section><section prefix="b">In order to obtain the benefits conferred by paragraph (a) of this subsection, the parent-child relationship shall be shown by birth certificate, adoption papers, or other documentary evidence. The spousal relationship shall be shown by a marriage certificate or other documentary evidence. The parent's or spouse's service and the cause of death shall be evidenced by certification from the records of the Kentucky Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the appropriate city or county law enforcement agency which employed the deceased, the administrative agency for the fire department or fire protection district recognized for funding under KRS 95A.262, or the administrative agency having jurisdiction over any paid firefighters of all counties and cities of all classes. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any person whose parent or any nonmarried widow or widower whose spouse was an employee participating in a state-administered retirement system, and not otherwise covered by subsection (1) of this section, and who died as a result of a duty-related injury as described in KRS 61.621 shall not be required to pay any matriculation or tuition fee upon admission to any state-supported university, community college, or vocational training institution. </section><section prefix="b">In order to obtain the benefits conferred by paragraph (a) of this subsection, the parent-child relationship shall be shown by birth certificate, adoption papers, or other documentary evidence. The spousal relationship shall be shown by a marriage certificate or other documentary evidence. The parent's or spouse's service and the cause of death shall be evidenced by certification from the records of the employing agency or the appropriate retirement system. </section></section><section prefix="3">If one so admitted to a state-supported university, community college, or vocational training institution under the provisions of this section shall have obtained a cash scholarship paid or payable to the institution, from whatever source, the amount of the scholarship shall be applied to the credit of the applicant in the payment of incidental expenses of his attendance at the institution, and any balance, if the terms of the scholarship permit, shall be returned to the applicant. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 171, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 197, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 2, effective April 4, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4233</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>