<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.285</section_number><catch_line>Filing of protest -- Decision by secretary. </catch_line><order_by>285</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or his designee, shall have authority to determine protests and other controversies of actual or prospective bidders or offerors in connection with the solicitation or selection for award of a contract. </section><section prefix="2">Any actual or prospective bidder, offeror, or contractor who is aggrieved in connection with the solicitation or selection for award of a contract may file a protest with the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. A protest or notice of other controversy must be filed promptly and in any event within two (2) calendar weeks after such aggrieved person knows or should have known of the facts giving rise thereto. All protests or notices of other controversies must be in writing. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall promptly issue a decision in writing. A copy of that decision shall be mailed or otherwise furnished to the aggrieved party and shall state the reasons for the action taken. </section><section prefix="4">The decision by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall be final and conclusive. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 57, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1979 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>