<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.070</section_number><catch_line>Persons not licensed or registered -- Prohibitions on practicing -- Penalties -- Disciplinary powers of board -- Exceptions -- Hearing in Circuit Court. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who is not licensed or registered to do so, or whose license or registration to do so has been suspended, revoked, or denied, shall not practice as a dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates subsection (1) of this section is guilty of a Class B misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class A misdemeanor for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall not preclude the board from revoking or increasing the suspension period of a person practicing as a dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant who has illegally practiced while his or her license or registration is under suspension or has been revoked. </section><section prefix="4">The filing of criminal charges or a criminal conviction for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the board from instituting or imposing board disciplinary action authorized by this chapter against any person or organization violating this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="5">The institution or imposition of disciplinary action by the board against any person or organization violating the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the filing of criminal charges against or a criminal conviction of any person or organization for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit students from performing dental operations under the supervision of competent instructors approved by the dental school, college, or department of a university. The board may authorize the students of any dental college, school, or department of a university to practice dentistry in any state or municipal institution or public school, or under the board of health, or in a public clinic or a charitable institution. No fee shall be accepted by the student beyond the expenses provided by the stipend. </section><section prefix="b">Students shall be at all times under the direct supervision of a dentist licensed in this state, who is an instructor of the institution at which they are studying. </section></section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit volunteer health practitioners providing services under KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366. </section><section prefix="8">Violations of this chapter shall be heard in the Circuit Court of the county in which the alleged offense occurred. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2636-8, 2636-19. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30816</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>