<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">D CONTINUITY OF GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>39D.020</section_number><catch_line>Designation of alternate or substitute places for local government -- Acts valid and binding. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When, during a state of emergency, it becomes imprudent, inexpedient, or impossible to conduct the affairs of local government at the regular or usual places, the governing body of each county, urban-county, charter county, and city of this Commonwealth may meet at any place within or without the territorial limits of that political subdivision, at the direction of the elected chief executive officer or his or her successor, and shall proceed to establish and designate by ordinance, resolution, or other manner, alternate or substitute places as the temporary locations of government where all, or any part, of the public business may be transacted and conducted during the emergency situation. The alternate or substitute places may be within or without the territorial limits of the county, urban-county, charter county, and city, and shall be within those of the state. If practicable, they shall be the places designated as the temporary locations of government in the current local emergency operations plan. </section><section prefix="2">While the public business is being conducted at a temporary location, the governing body and other officers of a county, urban-county, charter county, and city of this Commonwealth shall have and exercise, at that location, all of the executive, legislative, administrative, and judicial powers and functions conferred upon that body and officers under state law. The powers and functions, except judicial, may be exercised in the light of the exigencies of the emergency situation without regard to or compliance with time-consuming procedures and formalities prescribed by law and pertaining thereto. All acts of the body and officers shall be as valid and binding as if performed within the territorial limits of their county, urban-county, charter county and city. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall control notwithstanding any statutory charter or ordinance provision to the contrary. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 53, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21764</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>