<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.358</section_number><catch_line>Legislative oversight fund. </catch_line><order_by>358</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a block grant legislative oversight fund which may be expended by the Commission for the purpose of implementing and administering the provisions of KRS 45.351 to 45.359 and 273.453. </section><section prefix="2">Each state administering agency shall, to the extent permitted by federal law, withhold and place in the block grant legislative oversight fund one-fourth of one percent (0.25%) of the federal funds made available under the block grant. The funds placed in the block grant legislative oversight fund shall not lapse to the general fund. </section><section prefix="3">The Commission shall determine the actual cost to the Commission of implementing and administering the provisions of KRS 45.351 to 45.359 and 273.453 for each block grant under review. The Commission shall notify each state administering agency in writing of the actual cost determined. </section><section prefix="4">The Commission shall, for the purpose of implementing and administering the provisions of KRS 45.351 to 45.359 and 273.453 for each block grant under review and as permitted by federal law, expend no more than one-fourth of one percent (0.25%) of the federal funds made available under each block grant. </section><section prefix="5">The Commission shall return to the applicable state administering agency any unexpended federal moneys placed in the block grant legislative oversight fund under this section quarterly. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22250</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>