<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.370</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of city-county board as to public health and institutions. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>When the board has been organized and the properties transferred, as provided in KRS 212.350 to 212.620, the board, throughout said county, including all municipalities therein, shall, except as otherwise provided by law, have exclusive control and operation, under the acts of the General Assembly of Kentucky, the ordinances, if any, of the legislative bodies of the municipalities in said county, the orders and resolutions, if any, of the fiscal court of said county, the regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the rules and regulations of the board, of all matters relating to institutions safeguarding the public health, including city or county hospitals, tuberculosis hospitals, eruptive hospitals, chronic hospitals, medical care of the indigent, and all other matters affecting public health, including education of the public regarding such conditions, and the adoption of remedial measures, and the enforcement of all laws and regulations affecting public health, including existing ordinances of such city and, if any, of other municipalities in said county, and any ordinances which may be hereafter enacted by the legislative bodies of such municipalities, including laws and ordinances regulating sanitation, milk inspection, meat inspection, livestock inspection, wells, drinking water and fountains, vaults, vaccination and immunization, quarantine, and the maintenance of laboratories and clinics necessary for the promotion of public health. The board may expend funds for the purpose of conducting research work, including laboratory and biometrical work, and establishing, erecting, and maintaining laboratories and other buildings and all appurtenances thereto for research work as to the prevalence, causes, cure, and prevention of disease, and to that end the board is authorized to expend funds in the employment of such persons or organizations, scientists, or research experts as the board may deem proper. The board shall be charged with the responsibility for the collection from official and other sources and for the publication of such statistics and information as may be useful and necessary for the performance of its duties, and upon such other matters as such municipalities by ordinance and said county, by resolution of the fiscal court, respectively, or the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of Kentucky, by regulation, place under the control of said board. The board may charge reasonable fees to sewage treatment plant operators for the regulation and inspection of sewage treatment plants to be paid within twelve (12) months from the time of regulation and inspection. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 408, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 359, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 107(3); and ch. 351, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 2 </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>