<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.280</section_number><catch_line>Trucks and trailers owned by governmental units -- Regulation of trucks and trailers by cities.   </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 189.221 to 189.230 and 189.280 shall not apply to motor trucks, semitrailer trucks, or trailers owned by the United States, the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or any agency of them, any county or city. </section><section prefix="2">If any motor truck, semitrailer truck, or trailer is lawfully licensed by a city pursuant to KRS 186.270, then KRS 189.221 and subsection (1) of 189.222 shall not apply thereto, within the limits of the city issuing the license, or within fifteen (15) miles of the limits of the city, if it is a city with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, or within five (5) miles of its limits if it is a city with a population of less than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, except on such state-maintained highways or portions thereof, including connecting-link streets, as may be designated by the commissioner of highways, and on such county highways as may be designated by the county judge/executive; provided, however, that in no case shall any vehicle exceed the weight and size limitations established by the city ordinance when those limitations are less stringent than those provided in the aforementioned sections of the statutes. For the purposes of this subsection vehicles exempt from the imposition of a city license tax by reason of subsection (2) of KRS 281.830 shall be entitled to the same exemptions as those so licensed. </section><section prefix="3">Cities may, by ordinance, provide maximum limits with respect to the weight, height, width and length of motor trucks, semitrailer trucks, and trailers, within their respective boundaries, not less, however, than the maximum limits prescribed in KRS 189.221 and subsection (1) of 189.222, and may authorize the operation of trailers. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 267, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 30, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 180. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-92. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>