<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.121</section_number><catch_line>State airways system -- State airport plan -- Aeronautics controversies -- Injunctive proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>121</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may designate, design, establish, expand, or modify a state airways system which will best serve the interests of the state. It may chart such airways systems and arrange for publication and distribution of such maps, charts, notices and bulletins relating to such airways as may be required in the public interest. The system shall be supplementary to and coordinated in design and operation with the federal airways system. It may include all types of air navigation facilities, whether publicly or privately owned, provided that such facilities conform to federal safety standards. </section><section prefix="2">It may participate as party plaintiff or defendant, or as intervener on behalf of the state, or on behalf of any air board or governmental unit or other person in any controversy involving any right of the state or others pertaining to aeronautics. </section><section prefix="3">To enforce the provisions of this chapter the cabinet may in addition to all other remedies institute and prosecute injunctive proceedings without the execution of a bond. </section><section prefix="4">The Franklin Circuit Court shall hold concurrent venue with the courts of this Commonwealth of all civil and injunctive actions instituted by the cabinet for the enforcement of this chapter and the orders, rules and regulations of the cabinet thereunder. </section></text><history>Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 16. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 13. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5730</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>