<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.864</section_number><catch_line>Annual review of assessment program -- Termination of program. </catch_line><order_by>864</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall review the assessment program annually. If, at the end of each year after the first year of the assessment program, the board determines that there is dissatisfaction with the program, the Commissioner shall then conduct a referendum among the handlers in the area. If upon the referendum, a majority of the handlers voting in the area reject the program, it shall be terminated at the end of the year in which the referendum for the area was conducted; otherwise, the assessment program shall continue in force and effect. </section><section prefix="2">If the duly certified association expresses in writing its desire to the Commissioner to discontinue the assessment program and terminate the program, the Commissioner shall within fifteen (15) days following receipt of the request convene the board to review and act on the request. The board, after reviewing the request and conducting whatever proceedings are deemed appropriate and necessary in connection with the request, may terminate the program effective at the end of the year in which the board action is taken; and, in this event, the Commissioner shall notify, by registered or certified mail, the handlers affected thereby of the termination of the program. </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11849</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>