<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.390</section_number><catch_line>Board may issue subpoenas -- Penalty for false testimony or failure to comply with subpoena -- Circuit Court may compel the attendance of witnesses, production of documents and giving of testimony before board. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text>The board shall have the power to issue subpoenas requiring the attendance of such witnesses and the production of such records, books, papers, and documents as it may deem necessary for investigation of the case of any person before it. Subpoenas may be signed and oaths administered by any member of the board. Subpoenas so issued shall be served by any sheriff, constable, police, parole or probation officer, or other peace officer and a return made to the board in the same manner as similar process in the Circuit Court. Any person who testifies falsely or fails to appear when subpoenaed, or fails or refuses to produce documents, records, or other such material when subpoenaed, upon citation by the Circuit Courts where the board meets and after hearing by that court, shall be subject to the same order and penalties to which persons before that court are subject. Any Circuit Court, upon application of the board, may compel the attendance of witnesses, the production of documents, records or other such material, and the giving of testimony before the board. </text><history>Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 15, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19187</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>