<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates subsection (1) of KRS 229.071 or subsection (1) of KRS 229.021 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates subsection (2), (3), or (4) of KRS 229.021 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than ninety (90) days, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates KRS 229.081 where the violation does not constitute a violation of KRS 229.021, shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="4">Any peace officer who willfully fails to execute the duties required of him by KRS 229.240 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any of the provisions of this chapter for which no specific penalty is provided shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="6">Any person who fails to pay the taxes required by KRS 229.031 or ascertained to be due under KRS 229.041 together with the expenses incurred in the examination, within twenty (20) days after notice to the delinquent person of the amount fixed by the authority shall ipso facto forfeit his or her license. In addition he or she shall forfeit and pay into the State Treasury an additional amount equal to the taxes found to be due. </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 229.121 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) and no person who has been guilty of such an offense shall be allowed to participate in any boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling show or exhibition for one (1) year after being found guilty of the offense. </section><section prefix="8">Any person failing to make the report required by subsection (2) or (4) of KRS 229.031 shall be liable for any tax the Commonwealth may lose as a result of his or her failure to make the required report. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 22, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>