<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.355</section_number><catch_line>Fees set by local board of health -- Inspections to be made only on systems constructed after July 15, 1986 -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any local board of health authorized to serve as agent of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for the issuance of permits for on-site sewage disposal systems may set a schedule of fees reasonably related to the cost of administering programs including: <section prefix="a">Inspections incidental to construction, installation, and alteration of on-site sewage disposal systems; and </section><section prefix="b">Inspections incidental to maintenance and operation of on-site sewage disposal systems. </section></section><section prefix="2">Such fees shall be designed to fully cover the cost of the services but shall not exceed the cost of the services performed. Fees payable to the board shall be used by the board only for the administration of said program. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall authorize or allow the cabinet to inspect any on-site sewage disposal system constructed prior to July 15, 1986, unless such inspection is deemed necessary due to receipt of a complaint by the cabinet or the local health department. In such an instance, the cabinet shall document or shall require the local health department to document the source and nature of such complaint. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 354, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 297, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8386</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>