<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.095</section_number><catch_line>Officers required to take educational course on AIDS. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall require all officers employed by them to complete an educational course approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services on human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall develop literature on the human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome and a training curriculum of not more than four (4) hours for the instruction of officers. The literature and training curriculum shall include information of known modes of transmission and methods of controlling and preventing these diseases with an emphasis on appropriate behavior and attitude change. This training may be part of any other training required and for which law enforcement officers receive an allowance to attend. However, nonreceipt of allowance does not exclude a law enforcement officer from the training required in this section. </section><section prefix="2">All officers shall successfully complete the training required. Any person holding the position of officer shall not exercise that position for more than one (1) year without successfully completing the required training. If an officer does not successfully complete the required training within the time specified, he or she shall be suspended from further service as an officer until he or she successfully completes the required training. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 64, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 88, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 73, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1100</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>