<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="343" order_by="343">APPRENTICESHIP </unit></structure><section_number>343.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Apprentice" means a worker at least sixteen (16) years of age, except where a higher minimum age standard is otherwise fixed by law, who is employed to learn an apprenticeable occupation as provided in 29 C.F.R. pt. 29; </section><section prefix="2">"Apprenticeship agreement" means a written agreement, complying with 29 C.F.R. pt. 29 between an apprentice and either the apprentice's program sponsor, or an apprenticeship committee acting as agent for the program sponsors, which contains the terms and conditions of the employment and training of the apprentice; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards, under the direction and supervision of the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, or any person authorized to act in his or her behalf, having jurisdiction over laws or regulations governing wages and hours of employees working in this state; </section><section prefix="4">"Council" means the Commonwealth's Apprenticeship and Training Council, which provides advice and guidance to the Kentucky Labor Cabinet regarding the Commonwealth's apprenticeship program; </section><section prefix="5">"Supervisor" means supervisor of apprenticeship and training; </section><section prefix="6">"Trainee" means a person at least sixteen (16) years of age who has entered into an on-the-job training agreement with an employer or an association of employers or an organization of employees in a construction occupation under a program which has been approved by a federal agency as promoting equal employment opportunity in conjunction with federal-aid construction projects; </section><section prefix="7">"Apprenticeship program" means a plan containing all terms and conditions for the qualification, recruitment, selection, employment, and training of apprentices as required under 29 C.F.R. pts. 29 and 30, including such matters as the requirement for a written apprenticeship agreement; </section><section prefix="8">"On-the-job training program" means a plan containing all terms and conditions for the qualification, recruitment, selection, employment, and training of a trainee, including such matters as the requirement for a written on-the-job training agreement other than an apprenticeship program; provided, however, that said program has been approved by a federal agency as promoting equal employment opportunity in conjunction with federal-aid construction projects; </section><section prefix="9">"Sponsor" means any person, association, committee, or organization in whose name or title the program is or is to be registered, irrespective of whether such entity is an employer; </section><section prefix="10">"Employer" means any person or organization employing an apprentice or trainee whether or not such person or organization is a party to an apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement with the apprentice or trainee; and </section><section prefix="11">"Related instruction" means an organized and systematic form of instruction designed to provide the apprentice or trainee with knowledge of the theoretical and technical subjects related to the apprentice's occupation. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1863, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 40, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599c-34. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42986</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>