<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.023</section_number><catch_line>Approval of federally-funded construction projects -- Commission review of agreement and supporting documents -- Surcharge. </catch_line><order_by>023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this section shall apply to any construction project undertaken by a water association, commission, district, or combined water, gas or sewer district formed under KRS Chapter 74 or 273, which is financed in whole or in part under the terms of an agreement between the water utility and the United States Department of Agriculture or the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development. Because federal financing of such projects entails prior review and oversight by the federal agency and obligates the utility to certain actions, and because conflicting requirements by the federal agency and the Public Service Commission may place the water utility in an untenable position and delay or jeopardize such projects, it is declared to be the policy of the Commonwealth that such agreements shall be accepted by the Public Service Commission, and that the commission shall not prohibit a water utility from fulfilling its obligations under such an agreement. </section><section prefix="2">No agreement between a water utility and federal agency under this section shall take effect until thirty (30) days after such agreement, together with necessary applications and documentation, is filed with the commission, unless the commission acts within a lesser time. The commission in its administrative regulations shall list the specific documents required to be filed under this subsection. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall review the project and the agreement, may recommend changes to the utility and the federal agency, but shall not modify or reject any portion of the agreement on its own authority. The commission shall issue a certificate of necessity and convenience and such other orders as may be required to implement the terms of the agreement no later than thirty (30) days after filing. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall not prohibit the inclusion of any cost or the use of any accounting procedure in reviewing or setting the rates of the utility if such cost or procedure is required as a condition for federal financing of a construction project under an approved agreement between the water utility and federal agency. </section><section prefix="5">If the federal agency approves a surcharge to the water bills of customers who receive service through an extension of water facilities under this section, which is in lieu of an assessment against the customer for the cost of the extension, then the Public Service Commission shall allow collection of the surcharge to continue for the period of years for which the surcharge was established. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>