<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.665</section_number><catch_line>Institution of civil actions by commission or Attorney General -- Powers of court. </catch_line><order_by>665</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission or the Attorney General may file a civil action in Circuit Court for appropriate relief if the commission or Attorney General has probable cause to believe that: <section prefix="a">Any person or group of persons is engaged in a pattern or practice of resistance to the full enjoyment of any housing right granted by this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">Any group of persons has been denied any housing right granted by this chapter and the denial raises an issue of general public importance; or </section><section prefix="c">Any state or local zoning or land use law is a discriminatory housing practice. The action shall be brought within eighteen (18) months of the occurrence or termination of the alleged discriminatory practice; or </section><section prefix="d">A conciliation agreement has been breached. </section></section> The action shall be brought within ninety (90) days of the commission or Attorney General receiving notice of the breach. <section prefix="2">In an action under this section, the court: <section prefix="a">May award preventive relief, including a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order against the person responsible for a violation to assure the full enjoyment of the rights granted by this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">May award other appropriate relief, including compensatory and punitive damages; </section><section prefix="c">May award a reasonable attorney's fee and costs to the prevailing party to the same extent allowed in KRS 344.660. The state shall not be liable in any event for fees and costs; and </section><section prefix="d">May, to vindicate the public interest, assess a civil penalty against the respondent in an amount that does not exceed: <section prefix="1">Fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) for a first violation; and </section><section prefix="2">One hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) for a second or subsequent violation. </section></section><section prefix="e">A person may intervene in an action under this section if the person is: <section prefix="1">An aggrieved person to the discriminatory housing practice; or </section><section prefix="2">A party to a conciliation agreement concerning the discriminatory housing practice. </section></section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 31, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32673</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>