<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.130</section_number><catch_line>Alternative methods that may be used when strata shot. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>If any of the strata in the well have been shot, creating cavities that cannot readily be filled in the manner described in KRS 353.120, the well operator shall follow either of the following methods: <section prefix="1">If the stratum that has been shot is the lowest one in the well, there shall be placed, at the nearest suitable point but not less than twenty (20) feet above the stratum, a plug of cement or other suitable material that will completely seal the hole; but if the shooting has been done above one (1) or more oil or gas-bearing strata in the well, plugging in the manner specified shall be done at the nearest suitable point, but not less than twenty (20) feet below and above the stratum shot. </section><section prefix="2">When the cavity is in the lowest oil or gas-bearing stratum in the well, a liner shall be placed which shall extend from below the stratum to a suitable point, but not less than twenty (20) feet above the stratum in which the shooting has been done; but if the shooting has been done above one (1) or more oil or gas-bearing strata in the well, the liner shall be so placed that it will extend not less than twenty (20) feet above or less than twenty (20) feet below the stratum in which shooting has been done. After the liner is placed, it shall be compactly filled with cement, clay or other nonporous sealing material. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3766b-13. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33062</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>