<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.010</section_number><catch_line>Division of Forestry created -- Powers -- Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created and there shall be maintained within the Department for Natural Resources in the Energy and Environment Cabinet a Division of Forestry to supervise all forestry property and advance forest interests of the state through development of such property and interests. It shall initiate such projects as will promote public appreciation of forest protection and of reforestation; encourage tree planting in general and on the public highways in particular; grow, collect and distribute seedlings; form and foster junior forestry clubs; cooperate with local civic organizations in the care of trees and planting of more trees; provide for organized forest fire protection; cooperate with the federal government, state departments and landowners in the perpetuation of forests, the promotion of tree growth and the redemption of wasteland for agricultural purposes; and encourage an interest in forestry by correspondence, press, pamphlets, reports, moving pictures and organizations. </section><section prefix="2">The director of the Division of Forestry with the approval of the secretary for energy and environment shall adopt and enforce such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out the functions assigned the cabinet by law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 141, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974, Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(3). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 40. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2007h-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>