<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.100</section_number><catch_line>Administration of preliminary breath tests -- Visual recording of vehicle pursuits, traffic stops, and field  sobriety tests -- Conditions of recording -- Use and destruction of recordings. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Law enforcement agencies may administer preliminary breath tests using devices or equipment which will ensure an accurate determination of blood alcohol content. Such tests may be administered in the field to a person suspected of violation of KRS 189A.010 before the person is arrested. This test may be administered in addition to any other blood alcohol level test authorized by law. A person's refusal to take a preliminary breath test shall not be used against him in a court of law or in any administrative proceeding. </section><section prefix="2">Law enforcement agencies may record on film or videotape or by other visual and audible means the pursuit of a violator or suspected violator, the traffic stop, or field sobriety tests administered at the scene of an arrest for violation of KRS 189A.010 or such tests at a police station, jail, or other suitable facility subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The testing is recorded in its entirety (except for blood alcohol analysis testing); and </section><section prefix="b">The entire recording of the field sobriety tests and the entire recording of such portions of the pursuit and traffic stop as were recorded is shown in court unless the defendant waives the showing of any portions not offered by the prosecution; and </section><section prefix="c">The entire recording is available to be shown by the defense at trial if the defendant so desires regardless of whether it was introduced by the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="d">The defendant or his counsel is afforded an opportunity to view the entire recording a reasonable time before the trial in order to prepare an adequate defense; and </section><section prefix="e">Recordings shall be used for official purposes only, which shall include: <section prefix="1">Viewing in court; </section><section prefix="2">Viewing by the prosecution and defense in preparation for a trial; and </section><section prefix="3">Viewing for purposes of administrative reviews and official administrative proceedings. Recordings shall otherwise be considered as confidential records; and </section></section><section prefix="f">The videotape or film taken in accordance with this section shall, upon order of the District Court, be destroyed after the later of the following: <section prefix="1">Fourteen (14) months, if there is no appeal of any criminal or traffic case filed as a result of the videotape or film, or if the videotape or film does not record the actual happening of an accident involving a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">Fourteen (14) months after a decision has been made not to prosecute any case upon which an arrest has been made or a citation issued as a result of the videotape or film, if the videotape does not record the actual happening of an accident involving a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty-six (26) months, if there is no appeal of any criminal or traffic case filed as a result of the videotape or film, if the videotape or film records the actual happening of an accident involving a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="4">After all appeals have been exhausted arising from any criminal or traffic case filed as a result of the videotape; </section><section prefix="5">At the conclusion of any civil case arising from events depicted on the videotape or film; or </section><section prefix="6">At the conclusion of the exhaustion of all appeals arising from any law enforcement agency administrative proceedings arising from events depicted on the videotape or film; and </section></section><section prefix="g">Public officials or employees utilizing or showing recordings other than as permitted in this chapter or permitting others to do so shall be guilty of official misconduct in the first degree. </section></section><section prefix="3">When a peace officer makes a videotape or film recording of any transaction covered by subsection (2) of this section and a citation is issued or an arrest is made, the peace officer shall note on the uniform citation that a videotape has been made of the transaction. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 24, effective October 1, 2000. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> October 1, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>