<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2">CITIZENSHIP, EMBLEMS, HOLIDAYS, AND TIME </unit></structure><section_number>2.030</section_number><catch_line>State flag. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The official state flag of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall be of navy blue silk, nylon, wool or cotton bunting, or some other suitable material, with the seal of the Commonwealth encircled by a wreath, the lower half of which shall be goldenrod in bloom and the upper half the words "Commonwealth of Kentucky," embroidered, printed, painted, or stamped on the center thereof. The dimensions of the flag may vary, but the length shall be one and nine-tenths (1 9/10) times the width and the diameter of the seal and encirclement shall be approximately two-thirds (2/3) the width of the flag. </section><section prefix="2">The approved official drawings of the state flag shall be permanently retained in the files of the office of the Secretary of State. All state flags for official use of the Commonwealth shall conform as to color and design with these official drawings. </section><section prefix="3">The emblem at the head of a flagstaff used to display the flag of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall be the Kentucky cardinal in an alert but restful pose, cast in bronze, brass, or other suitable material. </section><section prefix="4">The flying of the state flag at all state buildings and installations including public school buildings, National Guard armories, state parks, and other such buildings is considered proper and is encouraged. </section><section prefix="5">No disrespect should be shown to the flag of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. With the exception of the flag of the United States of America, the flag of the Commonwealth of Kentucky should not be dipped to any person or thing. The flag should never touch anything beneath it, such as the ground, the floor, water, or merchandise. The flag, when it is in such condition that it is no longer a fitting emblem for display, should be destroyed in a dignified way, preferably by burning. </section><section prefix="6">All official flags of the Commonwealth of Kentucky purchased by a public institution shall be manufactured in the United States. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 114, secs. 1, 2, 3, and 4, effective June 14, 1942. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618m. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>