<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="436" order_by="436">OFFENSES AGAINST MORALITY </unit></structure><section_number>436.185</section_number><catch_line>Exhibition of walking horse where the horse's front legs or hoofs show evidence of burns, drugs, lacerations or any pain inflicting device. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The term "walking horse" as used in this section shall be construed to include only that breed of horses known as walking horses. </section><section prefix="b">The term "handler" as used in this section shall be construed to mean that person or persons who are in charge of grooming, preparing and readying said horse for competition. </section></section><section prefix="2">No walking horse shall be permitted to compete or exhibit in any exhibition or fair either for profit or pleasure, if said horse's front legs or hoofs show evidence of burns, drugs, lacerations, any sharp pointed instrument, or any pain inflicting device. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be the duty of the assigned ringmaster in charge of any such exhibition or competition to properly inspect the front legs and hoofs of each entry in each class or event. Said inspection shall be for the purpose of determining whether there is any evidence of burns, drugs, lacerations, any sharp pointed instrument, or any pain inflicting device appearing on said animal. </section><section prefix="4">If any such evidence appears to the satisfaction of the ringmaster, he shall immediately bar said horse from competition, and notify the sheriff of said county of said violation. The handler of said horse shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) or imprisoned for ten (10) days or both. For the second and each subsequent offense he shall be imprisoned for thirty (30) days. </section><section prefix="5">Any ringmaster who fails to perform these duties, and permits the commission of any of the offenses stated in subsection (2), shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense allowed. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall in no wise repeal any laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky on the subject of cruelty to animals and shall be construed by the courts as supplementary thereto. </section></text><history>Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 245, secs. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>May 18, 1956.</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18989</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>