<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="359" order_by="359">WAREHOUSES AND WAREHOUSEMEN </unit></structure><section_number>359.200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 359.210 to 359.250. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>As used in KRS 359.210 to 359.250, unless the context clearly requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Self-service storage facility" means any real property used for renting or leasing individual storage spaces in which the occupants themselves customarily store and remove their own personal property on a "self-service" basis; </section><section prefix="2">"Rental agreement" means any written agreement that establishes or modifies the terms, conditions, or rules concerning the use and occupancy of a self-service storage facility or self-contained storage unit; </section><section prefix="3">"Leased space" means the individual storage space at a self-service storage facility or in a self-contained storage unit which is rented to an occupant pursuant to a rental agreement; </section><section prefix="4">"Occupant" means a person, a sublessee, successor, or assign, entitled to the use of a leased space at a self-service storage facility or in a self-contained storage unit under a rental agreement; </section><section prefix="5">"Operator" means the owner, operator, lessor, or sublessor of a self-service storage facility or a self-contained storage unit, or an agent or any other person authorized to manage the facility or storage unit, but does not mean a warehouseman, unless the operator issues a warehouse receipt, bill of lading, or other document of title for the personal property stored; </section><section prefix="6">"Personal property" means movable property located within leased space at a self-service storage facility or in a self-contained storage unit and includes but is not limited to goods, wares, merchandise, motor vehicles, watercraft, and household items and furnishings; </section><section prefix="7">"Default" means the failure to perform on time any obligation or duty set forth in the rental agreement; </section><section prefix="8">"Last known address" means that postal address or electronic mail address provided by the occupant in the latest rental agreement or the postal address or electronic mail address provided by the occupant in a subsequent written notice of a change of address; </section><section prefix="9">"Self-contained storage unit" means any unit, including but not limited to a trailer, box, or other shipping container, which is leased by an occupant primarily for use as a storage space, whether the unit is located at a self-service storage facility or at another location designated by the occupant; </section><section prefix="10">"Verified electronic mail" means an electronic message or an executable program or computer file that is transmitted between two (2) or more computers or electronic terminals that the sender has verified by any reasonable means as being a working electronic mail address. The term includes electronic messages that are transmitted within or between computer networks; and </section><section prefix="11">"Verified mail" means any method of mailing that is offered by the United States Postal Service or private delivery service that provides evidence of mailing. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43280</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>