<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.590</section_number><catch_line>Technical advisory committees. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following technical advisory committees shall be established for the purpose of acting in an advisory capacity to the council with respect to the administration of the medical assistance program and in performing the function of peer review: <section prefix="a">A Technical Advisory Committee on Physician Services consisting of five (5) physicians appointed by the council of the Kentucky State Medical Association; </section><section prefix="b">A Technical Advisory Committee on Hospital Care consisting of five (5) hospital administrators appointed by the board of trustees of the Kentucky Hospital Association; </section><section prefix="c">A Technical Advisory Committee on Dental Care consisting of five (5) dentists appointed by the Kentucky Dental Association; </section><section prefix="d">A Technical Advisory Committee on Nursing Service consisting of five (5) nurses appointed by the board of directors of the Kentucky State Association of Registered Nurses; </section><section prefix="e">A Technical Advisory Committee on Nursing Home Care consisting of six (6) members of which five (5) members shall be appointed by the Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities, and one (1) member shall be appointed by the Kentucky Association of Nonprofit Homes and Services for the Aging, Inc.; </section><section prefix="f">A Technical Advisory Committee on Optometric Care consisting of five (5) members appointed by the Kentucky Optometric Association; </section><section prefix="g">A Technical Advisory Committee on Podiatric Care consisting of five (5) podiatrists appointed by the Kentucky Podiatry Association; </section><section prefix="h">A Technical Advisory Committee on Primary Care consisting of five (5) primary care providers, two (2) of whom shall represent licensed health maintenance organizations, appointed by the Governor, until such time as an association of primary care providers is established, whereafter the association shall appoint the members; </section><section prefix="i">A Technical Advisory Committee on Home Health Care consisting of five (5) members appointed by the board of directors of the Kentucky Home Health Association; </section><section prefix="j">A Technical Advisory Committee on Consumer Rights and Client Needs consisting of five (5) members, with one (1) member to be appointed by each of the following organizations: the Kentucky Combined Committee on Aging, the Kentucky Legal Services Corporation, the Arc of Kentucky, the Department of Public Advocacy, and the National Association of Social Workers-Kentucky Chapter; </section><section prefix="k">A Technical Advisory Committee on Behavioral Health consisting of six (6) members, with one (1) member to be appointed by each of the following organizations: the Kentucky Mental Health Coalition, the Kentucky Association of Regional Programs, the National Alliance on Mental Illness (NAMI) Kentucky, a statewide mental health consumer organization, the People Advocating Recovery (PAR), and the Kentucky Brain Injury Alliance; </section><section prefix="l">A Technical Advisory Committee on Children's Health consisting of ten (10) members, with one (1) member to be appointed by each of the following organizations: the Kentucky Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics, the Kentucky PTA, the Kentucky Psychological Association, the Kentucky School Nurses Association, the Kentucky Association for Early Childhood Education, the Family Resource and Youth Services Coalition of Kentucky, the Kentucky Youth Advocates, the Kentucky Association of Hospice and Palliative Care, a parent of a child enrolled in Medicaid or the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program appointed by the Kentucky Head Start Association, and a pediatric dentist appointed by the Kentucky Dental Association; </section><section prefix="m">A Technical Advisory Committee on Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities consisting of nine (9) members, one (1) of whom shall be a consumer who participates in a nonresidential community Medicaid waiver program, one (1) of whom shall be a consumer who participates in a residential community Medicaid waiver program, one (1) of whom shall be a consumer representative of a family member who participates in a community Medicaid waiver program, and one (1) of whom shall be a consumer representative of a family member who resides in an ICF/ID facility that accepts Medicaid payments, all of whom shall be appointed by the Governor; one (1) member shall be appointed by the Arc of Kentucky; one (1) member shall be appointed by the Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities; one (1) member shall be appointed by the Kentucky Association of Homes and Services for the Aging; and two (2) members shall be appointed by the Kentucky Association of Private Providers, one (1) of whom shall be a nonprofit provider and one (1) of whom shall be a for-profit provider; </section><section prefix="n">A Technical Advisory Committee on Therapy Services consisting of six (6) members, two (2) of whom shall be occupational therapists and shall be appointed by the Kentucky Occupational Therapists Association, two (2) of whom shall be physical therapists and shall be appointed by the Kentucky Physical Therapy Association, and two (2) of whom shall be speech therapists and shall be appointed by the Kentucky Speech-Language-Hearing Association; and </section><section prefix="o">A Technical Advisory Committee on Pharmacy consisting of five (5) pharmacists appointed by the Kentucky Pharmacists Association. </section></section><section prefix="2">The members of the technical advisory committees shall serve until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="3">Each appointive member of a committee shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses in carrying out his duties with reimbursement for expenses being made in accordance with state regulations relating to travel reimbursement. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 63, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 28, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 4. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 18. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 4. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VII, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42997</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>