<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.354</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensure for Massage Therapy -- Appointments -- Terms -- Reimbursement -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>354</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a board to be known as the Kentucky Board of Licensure for Massage Therapy, which shall be an independent agency. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint seven (7) members to serve on the board with the following representation: <section prefix="a">Five (5) members who are massage therapists licensed under KRS 309.350 to 309.364, who have been in the practice of massage therapy for at least five (5) of the last seven (7) years, and who have been residents of Kentucky for at least one (1) year; </section><section prefix="b">Of these five (5), at least one (1) but no more than two (2) shall own or direct a board-approved massage therapy training program; and </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members shall be appointed by the Governor and shall serve as members at large who are neither licensed massage therapists nor spouses of persons who are licensed, or have a direct or indirect interest in the profession regulated under KRS 309.350 to 309.364. One (1) of the two (2) may hold a license in another health care profession. </section></section><section prefix="3">Appointments shall be for three (3) years with initial appointments as follows: three (3) appointees shall serve three (3) year terms; two (2) shall serve two (2) year terms; and two (2) shall serve one (1) year terms. The Governor shall assign terms to initial members at his or her discretion. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall elect initially, and annually thereafter, a chair, vice chair, and secretary from its membership and shall meet at least once per year, and more often as deemed necessary, at a time and at a place in Kentucky for the board to fulfill its duties. </section><section prefix="5">Each member of the board shall receive a per diem not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) and other actual and necessary expenses for each day he or she is actually engaged in the discharge of the board's official duties. </section><section prefix="6">Upon recommendation of the board, the Governor may remove any member of the board for a poor attendance record, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1667, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 112, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003; and ch. 70, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 112, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (6/24/2003).  2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 5, and 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 5, are substantially identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>