<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.620</section_number><catch_line>Title to equipment or infrastructure -- Retention -- Transfer to district. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text>The Division of Conservation shall retain title to each piece of heavy or specialized equipment or any infrastructure purchased and made available to any soil and water conservation district until such time as the soil and water conservation districts fully amortize the commission's investment in the equipment or the infrastructure. If the soil and water conservation district purchases infrastructure with use of funds made available by the Division of Conservation for that purpose, then the Division of Conservation shall be listed on the deed to the property jointly with the district. After the commission's investment in the equipment or infrastructure has been fully amortized, it is authorized and empowered to transfer the title thereto to the district. If the district has purchased infrastructure with funds made available by the Division of Conservation, the district shall consult with the division prior to the dispossession of the property. </text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007 -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 64. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>