<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.630</section_number><catch_line>Sale of bonds -- Publication area. </catch_line><order_by>630</order_by><text>Bonds of the commission shall be sold in such form and in such manner as the commission deems appropriate in accordance with prevailing market conditions. If the bonds are sold on the basis of sealed bids or proposals, the "publication area," as that term is used in KRS Chapter 424, shall not be deemed to be the area within which the office of the commission is situated, but shall be deemed to be the "publication area" of the board of education executing the lease. If the bonds are sold on the basis of sealed bids or proposals, the sale shall be publicly advertised by means of a notice conforming to the provisions of KRS 424.140, and the same shall be published at least one (1) time, at least seven (7) days in advance of the date set forth for opening bids, in a daily newspaper having bona fide general circulation throughout the Commonwealth. If such publication is made, it shall be sufficient for publication in the "publication area" to be made only one <section prefix="1">time, at least seven (7) days in advance of the date set forth for the opening of bids. If </section>a copy of the sale notice be delivered or transmitted in good faith to the qualified newspaper of the "publication area" in time for publication in an issue thereof published seven (7) days or more in advance of the date set forth for the opening of bids, and with direction for publication therein, any failure of such newspaper to make publication as directed shall not invalidate the sale of the bonds by the commission on the designated date, nor require postponement or cancellation thereof. </text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 387, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 33, effective October 18, 1985. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 28, (3) at 623. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3357</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>