<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="66" order_by="66">ISSUANCE OF BONDS AND CONTROL OF FUNDS </unit></structure><section_number>66.045</section_number><catch_line>State local debt officer may provide technical and advisory assistance on issuance of bonds. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of this section to facilitate, through state technical and advisory assistance, the marketing of local government bonds and other long-term obligations at the lowest possible net interest costs. </section><section prefix="2">The state local debt officer may provide technical and advisory assistance regarding the issuance of bonds and obligations to those issuers whose governing bodies request that assistance. The assistance shall include, but need not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Advice on the marketing of bonds and obligations by issuers; </section><section prefix="b">Conduct of training courses in debt management; and </section><section prefix="c">Promotion of the use by local governments of such tools for sound financial management as adequate systems of budgeting, accounting, auditing, and reporting. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 58, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>