<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.340</section_number><catch_line>Licensee to obtain seal or stamp -- Use of seal or stamp. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each professional engineer or professional land surveyor shall, upon licensure, obtain a seal or stamp of the design authorized by the board, bearing his or her name, license number, and the words "Licensed Professional Engineer" or "Licensed Professional Land Surveyor." </section><section prefix="2">Use of the stamp, seal, or signature in an electronic transaction shall be conducted in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the board under KRS 322.290(13). </section><section prefix="3">The seal or stamp, signature, and the date shall be used to provide certification for all reports, specifications, drawings, and plans, if presented to a client or any public or governmental agency. Reproduction of original signatures shall be adequate to meet the requirements of this subsection. </section><section prefix="4">The seal or stamp and signature shall be used by licensees only if the work being stamped was under the licensee's complete direction and control. </section><section prefix="5">Every survey plat and physical description prepared by a professional land surveyor and submitted to a client or any public or governmental agency shall display the certification by the professional land surveyor under whose supervision the plat or description was prepared. </section><section prefix="6">It shall be unlawful for a licensee to affix, or permit to be affixed, his or her seal, stamp, or signature to any document described in subsection (3) or (5) of this section: <section prefix="a">After the expiration of a license; or </section><section prefix="b">For the purpose of aiding or abetting any other person to evade or attempt to evade any provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="7">A professional engineer shall check and have complete dominion and control of the design and engineering work of any engineer not licensed to practice in this state. Complete dominion and control shall include possession of the sealed and signed reproducible construction documents with all supporting design calculations, indicating all changes in the design. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 30, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 25. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-15. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31453</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>