<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Jail" means county jails and correctional or detention facilities, including correctional facilities defined in KRS 67B.020 and juvenile detention facilities, operated by and under the supervision of any political subdivision. </section><section prefix="2">"Holdover" means any jail housing prisoners for a maximum period of ninety-six (96) continuous hours and excluding times when a prisoner is released for a minimum of seven (7) hours for the purpose of working at his employment, attending an educational institution, or conducting other business pursuant to a court order, or when a prisoner is released for in court proceedings. </section><section prefix="3">"Prisoner" means any person confined in jail pursuant to any code, ordinance, law, or statute of any unit of government and who is: <section prefix="a">Charged with or convicted of an offense; or </section><section prefix="b">Held for extradition or as a material witness; or </section><section prefix="c">Confined for any other reason. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Unit of government" means that unit of government including the United States government whose law, statute, ordinance, or code a prisoner is charged with violating. If a person is imprisoned for contempt of court, the state shall be deemed the responsible unit of government. </section><section prefix="5">"Department" means the Department of Corrections. </section><section prefix="6">"Jail personnel" means deputy jailers, matrons, cooks, and other food service personnel, and other jail employees involved in the supervision, custody, care, or treatment of prisoners in jails but does not include maintenance or clerical personnel. </section><section prefix="7">"Regional jail" means a jail that may house prisoners for up to one (1) year and which is: <section prefix="a">Owned and operated by one (1) county and, on a regular basis, holds prisoners for another county or for the state; or </section><section prefix="b">Owned and operated by two (2) or more counties through a regional jail authority as provided in KRS 441.800. </section></section><section prefix="8">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of the Department of Corrections. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 113, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 415, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1982; and ch. 428, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19272</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>