<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9127</section_number><catch_line>Unit boundaries.   </catch_line><order_by>9127</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If walls, floors, or ceilings are designated as boundaries of a unit, all lath, furring, wallboard, plasterboard, plaster, paneling, tiles, wallpaper, paint, finished flooring, and any other materials constituting any part of the finished surfaces thereof are a part of the unit, and all other portions of the walls, floors, or ceilings are a part of the common elements unless otherwise specified in the declaration. </section><section prefix="2">If any chute, flue, duct, wire, conduit, heating system, air conditioning system, bearing wall, bearing column, or any other fixture lies partially within and partially outside the designated boundaries of a unit, any portion thereof serving only that unit is a limited common element allocated solely to that unit, and any portion thereof serving more than one (1) unit or any portion of the common elements is a part of the common elements unless otherwise specified in the declaration. </section><section prefix="3">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, all spaces, interior partitions, and other fixtures and improvements within the boundaries of a unit are a part of the unit. </section><section prefix="4">Any shutters, awnings, window boxes, doorsteps, stoops, porches, balconies, patios, and all exterior doors and windows or other fixtures designed to serve a single unit, but located outside the unit's boundaries, are limited common elements allocated exclusively to that unit. </section><section prefix="5">Any sprinkler system, alarm system, or other system of protection that serves more than one (1) unit, unless all units served are owned by the same owner, shall be part of the common elements. </section><section prefix="6">All interior hallways, stairways, and other interior space, including all fixtures located within these spaces, that are located outside of a unit shall be limited common elements allocated exclusively to the units appurtenant to or otherwise accessible from such interior spaces. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 14, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>