<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.171</section_number><catch_line>Authority to control and manage shows and exhibitions -- Development of regulatory programs and procedures. </catch_line><order_by>171</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall have and hereby is vested with the sole direction, management, control, and jurisdiction over all boxing, sparring, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, and wrestling shows or exhibitions to be conducted, held, or given within the Commonwealth. The authority is hereby given the sole control, authority, and jurisdiction over all licenses to hold boxing, sparring, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling shows or exhibitions for prizes or purses or where an admission fee or donation is received, or a ticket or invitation is required to attend and over all licenses to any and all persons who participate in the boxing, sparring, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling shows or exhibitions. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the authority shall be responsible for the following: <section prefix="a">Developing programs and procedures which will aggressively fulfill its oversight and regulatory role, with full accountability and internal controls to protect athletes in the ring; </section><section prefix="b">Adhering to the best regulatory practices and due process procedures to protect the regulated community and the interests of the Commonwealth, and ensuring that all education and training requirements for hearing officers and members serving as hearing officers under KRS Chapter 13B are met; </section><section prefix="c">Developing the Commonwealth's goals of providing the professional staff necessary to ensure that events are effectively regulated, while allowing authority members to provide the policy oversight necessary to protect the integrity of the regulatory program; and </section><section prefix="d">Recommending changes to statutory and regulatory authorities to best protect athletes, while promoting Kentucky as a world-class market for major events. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10799</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>