<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.510</section_number><catch_line>Certificates of operation -- Renewal -- Elevator or fixed guideway system installations -- Certification of compliance -- State inspectors.   </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No certificate of operation for any passenger elevator or fixed guideway system shall be issued until the elevator or fixed guideway system has been inspected and the inspection report filed with the department. The certificate of operation, when issued, shall bear the date of inspection, and shall be renewed as of the date of the subsequent inspection, provided the inspection is made at least one (1) year after the issuance of this certificate. If the inspection is made during the year the certificate is in force, the renewal date shall be one (1) year from the date of the certificate being renewed and the renewal certificate shall show the date of inspection. </section><section prefix="2">All new elevator or fixed guideway system installations shall be performed by a licensed elevator contractor. Subsequent to installation, the elevator contractor shall certify compliance with the applicable sections of KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540. The licensed elevator contractor shall complete and submit the initial registration for each new installation. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A state inspector shall inspect, in accordance with KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540, all newly installed elevators, platform lifts, and stairway chairlifts in private residences. </section><section prefix="b">A state inspector may inspect, in accordance with KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540, any existing installed elevators, platform lifts, and stairway chairlifts in private residences at the request of the owner of the private residence. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 269, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 116, sec. 27, effective July 1, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 7; and ch. 299, sec. 82. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><former-codification> KRS 336.640. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 116, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36618</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>