<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.1242</section_number><catch_line>Local option election for limited sale of alcoholic beverages at qualified historic sites -- Petition language.   </catch_line><order_by>1242</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">To promote economic development and tourism in any dry or moist county or city in which a qualified historic site is located, a local option election for the limited sales of alcoholic beverages by the drink may be held in the precinct of the county where the qualified historic site is located, notwithstanding any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="b">A petition seeking a local option election under this section shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election under this section on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at qualified historic sites in (name of precinct)?'". </section></section><section prefix="2">A local option election for the limited sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink held under subsection (1) of this section shall be conducted in the same manner as specified in KRS 242.020; 242.030(1), (2), and (5); 242.040; and 242.060 to 242.120. The form of the proposition to be voted upon shall be "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at qualified historic sites in the (name of precinct)?". </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 560, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42447</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>