<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.452</section_number><catch_line>Intermediate license to operate a motor vehicle. </catch_line><order_by>452</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 186.415, a person who is under eighteen (18) years of age may apply for an intermediate license to operate a motor vehicle if the person has: <section prefix="a">Held an instruction permit a minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days without a violation under KRS 186.450(4), (5), or (6), a conviction for a violation of KRS 189.292 or 189.294, a conviction for a moving violation under KRS Chapter 189 for which points are assessed by the cabinet, or a conviction for a violation of KRS 189A.010(1); and </section><section prefix="b">Presented a statement to the Department of Kentucky State Police signed by a parent or guardian of the applicant attesting that the applicant has completed at least sixty (60) hours of supervised driving experience, including at least ten (10) hours at night, while accompanied by a person who has attained the age of twenty-one (21) years and holds a valid operator's license occupying the seat beside the applicant. </section></section><section prefix="2">If an applicant for an intermediate license successfully completes the examinations required under KRS 186.480, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall affix an intermediate license sticker to the instruction permit and report the applicant's new status to the Transportation Cabinet. The Transportation Cabinet shall update the information in its computer system to reflect that the applicant has been granted an intermediate license. An intermediate license shall be valid for two (2) years and may be renewed. </section><section prefix="3">A person shall have the intermediate license in his or her possession at all times when operating a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="4">A person with an intermediate license who is under the age of eighteen (18) years shall not operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped between the hours of 12 midnight and 6 a.m. unless the person can demonstrate good cause for driving, including emergencies, involvement in school-related activities, or involvement in work-related activities. </section><section prefix="5">Except when accompanied by a driver training instructor affiliated with a driver training school licensed under KRS Chapter 332 or a public or nonpublic secondary school, a person with an intermediate license who is under the age of eighteen (18) years shall not operate a motor vehicle at any time when accompanied by more than one (1) unrelated person who is under the age of twenty (20) years. A peace officer shall not stop or seize a person nor issue a uniform citation for a violation of this subsection if the officer has no other cause to stop or seize the person other than a violation of this subsection. This subsection shall not apply to any operator of a vehicle registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(4) who is engaged in agricultural activities. </section><section prefix="6">A violation under subsection (3), (4), or (5) of this section, a conviction for a moving violation under KRS Chapter 189 for which points are assessed by the cabinet, or a conviction for a violation of KRS 189A.010(1) shall add an additional minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of the violation before a person who is under the age of eighteen (18) years may apply for an operator's license. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 194, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>