<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.802</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Office of Agritourism. </catch_line><order_by>802</order_by><text>The Office of Agritourism shall perform all duties necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 247.800 to 247.810, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Within the first year of its creation, developing a statewide master plan for implementation of KRS 247.800 and this section. The Office of Agritourism shall report on the plan to the Agritourism Advisory Council at the request of the council; </section><section prefix="2">Developing a unified Kentucky agritourism marketing strategy between the Department of Agriculture and the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet to promote Kentucky agritourism. The strategy shall include but not be limited to promotion of Kentucky agritourism through the creation of an agritourism Web site and advertisement through various media outlets; </section><section prefix="3">Coordinating efforts to educate the general public about the importance of Kentucky's agricultural heritage and industry; </section><section prefix="4">Developing regional agritourism development plans for each of the nine (9) tourism regions as follows: <section prefix="a">Bluegrass; </section><section prefix="b">Cave; </section><section prefix="c">Green River; </section><section prefix="d">Eastern Highlands-North; </section><section prefix="e">Eastern Highlands-South; </section><section prefix="f">Louisville-Lincoln; </section><section prefix="g">Northern Kentucky; </section><section prefix="h">Southern Lakes and Rivers; and </section><section prefix="i">Western Lakes and Rivers; </section></section><section prefix="5">Providing support, education, and resource materials for all interested persons, to include but not be limited to existing Kentucky agritourism businesses, displaced tobacco farmers and others engaged in agribusiness within the state, and other Kentuckians with the intent of developing an agritourism business. The agritourism office shall provide this assistance in the following areas, to include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Agritourism opportunities, networks, product development, and entrepreneurship; </section><section prefix="b">Agritourism funding opportunities, including but not limited to grants, loans, and partnerships; and </section><section prefix="c">Insurance and infrastructure concerns of the agritourism industry; </section></section><section prefix="6">Working and partnering with federal, state, and local organizations to carry out the purposes of KRS 247.800 to 247.810; </section><section prefix="7">Reporting to the Agritourism Advisory Council, as created in KRS 247.804, annually or at the request of the chair, and in accordance with subsection (1) of this section; and </section><section prefix="8">Considering the recommendations of the Agritourism Advisory Council, in accordance with KRS 247.806(2). </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 64, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 49, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>