<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.100</section_number><catch_line>Persons to whom KRS Chapter 319B does not apply. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>This chapter shall not apply to: <section prefix="1">The practice of orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics by a person who is employed by the federal government or any bureau, division, or agency of the federal government while in the discharge of the employee's official duties; </section><section prefix="2">The practice of orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics by: <section prefix="a">A student enrolled in a school of orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics; </section><section prefix="b">A resident continuing his or her clinical education in a residency accredited by CAAHEP or NCOPE; </section><section prefix="c">A student in a qualified work experience program or internship in pedorthics; or </section><section prefix="d">A physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311; or </section></section><section prefix="3">The measuring, fitting, or adjusting of an orthotic device by an employee or authorized representative of an orthosis manufacturer registered with the federal food and drug administration, when the employee or representative is directly supervised by a licensed health care professional authorized by law to prescribe, measure, or fit the device, and the measuring, fitting, or adjusting of the device occurs in the office of the licensed health care professional or in a health care facility. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31286</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>