<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.190</section_number><catch_line>Information furnished to board by providers -- Run report form -- Annual reports -- Confidentiality -- Report to medical facility, ambulance provider, and patient -- Records -- Disclosure and admissibility of data and records. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each licensed ambulance provider and medical first response provider as defined in this chapter shall collect and provide to the board run data and information required by the board by this chapter and administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall develop a run report form for the use of each class of ambulance provider and medical first response provider containing the data required in subsection (1) of this section. An ambulance provider or medical first response provider may utilize any run form it chooses in lieu of or in addition to the board developed run report form. However, the data captured on the run report form shall include at least that required by the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">An ambulance provider or medical first response provider shall report the required run report data and information by completing an annual report as established by the board or by transmitting the required data and information to the board in an electronic format. If the board requires the use of a specific electronic format, it shall provide a copy of the file layout requirements, in either written or electronic format, to the licensed ambulance provider or medical first response provider at no charge. </section><section prefix="4">The board may publish a comprehensive annual report reflecting the data collected, injury and illness data, treatment utilized, and other information deemed important by the board. The annual report shall not include patient identifying information or any other information identifying a natural person. A copy of the comprehensive annual report, if issued, shall be forwarded to the Governor and the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="5">Ambulance provider and medical first response provider run report forms and the information transmitted electronically to the board shall be confidential. No person shall make an unauthorized release of information on an ambulance run report form or medical first response run report form. Only the patient or the patient's parent or legal guardian if the patient is a minor, or the patient's legal guardian or person with proper power of attorney if the patient is under legal disability as being incompetent or mentally ill, or a court of competent jurisdiction may authorize the release of information on a patient's run report form or the inspection or copying of the run report form. Any authorization for the release of information or for inspection or copying of a run report form shall be in writing. </section><section prefix="6">If a medical first response provider or ambulance provider does not use a paper form but collects patient data through electronic means, it shall have the means of providing a written run report that includes all required data elements to the medical care facility. A copy of the medical first response form or a summary of the run data and patient information shall be made available to the ambulance service that transports the patient. A copy of the ambulance run report form shall be made available to any medical care facility to which a patient is transported and shall be included in the patient's medical record by that facility. If a patient is not transported to a medical facility, the copy of the run report form that is to be given to the transporting ambulance provider or medical care facility shall be given to the patient or to the patient's parent or legal guardian. If the ambulance provider, medical facility, patient, or patient's legal guardian refuses delivery of their run report form or is unavailable to receive the form, that copy of the form shall be returned to the medical first response provider or ambulance provider and destroyed. </section><section prefix="7">All ambulance services shall be required to keep adequate reports and records to be maintained at the ambulance base headquarters and to be available for periodic review as deemed necessary by the board. Required records and reports are as follows: <section prefix="a">Employee records, including a resume of each employee's training and experience and evidence of current certification; and </section><section prefix="b">Health records of all drivers and attendants including records of all illnesses or accidents occurring while on duty. </section></section><section prefix="8">Data and records generated and kept by the board or its contractors regarding the evaluation of emergency medical care and trauma care in the Commonwealth, including the identities of patients, emergency medical services personnel, ambulance providers, medical first-response providers, and emergency medical facilities, shall be confidential, shall not be subject to disclosure under KRS 61.805 to 61.850 or KRS 61.870 to 61.884, shall not be admissible in court for any purpose, and shall not be subject to discovery. However, nothing in this section shall limit the discoverability or admissibility of patient medical records regularly and ordinarily kept in the course of a patient's treatment that otherwise would be admissible or discoverable. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 36, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>