<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.812</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 387.810 to 387.854. </catch_line><order_by>812</order_by><text>As used in KRS 387.810 to 387.854: <section prefix="1">"Adult" means an individual who has attained eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="2">"Conservator" means a person appointed by the court to administer the property of an adult, including a person appointed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="3">"Guardian" means a person appointed by the court to make decisions regarding the person of an adult, including a person appointed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="4">"Guardianship order" means an order appointing a guardian; </section><section prefix="5">"Guardianship proceeding" means a judicial proceeding in which an order for the appointment of a guardian is sought or has been issued; </section><section prefix="6">"Incapacitated person" means an adult for whom a guardian has been appointed; </section><section prefix="7">"Party" means the respondent, petitioner, guardian, conservator, or any other person allowed by the court to participate in a guardianship or protective proceeding; </section><section prefix="8">"Person," except in the term "incapacitated person" or "protected person," means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity; </section><section prefix="9">"Protected person" means an adult for whom a protective order has been issued; </section><section prefix="10">"Protective order" means an order appointing a conservator or other order related to management of an adult's property; </section><section prefix="11">"Protective proceeding" means a judicial proceeding in which a protective order is sought or has been issued; </section><section prefix="12">"Record" means information that is inscribed on a tangible medium or that is stored in an electronic or other medium and is retrievable in perceivable form; </section><section prefix="13">"Respondent" means an adult for whom a protective order or the appointment of a guardian is sought; and </section><section prefix="14">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, a federally recognized Indian tribe, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39703</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>