<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.400</section_number><catch_line>Child victims' trust fund -- Limitation on disbursement. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The child victims' trust fund is created as a separate fund in the office of the State Treasurer. The fund shall be expended only as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The State Treasurer shall credit to the trust fund all amounts received for this purpose and any amounts received under KRS 141.440. </section><section prefix="3">The State Treasurer shall invest trust fund money in the same manner as surplus funds are invested. Earnings shall be credited to the trust fund. </section><section prefix="4">Until the total amount of assets in the trust fund exceeds twenty million dollars ($20,000,000), not more than one-half of the money contributed to the trust fund each year, plus the earnings credited to the trust fund during the previous fiscal year, and the money earned by the sale of child victims' trust fund license plates pursuant to KRS Chapter 186, shall be available for disbursement upon the authorization of the state board as provided in KRS 15.935. After such time that the State Treasurer certifies that the assets in the trust fund exceed twenty million dollars ($20,000,000), only the earnings credited to the trust fund shall be available for disbursement upon the authorization of the state board as provided in KRS 15.935. </section><section prefix="5">Funds granted or funds received as gifts or donations to the child victims' trust fund shall be available for disbursement upon appropriation by the General Assembly, and funds authorized for expenditure shall not be considered assets for purposes of subsection (4) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>