<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.715</section_number><catch_line>Burial rights in cemetery lots -- Abandonment -- Resale by cemetery. </catch_line><order_by>715</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "cemetery lot" is a lot containing one (1) or more grave spaces and located within a cemetery registered pursuant to KRS 367.946 in a county containing an urban-county government or in a city. </section><section prefix="2">An officer of the cemetery may cause to be filed, on behalf of the cemetery, an action in the Circuit Court of the county where the cemetery is located requesting that the burial rights in the unused portion of the lots in question be deemed abandoned and that the cemetery be authorized to sell the rights upon entry of the court's judgment. The defendants in the action shall be the unknown heirs of the original owner of the burial rights in the lots in question. </section><section prefix="3">The petition shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The name of the original owner of the burial rights in the lots in question. </section><section prefix="b">The name of all persons buried in the lots and the date of burial, if known. </section><section prefix="c">The name, address, and telephone number of the cemetery office. </section><section prefix="d">An affidavit by the petitioner that: <section prefix="1">No person has been buried in the cemetery lots in question for a period of at least one hundred (100) years; and </section><section prefix="2">The identity of any owner of the burial rights in the lot in question or any heir of the owner is unknown to any officer or employee of the cemetery and not discoverable after a good faith attempt by an officer or employee to identify the owner or heir. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Service of process shall be by warning order attorney, appointed by the court pursuant to CR 4.07. </section><section prefix="5">If the court finds the allegations set forth in paragraph (d) of subsection (3) of this section to be true, the court shall enter judgment deeming the burial rights in the lots in question abandoned and authorizing the cemetery to sell the rights. </section><section prefix="6">No judgment shall be entered declaring burial rights abandoned if an owner or heir of a cemetery lot has filed with the cemetery a statement in writing directing that certain grave spaces not be used. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35483</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>