<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.090</section_number><catch_line>County clerk's entry of information into automated vehicle information system -- Report, application and fees to Transportation Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county clerk shall enter information relating to the registration and titling of boats into the automated vehicle information system. This information shall include the name and address of those persons who have applied for title and registration of motorboats, the length and type of the motorboat, and the title and registration fee charged, and the amount of title and registration fee collected from the applicant. The applications for title and registration and the fees collected by the clerk shall be forwarded to the Transportation Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall submit a weekly report of all transactions involving boat titling and registration transactions to the Transportation Cabinet. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 21, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 8. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 9, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11053</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>