<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.125</section_number><catch_line>Permanency hearing after custody given to Department of Juvenile Justice or cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a child has been removed from the home and placed in the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet, a judge of the District Court shall conduct a permanency hearing no later than twelve (12) months after the date the child is considered to have entered foster care, and every twelve (12) months thereafter if custody and out-of-home placement continues, to determine the future status of the child. For purposes of this section, a child shall be considered to have entered foster care on the earlier of the date of the first judicial finding that the child has been subjected to child abuse or neglect or the date that is sixty (60) days after the date on which the child is removed from the home. <section prefix="a">If parental rights have not been terminated, whether the child should be </section><section prefix="b">Whether the child should be placed for adoption; </section><section prefix="c">Whether the child should be placed with a permanent custodian; and </section><section prefix="d">Whether the cabinet has documented a compelling reason that it is in the best </section></section> The court shall address the following areas: returned to the parent; interest of the child to be placed in another planned permanent living arrangement other than those listed in this subsection. <section prefix="2">If the cabinet or the Department of Juvenile Justice determines that reasonable efforts to reunify the child with the child's parent will not be made, the cabinet or Department of Juvenile Justice shall file a case permanency plan as defined by KRS 620.230 or case progress report with the court that documents the reasons for not making reasonable efforts. The court shall hold a permanency hearing within thirty (30) days of the filing of the cabinet's or Department of Juvenile Justice's plan or report with the Court. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall inform the court not less than sixty (60) days prior to the expiration of the time in which the hearing shall be held and within the time established in subsection (1) of this section, and shall further inform the court of the name and address of the child's foster parents, preadoptive parents, or relatives providing care to the child; court-appointed special advocate; and foster care review board member assigned to the case. For the hearing to be held pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, the names and addresses of the persons identified in this subsection shall be provided in the case permanency plan or case progress report to be filed with the court. The court shall set a time for the hearing and notify the child's parent, foster parents, preadoptive parents, or relatives providing care to the child and who also shall have a right to be heard; court-appointed special advocate; foster care review board member assigned to the case; attorney for the child; attorney for the parent, if any; and the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall present evidence to the court concerning the care and progress of the child since the last permanency hearing, including the following: <section prefix="a">The length of time the child has been committed to the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">The number, location, and date for each placement during the total period of the child's commitment; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the services and assistance provided to the parent or arranged by the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet since the last case permanency plan or case progress report, and the results achieved; </section><section prefix="d">A description of the efforts and progress of the child's parent since the last case permanency plan and case progress report, including the number and dates of parental visits and the extent, quality, and frequency of the parent's communication with the child; </section><section prefix="e">The familial and institutional barriers to: <section prefix="1">Returning the child to the home; </section><section prefix="2">Ending the commitment of the child to the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="3">Delivery of appropriate services needed by the child; </section></section><section prefix="f">Recommendations of services needed to make the transition from out-of-home care to independent living for children who have reached the age of sixteen (16) years; </section><section prefix="g">An evaluation of the child's current placement and services provided to the child; </section><section prefix="h">Recommendations for necessary services required to terminate the commitment of the child to the cabinet, to return the child home, or to facilitate another permanent placement; and </section><section prefix="i">Recommendations as to the permanency goal for the child. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The child's parent, foster parent, preadoptive parent, or relative providing care to the child shall have the right to be heard; and </section><section prefix="b">The attorney for the parent, attorney for the child, or court-appointed special advocate, if deemed appropriate by the court, may present any evidence relevant to the determination of a permanency goal for the child. </section></section><section prefix="6">Upon conclusion of the hearing the court shall make a written order determining the permanency plan for the child. </section><section prefix="7">If necessary, the case may be redocketed for further review of the progress toward the implementation of the permanency plan established at the permanency hearing. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 8, effective March 17, 1998; and ch. 398, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 26, effective July 1, 1997. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 489, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42301</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>