<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-400</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 154.20-400 to 154.20-420.   </catch_line><order_by>20-400</order_by><text>As used in KRS 154.20-400 to 154.20-420: <section prefix="1">"Alternative fuels" means: <section prefix="a">Alternative transportation fuels as defined in KRS 152.715; </section><section prefix="b">Synthetic natural gas as defined in KRS 152.715; </section><section prefix="c">Biodiesel produced from biomass resources as defined in KRS 152.715 that is used for purposes other than transportation fuel; </section><section prefix="d">Ethanol as defined in KRS 141.422; </section><section prefix="e">Cellulosic ethanol as defined in KRS 141.422; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other fuel that is produced from a renewable or sustainable source; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Eligible company" means any corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, business trust, person, group, city, county, charter county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, or unified local government entity, or other entity engaged in research and development and commercialization related to, or the production of, alternative fuels or renewable energy; </section><section prefix="3">"Kentucky-based" means a business with its principal place of business in Kentucky or at least fifty-one percent (51%) of its property and payroll located in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">"Qualified company" means an eligible company that may be granted funding pending final approval; </section><section prefix="5">"Renewable energy" means electricity produced by hydropower, solar power, landfill methane gas, wind power, geothermal, biomass, or other renewable sources; and </section><section prefix="6">"Science and technology organization" means an independent, nonprofit quasi-governmental organization with a statewide mission and demonstrated history of managing complicated programs in the areas of entrepreneurial innovation, research and development, and science and technology advancement. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 45, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42406</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>