<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.625</section_number><catch_line>Liability insurance -- Prerequisite for license. </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before any license will be issued or renewed, the applicant shall file or have on file with the department a liability insurance policy issued by an insurance carrier authorized to transact insurance business within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The policy of insurance must be issued in the name of the applicant licensee. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall by regulation establish the minimum amount of liability insurance required herein. </section><section prefix="3">No insurance carrier issuing any policy filed with the department shall be relieved from liability under the policy until after the expiration of fifteen (15) days' notice to the department of an intention to cancel the policy, provided, however, that a prior cancellation may be allowed in cases where one (1) policy is substituted for another policy when the substituted policy is in force and effect prior to the expiration of fifteen (15) days' notice to the department of an intention to cancel the policy which is being substituted. </section><section prefix="4">Upon cancellation of any policy of insurance required by this section, all operating rights granted by the license for which the said policy was filed, shall immediately cease and the department shall have the authority to immediately require the cessation of all operations conducted under the authority of the said license and to require the surrender of all licenses, certificates, and seals previously issued hereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 421, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10688</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>