<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.794</section_number><catch_line>Reading Diagnostic and Intervention Grant Steering Committee -- Membership -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>794</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Reading Diagnostic and Intervention Grant Steering Committee is hereby created for the purpose of advising the Kentucky Board of Education and the Department of Education concerning the implementation and administration of the reading diagnostic and intervention fund created in KRS 158.792. The committee shall be composed of sixteen (16) members including the commissioner of education or the commissioner's designee, the executive director of the Collaborative Center for Literacy Development, the president of the Council on Postsecondary Education or the president's designee, and the following members, to be appointed by the Governor: <section prefix="a">Four (4) primary program teachers with a specialty or background in reading and literacy; </section><section prefix="b">Four (4) university or college professors with a specialty or background in reading and literacy representing universities; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) elementary school principal; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) certified library media specialist; and </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) individuals from the state at large with an interest in reading and literacy. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each member of the committee, other than members who serve by virtue of their position, shall serve for a term of three (3) years or until a successor is appointed, except that upon initial appointment, five (5) members shall serve a one (1) year term, four (4) members shall serve a two (2) year term, and four (4) members shall serve a three (3) year term. </section><section prefix="3">A majority of the full authorized membership shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall elect, by majority vote, a chair, who shall be the presiding officer of the committee, preside at all meetings, and coordinate the functions and activities of the committee. The chair shall be elected or reelected each calendar year. </section><section prefix="5">The committee shall be attached to the Department of Education for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="6">The committee shall: <section prefix="a">Identify needs, trends, and issues in schools throughout the state regarding reading and literacy programs; </section><section prefix="b">Make recommendations regarding the content of administrative regulations to be promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education under KRS 158.792; </section><section prefix="c">Recommend approval of grant applications based upon the provisions of KRS 158.792 and administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education as required under KRS 158.792; and </section><section prefix="d">Advise the Kentucky Board of Education and the Department of Education regarding costs and effectiveness of various reading intervention programs. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 4, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 580, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 18, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, which included an amendment to this section, KRS 158.794, provides that the Act shall be cited as the "Read to Achieve Act of 2005." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3590</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>