<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.046</section_number><catch_line>Adjunct instructors. </catch_line><order_by>046</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, "adjunct instructor" means an individual who has training or experience in a specific subject area and who has met the requirements for certification as an adjunct instructor established by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="2">The Education Professional Standards Board shall adopt administrative regulations governing the qualifications and utilization of adjunct instructors. These administrative regulations shall specify the minimum essential competencies which must be demonstrated by persons seeking an adjunct instructor certificate. </section><section prefix="3">Holders of an adjunct instructor certificate shall be employed on an annual contract basis and shall not be eligible for continuing service status pursuant to KRS 161.740 or for the retirement provisions of KRS 161.220 through 161.714, except that the return to work limitations set forth in KRS 161.605 shall apply to any retired member of the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System who resumes employment as an adjunct instructor. The granting of successive annual contracts to the holder of an adjunct instructor certificate shall not give rise to a claim of expectation of continuing employment. </section><section prefix="4">Local school boards may contract with certificated adjunct instructors for part-time services on an hourly, daily, or other periodic basis as best meets the needs of the board. An adjunct instructor shall not fill a position that will result in the displacement of a qualified teacher with a regular certificate who is already employed in the district. </section><section prefix="5">An orientation program shall be developed and implemented for adjunct instructors by the local school board. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 24, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 589, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 61, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43294</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>