<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.130</section_number><catch_line>In-service training -- Records -- Penalties -- Board recognition of training. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The conduct of proper in-service training, including but not limited to in-house in-service training, in accordance with the standards specified by this chapter, administrative regulations, and the standards of relevant United States Department of Transportation curricula shall be that of the provider of the in-service training. </section><section prefix="2">If in-service training is conducted by an ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution, the organization, the instructor, and its medical director share responsibility for the provision of training which meets or exceeds the requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Persons and organizations providing in-service training for first responders, emergency medical technicians, or paramedics shall keep the records required by the board by administrative regulation and shall make them available to a representative of the board upon request. </section><section prefix="4">Failure to keep a record required by the board by administrative regulation or required to be kept by statute, falsifying a record, or grossly negligently maintaining a record required to be kept by administrative regulation or statute shall be subject to action by the office of the board. </section><section prefix="5">Providing in-service training not meeting or exceeding the requirements specified in subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall be subject to action of the office of the board. </section><section prefix="6">Penalties specified in this section shall be in addition to any action which the board may be permitted to take against the license or certification of any person or organization. </section><section prefix="7">The board may refuse to recognize any in-service training not conducted in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, United States Department of Transportation curricula, or administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter. If the board determines that in-service training will not be accepted, the denial of credit shall be extended to all persons who completed that specific in-service training. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30743</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>