<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="26" order_by="26">A COURT OF JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>26A.400</section_number><catch_line>Drug court program -- Administration -- No right to treatment conferred -- Exemption from division supervision while in program.   </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires, "drug court program" means any drug court program authorized and administered by the Kentucky Supreme Court. </section><section prefix="2">The Supreme Court of Kentucky shall administer the drug court program to: <section prefix="a">Develop standards, establish program eligibility, and provide oversight for operation for drug court programs; </section><section prefix="b">Define, develop, and gather outcome measures for drug court programs; </section><section prefix="c">Collect, report, and disseminate drug court data; </section><section prefix="d">Sponsor and coordinate state drug court training; and </section><section prefix="e">Apply for, administer, and evaluate any grant for drug court purposes. </section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing contained in this section shall confer a right or an expectation of a right to treatment for an offender within the criminal justice system or the juvenile justice system. </section><section prefix="4">If a defendant has been accepted into the drug court program and is supervised by that program as a condition of probation, the defendant shall not be subject to the supervision of the Division of Probation and Parole during his or her participation in the drug court program. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 25, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40912</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>