<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.240</section_number><catch_line>Case progress reports. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text>The cabinet shall file for each child a case progress report at least once every six (6) months with the court and the Administrative Office of the Courts Citizen Foster Care Review Board Program. The first case progress report after the child is placed in the custody of the cabinet by an order of temporary custody or commitment shall be mailed to the Administrative Office of the Courts Citizen Foster Care Review Board Program and subsequent case progress reports shall be provided to the local citizen foster care review board within the case file. The case progress report shall include but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">The length of time the child has been in the custody of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">The number, location, and date for each placement during the time the child has been in the custody of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the services and assistance provided or arranged by the cabinet to the parents since the last case permanency plan or case progress report, and results achieved; </section><section prefix="4">A description of the efforts and progress of the parents since the last case permanency plan and case progress report, including the number and dates of parental visits and the extent, quality, and frequency of the parents' communication with the child; </section><section prefix="5">The barriers, familial and institutional, to returning the child home or releasing the child from the custody of the cabinet and services that are not currently available in the community; </section><section prefix="6">An evaluation of the child's current placement and services provided to the child; </section><section prefix="7">Recommendations for necessary services required to release the child from the custody of the cabinet, to return the child home, or to facilitate another permanent placement; </section><section prefix="8">A timetable for the child's return home or other permanent placement; and </section><section prefix="9">If return home is not recommended, a specific recommendation for a permanent placement, including termination of parental rights if appropriate. If continued foster care is recommended, an explanation as to why another permanent placement is not appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 60, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 85, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20213</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>