<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-080</section_number><catch_line>Reinstatement. </catch_line><order_by>17-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a provision as follows: </section>  "Reinstatement: If any renewal premium be not paid within the time granted the insured for payment, a subsequent acceptance of premium by the insurer or by any agent duly authorized by the insurer to accept such premium, without requiring in connection therewith an application for reinstatement, shall reinstate the policy: provided, however, that if the insurer or such agent requires an application for reinstatement and issues a conditional receipt for the premium tendered, the policy will be reinstated upon approval of such application by the insurer or, lacking such approval, upon the forty-fifth day following the date of such conditional receipt unless the insurer has previously notified the insured in writing of its disapproval of such application. The reinstated policy shall cover only loss resulting from such accidental injury as may be sustained after the date of reinstatement and loss due to such sickness as may begin more than ten (10) days after such date. In all other respects the insured and insurer shall have the same rights thereunder as they had under the policy immediately before the due date of the defaulted premium, subject to any provisions indorsed hereon or attached hereto in connection with the reinstatement. Any premium accepted in connection with a reinstatement shall be applied to a period for which premium has not been previously paid, but not to any period more than sixty (60) days prior to the date of reinstatement." <section prefix="2">The last sentence of the provision contained in subsection (1) of this section may be omitted from any policy which the insured has the right to continue in force subject to its terms by the timely payment of premiums (a) until at least age fifty (50) or, (b) in the case of a policy issued after age forty-four (44), for at least five (5) years from its date of issue. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 17, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17294</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>