<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.071</section_number><catch_line>License requirement for shows and exhibitions -- Fees -- License preference to Kentucky residents. </catch_line><order_by>071</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall conduct or advertise a show or exhibition without a promoter license issued by the authority to conduct the show. Show dates shall be approved as determined in administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall provide training for such a show or exhibition in this state without a promoter license approved by the authority. </section><section prefix="3">If, in the judgment of the authority, the financial responsibility, experience, character, and general fitness of an applicant, including in the case of corporations its officers and stockholders, are such that the participation of the applicant will be consistent with the public interest, convenience, or necessity and with the best interests of boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling generally and in conformity with the purposes of this chapter, the authority may grant an annual license in accordance with the provisions of subsections (4), (5), and (6) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The annual license fee shall be established by the authority by promulgation of administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="5">No person may be issued an annual license unless he or she has been a resident of Kentucky for sixty (60) days prior to the issuance thereof, or in the case of a corporation, unless it has qualified to do business in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="6">In determining which applicant may be granted a license to conduct a boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling show, the authority shall give preference to Kentucky residents and domestic corporations. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10778</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>