<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="600" order_by="600">INTRODUCTORY MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>600.050</section_number><catch_line>Designation and documentation of commitment of children needing protection or needing extraordinary services. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">A child is deemed to need extraordinary services if the child is mentally or emotionally ill or has symptoms of mental or emotional illness and requires medical attention, and the child's parent, guardian, or other person exercising custodial control or supervision over the child is unable to provide for the required treatment, care, or supervision of the child, and: <section prefix="1">The inability is due primarily to the lack of financial means of the child's parent, guardian, or other person exercising custodial control or supervision unless assistance has been offered and rejected; </section><section prefix="2">The child's parent, guardian, or other person exercising custodial control or supervision has made a reasonable effort under the circumstances to meet the needs of the child; </section><section prefix="3">The inability is not due to a willful act of commission or act of omission by the child's parent, guardian, or other person exercising custodial control or supervision; and </section><section prefix="4">Commitment is not opposed by the parent, guardian, or other person exercising custodial control or supervision; and </section></section><section prefix="b">A child is deemed to need protection if the court determines the child is a dependent, abused, or neglected child and the needs of the child do not meet the definition of a child in need of extraordinary services. </section></section><section prefix="2">For children committed under KRS 620.140 after July 15, 1998, the court shall designate in the court order of commitment and the cabinet shall document in the official case file records showing whether the commitment is due to the child needing protection or the child needing extraordinary services. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20106</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>