<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="514" order_by="514">THEFT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>514.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Deprive" means: <section prefix="a">To withhold property of another permanently or for so extended a period as to appropriate a major portion of its economic value or with intent to restore only upon payment of reward or other compensation; or </section><section prefix="b">To dispose of the property so as to make it unlikely that the owner will recover it. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Financial institution" means a bank, insurance company, credit union, building and loan association, savings and loan association, investment trust or other organization held out to the public as a place of deposit of funds or medium of savings or collective investment. </section><section prefix="3">"Movable property" means property the location of which can be changed, including things growing on, affixed to, or found in land, and documents although the rights represented thereby have no physical location. "Immovable property" is all other property. </section><section prefix="4">"Obtain" means: <section prefix="a">In relation to property, to bring about a transfer or purported transfer from another person of a legal interest in the property, whether to the obtainer or another; or </section><section prefix="b">In relation to labor or service, to secure performance thereof. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Propelled vehicle" means any vehicle, including but not limited to motor vehicles, aircraft, boats, or construction machinery, which is propelled otherwise than by muscle power or which is readily capable of being towed otherwise than by muscle power. </section><section prefix="6">"Property" means anything of value, including real estate, tangible and intangible personal property, contract rights, documents, choses-in-action and other interests in or claims to wealth, admission or transportation tickets, captured or domestic animals, food and drink. </section><section prefix="7">"Property of another" includes property in which any person other than the actor has an interest which the actor is not privileged to infringe, regardless of the fact that the actor also has an interest in the property and regardless of the fact that the other person might be precluded from civil recovery because the property was used in an unlawful transaction or was subject to forfeiture as contraband. Property in possession of the actor shall not be deemed property of another who has only a security interest therein, even if legal title is in the creditor pursuant to a conditional sales contract or other security arrangement. </section><section prefix="8">"Receiving" means acquiring possession, control or title or lending on the security of the property. </section><section prefix="9">"Services" includes labor, professional service, transportation, telephone, electricity, gas, water or other public service, accommodation in hotels, restaurants or elsewhere, admission to exhibitions, use of vehicles or other movable property. </section><section prefix="10">"Tax liability" for purposes of this chapter means the amount of money by which a person understates the total amount of taxes due or collected and not remitted to the Commonwealth, or the amount he fails to pay to the state, or both. Any person whose income is subject to the withholding of income tax and from whose income taxes are withheld shall be considered, for purposes of this chapter, to have paid to the Commonwealth the sum of money withheld, whether or not such sum withheld is paid to the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="11">"Tax return" means any return, declaration, report or form issued or prescribed by the Department of Revenue and required to be filed with the Department of Revenue as prescribed by law. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 698, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 117, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19802</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>