<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-844</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited activities -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>17A-844</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After a hearing or upon agreement by the self-insured employer-organized association group, the commissioner may suspend or revoke the certificate of filing of a self-insured employer-organized association group, impose a civil penalty of up to five thousand dollars ($5,000) per violation on a self-insured employer-organized association group, or both, for: <section prefix="a">Violations of KRS 304.17A-800 to 304.17A-844 or administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="b">Obtaining a certificate of filing by unfair or deceptive means; </section><section prefix="c">Operating in a financially hazardous manner; </section><section prefix="d">Misappropriation, conversion, illegal withholding, or refusal to pay over upon proper demand any moneys that belong to a member, an employee of a member, or a person otherwise entitled thereto by the group or its administrator; or </section><section prefix="e">Unfair or deceptive business practices. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner, in his or her discretion and without advance notice or a hearing thereon, may suspend or revoke the certificate of filing of any self-insured employer-organized association group upon the commencement of the following proceedings: <section prefix="a">Receivership; </section><section prefix="b">Conservatorship; </section><section prefix="c">Rehabilitation; or </section><section prefix="d">Other delinquency proceedings. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1271, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 23, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29383</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>