<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159">COMPULSORY ATTENDANCE </unit></structure><section_number>159.150</section_number><catch_line>Definitions of truant and habitual truant -- Attendance record requirements -- Adoption of truancy policies by local school boards -- Implementation of early intervention and prevention programs.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any student who has attained the age of six (6) years, but has not reached his or her eighteenth birthday, who has been absent from school without valid excuse for three (3) or more days, or tardy without valid excuse on three (3) or more days, is a truant. </section><section prefix="2">Any student enrolled in a public school who has attained the age of eighteen (18) years, but has not reached his or her twenty-first birthday, who has been absent from school without valid excuse for three (3) or more days, or tardy without valid excuse on three (3) or more days, is a truant. </section><section prefix="3">Any student who has been reported as a truant two (2) or more times is an habitual truant. </section><section prefix="4">For the purposes of establishing a student's status as a truant, the student's attendance record is cumulative for an entire school year. If a student transfers from one (1) Kentucky public school to another during a school year, the receiving school shall incorporate the attendance information provided under KRS 159.170 in the student's official attendance record. </section><section prefix="5">A local board of education may adopt reasonable policies that: <section prefix="a">Require students to comply with compulsory attendance laws; </section><section prefix="b">Require truants and habitual truants to make up unexcused absences; </section><section prefix="c">Impose sanctions for noncompliance; and </section><section prefix="d">Collaborate and cooperate with the Court of Justice, the Department for Community Based Services, the Department of Juvenile Justice, regional community mental health centers, and other service providers to implement and utilize early intervention and prevention programs, such as truancy diversion, truancy boards, mediation, and alternative dispute resolution to reduce referrals to a court-designated worker. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 15, effective July 1, 2015. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 611, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 413, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4434-14. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43959</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>