<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.580</section_number><catch_line>Expiration of permit -- Extensions. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each permit issued under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall expire one (1) year after the date issued, unless the drilling, deepening, or reopening of a well is commenced pursuant thereto prior to the expiration of the one (1) year period. However, the permit term shall be extended by one (1) year if, prior to the expiration date, the permit applicant notifies the department in writing of the applicant's request for an extension, notifies the owner, record coal lessee, or mine licensee originally entitled to receive a copy of the plat under KRS 353.050, submits an affidavit stating that the information in the original permit application is still correct, and submits a fee for the extension in an amount equal to the permit fee required by KRS 353.590. With respect to permits issued prior to July 15, 2002, no extension shall be granted for any permit in cases where there has been a complete severance of the ownership of the oil and gas from the ownership of the surface to be disturbed, unless the requested extension is agreed to in writing by the surface owner. </section><section prefix="2">The extension of the permit term pursuant to subsection (1) of this section shall not create a right to object to the well location under KRS 353.060 nor to mediation under KRS 353.5901. </section><section prefix="3">All permits issued by the department under any previous statute shall continue in force as written, only if the drilling of the well has been commenced pursuant thereto on or before sixty (60) days after June 16, 1960. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 10, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>