<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.120</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of recreational commission -- Members -- Terms -- Removal -- Vacancies -- Rules and regulations -- Revenues -- Fees -- Compliance with KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090.   </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In cities of the first class and in cities with populations equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, the city recreational committee shall consist of not less than three (3) nor more than seven (7) members, the exact number to be at the discretion of the city legislative body. In cities with populations of less than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, the city recreational committee shall consist of three (3) members. <section prefix="a">In cities of any class the city recreational committee shall be appointed by the mayor, with the approval of a majority of the members of the legislative body of the city, for terms of four (4) years, except that the members first appointed shall be so appointed that the terms of the members will expire in different years. </section><section prefix="b">The members shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="c">The members shall be legal voters of the city. </section><section prefix="d">If any member during the term of his or her office becomes a candidate for, or is elected or appointed to any public office, he or she shall automatically vacate his membership on the commission and another person shall be appointed in his or her place; but this provision shall not prevent a member of the commission from serving as a member of any other appointive commission of the city, county, state or federal government. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any member of the commission may be removed by the vote of three-fourths (3/4) of the elected members of the city legislative body. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as in the original appointment. The city may require each commissioner to execute a bond in the penal sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000). If the commissioners are required to execute bonds, the bonds shall be approved by the legislative body of the city, and the cost thereof may either be paid by the city or by the commission out of its revenue. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall provide rules and regulations for the management of the recreational project or projects, and out of the revenue derived from the project or projects it shall pay all operating expenses, provide for necessary repairs and additions, provide a sufficient reserve fund to insure the buildings and improvements against fire and tornado, provide a fund for payment of any incidental or emergency expenses that may arise, and set up a fund to provide for the payment of any debts created in connection with the establishment and maintenance of the project or projects. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may levy and collect fees for the use of or admission to the project or projects and expend or invest the income from the fees for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 176, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 46, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2741p-14. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>