<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.090</section_number><catch_line>Findings of fact -- Evidence -- Recording of hearing -- Burdens of proof. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In an administrative hearing, findings of fact shall be based exclusively on the evidence on the record. The hearing officer shall exclude evidence that is irrelevant, immaterial, unduly repetitious, or excludable on constitutional or statutory grounds or on the basis of evidentiary privilege recognized in the courts of this Commonwealth. Hearsay evidence may be admissible, if it is the type of evidence that reasonable and prudent persons would rely on in their daily affairs, but it shall not be sufficient in itself to support an agency's findings of facts unless it would be admissible over objections in civil actions. </section><section prefix="2">All testimony shall be made under oath or affirmation. Any part of the evidence may be received in written form if doing so will expedite the hearing without substantial prejudice to the interests of any party. The hearing officer may make a recommended order in an administrative hearing submitted in written form if the hearing officer determines there are no genuine issues of material fact in dispute and judgment is appropriate as a matter of law. </section><section prefix="3">Any party shall have the right to inspect, at least five (5) days prior to the hearing, a list of all witnesses every other party expects to call at the hearing, and the available documentary or tangible evidence relating to an administrative hearing either in person or by counsel. Copies of documentary evidence may be obtained upon the payment of a fee, except documents protected from disclosure by state or federal law. Nothing in this section shall be construed as giving a party the right to examine or copy the personal notes, observations, or conclusions of the agency staff, unless exculpatory in nature, nor shall it be construed as allowing access to the work product of counsel for the agency. Conditions for examining and copying agency records, fees to be charged, and other matters pertaining to access to these records shall be governed by KRS 61.870 to 61.884. To the extent required by due process, the hearing officer may order the inspection of any records excluded from the application of KRS 61.870 to 61.884 under KRS 61.878 that relate to an act, transaction, or event that is a subject of the hearing, and may order their inclusion in the record under seal. </section><section prefix="4">Objections to evidentiary offers may be made by any party and shall be noted in the record. </section><section prefix="5">The hearing officer may take official notice of facts which are not in dispute, or of generally-recognized technical or scientific facts within the agency's specialized knowledge. The hearing officer shall notify all parties, either before or during the hearing, or in preliminary reports or otherwise, of any facts so noticed and their source. All parties shall be given an opportunity to contest facts officially noticed. </section><section prefix="6">The agency shall cause all testimony, motions, and objections in a hearing to be accurately and completely recorded. Any person, upon request, may receive a copy of the recording or a copy of the transcript, if the hearing has been transcribed, at the discretion of the agency, unless the hearing is closed by law. The agency may prepare a transcript of a hearing or a portion of a hearing upon request but the party making the request shall be responsible for the transcription costs. The form of all requests and fees charged shall be consistent with KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="7">In all administrative hearings, unless otherwise provided by statute or federal law, the party proposing the agency take action or  grant a benefit has the burden to show the propriety of the agency action or entitlement to the benefit sought. The agency has the burden to show the propriety of a penalty imposed or the removal of a benefit previously granted. The party asserting an affirmative defense has the burden to establish that defense. The party with the burden of proof on any issue has the burden of going forward and the ultimate burden of persuasion as to that issue. The ultimate burden of persuasion in all administrative hearings is met by a preponderance of evidence in the record. Failure to meet the burden of proof is grounds for a recommended order from the hearing officer. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=793</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>