<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Association" means the Kentucky Psychological Association; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Examiners of Psychology; </section><section prefix="3">"Credential holder" means any person who is regulated by the board; </section><section prefix="4">"EPPP" means the Examination for Professional Practice in Psychology developed by the Association of State and Provincial Psychology Boards; </section><section prefix="5">"IPC" means the Interjurisdictional Practice Certificate developed by the Association of State and Provincial Psychology Boards; </section><section prefix="6">"License" means the credential issued by the board to a licensed psychologist, licensed psychological practitioner, certified psychologist with autonomous functioning, certified psychologist, or a licensed psychological associate; </section><section prefix="7">"Practice of psychology" means rendering to individuals, groups, organizations, or the public any psychological service involving the application of principles, methods, and procedures of understanding, predicting, and influencing behavior, such as the principles pertaining to learning, perception, motivation, thinking, emotions, and interpersonal relationships; the methods and procedures of interviewing, counseling, and psychotherapy; and psychological testing in constructing, administering, and interpreting tests of mental abilities, aptitudes, interests, attitudes, personality characteristics, emotion, and motivation. The application of said principles in testing, evaluation, treatment, use of psychotherapeutic techniques, and other methods includes, but is not limited to: diagnosis, prevention, and amelioration of adjustment problems and emotional, mental, nervous, and addictive disorders and mental health conditions of individuals and groups; educational and vocational counseling; the evaluation and planning for effective work and learning situations; and the resolution of interpersonal and social conflicts; </section><section prefix="8">"Psychotherapy" means the use of learning, conditioning methods, and emotional reactions, in a professional relationship, to assist a person or persons to modify feelings, attitudes, and behavior which are intellectually, socially, or emotionally maladjustive or ineffectual; and </section><section prefix="9">"Psychologist" means any person who holds himself or herself out by any title or description of services incorporating the words "psychologic," "psychological," "psychologist," "psychology," "psychopractice," or any other term or terms that imply he or she is trained, experienced, or an expert in the field of psychology. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>