<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.570</section_number><catch_line>Compensation of members -- Employees -- Duties of secretary-treasurer -- Effect of compact. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Members of the authority shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for any actual and necessary expenses incurred by them in the conduct of the affairs of the authority. The authority shall, upon the appointment of its members, organize and elect officers. The authority shall choose a chairman and vice chairman who shall serve for terms of one (1) year. The authority may fix a salary for the secretary-treasurer, and the secretary-treasurer shall execute an official bond to be set and approved by the authority, and the cost thereof shall be paid by the authority. </section><section prefix="2">The authority may employ or retain necessary counsel, agents, employees, or other persons to carry out its purposes, work, and functions and may prescribe such rules and regulations as it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary-treasurer shall keep the minutes of all meetings of the authority and shall also keep a set of books showing the receipts and expenditures of the authority. He shall preserve on file duplicate vouchers for all expenditures and shall present to the authority, upon request, complete reports of all financial transactions and the financial condition of the authority. Such books and vouchers shall at all times be subject to examination by the legislative body or bodies by whom the authority was created. He shall transmit at least once annually a detailed report of all acts and doings of the authority to the legislative body or bodies by whom the authority was created. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding subsection (1) of this section, when a city of the first class and a county containing such city have in effect a compact under KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the secretary-treasurer or executive director, as the case may be, shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court as provided in KRS 67.040; fiscal court shall fix the salary. Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing that city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the secretary-treasurer or executive director, as the case may be, shall be appointed by and shall serve at the pleasure of the mayor. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 5. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 2(5) to (7). </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23429</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>