<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.290</section_number><catch_line>Functions of board. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text>The board shall: <section prefix="1">Administer this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Adopt an official seal; </section><section prefix="3">Provide suitable office quarters at its own expense; </section><section prefix="4">Adopt and amend all bylaws and rules of procedure, and promulgate administrative regulations, consistent with the Constitution and laws of the state and reasonably necessary for the proper performance of its duties and the regulation and fair conduct of the proceedings before it; </section><section prefix="5">Appoint an executive director and assistant executive directors and fix their compensation; </section><section prefix="6">Employ any clerk or other assistants necessary for the proper performance of its work; </section><section prefix="7">Appoint a general counsel and any assistant general counsel as it deems necessary and fix their compensation; </section><section prefix="8">Appoint investigatory personnel, as it deems necessary, and fix their compensation; </section><section prefix="9">Appoint committees of licensees, as it deems necessary, to review issues before the board and make recommendations to the board; </section><section prefix="10">Make expenditures, as it deems necessary, for any purpose that it considers reasonably necessary for the proper performance of its duties, including paying the expenses of the board's delegates to national conventions of and membership dues to the National Council of Examiners for Engineering and Surveying or other affiliated national boards or societies; </section><section prefix="11">Adopt and promulgate by administrative regulation a code of professional practice and conduct, which shall be based upon generally recognized principles of professional ethical conduct and binding upon persons licensed under this chapter. A code of professional practice and conduct shall be made known to all licensees and applicants and shall include but not be limited to the following objectives: <section prefix="a">The protection of the public health, safety, and welfare; </section><section prefix="b">The maintenance of standards of objectivity, truthfulness, and reliability in public statements; </section><section prefix="c">The avoidance of conflicts of interest; </section><section prefix="d">The prohibition of solicitation or acceptance of engineering or land surveying work on any basis other than qualifications for the work offered; </section><section prefix="e">The prohibition of association with any person engaging in illegal or dishonest activities; and </section><section prefix="f">The limitation of professional service to the area of competence of the licensee; </section></section><section prefix="12">Adopt appropriate standards of practice; </section><section prefix="13">Promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish rules for the use of stamps, seals, and signatures in electronic transactions; </section><section prefix="14">Bring, in its name, injunctive proceedings in the Franklin Circuit Court to enjoin any person, business entity, or combination thereof in violation of KRS 322.020 or KRS 322.060; </section><section prefix="15">Adopt a program for continuing education for its individual land surveyor licensees. No individual land surveyor licensee shall be permitted to renew his or her license unless the minimum annual continuing education requirements are met, in addition to any other requirement for renewal. The program for continuing education shall not exceed a total of eight (8) credit clock hours per year and shall not include testing or examination of the licensee in any manner; and </section><section prefix="16">Adopt a program for continuing education for its individual engineer licensees. <section prefix="a">The program for continuing education shall not exceed a total of fifteen (15) credit clock hours per year and shall not include testing or examination of the licensee in any manner. </section><section prefix="b">No individual engineer licensee shall be permitted to renew his or her license unless the minimum annual continuing education requirements are met, except as provided in paragraph (c) of this subsection, in addition to any other requirement for renewal. </section><section prefix="c">Any person licensed under this chapter as a professional engineer prior to January 1, 1972, who has maintained his or her license in good standing since becoming licensed shall not be subject to any continuing education requirements. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 26, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 22. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599e-3, 1599e-8, 1599e-9, 1599e-21, 1599e-23. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal numbering system and rearranged some text of subsection (16) of this statute. No words were changed in the process. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31448</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>