<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.475</section_number><catch_line>Allocation of enrollment positions by state schools of medicine and dentistry -- Competitive selection of entering class medical, dental, or law students. </catch_line><order_by>475</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The boards of trustees of the state colleges and universities offering degree programs in medicine or dentistry shall allocate seventy percent (70%) of the enrollment positions for the entering class each year, equally among each of the Kentucky Supreme Court districts, using the population of each Supreme Court district as determined by the last decennial federal census to determine that district's proportion of the positions, and shall assign these apportioned enrollment positions for each district to those applicants who are legal residents in that Supreme Court district. </section><section prefix="2">Fifteen percent (15%) of the remaining positions shall be allocated to the state at-large and assigned to applicants who are legal residents at any place within the State of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">Any qualified legal resident shall have a preference in securing an assignment to a position when compared to a nonresident. </section><section prefix="4">The total number of nonresidents assigned positions shall not exceed fifteen percent (15%) of the total entering class enrollment positions assigned for any school year. </section><section prefix="5">The selection of entering class medical, dental, or law students shall be accomplished competitively with due consideration being given scholastic standings, recommendations of the pre-professional advisory committees of the various schools where the applicants pursue the pre-professional academic program, and their performance on any required admission test, and any other procedures that deal fairly with the applicant group as a whole. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4295</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>