<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">A LICENSING OF NURSING HOME ADMINISTRATORS </unit></structure><section_number>216A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Licensure for Long-term Care Administrators established in KRS 216A.040; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Long-term care administrator" means any individual responsible for planning, organizing, directing, and controlling the operation of a licensed long-term care facility, or who in fact performs those functions, whether or not those functions are shared by one (1) or more other persons; </section><section prefix="4">"Long-term care facility" means a health care facility which is defined by the cabinet to be an intermediate care facility, skilled-nursing facility, nursing facility in accordance with Pub. L. No. 100-203, nursing home, or intermediate care facility for individuals with an intellectual or developmental disability; and </section><section prefix="5">"Resident" means any person who is admitted to a long-term care facility. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 55, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 129 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. The amendments are identical, except that in subsection (1), ch. 129 refers to KRS 216A.040 ("Section 4 of this Act") and ch. 158 refers to KRS 216A.030 ("Section 57 of this Act"). It is clear from the context that the reference in both bills is intended to be to KRS 216A.040, and the Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error under KRS 7.136(1). (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 144, directs the Reviser of Statutes to replace references in the statutes to "mentally retarded" with "individuals with an intellectual disability." A reference in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1(4) (this statute), to "the mentally retarded and developmentally disabled" has been changed in codification to "individuals with an intellectual or developmental disability" to comply with the directive in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146 and usage found elsewhere in the statutes. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>