<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.027</section_number><catch_line>Hearing required before promulgation, amendment, or repeal of administrative regulations affecting property owners or occupants of property adjacent to a lake or other real property owned or controlled by the department. </catch_line><order_by>027</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Not less than sixty (60) days nor more than ninety (90) days prior to the submission of a proposed administrative regulation, proposed amendment to an administrative regulation, or proposed repeal of an administrative regulation to the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee which affects property owners or occupants of property adjacent to any lake or other real property owned or controlled by the department, the department shall: <section prefix="a">Hold a public hearing at a time and location most convenient to the public at a location within ten (10) miles of the boundary of the lake so that the public can make comments about the proposed administrative regulation, proposed amendment to an administrative regulation, or proposed repeal of an administrative regulation. Copies of the proposed administrative regulation, proposed amendment to an administrative regulation, or proposed repeal of an administrative regulation shall be distributed to members of the public attending the meeting without cost; </section><section prefix="b">Advertise the hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 424; </section><section prefix="c">Electronically record the hearing and the comments made at the hearing; and </section><section prefix="d">Within thirty (30) days of the close of the hearing, file a statement of consideration with the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee summarizing the comments made at the hearing and the department's response thereto containing the information required by KRS 13A.010. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee shall find deficient any proposed administrative regulation, proposed amendment to an administrative regulation, or proposed repeal of an administrative regulation covered by this section which does not comply with the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1937</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>