<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.537</section_number><catch_line>Director of association -- Qualifications -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>537</order_by><text>If the state board employs a full-time staff person to serve as the director of the association, then: <section prefix="1">The state director shall be a person who by a combination of education, professional qualification, training, and experience is qualified to perform the duties of this position. The state director shall be of good moral character with at least two (2) years of experience working in a position managing a human services program and who has received a: <section prefix="a">Master's degree in social work, sociology, psychology, guidance and counseling, education, criminal justice, or other human service field; or </section><section prefix="b">Baccalaureate degree in social work, sociology, psychology, guidance and counseling, education, criminal justice, or other human service field with, in addition to the work experience required in this subsection, at least two (2) more years of experience working in the human services field. </section></section><section prefix="2">The duties of the state director shall be: <section prefix="a">To manage the state court-appointed special advocate office, including staff; </section><section prefix="b">To coordinate the activities of the association; </section><section prefix="c">To monitor the policies and practices of local CASA programs for compliance with state laws, National CASA Association Standards for Programs, and reporting requirements established by the state association; to assist local CASA programs in efforts to achieve compliance; and to report to the state association the status of compliance by local CASA programs; </section><section prefix="d">Upon request of local CASA programs, to provide technical assistance to local CASA programs; </section><section prefix="e">To provide technical assistance and support to chief judges of family courts, Chief District Judges, and others in development of new local CASA programs; </section><section prefix="f">To coordinate a statewide public awareness campaign for generating interest in developing new CASA programs, recruiting volunteers, and informing the public of the issues concerning child abuse and neglect; and </section><section prefix="g">Other duties as directed by the association. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20235</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>