<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.056</section_number><catch_line>"Certified psychologist with autonomous functioning" -- "Certified psychologist" -- Practice and title authorization. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person currently authorized to use the title "certified psychologist with autonomous functioning" may continue to function with that title or may choose to permanently change this title to "licensed psychological practitioner" and notify the board of this choice. The board shall issue a license at the time of renewal to the credential holder with the title of choice. </section><section prefix="2">A certified psychologist with autonomous functioning or a licensed psychological practitioner may continue to function without supervision unless the board revokes his or her license pursuant to KRS 319.082. He or she shall not supervise certified psychologists, licensed psychological practitioners, or licensed psychological associates. </section><section prefix="3">A person currently authorized to use the title "certified psychologist" may continue to function with that title or may choose to permanently change this title to "licensed psychological associate" and notify the board of this choice. The board shall issue a license at the time of renewal to the credential holder with the title of choice. </section><section prefix="4">A certified psychologist or a licensed psychological associate may continue to function under the supervision of a licensed psychologist unless the board revokes his certificate pursuant to KRS 319.082. </section><section prefix="5">A certified psychologist, whether functioning under that title or as a licensed psychological associate, may perform certain functions within the practice of psychology only under the supervision of a licensed psychologist approved by the board, and shall not employ or supervise other certified psychologists, licensed psychological practitioners, or licensed psychological associates. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 9, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31229</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>