<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.310</section_number><catch_line>Repeal or permissive withdrawal of administrative regulation. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An administrative regulation, once adopted, cannot be withdrawn but shall be repealed if it is desired that it no longer be effective. </section><section prefix="2">An administrative regulation, once adopted, cannot be suspended but shall be repealed if it is desired to suspend its effect. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">An administrative regulation shall be repealed only by the promulgation of an administrative regulation that: <section prefix="1">Is titled "Repeal of (state number of administrative regulation to be repealed)"; </section><section prefix="2">Contains the reasons for repeal in the "NECESSITY, FUNCTION, AND CONFORMITY" paragraph; </section><section prefix="3">Includes in the body of the administrative regulation, a citation to the number and title of the administrative regulation or regulations being repealed; and </section><section prefix="4">Meets the filing and formatting requirements of KRS 13A.220. </section></section><section prefix="b">On the effective date of an administrative regulation that repeals an administrative regulation, the regulations compiler shall delete the repealed administrative regulation and the repealing administrative regulation from the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service. </section><section prefix="c">An administrative body may repeal more than one (1) administrative regulation in an administrative regulation promulgated pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection if the administrative regulations being repealed are contained in the same chapter of the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">An ordinary administrative regulation may be withdrawn by the promulgating administrative body at any time prior to its adoption. </section><section prefix="b">An ordinary administrative regulation that has been found deficient may be withdrawn by the promulgating administrative body at any time prior to receipt by the regulations compiler of the determination of the Governor made pursuant to KRS 13A.330 or 13A.331 or may be withdrawn by the Governor. </section><section prefix="c">If an ordinary administrative regulation is withdrawn, the administrative body or the Governor shall inform the regulations compiler of the reasons for withdrawal in writing. </section></section><section prefix="5">Once an ordinary administrative regulation is withdrawn it shall not be reinstated, except by repromulgation as a totally new matter. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 19, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 29, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 31, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>