<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.146</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance of records relating to vital statistics by various persons. </catch_line><order_by>146</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person in charge of an institution shall keep a record of personal data concerning each person admitted or confined to the institution. This record shall include the information required for certificates of birth and death and the reports of fetal death and induced termination of pregnancy required by this chapter. The record shall be made at the time of admission from information provided by the person being admitted or confined but, if it cannot be so obtained, the information shall be obtained from relatives or other persons acquainted with the facts. The name and address of the person providing the information shall be a part of the record. </section><section prefix="2">If a dead body or dead fetus is released or disposed of by an institution, the person in charge of the institution shall keep a record showing the name of the decedent, date of death, name and address of the person to whom the body or fetus is released, and the date of removal from the institution. If final disposition is made by the institution, the date, place, and manner of disposition shall also be recorded on the certificate of death or fetal death and filed in accordance with KRS 213.076 and 213.096. </section><section prefix="3">A funeral director, embalmer, sexton, or other person who removes from the place of death, transports, or makes final disposition of a dead body or fetus shall, in addition to filing any certificate or other report required by this chapter or regulation promulgated hereunder, keep a record which shall identify the body and the information pertaining to the persons receipt, removal, delivery, burial, or cremation of the body as may be required by regulations adopted by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Records maintained under this section shall be retained for a period of not less than five (5) years and shall be made available for inspection by the cabinet or its designee upon request. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>