<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="24" order_by="24">A DISTRICT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>24A.100</section_number><catch_line>Trial commissioners. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any county which does not have a District Judge resident in the county there shall be a trial commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Trial commissioners shall be appointed in the manner required by Section 113 of the Constitution of Kentucky and shall perform such duties as may be directed by the Supreme Court. </section><section prefix="3">Trial commissioners in District Court shall be compensated as provided in the judicial personnel system, provided, however that no trial commissioner shall be compensated at a rate greater than seven thousand two hundred dollars ($7,200) per year. Except that during the disability or suspension of a District Judge for a period in excess of sixty (60) days, a trial commissioner who is qualified as an attorney and who is authorized to perform extraordinary duties, may be compensated by the Supreme Court in an amount not exceeding the salary of a District Judge, provided such trial commissioner shall not engage in the practice of law during the period of extraordinary service. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 78, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><budget-ref>See Judicial Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 122, Pt. III, 9 at 781. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20689</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>