<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.380</section_number><catch_line>Duties of treasurer -- Custodian of securities. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Treasurer is the custodian of all cash funds of the retirement system. He shall honor and pay all vouchers drawn on the retirement funds. The Treasurer shall honor and pay all vouchers drawn on the retirement funds for payment of securities purchased upon order of the board. All payments from the several funds of the retirement system shall be made only upon vouchers signed by the executive secretary, the chairman of the board of trustees of the retirement system, or persons delegated in writing by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees shall appoint a custodian or custodians of the securities acquired under authority of KRS 161.430 and the custodian or custodians shall be responsible for the safekeeping of all securities placed in his custody. The custodian shall collect dividends, interests, and payments on principal as they become due, and deposit such funds with the State Treasurer for credit to the guarantee fund of the system. The custodian shall, upon delivery of the securities to him, make payment for same as authorized by the board of trustees. When securities are sold by the board of trustees, the custodian shall deliver such securities to the purchaser upon receipt of payment from said purchaser. </section><section prefix="3">The board of trustees may require such surety from the custodian as they deem necessary for the protection of securities held by such custodian. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 495, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1974. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4506b-22. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>