<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="137" order_by="137">LICENSE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>137.160</section_number><catch_line>Valuation of oil for assessment by Department of Revenue -- Notice -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the Department of Revenue has received the reports provided for in KRS 137.130, it shall, upon such reports and such other reports and information as it may secure, assess the value of all grades or kinds of crude petroleum reported for each month. </section><section prefix="2">Where the report shows no sale of crude petroleum during the month covered by the report, the market value of crude petroleum on the first business day after the tenth day of the month in which the report is made shall be fixed by the department as the assessed value of all crude petroleum covered by the report. Where the report shows that all crude petroleum reported has been sold during the month covered by the report, the market price of such crude petroleum on each day of sale shall be the assessed value of all crude petroleum sold on that date of sale, and the total amount of the tax to be reported as the assessment on the report shall be the total of the assessments made on such sales. If the report shows that part of the crude petroleum reported has been sold and part remains unsold, the market price of the crude petroleum on the first business day after the tenth day of the month following the month covered by the report shall be fixed as the assessed value of the portion of the crude petroleum unsold, the market price of the crude petroleum on each day of sale shall be the assessed value of the portion sold, and the total amount of the tax to be reported as the assessment on the report shall be the total of the assessments made on the sold and unsold crude petroleum. The department, in making its assessments, shall take into consideration transportation charges. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall, by the last day of the month in which the reports are required to be made, notify each transporter of his assessment, and certify the assessment to the county clerk of each county that has reported the levy of a county tax under KRS 137.150. The county clerk shall immediately deliver a copy thereof to the sheriff for collection of the county tax. The transporter so notified of the assessment shall have the right to an appeal to the Kentucky board of tax appeals. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 343, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 24. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4223c-6. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28634</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>