<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-090</section_number><catch_line>Notice of claim. </catch_line><order_by>17-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a provision as follows:  </section>  "Notice of Claim: Written notice of claim must be given to the insurer within sixty (60) days after the occurrence or commencement of any loss covered by the policy, or as soon thereafter as is reasonably possible. Notice given by or on behalf of the insured or the beneficiary to the insurer at .... (insert the location of such office as the insurer may designate for the purpose), or to any authorized agent of the insurer, with information sufficient to identify the insured, shall be deemed notice to the insurer."  <section prefix="2">In a policy providing a loss-of-time benefit which may be payable for at least two (2) years, an insurer may at its option insert the following between the first and second sentences of the provision contained in subsection (1) of this section:  </section>  "Subject to the qualifications set forth below, if the insured suffers loss of time on account of disability for which indemnity may be payable for at least two (2) years, he shall at least once in every six (6) months after having given notice of claim, give to the insurer notice of continuance of said disability, except in the event of legal incapacity. The period of six (6) months following any filing of proof by the insured or any payment by the insurer on account of such claim or any denial of liability in whole or in part by the insurer shall be excluded in applying this provision. Delay in the giving of such notice shall not impair the insured's right to any indemnity which would otherwise have accrued during the period of six (6) months preceding the date on which such notice is actually given."  </text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 17, sec. 9, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17295</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>