<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.012</section_number><catch_line>"Abandoned urban property" defined -- Classification as real property for tax purposes. </catch_line><order_by>012</order_by><text>As used in this section and in KRS 92.305 and 91.285, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Abandoned urban property" means any vacant structure or vacant or unimproved lot or parcel of ground in a predominantly developed urban area which has been vacant or unimproved for a period of at least one (1) year and which: <section prefix="a">Because it is dilapidated, unsanitary, unsafe, vermin infested, or otherwise dangerous to the safety of persons, it is unfit for its intended use; or </section><section prefix="b">By reason of neglect or lack of maintenance has become a place for the accumulation of trash and debris, or has become infested with rodents or other vermin; or </section><section prefix="c">Has been tax delinquent for a period of at least three (3) years; or </section><section prefix="d">Is located within a development area established under KRS 65.7049, 65.7051, and 65.7053. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of local taxation in cities of any class or consolidated local governments, there shall be a classification of real property known as abandoned urban property. The legislative body of a city of any class, county containing a city of the first class, or consolidated local government may levy a rate of taxation on abandoned urban property higher than the prevailing rate of taxation on other real property in the city, county containing a city of the first class, or consolidated local government. The limitation upon tax rates established by KRS 132.027 shall not apply to the rate of taxation on abandoned urban property. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 25, effective March 23, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 160, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 513, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 23, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28198</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>