<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.935</section_number><catch_line>Purposes for disbursement of funds. </catch_line><order_by>935</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state board may authorize the disbursement of available money from the trust fund, upon legislative appropriations, for exclusively the following purposes, which are listed in the order of preference for expenditure: <section prefix="a">To fund a private nonprofit or public organization in the development or operation of a prevention program if at least all of the following conditions are met: <section prefix="1">The appropriate local task force has reviewed and approved the program. This subparagraph does not apply if a local task force does not exist for the geographic area to be served by the program; </section><section prefix="2">The organization agrees to match fifty percent (50%) of the amount requested from the trust fund. At least ten percent (10%) of the amount requested shall be matched through dollars, and the remaining match shall be through in-kind contributions. The type of contributions shall be subject to the approval of the state board; </section><section prefix="3">The organization demonstrates a willingness and ability to provide program models and consultation to organizations and communities regarding program development and maintenance; and </section><section prefix="4">Other conditions that the state board may deem appropriate; </section></section><section prefix="b">To fund the cost of medical examinations of victims of suspected child sexual abuse to the extent the fee for an examination is a service not eligible to be paid for by Medicaid or private insurance. The fees paid for this examination shall not exceed reasonable, usual, and customary charges as set by the state board; </section><section prefix="c">To fund the cost of counseling and other mental health services to victims of child sexual abuse to the extent the fees for counseling and mental health services are services not eligible to be paid for by Medicaid or private insurance. The fees paid for counseling and mental health services shall not exceed reasonable, usual, and customary charges as set by the state board; </section><section prefix="d">To fund local task forces; </section><section prefix="e">To fund a statewide public education and awareness campaign on child sexual abuse, making use of electronic and print media to inform the public about the nature of child sexual abuse, legal reporting requirements, victim rights, legal remedies, agency services, and prevention strategies; </section><section prefix="f">To fund and evaluate the comparative success of statewide comprehensive approaches to prevention education making use of multiple approaches; and </section><section prefix="g">To fund the state board created in KRS 15.905 for the actual and necessary operating expenses that the board incurs in performing its duties. </section></section><section prefix="2">Authorizations for disbursement of trust fund money under subsection (1)(g) of this section shall be kept at a minimum in furtherance of the primary purpose of the trust fund which is to disburse money under subsections (1)(a), (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f) of this section to encourage the direct provision of services to prevent child abuse and exploitation, and to provide medical examination and counseling or other mental health services for victims of child sexual abuse. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1017</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>