<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.760</section_number><catch_line>Functions of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>760</order_by><text>The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall be responsible for promotion of interest in the development of additional facilities for the housing and care of the elderly, and for providing consultative and technical assistance to public and private groups engaged in the development of such facilities. The cabinet's functions shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Promotion of local and community interest in the problem of housing and care for the elderly. </section><section prefix="2">Assisting local housing commissions in the development of low-rent housing projects for the elderly. </section><section prefix="3">Provision of information as to need for facilities in particular areas or locations. </section><section prefix="4">Provision of advice and assistance in the planning of facilities as to area to be served, size, type, staffing, operation, and maintenance. </section><section prefix="5">Provision of information as to the availability of federal financial assistance and the procedures which should be followed in applying for such assistance. </section><section prefix="6">Provision of information as to the availability of state financial assistance and the procedures which should be followed in applying for such assistance. </section><section prefix="7">Provision of information as to the availability of private financial assistance. </section><section prefix="8">Provision of information as to licensing requirements of the state or its political subdivisions. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 488, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 434, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (14). -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9109</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>