<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.281</section_number><catch_line>Contents of subdivision regulations. </catch_line><order_by>281</order_by><text>Subdivision regulations shall be based on the comprehensive plan, in those counties which have adopted a comprehensive plan, and all subdivision regulations shall contain: <section prefix="1">The procedure for the submission and approval of preliminary and final plat and the recordation of final plats. The commission may delegate to its secretary or any other officer or employee the power to approve plats in accordance with the commission's adopted requirements, but all plats, preliminary and final, shall be approved or disapproved within ninety (90) days; </section><section prefix="2">Specifications for the contents and the format of all subdivision plats; </section><section prefix="3">Requirements for the design of streets, blocks, lots, utilities, recreation areas, other facilities, hazardous areas, and areas subject to flooding. Such requirements may deal with all forms of land use including residential, commercial, industrial, and other uses. If the subdivision plat includes a proposal for any street to cross a jurisdictional line out of the planning unit, the commission shall require that notice of the proposal be given to the planning commission serving the planning unit into which the road will cross. If there is no planning unit for that area, the notice shall be given to the affected city or county government; </section><section prefix="4">Specifications for the physical improvements of streets, utilities, and other facilities, and the extent to which they shall be installed or dedicated as conditions precedent to approval of any plat, including the provision of good and sufficient surety to insure proper completion of physical improvements; and </section><section prefix="5">Specifications for the extent to which land is to be used for public purposes shall be reserved as a condition precedent to approval by the commission of any subdivision plat. The planning commission may require a reservation, not to exceed two (2) years, for parks, open space, school, and other public uses. </section><section prefix="6">The text may empower the planning commission to hear and finally decide applications for variances when a proposed development requires a subdivision and one (1) or more variances. </section><section prefix="7">In any regulation adopted pursuant to subsection (6) of this section: <section prefix="a">The text shall provide that the planning commission shall assume all powers and duties otherwise exercised by the board of adjustment pursuant to KRS 100.231, 100.233, 100.237, 100.241, 100.243, 100.247, and 100.251 in a circumstance provided for by subsection (6) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">The text shall provide that the applicant for the subdivision at the time of the filing of the application for the subdivision may elect to have any variance for the same development to be heard and finally decided by the planning commission at the same public hearing set for the subdivision, or by the board of adjustment as otherwise provided for in this chapter. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 141, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 64. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>