<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.040</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of hearing officer. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who has served as an investigator or prosecutor in an administrative hearing or in its preadjudicative stage shall not serve as hearing officer or assist or advise a hearing officer in the same proceeding. This shall not be construed as preventing a person who has participated as a hearing officer in a determination of probable cause or other equivalent preliminary determination from serving as a hearing officer in the same proceeding. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A hearing officer, agency head, or member of an agency head who is serving as a hearing officer shall voluntarily disqualify himself and withdraw from any case in which he cannot afford a fair and impartial hearing or consideration. Any party may request the disqualification of a hearing officer, agency head, or member of the agency head by filing an affidavit, upon discovery of facts establishing grounds for a disqualification, stating the particular grounds upon which he claims that a fair and impartial hearing cannot be accorded. A request for the disqualification of a hearing officer shall be answered by the agency head within sixty (60) days of its filing. The request for disqualification and the disposition of the request shall be a part of the official record of the proceeding. Requests for disqualification of a hearing officer shall be determined by the agency head. Requests for disqualification of a hearing officer who is a member of the agency head shall be determined by the majority of the remaining members of the agency head. </section><section prefix="b">Grounds for disqualification of a hearing officer shall include, but shall not be limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Serving as an investigator or prosecutor in the proceeding or the preadjudicative stages of the proceeding; </section><section prefix="2">Participating in an ex parte communication which would prejudice the proceedings; </section><section prefix="3">Having a pecuniary interest in the outcome of the proceeding; or </section><section prefix="4">Having a personal bias toward any party to a proceeding which would cause a prejudgment on the outcome of the proceeding. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=788</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>