<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.020</section_number><catch_line>County health boards -- Appointment -- Membership -- Term --  Compensation -- Removal of board members. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall appoint, from a list of nominees, three (3) qualified, licensed, and practicing physicians; one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing dentist; one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing registered nurse; one (1) licensed engineer engaged in the practice of civil or sanitary engineering; one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing optometrist; one (1) qualified licensed and practicing veterinarian; one (1) licensed pharmacist; and one (1) lay person knowledgeable in consumer affairs residing in each county who, together with the county judge/executive and one (1) person appointed by the fiscal court in each county, shall constitute a local board of health for the respective counties in which they reside. The list of nominees submitted to the secretary shall be accepted from any source and shall be solicited and obtained from the county judge/executive, fiscal court, and county health department staff; and nominations of physicians, dentists, nurses, engineers, optometrists, veterinarians, and pharmacists shall be solicited and obtained from the county's medical society, dental society, nursing association, engineering association, optometric association, veterinarian association, and pharmacists' association, respectively. If a county does not have three (3) qualified, licensed, and practicing physicians or one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing dentist or one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing registered nurse or one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing civil or sanitary engineer or one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing optometrist or one (1) qualified, licensed, and practicing veterinarian, or one (1) licensed pharmacist residing therein, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services may appoint a resident lay person knowledgeable in consumer affairs in lieu thereof for each such vacancy. The members of the local board shall hold office for a term of two (2) years with physicians, dentists, pharmacists, and fiscal court appointees appointed in even-numbered years and nurses, engineers, optometrists, veterinarians, and lay appointees appointed in odd-numbered years, for terms from the date of their appointment, beginning on or after January 1, 1993, and until their successors are appointed, except the terms of the first appointment of all physician and fiscal court appointee terms beginning on January 1, 1993, shall expire on December 31, 1993; dentist terms beginning on August 1, 1992, shall expire on December 31, 1993; nurse, engineer, and optometrist appointments beginning on August 1, 1992, shall expire on December 31, 1994; and veterinarian and lay appointments beginning on October 1, 1992, shall expire on December 31, 1994. The members of the board shall receive no compensation for their services. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall remove any member, other than the county judge/executive or fiscal court appointee, who fails to attend three (3) consecutive scheduled meetings, and may remove any board member, except the county judge/executive or fiscal court appointee, as provided by KRS 65.007. The fiscal court may remove its appointee in like fashion. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 395, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 346, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2055. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8569</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>