<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.686</section_number><catch_line>Authorization for coroners to establish local child fatality response teams -- Confidentiality of team proceedings and records. </catch_line><order_by>686</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local child fatality response team may be established in every county or group of contiguous counties by the coroner or coroners with jurisdiction in the county or counties. The local coroner may authorize the creation of additional local teams within the coroner's jurisdiction as needed. </section><section prefix="2">Membership of the local team may include representatives of the coroner, the local office of the Department for Community Based Services, law enforcement agencies with investigation responsibilities for child fatalities which occur within the jurisdiction of the local team, the Commonwealth's and county attorneys, representatives of the medical profession, and other members whose participation the local team believes is important to carry out its purpose. Each local team member shall be appointed by the agency the member is representing and shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authority. </section><section prefix="3">The purpose of the local child fatality response team shall be to: <section prefix="a">Allow each member to share specific and unique information with the local team; </section><section prefix="b">Generate overall investigative direction and emphasis through team coordination and sharing of specialized information; </section><section prefix="c">Create a body of information that will assist in the coroner's effort to accurately identify the cause and reasons for death; and </section><section prefix="d">Facilitate the appropriate response by each member agency to the fatality, including but not limited to, intervention on behalf of other children who may be adversely affected by the situation, implementation of health services necessary for protection of other citizens, further investigation by law enforcement, or legal action by Commonwealth's or county attorneys. </section></section><section prefix="4">The local team may: <section prefix="a">Analyze information regarding local child fatalities to identify trends, patterns, and risk factors; </section><section prefix="b">Recommend to the state team, and any other entities deemed appropriate, changes in state or local programs, legislation, administrative regulations, policies, budgets, and treatment and service standards which may facilitate strategies for prevention and reduce the number of child fatalities; and </section><section prefix="c">Evaluate the effectiveness of local prevention and intervention strategies. </section></section><section prefix="5">The local team may establish a protocol for the investigation of child fatalities and may establish operating rules and procedures as it deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The review of a child fatality by a local team may include information from reports generated or received by agencies, organizations, or individuals that are responsible for investigation, prosecution, or treatment in the case. </section><section prefix="7">The proceedings, records, opinions, and deliberations of the local team shall be privileged and shall not be subject to discovery, subpoena, or introduction into evidence in any civil action in any manner that would directly or indirectly identify specific persons or cases reviewed by the local team. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to restrict or limit the right to discover or use in any civil action any evidence that is discoverable independent of the proceedings of the local team. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 43, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>