<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.600</section_number><catch_line>Seal of approval required on manufactured homes offered for sale -- Seal for manufactured homes purchased in another state. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any retailer who has acquired a previously owned manufactured home, mobile home, or recreational vehicle without a seal shall apply to the department for the appropriate seal by submitting an affidavit that the unit has been brought up to or meets reasonable standards established by the board for previously owned manufactured homes, mobile homes, or recreational vehicles. Those manufactured homes or mobile homes taken in trade must be reinspected and certified. A numbered Class B1 Seal shall be affixed by the retailer to the unit prior to sale. A seal will not be required if such retailer submits an affidavit that the unit will not be resold for use as such by the public. A retailer shall not transport or install a manufactured or mobile home which is to be used for residential purposes which does not have a Class B1 Seal. </section><section prefix="2">The owner of any manufactured home or mobile home which is not covered by the federal act and which was purchased in another state and not bearing a seal of approval shall purchase a seal from the department. Application to purchase a seal of approval shall be made to the department. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall make available suitable forms for application for seals of approval for previously owned manufactured homes or mobile homes which are not covered by the federal act and for previously owned recreational vehicles. </section><section prefix="4">The clerk of the county in which a manufactured home, mobile home, or previously owned recreational vehicle is sought to be registered after June 1, 1976, which was purchased out of Kentucky, shall require production of proof of purchase of a seal of approval as provided in subsection (2) of this section before registering or issuing a license for any manufactured home, mobile home, or previously owned recreational vehicle. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 417, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 6; and ch. 237, sec. 1. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>