<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.748</section_number><catch_line>Resolution for maintenance and operation of project -- Notice -- Hearing -- Election -- Assessment. </catch_line><order_by>748</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon determination by the board of directors of a watershed conservancy district that the improvement, continuing operation, or maintenance of a watershed project is necessary, the board of directors may adopt a resolution which shall set out: <section prefix="a">A list of the benefited lands located in the flood plain, as determined by the board of directors, giving the acreage of such lands and the names of the owners thereof as defined by KRS 262.010(7) with a classification of such lands or parts thereof into classes in order that assessments may be made according to direct benefits; and </section><section prefix="b">The annual assessments to be levied upon the lands set out in the resolution on the basis of a certain amount per acre according to benefits received, not to exceed in any one (1) year a sum per acre specified in the resolution. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board of directors shall cause due notice of the resolution to be given to all the owners of benefited lands, as determined by the board. Said notice shall set out the time and place of a meeting of the board of directors of the watershed conservancy district at which owners of benefited lands who may be liable for the annual assessments may be heard. </section><section prefix="3">At the hearing upon the resolution, owners of benefited lands may voice their views concerning the proposal as to whether it should be undertaken, and the scope thereof, or the degree of benefit received by their lands. The board shall prepare a record summarizing the proceedings. If the board of directors determines as a result of the hearing that the proposal should be carried out as planned, it may make such changes or revisions in the resolution as it deems proper and shall give due notice of an election to be held at which benefited landowners may vote on the question of annual special assessments to defray the cost. The notice of the election shall include the text of the resolution of the board in its final form. The board of directors may give due notice as provided in KRS 262.010(4). </section><section prefix="4">The board of directors shall prepare the following question to be presented to the voters: "Should the assessment for improvement, continuing operation, or maintenance proposed by resolution of the........ Watershed Conservancy District be adopted?" Voters shall be instructed to vote "yes" or "no" on the proposition. Only owners of benefited land as set out in the resolution shall be eligible to vote. The board of directors may provide for a meeting of the landowners at which the vote may be cast, in which case qualified voters may vote by absentee vote. The board shall appoint a polling superintendent and other necessary election officers, giving representation to the opponents of the question as well as to proponents. </section><section prefix="5">If a majority of those voting upon the proposition favor the assessment the board shall give due notice of the vote. Any owner of property to be benefited by the project may, within forty (40) days after publication of such notice, file an action in the Circuit Court of the county in which his lands are located seeking relief by declaratory judgment or injunction. If a suit is filed, the county attorney shall represent the board of directors in upholding the validity of the proposed assessment. After the lapse of time specified herein all actions by owners of properties to be benefited shall be forever barred. </section><section prefix="6">If no suit is filed and no injunction issued within the time allowed in subsection (5) of this section, the board of directors shall levy annual assessments effective only upon the benefited properties and based on the acreage thereof. The annual assessment shall be made by the board of directors at the same time and in the same manner as provided in KRS 262.765 for taxes generally and shall be collected as provided in KRS 262.770. The assessments shall constitute liens against the land benefited and shall attach to the land, taking precedence over all other liens except state, county and municipal taxes and prior improvement assessments. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 82, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12793</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>