<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.155</section_number><catch_line>Removal of board members. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor may remove a member of the board for any of the following reasons: <section prefix="a">Refusal or inability of a board member to perform his duties as a member of the board in an efficient, responsible and professional manner; </section><section prefix="b">Misuse of the office by a member of the board to obtain personal, pecuniary, or material gain or advantage for himself or another; </section><section prefix="c">Willful violation of any provision of KRS Chapter 315 or any rule or regulation promulgated thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person may file a complaint with the executive director of the board against a board member alleging specific facts which constitute grounds for removal from the board. The executive director shall transmit a copy of any such complaint to the Governor, the president of the board and the accused board member. Upon a written recommendation of the Governor or two-thirds (2/3) of the members of the board, a hearing shall be conducted before an impartial hearing officer pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">The hearing officer shall submit a transcript of the hearing to the Governor with a recommendation based on evidence presented in the hearing. The Governor shall review the transcript to determine if the evidence supports the recommendation, and he shall enter a finding in accordance with such determination. </section><section prefix="4">In the event a board member is removed, his removal shall be effective as of the date of the Governor's finding and a vacancy shall be deemed to exist. Any board member so removed shall be entitled to appeal the removal in the Franklin Circuit Court. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31020</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>