<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6911</section_number><catch_line>Office may refuse to issue certificate -- Renewal of registration. </catch_line><order_by>6911</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section, the office shall issue a certificate of registration to an individual who complies with KRS 164.6909(1) or whose application has been accepted under KRS 164.6909(2). </section><section prefix="2">The office may refuse to issue a certificate of registration if the office determines that the applicant has engaged in conduct that has a significant adverse effect on the applicant's fitness to act as an athlete agent. In making the determination, the office may consider whether the applicant has: <section prefix="a">Been convicted of a crime that, if committed in this state, would be a crime involving moral turpitude or a felony; </section><section prefix="b">Made a materially false, misleading, deceptive, or fraudulent representation in the application or as an athlete agent; </section><section prefix="c">Engaged in conduct that would disqualify the applicant from serving in a fiduciary capacity; </section><section prefix="d">Engaged in conduct prohibited by KRS 164.6925; </section><section prefix="e">Had a registration or licensure as an athlete agent suspended, revoked, or denied, or been refused renewal of registration or licensure as an athlete agent in any state; </section><section prefix="f">Engaged in conduct the consequence of which was that a sanction, suspension, or declaration of ineligibility to participate in an interscholastic or intercollegiate athletic event was imposed on a student-athlete or educational institution; or </section><section prefix="g">Engaged in conduct that significantly adversely reflects on the applicant's credibility, honesty, or integrity. </section></section><section prefix="3">In making a determination under subsection (2) of this section, the office shall consider: <section prefix="a">How recently the conduct occurred; </section><section prefix="b">The nature of the conduct and the context in which it occurred; and </section><section prefix="c">Any other relevant conduct of the applicant. </section></section><section prefix="4">An athlete agent may apply to renew a registration by submitting an application for renewal in a form prescribed by the office. An application filed under this section is a public record. The application for renewal must be signed by the applicant under penalty of perjury and must contain current information on all matters required in an original registration. </section><section prefix="5">An individual who has submitted an application for renewal of registration or licensure in another state, in lieu of submitting an application for renewal in the form prescribed pursuant to subsection (4) of this section, may file a copy of the application for renewal and a valid certificate of registration or licensure from the other state. The office shall accept the application for renewal from the other state as an application for renewal in this state if the application to the other state: <section prefix="a">Was submitted in the other state within six (6) months next preceding the filing in this state and the applicant certifies the information contained in the application for renewal is current; </section><section prefix="b">Contains information substantially similar to or more comprehensive than that required in an application for renewal submitted in this state; and </section><section prefix="c">Was signed by the applicant under penalty of perjury. </section></section><section prefix="6">A certificate of registration or a renewal of registration is valid for one (1) year. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 217, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4392</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>