<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.225</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Horse Racing Commission -- Membership -- Terms -- Compensation -- Office -- Meetings -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Horse Racing Commission is created as an independent agency of state government to regulate the conduct of horse racing and pari-mutuel wagering on horse racing, and related activities within the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The racing commission shall be attached to the Public Protection Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Horse Racing Commission shall consist of fifteen (15) members appointed by the Governor, with the secretaries of the Public Protection Cabinet, Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, and Economic Development Cabinet serving as ex officio, nonvoting members. Two (2) members shall have no financial interest in the business or industry regulated. The members of the racing commission shall be appointed to serve for a term of three (3) years. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring other than by expiration of a term shall be appointed for the remainder of the unexpired term. In making appointments, the Governor may consider members broadly representative of the Thoroughbred industry and members broadly representative of the standardbred, quarter horse, Appaloosa, or Arabian industries. The Governor may also consider recommendations from the Kentucky Thoroughbred Owners and Breeders, Inc., the Kentucky Division of the Horsemen's Benevolent and Protective Association, the Kentucky Harness Horsemen's Association, and other interested organizations. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the racing commission shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each meeting attended and shall be reimbursed for all expenses paid or incurred in the discharge of official business. The Governor shall appoint one (1) member of the racing commission to serve as its chairperson who shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. The Governor shall further designate a second member to serve as vice chair with authority to act in the absence of the chairperson. Before entering upon the discharge of their duties, all members of the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission shall take the constitutional oath of office. </section><section prefix="4">The racing commission shall establish and maintain a general office for the transaction of its business and may in its discretion establish a branch office or offices. The racing commission may hold meetings at any of its offices or at any other place when the convenience of the racing commission requires. All meetings of the racing commission shall be open and public, and all persons shall be permitted to attend meetings. A majority of the voting members of the racing commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of its business or exercise of any of its powers. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided, the racing commission shall be responsible for the following: <section prefix="a">Developing and implementing programs designed to ensure the safety and well-being of horses, jockeys, and drivers; </section><section prefix="b">Developing programs and procedures that will aggressively fulfill its oversight and regulatory role on such matters as medical practices and integrity issues; </section><section prefix="c">Recommending tax incentives and implementing incentive programs to ensure the strength and growth of the equine industry; </section><section prefix="d">Designing and implementing programs that strengthen the ties between Kentucky's horse industry and the state's universities, with the goal of significantly increasing the economic impact of the horse industry on Kentucky's economy, improving research for the purpose of promoting the enhanced health and welfare of the horse, and other related industry issues; and </section><section prefix="e">Developing and supporting programs which ensure that Kentucky remains in the forefront of equine research. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 446, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 58, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>