<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="259" order_by="259">STRAYS AND ANIMALS RUNNING AT LARGE </unit></structure><section_number>259.210</section_number><catch_line>Cattle not to run at large -- Damages -- Lien, impounding -- Powers of cities. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall permit any cattle owned by him or under his control or in his custody, to run at large. </section><section prefix="2">If any damage is committed by cattle permitted to run at large, the owner of the cattle shall be liable for all damages, whether the place where the damages occurred is inclosed by lawful fence or not. The person damaged shall have a lien on the cattle committing the damage for the amount of the damage and cost of suit. </section><section prefix="3">The sheriff or any other peace officer shall impound any cattle found running at large in the county, and the owner or bailee of the cattle shall pay to the officer impounding, for each head impounded, one dollar ($1) and the cost of feeding and taking care of the cattle, but the cost of impounding any number of cattle shall not exceed three dollars ($3) and the cost of feeding. The sheriff or any other peace officer shall have a lien on the cattle impounded for his fees and expenses, which he may enforce in the same manner in which mortgage liens are enforced. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting any powers possessed by cities to regulate cattle running at large. </section></text><history>Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 20, secs. 1 to 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12526</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>