<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.210</section_number><catch_line>Maximum weight permitted on highway. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall operate on a highway any vehicle, object or contrivance, other than a motor truck or semitrailer truck, which weighs more than fifteen (15) tons, including the weight of the vehicle, object or contrivance and load, except as provided by subsection (2). This shall not apply to vehicles run upon tracks or fire apparatus belonging to any municipal or volunteer fire department or used by such a department in the discharge of its functions. </section><section prefix="2">The county judge/executive or the county road engineer of any county upon an application in writing by the owner or person having charge of, may grant permission for the movement of vehicles, objects or structures limited by subsection (1), over the highways within that county and located outside of a city. The permission shall be in writing and the county judge/executive or the county road engineer may grant it subject to such conditions and restrictions as in his judgment are necessary for the preservation and protection of the highways. The city engineer or mayor of any city may in like manner grant permission as to the highways within the city. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4345a-1, 4345a-2. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6322</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>