<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.365</section_number><catch_line>Time for filing certificates and petitions of nomination -- Statement-of-candidacy forms -- Petitions for recall elections or elections on public questions. </catch_line><order_by>365</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Certificates of nomination issued by the State Board of Elections shall be filed by that board with the Secretary of State immediately. The certificates issued by the county board of elections shall be filed by that board with the county clerk immediately. </section><section prefix="2">Petitions of nomination for candidates for city offices except as provided in KRS 83A.047, for candidates for members of boards of education, and for candidates for supervisors of soil and water conservation districts shall be filed with the county clerk not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the office will appear on the ballot and not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day fixed by law for the holding of regular elections for the offices sought. </section><section prefix="3">Candidates for an office, the nomination to which is to be made by a convention pursuant to KRS 118.325(1) and (2), except for the office of electors of President and Vice President of the United States, shall file the statements required by KRS 118.325(3), with the official designated in KRS 118.165 with whom notification and declaration are filed for the office, not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the office will appear on the ballot and not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the regular election for the office sought. </section><section prefix="4">Certificates of nomination made by the governing authority of a political party within the meaning of KRS 118.015 or a political organization not constituting a political party within the meaning of KRS 118.015 but whose candidate received two percent (2%) of the vote of the state at the last preceding election for presidential electors to fill vacancies in office, as provided in KRS 118.115 and 118.325, shall be filed as required with the Secretary of State or county clerk not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the offices will appear on the ballot and not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day fixed by law for the election of the person in nomination. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided in this section, petitions of nomination shall be filed as required with the Secretary of State or county clerk not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the offices will appear on the ballot and not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day fixed by law for the holding of regular elections for the offices sought. Certificates of nomination shall be filed with the Secretary of State or county clerk, as required by law, not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the offices will appear on the ballot and not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day fixed by law for the holding of regular elections for the offices sought. The filing of petitions of nomination for independent, or political organization, or political group candidates shall not be accepted by the Secretary of State or the county clerk if the candidate has not filed a statement-of-candidacy form as required by KRS 118.367. </section><section prefix="6">Petitions and certificates of nomination for electors of President and Vice President of the United States shall be filed with the Secretary of State not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which there is an election for President and Vice President of the United States and not later than the Friday following the first Tuesday in September preceding the date fixed by law for the election of the electors. </section><section prefix="7">Petitions for recall elections or elections on public questions shall be filed as required with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the day fixed by law for holding a regular election. </section><section prefix="8">Petitions of any kind named in this section, statements, and certificates of nomination shall be filed no later than 4 p.m. local time at the place of filing when filed on the last date on which papers are permitted to be filed. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 3, effective April 5, 2007. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 47, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 169, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 305, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1987; and ch. 470, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 185, sec. 21, effective January 2, 1985. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 254, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 122, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>