<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-080</section_number><catch_line>Security covering motor vehicle. </catch_line><order_by>39-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Security covering the vehicle" is the insurance or other security so provided. The vehicle for which the security is so provided is the "secured vehicle." </section><section prefix="2">"Basic reparation insurance" includes a contract, self-insurance, or other legal means under which the obligation to pay basic reparation benefits arises. </section><section prefix="3">This Commonwealth, its political subdivisions, municipal corporations, and public agencies may continuously provide, pursuant to subsection (6) of this section, security for the payment of basic reparation benefits in accordance with this subtitle for injury arising from maintenance or use of motor vehicles owned by those entities and operated with their permission. </section><section prefix="4">The United States and its public agencies and any other state, its political subdivisions, municipal corporation, and public agencies may provide, pursuant to subsection (6) of this section, security for the payment of basic reparation benefits in accordance with this subtitle for injury arising from maintenance or use of motor vehicles owned by those entities and operated with their permission. </section><section prefix="5">Except for entities described in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, every owner or operator of a motor vehicle registered in this Commonwealth or operated in this Commonwealth with an owner's permission shall continuously provide with respect to the motor vehicle while it is either present or registered in this Commonwealth, and any other person may provide with respect to any motor vehicle, by a contract of insurance or by qualifying as a self-insurer, security for the payment of basic reparation benefits in accordance with this subtitle and security for payment of tort liabilities, arising from maintenance or use of the motor vehicle. The owner of a motor vehicle who fails to maintain security on a motor vehicle in accordance with this subsection shall have his or her motor vehicle registration revoked in accordance with KRS 186A.040 and shall be subject to the penalties in KRS 304.99-060. An owner who permits another person to operate a motor vehicle without security on the motor vehicle as required by this subtitle shall be subject to the penalties in KRS 304.99-060. </section><section prefix="6">Security may be provided by a contract of insurance or by qualifying as a self-insurer or obligated government in compliance with this subtitle. </section><section prefix="7">Self-insurance, subject to approval of the commissioner of insurance, is effected by filing with the commissioner in satisfactory form: <section prefix="a">A continuing undertaking by the owner or other appropriate person to pay tort liabilities or basic reparation benefits, or both, and to perform all other obligations imposed by this subtitle; </section><section prefix="b">Evidence that appropriate provision exists for prompt and efficient administration of all claims, benefits, and obligations provided by this subtitle; and </section><section prefix="c">Evidence that reliable financial arrangements, deposits, or commitments exist providing assurance, substantially equivalent to that afforded by a policy of insurance, complying with this subtitle, for payment of tort liabilities, basic reparation benefits, and all other obligations imposed by this subtitle. </section></section><section prefix="8">An entity described in subsection (3) or (4) of this section may provide security by lawfully obligating itself to pay basic reparation benefits in accordance with this subtitle. </section><section prefix="9">A person providing security pursuant to subsection (7) of this section is a "self-insurer." An entity described in subsection (3) or (4) of this section that has provided security pursuant to subsection (6) of this section is an "obligated government." </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1526, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 442, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30032</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>