<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.410</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of articles of incorporation. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A cooperative may amend its articles of incorporation by complying with the following requirements, provided, however, that a change of location of principal office may be effected in the manner set forth in KRS 279.420. The proposed amendment shall be presented to a meeting of the members, the notice of which shall set forth or have attached thereto the proposed amendment. If the proposed amendment, with any changes, is approved by the affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds (2/3) of those members voting thereon at such meeting, articles of amendment shall be executed and acknowledged on behalf of the cooperative by its president or vice president and its seal shall be affixed thereto and attested by its secretary. The articles of amendment shall recite that they are executed pursuant to this section and shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the cooperative; </section><section prefix="b">The address of its principal office; and </section><section prefix="c">The amendment to its articles of incorporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The president or vice president executing such articles of amendment shall make and annex thereto an affidavit stating that the provisions of this section in respect of the amendment set forth in such articles were duly complied with. </section></text><history>Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 11, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 1950 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>