<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.10-020</section_number><catch_line>Amendment by board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>10-020</order_by><text>Unless the articles of incorporation provide otherwise, a corporation's board of directors may adopt one (1) or more amendments to the corporation's articles of incorporation without shareholder action: <section prefix="1">To extend the duration of the corporation if it was incorporated at a time when limited duration was required by law; </section><section prefix="2">To delete the names and addresses of the initial directors; </section><section prefix="3">To delete the name and address of the initial registered agent or registered office, if a statement of change is on file with the Secretary of State; </section><section prefix="4">To delete the mailing address of the corporation's initial principal office if the statement containing the mailing address of new principal office is on file with the Secretary of State; </section><section prefix="5">To change each issued and unissued authorized share of an outstanding class into a greater number of whole shares if the corporation has only shares of that class outstanding; </section><section prefix="6">To change the corporate name by substituting the word "corporation," "incorporated," "company," "limited," or the abbreviation "corp.," "inc.," "co.," or "ltd.," for a similar word or abbreviation in the name, or by adding, deleting, or changing a geographical attribution for the name; or </section><section prefix="7">To make any other change expressly permitted by this chapter to be made without shareholder action. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 104, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13408</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>