<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.700</section_number><catch_line>Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault -- Membership -- Executive committee -- Duties and responsibilities of council -- Administrative and staff assistance.   </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Council on Domestic Violence and Sexual Assault is created and established for the purpose of planning and direction of legal, protection, and support services related to domestic violence and sexual assault, and to increase the awareness of all Kentuckians regarding the prevalence and impact of these crimes. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the council shall include: <section prefix="a">The Attorney General or a designee; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or a designee; </section><section prefix="c">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or a designee; </section><section prefix="d">The public advocate or a designee; </section><section prefix="e">The commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services or a designee; </section><section prefix="f">The executive director of the Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="g">The executive director of the Commission on Women; </section><section prefix="h">At the direction of the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, the director of the Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) Circuit Court Judge, one (1) family court judge, and one (1) District Court Judge, who shall be appointed by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court; </section><section prefix="j">The executive director of the Kentucky Domestic Violence Association; </section><section prefix="k">The president of the Kentucky Domestic Violence Association or a designee; </section><section prefix="l">The executive director of the Kentucky Association of Sexual Assault Programs; </section><section prefix="m">The president of the Kentucky Association of Sexual Assault Programs or a designee; </section><section prefix="n">Two (2) members of the Senate who shall be appointed by the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="o">Three (3) members of the House of Representatives who shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House; and </section><section prefix="p">The following members, who shall be appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. To be eligible for appointment under this paragraph, a person shall have an understanding of, and demonstrated commitment to, addressing crimes involved in domestic or sexual violence: <section prefix="1">One (1) county attorney; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) Commonwealth's attorney; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) Circuit Court Clerk; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) sheriff; </section><section prefix="5">One (1) peace officer; </section><section prefix="6">Two (2) representatives of local domestic violence coordinating councils or sexual assault response teams; </section><section prefix="7">One (1) advocate for adult victims of domestic or sexual violence; </section><section prefix="8">One (1) advocate for child witnesses of domestic or sexual violence; </section><section prefix="9">One (1) physician; </section><section prefix="10">One (1) sexual assault nurse examiner; </section><section prefix="11">One (1) mental health professional with demonstrated expertise in treating offenders; </section><section prefix="12">One (1) employee of the Department for Community Based Services who provides direct services to victims of domestic violence; </section><section prefix="13">One (1) person employed as a probation or parole officer; and </section><section prefix="14">Two (2) citizen at-large members. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall appoint two (2) co-chairs and two (2) vice chairs of the council. One (1) of the vice chairs shall be a council member who is a criminal justice professional. The co-chairs and vice chairs shall serve for a term of one (1) year after which they may be reappointed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="4">Council members shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authority but shall not serve longer than four (4) years without reappointment. Members shall not serve longer than two (2) consecutive four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall establish an executive committee, the membership of which shall be named by the co-chairs of the council. </section><section prefix="6">The duties and responsibilities of the council shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Promoting coordination among agencies and officials responsible for addressing domestic violence and sexual assault; </section><section prefix="b">Determining the availability of services for victims, children who witness domestic violence or sexual assault, and offenders; </section><section prefix="c">Facilitating the development of local domestic violence councils and sexual assault response teams that shall include publication of model protocols, training, and technical assistance; </section><section prefix="d">Promoting community awareness and the prevention of domestic and sexual violence; </section><section prefix="e">Providing assistance to the Attorney General, the Administrative Office of the Courts, the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in the development of training curricula, treatment programs, and model policies related to domestic violence and sexual assault; </section><section prefix="f">Reviewing and analyzing data and information relating to domestic violence and sexual assault from existing sources including but not limited to the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Department of Corrections, and the Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="g">Recommending to the appropriate entity changes in state programs, legislation, administrative regulations, policies, budgets, and treatment and service standards relating to domestic violence and sexual assault; and </section><section prefix="h">Preparing a biennial report to be submitted no later than July 1 of every odd-numbered year to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court. </section></section><section prefix="7">The council shall establish any committees necessary to carry out its duties. </section><section prefix="8">The council shall be attached to the Department for Community Based Services for administrative purposes. Members of the council shall be eligible to receive actual and reasonable travel expenses. </section><section prefix="9">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet and the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide the necessary staff to assist the council in carrying out its duties and responsibilities. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 68, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 304, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 68, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>