<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.525</section_number><catch_line>Licensing requirements -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>525</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue a "professional clinical counselor" license to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">Has paid the application fee and the appropriate examination fee to the board; </section><section prefix="b">Is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">Has received a master's, specialist, or doctoral degree in counseling or a related field from a regionally accredited institution; </section><section prefix="d">Has completed a minimum of sixty (60) graduate semester hours in the following: <section prefix="1">The helping relationship, including counseling theory and practice; </section><section prefix="2">Human growth and development; </section><section prefix="3">Lifestyle and career development; </section><section prefix="4">Group dynamics, process, counseling, and consulting; </section><section prefix="5">Assessment, appraisal, and testing of individuals; </section><section prefix="6">Social and cultural foundations, including multicultural issues; </section><section prefix="7">Principles of etiology, diagnosis, treatment planning, and prevention of mental and emotional disorders and dysfunctional behavior; </section><section prefix="8">Research and evaluation; and </section><section prefix="9">Professional orientation and ethics; </section></section><section prefix="e">Has completed a minimum of four thousand (4,000) hours of experience in the practice of counseling, all of which must have been obtained since obtaining the master's degree and must be under approved supervision and shall include but not be limited to a minimum of one thousand six hundred (1,600) hours of direct counseling with individuals, couples, families, or groups and a minimum of one hundred (100) hours of individual, face-to-face clinical supervision with an approved supervisor. Each applicant is encouraged to include as part of the total hours of experience a minimum of ten (10) hours of direct counseling with individuals in a jail or corrections setting. All applicants shall complete an organized practicum or internship consisting of at least four hundred (400) hours; and </section><section prefix="f">Has achieved passing scores on all portions of the examinations required by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board may issue a "professional counselor associate" license to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">Has completed all requirements under paragraphs (a) to (d) of subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Has not met the requirements of paragraphs (e) or (f) of subsection (1) of this section; and </section><section prefix="c">Has obtained a board-approved supervisor of record. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">On July 15, 2002, a previously certified professional counselor in Kentucky shall be entitled to use the term "licensed professional clinical counselor" and shall be issued a professional clinical counselor license upon annual renewal. </section><section prefix="b">An applicant who has been issued a professional clinical counselor license shall be entitled to use the title "licensed professional clinical counselor." </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">On July 15, 2002, a previously certified professional counselor associate shall be entitled to use the term "licensed professional counselor associate" and shall be issued a professional counselor associate license upon annual renewal. </section><section prefix="b">An applicant who has been issued a professional counselor associate license shall be entitled to use the title "licensed professional counselor associate." </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A licensed professional counselor associate shall maintain ongoing supervision as approved by the board. </section><section prefix="b">A licensed professional counselor associate may apply for the credential of licensed professional clinical counselor upon completion of the hours of experience and passing the examinations required under paragraphs (e) and (f) of subsection (1) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="6">The application fee for licensure and the examination fee shall be established pursuant to administrative regulation promulgated by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 312, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>