<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="383" order_by="383">LANDLORD AND TENANT </unit></structure><section_number>383.560</section_number><catch_line>Notice. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person has notice of a fact if: <section prefix="a">He has actual knowledge of it; </section><section prefix="b">He has received a notice or notification of it; or </section><section prefix="c">From all the facts and circumstances known to him at the time in question he has reason to know that it exists. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person knows or has knowledge of a fact if he has actual knowledge of it. </section><section prefix="3">A person notifies or gives a notice or notification to another person by taking steps reasonably calculated to inform the other in ordinary course whether or not the other actually comes to know of it. A person receives a notice or notification when: <section prefix="a">It comes to his attention; or </section><section prefix="b">In the case of the landlord, it is delivered in writing at the place of business of the landlord through which the rental agreement was made or at any place held out by him as the place for receipt of the communications, or mailed by certified mail to him at his place of business or at any place held out by him as the place for receipt of any communication; </section><section prefix="c">In the case of the tenant, it is delivered in hand to the tenant or mailed by registered or certified mail to him at the place held out by him as the place for receipt of the communication, or in the absence of such designation, to his last known place of residence. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notice, knowledge, or a notice or notification received by an organization is effective for a particular transaction from the time it is brought to the attention of the individual conducting that transaction, and in any event from the time it would have been brought to his attention if the organization had exercised reasonable diligence. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011). The Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in subsection (4) of this statute by changing "Notice, knowledge or a notice or notification received by an organization if effective..." to read "Notice, knowledge, or a notice or notification received by an organization is effective..." under the authority of KRS 7.136 to conform with the text of the Uniform Residential Landlord and Tenant Act, Section 1.304(c) from which it was derived. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>