<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.240</section_number><catch_line>Examinations -- Rating -- Eligible list -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The civil service commission shall prescribe and propound such said examinations as are proper, commensurate with vacant positions within the various departments of the urban-county government, according to classification prescribed by ordinance, shall set such times and places for holding examinations as may be proper and shall give public notice of vacancies by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, and shall give actual notice to all eligible applicants of time and place of examinations. Provided, however, that the civil service commission may prescribe and propound job descriptions which reasonably establish minimum qualifications and standards for eligibility to take such examinations, but in no event shall such job descriptions be a subterfuge for the evasion of the requirement that employment be determined on the basis of the principles set out herein. </section><section prefix="2">The civil service commission shall, as soon after examinations as is practicable, certify to the appointing authority, a list of the applicants so examined, with the one having the highest average ranked first, and all others ranked numerically according to the result of the examination. After the compilation of such a list the commission may provide for further, substantially identical examinations, given on the same basis as the original examination, to supplement the list so compiled, and the results of each such subsequent examination shall be consolidated with the results of the prior examinations to provide an eligible list from among all of those who have taken such several examinations. </section><section prefix="3">Every soldier, sailor, marine, members of the air forces, Army Nurses Corps and members of other branches of the military services and Red Cross nurses who served during a period of hostilities between the United States and another power in World War II, the Korean or Vietnam conflict, the Persian Gulf War, Operation Iraqi Freedom, or Operation Enduring Freedom, who has not been dishonorably discharged, and who is an applicant for any position of civil service of the urban-county government shall be entitled to five percent (5%) increase on his examination mark on entrance into civil service employment. </section><section prefix="4">The civil service commission of urban-county governments shall maintain an eligible list of all individuals who, based on the outcome of examinations, are qualified for each position to be filled. </section><section prefix="5">The legislative body may designate certain civil service positions and prescribe that for such positions the examinations shall first be given exclusively to current employees; provided, however, that if no employee with a minimum of six (6) months' seniority achieves a passing grade, an examination shall be held in accordance with subsection (1) of this section, and shall be held, if less than five (5) such persons achieve a passing grade if the appointing authority so determines. </section><section prefix="6">Upon the approval of the civil service commission, the appointing authority may promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 4, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42592</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>