<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.070</section_number><catch_line>Protection of another. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when: <section prefix="a">The defendant believes that such force is necessary to protect a third person against the use or imminent use of unlawful physical force by the other person; and </section><section prefix="b">Under the circumstances as the defendant believes them to be, the person whom he seeks to protect would himself have been justified under KRS 503.050 and 503.060 in using such protection. </section></section><section prefix="2">The use of deadly physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when: <section prefix="a">The defendant believes that such force is necessary to protect a third person against imminent death, serious physical injury, kidnapping, sexual intercourse compelled by force or threat, or other felony involving the use of force, or under those circumstances permitted pursuant to KRS 503.055; and </section><section prefix="b">Under the circumstances as they actually exist, the person whom he seeks to protect would himself have been justified under KRS 503.050 and 503.060 in using such protection. </section></section><section prefix="3">A person does not have a duty to retreat if the person is in a place where he or she has a right to be. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 32, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>