<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.731</section_number><catch_line>General standards of conduct -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>731</order_by><text>A legislator, by himself or through others, shall not intentionally: <section prefix="1">Use or attempt to use his influence as a member of the General Assembly in any matter which involves a substantial conflict between his personal interest and his duties in the public interest. Violation of this subsection is a Class A misdemeanor; </section><section prefix="2">Use his official position or office to obtain financial gain for himself, any members of the legislator's family, or a business associate of the legislator. Violation of this subsection is a Class D felony; </section><section prefix="3">Use or attempt to use his official position to secure or create privileges, exemptions, advantages, or treatment for himself or others in direct contravention of the public interest at large. Violation of this subsection is a Class A misdemeanor; </section><section prefix="4">Use public funds, time, or personnel for his private gain or that of another, unless the use is authorized by law. Violation of this subsection is a Class A misdemeanor; </section><section prefix="5">Use public funds, time, or personnel for partisan political campaign activity, unless the use is: <section prefix="a">Authorized by law; or </section><section prefix="b">Properly incidental to another activity required or authorized by law, such as elections to constitutional or party offices within the General Assembly. Violation of this subsection is a Class A misdemeanor; </section></section><section prefix="6">Use his official legislative stationery, or a facsimile thereof, to solicit a vote or a contribution for his or another person's campaign for election or reelection to public office, or use the great seal of the Commonwealth on his campaign stationery or campaign literature. For purposes of this subsection, "official legislative stationery" means the stationery used by a legislator on a day-to-day basis for correspondence related to his duties as a member of the General Assembly. Violation of this subsection is ethical misconduct. </section><section prefix="7">While in the discharge of the duties of his office, become intoxicated by the use of spiritous, vinous, or malt liquors, or any controlled substance, as defined in KRS 218A.010. Any legislator who is unable, incompetent, or disqualified to discharge any of the duties of his office because of the use of spiritous, vinous, or malt liquors, or any controlled substance, as defined in KRS 218A.010, shall be deemed to have violated this subsection. Violation of this subsection is ethical misconduct. </section></text><history>Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 6, effective September 16, 1993. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 420, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><former-codification> KRS 6.775. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=366</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>