<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.100</section_number><catch_line>Persons who may not be licensed. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>A natural person shall not become a licensee under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 if he or she: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Has been convicted of any felony until five (5) years have passed from the date of conviction, release from custody or incarceration, parole, or termination of probation, whichever is later; </section><section prefix="b">Has been convicted of any misdemeanor described under KRS 218A.050, 218A.060, 218A.070, 218A.080, 218A.090, 218A.100, 218A.110, 218A.120, or 218A.130 in the two (2) years immediately preceding the application; </section><section prefix="c">Has been convicted of any misdemeanor directly or indirectly attributable to the use of alcoholic beverages in the two (2) years immediately preceding the application; </section><section prefix="d">Is under the age of twenty-one (21) years; </section><section prefix="e">Has had any license issued under this statute relating to the regulation of the manufacture, sale, and transportation of alcoholic beverages revoked for cause or has been convicted of a violation of any such statute, until the expiration of two (2) years from the date of the revocation or conviction; or </section><section prefix="f">Is not a citizen of the United States and has not had an actual, bona fide residence in this state for at least one (1) year before the date on which his or her application for a license is made. This subsection shall not apply to applicants for manufacturers' licenses, to applicants that are corporations authorized to do business in this state, or to persons licensed on March 7, 1938. </section></section><section prefix="2">A partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, corporation, or governmental agency shall not be licensed if: <section prefix="a">Each member of the partnership or each of the directors, principal officers, or managers does not qualify under subsection (1)(a), (b), (c), and (d) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">It has had any license issued under this statute relating to the regulation of the manufacture, sale, and transportation of alcoholic beverages revoked for cause or has been convicted of a violation of any such statute, until the expiration of two (2) years from the date of the revocation or conviction; or </section><section prefix="c">It is a partnership or corporation, if any member of the partnership or any director, manager, or principal officer of the corporation has had any license issued under any statute relating to the regulation of the manufacture, sale, and transportation of alcoholic beverages, revoked for cause or has been convicted of a violation of any such statute, until the expiration of the later of two (2) years from the date of the revocation or two (2) years from the date of conviction. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of subsection (1)(a) and (b) shall apply to anyone applying for a new license under this chapter after July 15, 1998, but shall not apply to those who renew a license that was originally issued prior to July 15, 1998, or an application for a supplemental license where the original license was issued prior to July 15, 1998. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 12a. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-154. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43017</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>