<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.597</section_number><catch_line>Agreement of affiliation between county and crime stoppers organization -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>597</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any crime stoppers organization that enters into a written agreement of affiliation, as provided in subsection (2) of this section, with a county in which the organization operates shall be funded in part by a one dollar ($1) fee added to court costs in that county. The fee shall be imposed on every person who is: <section prefix="a">Convicted of any misdemeanor or violation, other than a violation of KRS Chapters 186, 187, 188, 189, or 189A; and </section><section prefix="b">Sentenced to pay a fine for the misdemeanor or violation, regardless of whether the person is also incarcerated, or whether the fine is suspended, waived, or otherwise not imposed. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any crime stoppers organization may enter into a written agreement of affiliation, approved by a fiscal court or urban-county council, with any county, or with any number of counties, in which the organization operates. Agreements of affiliation shall be valid for two (2) years and may be renewed. The agreements shall specify: <section prefix="a">The relationship between the crime stoppers organization, the county, and law enforcement agencies in the county; and </section><section prefix="b">That the crime stoppers organization shall account annually to the fiscal court or urban-county council for all funds raised by the organization from all sources and all funds expended by the organization for any purpose. The agreement shall allow the crime stoppers organization to identify the sources of funds raised generically rather than by name. The agreement shall not require the crime stoppers organization to divulge the amounts of individual rewards paid nor the identity of any person to whom a reward was paid. </section></section><section prefix="3">In every county where an agreement of affiliation is approved, the county clerk shall notify the circuit clerk to collect the fee required by this section. The circuit clerk shall collect the fee for two (2) years from the date the agreement was signed. When the circuit clerk pays fines and costs over to the state, the circuit clerk shall pay all money collected under this section to the crime stoppers organization named in the agreement. </section><section prefix="4">The crime stoppers fee shall not be waived or suspended.  Failure to pay the fee shall be treated as a failure to pay a fine under KRS Chapter 534. </section><section prefix="5">Crime stoppers organizations may use the funds they receive under this section for any purpose authorized by KRS 431.575. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18648</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>