<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Automobile utility trailer" means any trailer or semitrailer designed for use with and towed behind a passenger motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">"Automobile utility trailer certificate" means a certificate authorizing a person to engage in the business of automobile utility trailer lessor; </section><section prefix="3">"Automobile utility trailer lessor" means any person operating under an automobile utility trailer certificate who is engaged in the business of leasing or renting automobile utility trailers, but shall not include the agents of such persons; </section><section prefix="4">"Broker" means a person selected by the cabinet through a request for proposal process to coordinate human service transportation delivery within a specific delivery area. A broker may also provide transportation services within the specific delivery area for which the broker is under contract with the cabinet; </section><section prefix="5">"Bus" means a motor vehicle operating under a bus certificate transporting passengers for hire between points over regular routes; </section><section prefix="6">"Bus certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more buses; </section><section prefix="7">"Cabinet" means the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="8">"Certificate" means a certificate of compliance issued under this chapter to motor carriers; </section><section prefix="9">"Charter bus" means a motor vehicle operating under a charter bus certificate providing for-hire intrastate transportation of a group of persons who, pursuant to a common purpose under a single contract at a fixed charge for the motor vehicle, have acquired the exclusive use of the motor vehicle to travel together under an itinerary either specified in advance or modified after having left the place of origin; </section><section prefix="10">"Charter bus certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more charter buses; </section><section prefix="11">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation; </section><section prefix="12">"CTAC" means the Coordinated Transportation Advisory Committee created in KRS 281.870; </section><section prefix="13">"Department" means the Department of Vehicle Regulation; </section><section prefix="14">"Delivery area" means one (1) or more regions established by the cabinet in administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A for the purpose of providing human service transportation delivery in that region; </section><section prefix="15">"Disabled persons vehicle carrier" means a motor carrier for hire, transporting passengers including the general public who require transportation in disabled persons vehicles; </section><section prefix="16">"Disabled persons vehicle" means a motor vehicle operating under a disabled persons vehicle certificate especially equipped for the transportation of passengers with disabilities in accordance with 49 C.F.R. pt. 38, and is designed or constructed with not more than fifteen (15) regular seats. It shall not mean an ambulance as defined in KRS 311A.010. It shall not mean a motor vehicle equipped with a stretcher; </section><section prefix="17">"Disabled persons vehicle certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more disabled persons vehicles transporting passengers for hire; </section><section prefix="18">"Driveaway" means the transporting and delivering of motor vehicles, except semitrailers and trailers, whether destined to be used in either a private or for-hire capacity, under their own power or by means of a full mount method, saddle mount method, the tow bar method, or any combination of them over the highways of this state from any point of origin to any point of destination for hire. "Driveaway" does not include the transportation of such vehicles by the full mount method on trailers or semitrailers; </section><section prefix="19">"Driveaway certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more motor carrier vehicles operating as a driveaway; </section><section prefix="20">"Driver" means the person physically operating the motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="21">"Highway" means all public roads, highways, streets, and ways in this state, whether within a municipality or outside of a municipality; </section><section prefix="22">"Household goods" has the same meaning as in 49 C.F.R. sec. 375.103; </section><section prefix="23">"Household goods carrier" has the same meaning as "household goods motor carrier" in 49 C.F.R. sec. 375.103; </section><section prefix="24">"Household goods certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more household goods vehicles; </section><section prefix="25">"Human service transportation delivery" means the provision of transportation services to any person that is an eligible recipient in one (1) of the following state programs: <section prefix="a">Nonemergency medical transportation under KRS Chapter 205; </section><section prefix="b">Mental health, intellectual disabilities, or comprehensive care under KRS Chapter 202A, 202B, 210, or 645; </section><section prefix="c">Work programs for public assistance recipients under KRS Chapter 205; </section><section prefix="d">Adult services under KRS Chapter 205, 209, 216, or 273; </section><section prefix="e">Vocational rehabilitation under KRS Chapter 151B or 157; or </section><section prefix="f">Blind industries or rehabilitation under KRS Chapter 151B or 163; </section></section><section prefix="26">"Interstate commerce" has the same meaning as in 49 C.F.R. sec. 390.5; </section><section prefix="27">"Intrastate commerce" has the same meaning as in 49 C.F.R. sec. 390.5; </section><section prefix="28">"Limousine" means a motor vehicle operating under a limousine certificate that is designed or constructed with not more than fifteen (15) regular seats; </section><section prefix="29">"Limousine certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more limousines transporting passengers for hire; </section><section prefix="30">"Mobile application" means an application or a computer program designed to run on a smartphone, tablet computer, or other mobile device that is used by a TNC to connect drivers with potential passengers; </section><section prefix="31">"Motor carrier" means any person in either a private or for-hire capacity who owns, controls, operates, manages, or leases, except persons leasing to authorized motor carriers, any motor vehicle for the transportation of passengers or property upon any highway, and any person who engages in the business of automobile utility trailer lessor, driveaway, or U-Drive-It; </section><section prefix="32">"Motor carrier vehicle" means a motor vehicle used by a motor carrier to transport passengers or property; </section><section prefix="33">"Motor carrier vehicle license" means a license issued by the department for a motor carrier vehicle authorized to operate under a certificate; </section><section prefix="34">"Motor carrier license plate" means a license plate issued by the department to a motor carrier authorized to operate under a certificate other than a household goods, property, TNC, or U-Drive-It certificate; </section><section prefix="35">"Motor vehicle" means any motor-propelled vehicle used for the transportation of passengers or property on a public highway, including any such vehicle operated as a unit in combination with other vehicles; </section><section prefix="36">"Passenger" means an individual or group of people; </section><section prefix="37">"Permit" means a temporary permit of compliance issued under this chapter for a specified period not to exceed ten (10) days, and for a specific vehicle, to any motor carrier, including one who is a nonresident of the Commonwealth, who operates a motor vehicle and is not entitled to an exemption from the payment of fees imposed under KRS 186.050 because of the terms of a reciprocal agreement between the Commonwealth and the state in which the vehicle is licensed; </section><section prefix="38">"Person" means any individual, firm, partnership, corporation, company, association, or joint stock association, and includes any trustee, assignee, or personal representative thereof; </section><section prefix="39">"Prearranged ride" means the period of time that begins when a transportation network company driver accepts a requested ride through a digital network or mobile application, continues while the driver transports the rider in a personal vehicle, and ends when the transportation network company services end; </section><section prefix="40">"Pre-trip acceptance liability policy" means the transportation network company liability insurance coverage for incidents involving the driver for a period of time when a driver is logged into a transportation network company's digital network or mobile application but is not engaged in a prearranged ride; </section><section prefix="41">"Property" means general or specific commodities, including hazardous and nonhazardous materials; </section><section prefix="42">"Property certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the transportation of property, other than household goods, not exempt under KRS 281.605; </section><section prefix="43">"Regular route" means the scheduled transportation of passengers between designated points over designated routes under time schedules that provide a regularity of services; </section><section prefix="44">"Regular seat" means a seat ordinarily and customarily used by one (1) passenger and, in determining such seating capacity, the manufacturer's rating may be considered; </section><section prefix="45">"Street hail" means a request for service made by a potential passenger using hand gestures or verbal statement; </section><section prefix="46">"Subcontractor" means a person who has signed a contract with a broker to provide human service transportation delivery within a specific delivery area and who meets human service transportation delivery requirements, including proper operating authority; </section><section prefix="47">"Tariff" means the listing of compensation received by a motor carrier for household goods that includes the manner in which and the amount of fares an authorized motor carrier may charge; </section><section prefix="48">"Taxicab" means a motor vehicle operating under a taxicab certificate that is designed or constructed with not more than eight (8) regular seats and may be equipped with a taximeter; </section><section prefix="49">"Taxicab certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more taxicabs transporting passengers for hire; </section><section prefix="50">"Taximeter" means an instrument or device approved by the department that automatically calculates and plainly indicates the charge to a passenger for hire who is being charged on the basis of mileage; </section><section prefix="51">"Transportation network company" or "TNC" means a person or entity that connects passengers through its digital network or mobile application to its drivers for the provision of transportation network company services; </section><section prefix="52">"Transportation network company certificate" or "TNC certificate" means a certificate granting the authority for the operation of one (1) or more transportation network company vehicles transporting passengers for hire; </section><section prefix="53">"Transportation network company driver" or "TNC driver" means an individual who operates a motor vehicle that is owned or leased by the individual, or a motor vehicle for which the driver is an insured driver and has the permission of the owner or lessee of the motor vehicle, and used to provide transportation network company services; </section><section prefix="54">"Transportation network company service" or "TNC service" means a prearranged passenger transportation service offered or provided through the use of a transportation network company mobile application or digital network to connect potential passengers with transportation network company drivers; </section><section prefix="55">"Transportation network company vehicle" or "TNC vehicle" means a privately owned or leased motor vehicle, designed or constructed with not more than eight (8) regular seats, operating under a transportation network company certificate; </section><section prefix="56">"U-Drive-It" means any person operating under a U-Drive-It certificate who leases or rents a motor vehicle for consideration to be used for the transportation of persons or property, but for which no driver is furnished, and the use of which motor vehicle is not for the transportation of persons or property for hire by the lessee or rentee; and </section><section prefix="57">"U-Drive-It certificate" means a certificate granting authority for the operation of one (1) or more U-Drive-Its. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 5, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(2). -- Repealed and reenacted 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 1. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 7, effective June 15, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 57, effective June 15, 1950. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739j-1, 2739j-42, 2739j-94, 27391-9, 2730o-1. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 281.010: </former-history-former-name><lrc-note> (3/16/2011).  The Reviser of Statutes has corrected the form of a citation to "49 C.F.R. sec. 390.5" in this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44150</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>