<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.010</section_number><catch_line>Statute of frauds -- Contracts to be written. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>No action shall be brought to charge any person: <section prefix="1">For any representation or assurance concerning the character, conduct, credit, ability, trade, or dealings of another, made with intent that such other may obtain thereby credit, money, or goods; </section><section prefix="2">Upon any promise to pay a debt contracted during infancy, or any ratification of a contract or promise made during infancy; </section><section prefix="3">Upon any promise of a personal representative as such to answer any liability of his decedent out of his own estate; </section><section prefix="4">Upon any promise to answer for the debt, default, or misdoing of another; </section><section prefix="5">Upon any agreement made in consideration of marriage, except mutual promises to marry; </section><section prefix="6">Upon any contract for the sale of real estate, or any lease thereof for longer than one year; </section><section prefix="7">Upon any agreement that is not to be performed within one year from the making thereof; </section><section prefix="8">Upon any promise, agreement, or contract for any commission or compensation for the sale or lease of any real estate or for assisting another in the sale or lease of any real estate; or </section><section prefix="9">Upon any promise, contract, agreement, undertaking, or commitment to loan money, to grant, extend, or renew credit, or make any financial accommodation to establish or assist a business enterprise or an existing business enterprise including, but not limited to the purchase of realty or real property, but this subsection shall not apply to agreements pursuant to which credit is extended by means of a credit card or similar device, or to consumer credit transactions; </section>unless the promise, contract, agreement, representation, assurance, or ratification, or some memorandum or note thereof, be in writing and signed by the party to be charged therewith, or by his authorized agent. It shall not be necessary to express the consideration in the writing, but it may be proved when necessary or disproved by parol or other evidence. </text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 470. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>