<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.705</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of students' education records -- Procedures for protection and preservation of education records and recordings of school activities.   </catch_line><order_by>705</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Education records of students in the public educational institutions in this state are deemed confidential and shall not be disclosed, or the contents released, except under the circumstances described in KRS 160.720. </section><section prefix="2">School officials shall take precautions to protect and preserve all education records, including records generated and stored in the education technology system. School officials shall: <section prefix="a">Retain for a minimum period of one (1) week a master copy of any digital, video, or audio recordings of school activities without editing, altering, or destroying any portion of the recordings, although secondary copies of the master copy may be edited; and </section><section prefix="b">Retain for a minimum of one (1) month in an appropriate format, a master copy of any digital, video, or audio recordings of activities that include, or allegedly include, injury to students or school employees without editing, altering, or destroying any portion of the recordings. </section></section><section prefix="3">Recordings of school activities shall be subject to privacy and confidentiality requirements as provided in this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>