<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.121</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of certificate or report. </catch_line><order_by>121</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A certificate or report registered under this chapter may be amended only in accordance with this section and administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet to protect the integrity and accuracy of vital records. </section><section prefix="2">A certificate or report that is amended under this section shall be marked "amended," except as otherwise provided in this section. The date of amendment and a summary description of the evidence submitted in support of the amendment shall be endorsed on or made a part of the record. The cabinet shall prescribe by administrative regulation the conditions under which additions or minor corrections may be made to certificates or records within one (1) year after the date of the event without the certificate or record being marked "amended." </section><section prefix="3">Upon written request of both parents and receipts of a sworn acknowledgment of paternity signed by both parents of a child born to an unmarried woman, the state registrar shall amend the certificate of birth to show the paternity, if paternity is not already shown on the certificate of birth. The certificate shall not be marked "amended." </section><section prefix="4">Upon receipt of a certified copy of an order of a court changing the name of a person born in the Commonwealth and upon request of the person or the person's parents, guardian, or legal representative, the state registrar shall amend the certificate of birth to show the new name. </section><section prefix="5">Upon receipt of a sworn statement by a licensed physician indicating that the gender of an individual born in the Commonwealth has been changed by surgical procedure and a certified copy of an order of a court of competent jurisdiction changing that individual's name, the certificate of birth of the individual shall be amended as prescribed by regulation to reflect the change. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 23, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8741</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>