<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.030</section_number><catch_line>Functions of experiment station. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The experiment station shall make field experiments in order to ascertain by chemical and physical examination of soils and by direct experiments in laboratory and fields what crops and treatment are best suited to each type of soil, whether the present methods are tending to best results and to the preservation or reduction of fertility, what rotation and treatment will be most effective in retaining productive capacities of the soils of the various sections of the state and discover and demonstrate the best methods of marketing of fruits and vegetables.  </section><section prefix="2">It shall conduct investigations calculated to develop the beef, pork and mutton producing interests of the state, and especially feeding experiments intended to demonstrate the most successful combination of stock foods, discovering, if possible, the most economical and successful methods of maintaining animals and fitting them for the market. It shall also conduct pathological investigations and investigate livestock conditions both at home and abroad, in so far as they affect market values.  </section><section prefix="3">It shall conduct investigations for the purpose of developing the dairy interests of the state and undertake feeding experiments for production of milk and butter and the rearing of calves. It shall also study contagious diseases for the purpose of finding remedies for those diseases.  </section><section prefix="4">It shall conduct investigations for the purpose of developing the horse interests of the state, and study the best methods of feeding and breeding, and diseases.  </section><section prefix="5">It shall conduct experiments for the advancement of the poultry interests of the state and the economical production of poultry and eggs, including experiments in breeding for egg production and methods best adapted for hatching and raising of chicks.  </section><section prefix="6">It shall bring the scientific knowledge which it obtains concerning agriculture and home economics, to the farm and home by means of personal visitation, correspondence, cooperative demonstrations and experiments and the solution of local problems by station experts visiting the locality and studying the problems of the farm and home.  </section><section prefix="7">It shall conduct research and investigations for the purpose of advancing the development of a market for the commercial production of earthworms, including their potential for use in the areas of waste disposal and land reclamation.  </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4636f-1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11576</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>