<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.330</section_number><catch_line>Permit required for auction or community sale of baby chicks or poults -- Application -- Fee -- Inspection -- Destruction of diseased chicks or poults. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before any baby chicks or baby poults are offered for sale at any auction or auctions, sale barn, or community sale, except public sales conducted by farmers selling baby chicks or baby poults reared on their own premises, a permit shall be secured from the Division of Animal Health of the Department of Agriculture, or the state veterinarian. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who desires to offer baby chicks or baby poults for sale at any auction or auctions, sale barn, or community sale, shall apply to the division or the state veterinarian for a permit to hold the sale. A form shall be prescribed and furnished by the division. This application shall be submitted at least three (3) days before the sale to allow time for inspection of the chicks or poults offered, by a representative of the division or the state veterinarian before any chicks or poults are sold. This application shall be signed by the person who proposes to conduct the sale, together with the person who owns the property in or on which the sale is to be conducted, if the person who proposes to conduct the sale does not own the property. The application shall designate the date of the proposed sale, the number and breed of the chicks or poults to be offered for sale, and the person or firm by whom they were produced, and shall be accompanied by a fee in the sum of one dollar ($1) per hundred (100) chicks or poults to be offered for sale. The division or the state veterinarian shall be authorized in their discretion to grant or to deny the permit requested in the application, and if deemed necessary or advisable to require the applicant to submit a certificate in a form as the division or the state veterinarian may prescribe, certifying that the baby chicks or baby poults which may be offered for sale are in healthy condition. </section><section prefix="3">On inspection by the representative of the division or state veterinarian, if the chicks or poults offered for sale are found to be diseased, the representative may confiscate all chicks or poults found to be diseased and may destroy the chicks and poults. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 103, secs. 1, 2, and 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>