<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.070</section_number><catch_line>Contracts for buildings, improvements, and materials to be let on competitive bidding -- When advertisements not required. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text>The contracts for the erection of new school buildings, additions and repairs to old buildings, except additions or repairs not exceeding seven thousand five hundred dollars ($7,500), shall be made by the board of education with the lowest and best responsible bidder complying with the terms of the letting, after advertisement for competitive bids pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, but the board may reject any or all bids. All necessary specifications and drawings shall be prepared for all such work. The board shall advertise for bids on all supplies and equipment that it desires to purchase, except where the amount of the purchase does not exceed seven thousand five hundred dollars ($7,500), and shall accept the bid of the lowest and best bidder taking into consideration the price and the reciprocal preference for resident bidders under KRS 45A.494, but the board may reject any and all bids. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 252, effective July 13, 1990. -- Reenacted 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 106, effective January 1, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 148. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-48. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 162.070:</former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4032</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>