<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.090</section_number><catch_line>State fair board -- Membership -- Vacancies. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Fair Board shall be composed of fifteen (15) members, as follows: <section prefix="a">The Governor; </section><section prefix="b">The Commissioner; </section><section prefix="c">The dean of the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Nine (9) members appointed from the state at large by the Governor with due consideration to geographical distribution throughout the state; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member appointed by the Governor selected from a list provided by the Kentucky Association of Fairs and Horse Shows of six (6) eligible members of the association; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member shall be appointed from the state at large by the President of the Senate of the Kentucky General Assembly and one (1) member shall be appointed from the state at large by the Speaker of the House of Representatives of the Kentucky General Assembly. </section></section><section prefix="2">The terms of the appointed members of the board shall be for four (4) years, dating from the beginning of the terms for which they were respectively appointed, and until their successors are appointed and qualify. As the terms of each group of members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify. Beginning with the appointments to be made for the terms commencing December 12, 1948, one (1) member of the first group of successor members to be appointed shall be appointed from a list of six (6) nominees consisting of three (3) names from each of the two (2) political parties polling the largest number of votes in the state at general elections submitted to the Governor by the governing body of the Kentucky Livestock Improvement Association, and beginning December 12, 1972, one (1) member of the first group shall be appointed from a list of six (6) nominees so submitted by the governing body of the Kentucky State National Farmers Organization; one (1) member of the second such group shall be appointed from a list of six (6) nominees so submitted by the governing body of the American Saddle Horse Breeders Association; and one (1) member of the third group shall be appointed from a list of six (6) nominees so submitted by the governing body of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation. It is the intention of the General Assembly that the political affiliation of the appointed members shall be as evenly divided as possible between the two (2) political parties polling the largest number of votes in the state at general elections. </section><section prefix="3">In case of a vacancy among the appointed members of the board, the unexpired term so occurring shall be filled pursuant to the requirements and procedures for original appointments. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 454, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 4; and ch. 62, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618i-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11587</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>