<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.715</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees -- Selection -- Terms -- Officers -- Removal of appointed members. </catch_line><order_by>715</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon creation of a subdivision road district as provided in KRS 179.700 to 179.735, the affairs of the district shall be conducted by the board of trustees consisting of seven (7) members, four (4) to be elected by the residents of the district as hereinafter set out and three (3) to be appointed by the county judge/executive. Four (4) members of the board of trustees shall be elected by the residents of the subdivision road district and shall be residents and property owners of the district. The county judge/executive of the county in which the greater part of the district is located shall, with approval of the fiscal court, appoint three (3) members of the board of trustees, who shall reside in a county in which the district is located. At the first election held after the district is formed, two (2) residents and property owners of the district shall be elected to serve on the board of trustees for a period of two (2) years and two (2) for a period of four (4) years. On the expiration of the respective terms, the successor to each shall have the same qualifications as his predecessor and shall be elected for a term of four (4) years. In the event of a vacancy in the term of an elected trustee, the remaining elected trustees shall elect a trustee to fill the vacancy for the balance of the term. The original appointed members of the board of trustees shall be appointed for terms of one (1), two (2), and three (3) years respectively; and on the expiration of their respective terms, the successor to each shall have the same qualifications as his predecessor and shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. In the event of a vacancy in the term of an appointed trustee, the county judge/executive shall appoint a trustee for the remainder of the term. </section><section prefix="2">The elective offices of members of the board of trustees shall be filled by an election to be held once each year on a date determined by the county judge/executive. The polls shall be located at the principal voting location in the district. The date, time, and place of the election shall be advertised in accordance with KRS 424.120. This notice shall be advertised at least thirty (30) days prior to the election date and shall include the names and addresses of the candidates to be voted on for each position of trustee. The terms of the three (3) trustees appointed by the county judge/executive shall start at the same time as the term of the elected trustees. The terms of the trustees shall begin on the beginning of the fiscal year or calendar year, depending on which basis the subdivision road district is being operated. </section><section prefix="3">Such trustees shall elect from their number a chairman, a secretary, and a treasurer, the latter of whom shall give bond in such amount as shall be determined by the county judge/executive of the county in which the greater part of the subdivision road district is located, conditioned upon the faithful discharge of the duties of his office, and the faithful accounting for all funds which may come into his possession as such treasurer. The premiums on such bonds shall be paid out of the funds of the district. </section><section prefix="4">An appointed member of the board of trustees may be removed pursuant to KRS 65.007. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5526</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>