<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-958</section_number><catch_line>Filings required for merger -- Effective date. </catch_line><order_by>2-958</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After a plan of merger is approved by each domestic or foreign partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, or corporation that is a party to the merger, the surviving domestic or foreign partnership, limited partnership, limited liability company, or corporation shall deliver to the Secretary of State for filing articles of merger duly executed by each party to the merger setting forth: <section prefix="a">The name and jurisdiction of formation or organization of each constituent business entity which is to merge; </section><section prefix="b">The plan of merger; </section><section prefix="c">The name of the surviving business entity; </section><section prefix="d">A statement that the plan of merger was duly authorized and approved by each constituent business entity in accordance with the laws applicable to such business entity; and </section><section prefix="e">If the surviving entity is not a business entity organized under the laws of this Commonwealth, a statement that the surviving business entity: <section prefix="1">Agrees that it may be served with process in this Commonwealth in any proceeding for enforcement of any obligation of any constituent business entity party to the merger that was organized under the laws of this Commonwealth, as well as for enforcement of any obligation of the surviving business entity arising from the merger; and </section><section prefix="2">Appoints the Secretary of State as its agent for service of process in any such proceedings. The surviving entity shall specify the address to which a copy of process shall be mailed to it by the Secretary of State. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The merger shall take effect on the later of the date of the filing of the articles of merger or the date set forth in the articles of merger, in which case it shall not be later than ninety (90) days after the date on which the articles of merger were filed. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the merger taking effect, if the surviving entity in the merger is a foreign partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company, the entity shall be deemed: <section prefix="a">To appoint the Secretary of State as its agent for service of process in a proceeding to enforce any obligation or rights of dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation party to the merger; and </section><section prefix="b">To agree that it will promptly pay to the dissenting shareholders of each domestic corporation party to the merger the amount, if any, to which they are entitled under Subtitle 13 of KRS Chapter 271B. </section></section><section prefix="4">The articles of merger filed by the surviving entity in accordance with this section shall also be deemed to have been filed for any domestic limited liability company party to the merger in accordance with the applicable provisions of KRS Chapter 275 and for any domestic corporation party to the merger in accordance with KRS Chapter 271B. </section><section prefix="5">The filing of articles of merger shall act to cancel the certificate of limited partnership for a domestic limited partnership that is not the surviving entity of the merger and that partnership's certificate of limited partnership shall be canceled upon the effective date of the articles of merger. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 162, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 162, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 183, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><former-codification>KRS 362.2-1108. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41522</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>