<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.2256</section_number><catch_line>TRICARE supplement insurance for public employees.   </catch_line><order_by>2256</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this section shall take effect to the extent that they are not preempted by 10 U.S.C. sec. 1097c, other federal law, or federal regulation. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"TRICARE" means the Department of Defense health care program for active duty and retired uniformed service members and their families; and </section><section prefix="b">"Employee" has the same meaning as in KRS 18A.225. </section></section><section prefix="3">Beginning with plan year 2009, the Personnel Cabinet, Department of Employee Insurance, shall select and contract with one (1) or more providers to offer a group TRICARE supplement product to eligible employees who are eligible TRICARE beneficiaries. </section><section prefix="4">The Commonwealth of Kentucky shall pay the cost of individual TRICARE supplement insurance to cover the employee, not to exceed the cost of the lowest-priced individual plan offered to public employees. The employee shall pay the cost of coverage for his or her spouse and dependent children. </section><section prefix="5">Those employees eligible for TRICARE insurance who elect the Commonwealth of Kentucky-sponsored TRICARE supplement insurance shall not be eligible for other coverage offered through the Public Employee Health Insurance Program. Those employees eligible for TRICARE insurance who choose not to elect the Commonwealth of Kentucky-sponsored TRICARE supplement insurance shall continue to be eligible for the coverage offered through the Public Employee Health Insurance Program. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40099</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>