<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.3-404</section_number><catch_line>Impostors -- Fictitious payees. </catch_line><order_by>3-404</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an impostor, by use of the mails or otherwise, induces the issuer of an instrument to issue the instrument to the impostor, or to a person acting in concert with the impostor, by impersonating the payee of the instrument or a person authorized to act for the payee, an indorsement of the instrument by any person in the name of the payee is effective as the indorsement of the payee in favor of a person who, in good faith, pays the instrument or takes it for value or for collection. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If: <section prefix="1">A person whose intent determines to whom an instrument is payable (KRS 355.3-110(1) or (2)) does not intend the person identified as payee to have any interest in the instrument; or </section><section prefix="2">The person identified as payee of an instrument is a fictitious person, </section></section> the rules set out in paragraph (b) of this subsection apply until the instrument is negotiated by special indorsement. <section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Any person in possession of the instrument is its holder. </section><section prefix="2">An indorsement by any person in the name of the payee stated in the instrument is effective as the indorsement of the payee in favor of a person who, in good faith, pays the instrument or takes it for value or for collection. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Under subsection (1) or (2) of this section, an indorsement is made in the name of a payee if: <section prefix="a">It is made in a name substantially similar to that of the payee; or </section><section prefix="b">The instrument, whether or not indorsed, is deposited in a depositary bank to an account in a name substantially similar to that of the payee. </section></section><section prefix="4">With respect to an instrument to which subsection (1) or (2) of this section applies, if a person paying the instrument or taking it for value or for collection fails to exercise ordinary care in paying or taking the instrument and that failure substantially contributes to loss resulting from payment of the instrument, the person bearing the loss may recover from the person failing to exercise ordinary care to the extent the failure to exercise ordinary care contributed to the loss. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 42, effective January 1, 1997. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 3-404, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>