<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.590</section_number><catch_line>Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall make and the department shall enforce rules and regulations reasonably required to effectuate the provisions of KRS 227.550 to 227.660 and to carry out the department's responsibilities as a state administrative agency for the enforcement and administration of the federal act. </section><section prefix="2">At least thirty (30) days before the adoption or promulgation of any change in or addition to the rules and regulations authorized in subsection (5) of this section the department shall mail to all manufacturers possessing valid certificates of acceptability and retailers possessing valid licenses a notice including a copy of the proposed changes and additions and the time and place that the board will consider any objections to the proposed changes and additions. After giving the notice required by this section, the board shall afford interested persons an opportunity to participate in the rule making through submission of written data, views, or arguments with or without opportunity to present the same orally in any manner. </section><section prefix="3">Every rule or regulation or modification, amendment, or repeal of a rule or regulation adopted by the board shall state the date it shall take effect. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 227.550 to 227.660, the board shall have the authority to promulgate rules and regulations exempting manufacturers and retailers from the provisions of KRS 227.550 to 227.660 when manufactured homes or mobile homes are brought into this state for exhibition only. </section><section prefix="5">All rules, regulations, codes, fees, and charges adopted by the board pursuant to KRS 227.550 to 227.660 shall be prepared and filed in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall have the authority to promulgate rules and regulations to issue temporary licenses, not to exceed thirty (30) days, to out-of-state retailers for the purpose of participating in manufactured home shows in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 416, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 4, effective January 1, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 1. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10683</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>