<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.047</section_number><catch_line>Inactive status for certificate or license -- Effect -- Reactivation. </catch_line><order_by>047</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon written request, any certificate holder or licensee may request to place his or her certificate or license in inactive status for a period not to exceed three (3) years. <section prefix="a">The written request shall be made by completing a signed and sworn affidavit on a form approved by the board. </section><section prefix="b">The board may require a fee of fifty dollars ($50) for each change in status of the certificate holder or licensee. </section><section prefix="c">A license issued to an individual as a trainee real property appraiser shall not be eligible for inactive status. </section></section><section prefix="2">No inactive status certificate holder or licensee shall: <section prefix="a">Assume or use any title, designation, or abbreviation likely to create the impression that he or she holds a certificate or license issued by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Describe or refer to any appraisal or evaluation of real estate by the term, "state certified," "state licensed," or words of substantially similar meaning; or </section><section prefix="c">Prepare real estate appraisals for federally related transactions which, under Title XI of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989, require the services of a state-certified or state-licensed appraiser. </section></section><section prefix="3">To return to active status, a certificate holder or licensee shall: <section prefix="a">Petition the board for reactivation of the certificate or license; </section><section prefix="b">Pay the applicable renewal fee and roster fee required by this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide evidence of completion of the annually required continuing education hours, as established by the board and promulgated in administrative regulations, for each year of inactive status. </section></section><section prefix="4">A certificate holder or licensee who petitions to return to active status after an inactive period exceeding three (3) years shall be required to meet all the requirements for original issuance of a license or certificate under this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">Violation of this subsection (2) of this section shall be grounds for disciplinary action under this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31631</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>