<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.350 shall be fined not more than twenty-five dollars ($25). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 217.390 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned for not more than fifty (50) days, or both. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.280 to 217.390 or who refuses to comply with any lawful order or requirement duly made in writing as provided in KRS 217.380, shall, for the first offense, be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100), or imprisoned for not more than thirty (30) days, or both, and for any subsequent offense shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200), or imprisoned for not more than ninety (90) days, or both. Each day after the expiration of the time limit for abating unsanitary conditions and completing improvements to abate such conditions, as ordered under KRS 217.380, shall be a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.400 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.420 to 217.440 shall be fined not less than two hundred dollars ($200) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than one (1) year, or both. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.450 shall be fined one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 217.801 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisoned for not less than thirty (30) days nor more than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="8">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.808 to 217.812, or any rule or regulation adopted thereunder, or who operates a vending machine company or vending machine commissary without a permit as prescribed in KRS 217.808 to 217.812, or who fails to comply with any order of the cabinet or of any local health department issued pursuant thereto shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). Each day of violation or noncompliance shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="9">Willful noncompliance with KRS 217.816 shall constitute a violation and shall subject the violator to a fine of not over fifty dollars ($50) for the first offense and not over two hundred dollars ($200) for a subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="10">Any person who willfully fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 217.816 to 217.826 shall be guilty of a violation and shall be subject to a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for each violation. </section><section prefix="11">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.177 shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or be imprisoned in the county jail for not less than five (5) nor more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section><section prefix="12">Any manufacturer or distributor who dispenses, sells, or otherwise provides to any other person any legend drug in solid dosage form that fails to comply with the requirements of KRS 217.907 to 217.915 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) for each offense. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 8. effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 399, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 126, secs. 4 and 9; ch. 356, para. (3), sec. 1; and ch. 365, sec. 5. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 24. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 13; and ch. 126, sec. 28. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 10. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1276, 1282, 1283a-3, 1905a-60-6, 1905a-60c, 1905a-68, 2060, 2060b-8, 2060b-12, 2060b-13, 2630, 2635a-1, 2635b-5. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by two 1982 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>