<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.915</section_number><catch_line>Functions of council.   </catch_line><order_by>915</order_by><text>The functions of the council shall be to: <section prefix="1">Create and update annually a five (5) year management and operational plan to make as effective as possible the coordination, delivery, and marketing of all state environmental education programs; </section><section prefix="2">Establish an interagency subcommittee to advise the council on environmental education matters; </section><section prefix="3">Establish and help coordinate the activities of regional environmental education centers and advisory committees at all state universities and at the central office of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System to serve as networks for the dissemination of environmental education programs, materials, and information across the state; </section><section prefix="4">Establish a competitive system for awarding grants for the establishment and maintenance of regional environmental education centers; </section><section prefix="5">Seek and receive private support to fund state and regional environmental education initiatives; </section><section prefix="6">Assist in the integration and evaluation of environmental education in existing school curricula; </section><section prefix="7">Monitor and report periodically on environmental literacy in Kentucky and continually assess trends and needs in environmental education on a local, state, national, and global basis; and </section><section prefix="8">Make recommendations and seek changes through regulations, legislation, and other means to promote environmental literacy in Kentucky. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42351</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>