<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-205</section_number><catch_line>Bluegrass State Skills Corporation -- Board. </catch_line><order_by>12-205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created an independent, de jure corporation of the Commonwealth with all the general corporate powers incidental thereto which shall be known as the "Bluegrass State Skills Corporation." The corporation shall be a political subdivision of the state and shall be attached to the Cabinet for Economic Development. </section><section prefix="2">The corporation is created and established to improve and promote the employment opportunities of the citizens of the Commonwealth by creating and expanding programs of skills training and education which meet the needs of business and industry. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall be governed by a board of directors consisting of eighteen (18) members, including the following six (6) ex officio members: the commissioner of the Department of Workforce Investment or his or her designee, the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development, the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, the president of the Council on Postsecondary Education, the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, and the president of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. The twelve (12) other members shall be appointed by the Governor, including persons having knowledge and experience in business and industry, skills training, education, and minority employment; and at least one (1) of the twelve (12) members shall be appointed to represent labor organizations. Each member appointed by the Governor shall serve for a term of four (4) years, except that in making the initial appointments, the Governor shall appoint three (3) members to serve for one (1) year, three (3) members to serve for two (2) years, three (3) members to serve for three (3) years, and three (3) members to serve for four (4) years. All succeeding appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="4">In the event of a vacancy, the Governor may appoint a replacement member who shall hold office during the remainder of the term so vacated. </section><section prefix="5">Any member may be removed from his appointment by the Governor for cause. </section><section prefix="6">The Governor shall designate a member of the board as its chairman. </section><section prefix="7">Members of the board of directors of the corporation, except for ex officio members, shall be entitled to compensation for their services in the amount of one hundred dollars ($100) for each regular or special called meeting of the corporation, and all members shall be entitled to reimbursement for any actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="8">The board of directors of the corporation shall annually elect a vice chairman, a secretary, and a treasurer. The secretary shall keep a record of the proceedings of the corporation and shall be custodian of all books, documents, and papers filed with the corporation, and its official seal. </section><section prefix="9">The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development shall hire an executive director and establish his salary. The executive director shall be the chief administrative and operational officer of the corporation and shall direct and supervise its administrative affairs and general management subject to the policies, control, and direction of the board. </section><section prefix="10">All officers and employees of the corporation having access to its funding shall give bond to the corporation, at its expense, in the amount and with the surety as the board may prescribe. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 195, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 32, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 64, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 55, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 52, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 417, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 195, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 205, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 157.720 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2619</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>