<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.13-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>13-010</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle: <section prefix="1">"Corporation" means the issuer of the shares held by a dissenter, except that in the case of a merger where the issuing corporation is not the surviving corporation, then, after consummation of the merger, "corporation" shall mean the surviving corporation. </section><section prefix="2">"Dissenter" means a shareholder who is entitled to dissent from corporate action under KRS 271B.13-020 and who exercises that right when and in the manner required by KRS 271B.13-200 to 271B.13-280. </section><section prefix="3">"Fair value," with respect to a dissenter's shares, means the value of the shares immediately before the effectuation of the corporate action to which the dissenter objects, excluding any appreciation or depreciation in anticipation of the corporate action unless exclusion would be inequitable. In any transaction subject to the requirements of KRS 271B.12-210 or exempted by KRS 271B.12-220(2), "fair value" shall be at least an amount required to be paid under KRS 271B.12-220(2) in order to be exempt from the requirements of KRS 271B.12-210. </section><section prefix="4">"Interest" means interest from the effective date of the corporate action until the date of payment, at the average rate currently paid by the corporation on its principal bank loans or, if none, at a rate that is fair and equitable under all the circumstances. </section><section prefix="5">"Record shareholder" means the person in whose name shares are registered in the records of a corporation or the beneficial owner of shares to the extent of the rights granted by a nominee certificate on file with a corporation. </section><section prefix="6">"Beneficial shareholder" means the person who is a beneficial owner of shares held in a voting trust or by a nominee as the record shareholder. </section><section prefix="7">"Shareholder" means the record shareholder or the beneficial shareholder. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 123, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13433</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>