<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.894</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 199.892 to 199.896. </catch_line><order_by>894</order_by><text>As used in KRS 199.892 to 199.896, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" means secretary for health and family services; </section><section prefix="3">"Child-care center" means any child-care center which provides full or part-time care, day or night, to at least seven (7) children who are not the children, grandchildren, nieces, nephews, or children in legal custody of the operator. "Child-care center" shall not include any child-care facility operated by a religious organization while religious services are being conducted, or a youth development agency. For the purposes of this section, "youth development agency" means a program with tax-exempt status under 26 U.S.C. sec. 501(c)(3), which operates continuously throughout the year as an outside-school-hours center for youth who are six (6) years of age or older, and for which there are no fee or scheduled-care arrangements with the parent or guardian of the youth served; </section><section prefix="4">"Department" means the Department for Community Based Services; and </section><section prefix="5">"Family child-care home" means a private home that provides full or part-time care day or night for six (6) or fewer children who are not the children, siblings, stepchildren, grandchildren, nieces, nephews, or children in legal custody of the provider. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 193, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 17, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 156, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (13), (21) and (30). -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7237</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>