<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.370</section_number><catch_line>Closing of roads and bridges for repairs -- Temporary roads. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If it appears necessary to close a county road or bridge which is being constructed or repaired, the county engineer shall execute a notice in duplicate, stating the necessity for closing the road or bridge, and describing the portion to be closed. He shall cause a copy of the notice to be posted at each end of the portion of the road or bridge to be closed, and shall close such portion to travel by erecting suitable obstructions and posting conspicuous notices to the effect that it is closed. Not more than one (1) mile of any county road shall be closed at one (1) time.  </section><section prefix="2">The county engineer shall provide a new location for constructing a temporary road to be used in lieu of the closed road, and may erect temporary bridges when necessary. For the purposes of locating or constructing the temporary road or bridge, the county engineer may enter upon the lands adjoining or near the closed road, and may, with the approval of the fiscal court, agree with the owners of the lands as to the damages caused thereby.  </section><section prefix="3">If the county engineer is unable to agree with the owner upon the amount of damages sustained, the amount shall be ascertained and paid as provided in KRS 178.110.  </section><section prefix="4">When a county road, or bridge, has been closed to the public as provided in this section, no person shall disregard the obstructions and notices and drive or ride over the portion of the road, or bridge, so closed. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356f. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5509</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>