<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.512</section_number><catch_line>Tuition waiver for disabled child of veteran. </catch_line><order_by>512</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The child of a veteran, regardless of age, who has acquired a disability as a direct result of the veteran's service shall be eligible to receive a waiver of tuition upon admission to any state-supported university, college, or vocational training institute. </section><section prefix="2">To be entitled to benefits under this section, the child claiming benefits must have acquired a disability determined by the United States Veterans Administration as compensable. </section><section prefix="3">The parent-child relationship must be shown by birth certificate, marriage certificate, or other documentary evidence. </section><section prefix="4">To entitle a child to benefit under this section the member of the National Guard or Reserve Component veteran living or deceased must have served on state active duty, active duty for training, or inactive duty training or the veteran must have served on active duty with the Armed Forces of the United States, and the discharge must have been under honorable conditions. The veteran must be a resident or, if deceased, must have been a resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4308</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>