<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.357</section_number><catch_line>Certification of installers of on-site sewage disposal systems. </catch_line><order_by>357</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall establish a program to certify persons as installers of on-site sewage disposal systems. A master plumber licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 318 or a person who provides written verification from the local health department in the county in which the work was completed that he installed five (5) lateral fields and septic tank systems prior to July 13, 1984, and that these installations had been inspected by a certified inspector and passed inspection, shall be certified automatically. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall establish as a part of the certification program referenced in subsection (1) of this section a means of issuing a probationary certification for installers of on-site sewage disposal systems. This probationary certification shall automatically be converted to a full certification at the time that the holder of the probationary certificate has installed five (5) lateral fields and septic tank systems and has provided written verification from the local health department in the county in which the work was completed that these installations have been inspected by a certified inspector and passed the inspection. The cabinet shall issue a full certificate to the holder of the probationary certificate no later than sixty (60) days after receipt of verification. In order to be issued a probationary certification, eligible persons shall certify in writing that they will make installations in accordance with requirements set forth by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="3">Persons certified as installers, except master plumbers licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 318, shall pay a reasonable fee of not more than twenty-five dollars ($25) for certification. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may revoke or suspend any certification issued pursuant to this section upon proof that the certified person has: <section prefix="a">Knowingly violated the provisions of this chapter or the regulations of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Practiced fraud or deception in applying for or obtaining a certificate; </section><section prefix="c">Is incompetent to install on-site sewage disposal systems; </section><section prefix="d">Permitted the certification to be used directly or indirectly by another to install on-site sewage disposal systems; or </section><section prefix="e">Is guilty of other unprofessional or dishonorable conduct of a character likely to deceive or defraud the public. </section></section><section prefix="5">Upon appeal of any decision to revoke or suspend a certification, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in this section shall be construed to condone the installation of on-site sewage disposal systems contrary to specifications for these systems established by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 355, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 298, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 106, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>