<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.420</section_number><catch_line>Rural Kentucky dental scholarship fund -- Granting scholarships. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, a rural Kentucky dental scholarship fund. </section><section prefix="2">There shall be available each fiscal year to applicants selected by the board with the approval of the Dental Health Program of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, no less than ten (10) scholarships for the study of dentistry leading to the attainment of the degree of Doctor of Dental Surgery, or some equivalent degree. </section><section prefix="3">The amount of each scholarship shall be a reasonable sum determined by the board, but shall not be less than one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) per annum. </section><section prefix="4">In granting scholarships the board shall make a careful and full investigation of the ability, character, and qualifications of each applicant, and may personally examine each applicant. The board shall, whenever possible, grant financial assistance to the applicants with the greatest financial need, provided such persons are found to possess such qualities as give reasonable assurance of their successfully completing the course of study made possible by the scholarship. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 357, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 301, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 68; ch. 231, sec. 1; and ch. 365, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>