<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.845</section_number><catch_line>Custodian of property taken by peace officers or courts -- Property clerks -- Disposition. </catch_line><order_by>845</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive authority of any city which maintains a police department may designate the chief of police as custodian of all property which comes within the purview of KRS 67.592 which is taken by peace officers or courts within the city. </section><section prefix="2">The legislative body of any city may authorize the employment of a property clerk and deputy property clerks, as necessary, subject to the same conditions as in KRS 67.592 and 67.594. The property clerk and deputy property clerks shall be appointed by the executive authority of the city. </section><section prefix="3">Custody and disposition of all property in custody of the property clerk shall be governed by the provisions of KRS 67.592 and 67.594 except that: <section prefix="a">The legislative body of the city may prescribe the duties of the property clerk and deputy property clerks and require security for the faithful performance of the duties imposed by KRS 67.594; and </section><section prefix="b">The proceeds of all property subject to the provisions of subsection (4) of KRS 67.594 which is sold as provided in that section shall be credited to the police department. </section></section><section prefix="4">All other provisions of KRS 67.592 and 67.594 shall apply to the city and to the property clerk and deputies in the same manner as they do to the county. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26073</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>