<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.680</section_number><catch_line>Records management by agencies.   </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The head of each state and local agency shall establish and maintain an active, continuing program for the economical and efficient management of the records of the agency.  </section><section prefix="2">Such program shall provide for:  <section prefix="a">Effective controls over the creation, maintenance, and use of records in the conduct of current business;  </section><section prefix="b">Cooperation with the department in applying standards, procedures, and techniques designed to improve the management of records;  </section><section prefix="c">Promotion of the maintenance and security of records deemed appropriate for preservation, and facilitation of the segregation and disposal of records of temporary value;  </section><section prefix="d">Compliance with the provisions of KRS 171.410 to 171.740 and the rules and regulations of the department; and </section><section prefix="e">Compliance with the provisions of KRS 61.931 to 61.934. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 53. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 28. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 10 provided that "the provisions of this Act shall not impact the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884." That proviso applies to this statute as amended in Section 9 of that Act. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>