<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.1-020</section_number><catch_line>Mission and goals of Commonwealth's economic development system. </catch_line><order_by>1-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The mission of the Commonwealth's economic development system shall be to achieve the best quality of life for all Kentuckians through long-term strategic planning and implementation that fosters sustainable growth in jobs and incomes and enables communities, businesses, governments, and individuals to compete in the global marketplace. </section><section prefix="2">The goals for the Commonwealth's economic development system shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">By the year 1993, Kentucky will have an economic development partnership of government, business, education, communities, and individuals that provides a coordinated planning and implementation process which establishes government priorities for action and accountability, supports rural and urban communities to invest in their own futures, assists businesses to acquire the resources to compete, and prepares individuals for work in high quality jobs; and </section><section prefix="b">By the year 2000, Kentucky will have people and institutions with the capacity to adapt to future change; a skilled, competitive workforce; thriving and healthy communities throughout the state; and increased wealth and high quality jobs with greater opportunities to compete for them. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification>KRS 154.01-020. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41626</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>