<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.106</section_number><catch_line>Right of employees and other persons to possess firearms in vehicle -- Employer liable for denying right -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>106</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, including but not limited to an employer, who is the owner, lessee, or occupant of real property shall prohibit any person who is legally entitled to possess a firearm from possessing a firearm, part of a firearm, ammunition, or ammunition component in a vehicle on the property. </section><section prefix="2">A person, including but not limited to an employer, who owns, leases, or otherwise occupies real property may prevent a person who is prohibited by state or federal law from possessing a firearm or ammunition from possessing a firearm or ammunition on the property. </section><section prefix="3">A firearm may be removed from the vehicle or handled in the case of self-defense, defense of another, defense of property, or as authorized by the owner, lessee, or occupant of the property. </section><section prefix="4">An employer that fires, disciplines, demotes, or otherwise punishes an employee who is lawfully exercising a right guaranteed by this section and who is engaging in conduct in compliance with this statute shall be liable in civil damages. An employee may seek and the court shall grant an injunction against an employer who is violating the provisions of this section when it is found that the employee is in compliance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any real property: <section prefix="a">Owned, leased, or occupied by the United States government, upon which the possession or carrying of firearms is prohibited or controlled; </section><section prefix="b">Of a detention facility as defined in KRS 520.010; or </section><section prefix="c">Where a section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes specifically prohibits possession or carrying of firearms on the property. </section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>