<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.402</section_number><catch_line>Employee purchase of service credit -- Payment procedures. </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (d) of this subsection, any member whose participation date in the fund is prior to March 14, 2013, who has at least five (5) years of total service credit as a member of the fund may purchase service credit, that is not otherwise purchasable, for up to a maximum of four (4) years of service.  </section><section prefix="b">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (d) of this subsection, any member whose participation date in the fund is on or after March 14, 2013, who has at least five (5) but no more than ten (10) years of membership service may, subject to the limitations provided by this section, purchase periods of active military duty service in the Armed Forces of the United States, not to exceed four (4) years, that are not otherwise credited under KRS 67A.400(2)(c). The member shall provide verification of the period of active military duty as prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="c">The member shall not be entitled to purchase any service credit under this section for which he or she has been given credit in another defined benefit retirement fund; however, the member may purchase government service credit by transferring funds directly from another public defined benefit retirement plan if the member provides proof that he or she is not eligible for a retirement benefit from the other public defined benefit retirement fund. </section><section prefix="d">Any provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding: <section prefix="1">No service credit purchase under this subsection shall be counted toward the accrual of a health or other medical insurance retirement benefit in this fund; </section><section prefix="2">No service purchased under this section by a member whose participation date in the fund is on or after March 14, 2013, shall be used to determine the member's eligibility to retire or to withdraw on a certificate under KRS 67A.410(2) or (3)(b); and </section><section prefix="3">The amount of service a member can purchase under this section shall not exceed the amounts specified by paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A member who purchases service credit shall file an application with the board no later than sixty (60) days prior to the anticipated service purchase payment date. The member shall pay to the fund an amount which shall be determined by actuarial method consistent with the methods prescribed for determining the purchase of prior service credit which shall be the principal. </section><section prefix="3">Payment of the principal shall be made in a lump sum or payment of the principal and interest may be made by installments. Interest, at the annual rate of return on investments of the fund for the preceding year, shall be established by the commissioner of finance on or before August 31 of each year and shall be based on financial statements of the fund for the year ending June 30, except that the interest shall not be less than three percent (3%). Interest shall be added to the principal for the time period for which installments are to be made. </section><section prefix="4">If payments are made by installment, the cost of purchasing the service credit shall be recalculated annually based upon the member's current salary, the interest rate established by the commissioner of finance, and other factors required by the actuarial method. The member's payments shall be adjusted annually to reflect the annual recalculation of the cost of purchasing service credit. Installment payments shall be consecutive and the total number of monthly installments shall not be less than twelve (12) or more than two hundred forty (240). The member shall pay the installments by payroll deduction. </section><section prefix="5">Payments shall not be picked up by the urban-county government. No employer contribution shall be paid on the installments. The board shall determine how much of the total cost represents payment for one (1) quarter of the service to be purchased and the member shall receive service credit for one (1) quarter of the service each time this amount is paid. </section><section prefix="6">If the member dies, retires, or ceases to be a member of the fund before he or she has made all installment payments for the purchase of service credit, the fund shall refund to the member, his or her qualified surviving spouse, or his or her estate, the portion of any payment that does not represent a full quarter of service. </section><section prefix="7">A member whose participation date in the fund is prior to March 14, 2013, who does not repay a refund of contributions, as provided in KRS 67A.500(3), shall be entitled to purchase service credit for prior membership service. </section><section prefix="8">The member may cancel a purchase obligation at any time, but once canceled, a member shall have forever forfeited, waived, and relinquished the right to purchase service credit. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 4, effective March 14, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 2, effective April 4, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 484, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 14, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41658</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>