<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.101</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of section -- Definition of "instructional leader" -- Instructional leader improvement program. </catch_line><order_by>101</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of this section is to encourage and require the maintenance and development of effective instructional leadership in the public schools of the Commonwealth and to recognize that principals, with the assistance of assistant principals, supervisors of instruction, guidance counselors, and directors of special education, have the primary responsibility for instructional leadership in the schools to which they are assigned. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of this section, "instructional leader" shall be defined as an employee of the public schools of the Commonwealth employed as a principal, assistant principal, supervisor of instruction, guidance counselor, director of special education, or other administrative position deemed by the Education Professional Standards Board to require an administrative certificate. </section><section prefix="3">In order to carry out the purpose of this section, the Kentucky Board of Education shall establish a statewide program to improve and maintain the quality and effectiveness of instructional leadership in the public schools of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The instructional leader improvement program shall contain the following provisions: <section prefix="a">Each instructional leader employed by the public schools of the Commonwealth shall participate in a continuing intensive training program designed especially for instructional leaders; </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Effective until June 30, 2006, every two (2) years each instructional leader shall complete an intensive training program approved by the Kentucky Board of Education to include no fewer than forty-two (42) participant hours of instruction; </section><section prefix="2">Effective July 1, 2006, each instructional leader shall annually complete an intensive training program approved by the Kentucky Board of Education to include no fewer than twenty-one (21) participant hours of instruction; </section></section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Board of Education shall prescribe specific criteria for the training program, which shall include a provision to allow an instructional leader to annually receive three (3) participant hours credit for duties performed as part of a beginning teacher committee pursuant to KRS 161.030(6). A maximum of six (6) participant hours credit shall be awarded annually for serving on multiple beginning teacher committees. The Kentucky Department of Education may contract for specific training with qualified agencies or institutions or approve programs offered by training providers, including local district training programs, except that the department shall ensure the requirements of paragraph (d) of this subsection are met; and </section><section prefix="d">Annually, each local district superintendent shall report to the Kentucky Department of Education any instructional leader who fails to complete the training requirements of paragraph (b) of this subsection and shall place the leader on probation for one (1) year. The Department of Education shall verify completion of the required training. If the required training for the prior year and the current year is not completed during the probationary period, the Department of Education shall forward the information to the Education Professional Standards Board, which shall revoke the instructional leader's certificate. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Department of Education shall ensure that training options in human resource management and conflict resolution techniques are available to education leaders throughout the state. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall be known as the "Effective Instructional Leadership Act." </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 130, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 442, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 2, effective October 18, 1985. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 365, secs. 1 and 2, effective July 13,1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3119</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>