<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.575</section_number><catch_line>Family preservation services programs. </catch_line><order_by>575</order_by><text>"Family preservation services" means programs that: <section prefix="1">Follow intensive, home-based service models with demonstrated effectiveness in reducing or avoiding the need for out-of-home placement; </section><section prefix="2">Provide such services that their operation results in lower costs than would out-of-home placement; </section><section prefix="3">Employ specially trained caseworkers who shall: <section prefix="a">Provide at least half their services in the family's home or other natural community setting; </section><section prefix="b">Provide services to no more than four (4) families at any one (1) time; </section><section prefix="c">Provide direct therapeutic services available twenty-four (24) hours per day for an average of at least forty-five (45) days per family; </section><section prefix="d">Aid in the solution of practical problems that contribute to family stress so as to effect improved parental performance and enhanced functioning of the family unit; </section><section prefix="e">Arrange for additional assistance, including but not limited to, housing, child care, education, and job training, emergency cash grants, state and federally funded public assistance, and other basic support needs; and </section><section prefix="f">Supervise any paraprofessionals or "family aides" made available to provide specialized services or skills to manage everyday problems and better provide and care for its children. </section></section><section prefix="4">Have available moneys to be spent at the caseworker's discretion to enhance the success of the intervention. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>