<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.320</section_number><catch_line>Capacity building grant program -- Challenge grant program -- Administrative regulations -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Local Government may: <section prefix="a">Establish a capacity building grant program, through which it may provide qualified community foundations, county-specific component funds, and affiliate community foundations with grants from the fund for the purpose of developing and enhancing the receiving foundation's capacity to operate and execute its mission, subject to the following restrictions: <section prefix="1">No qualified community foundation, county-specific component fund, or affiliate community foundation may receive more than one (1) capacity building grant during any fiscal year; </section><section prefix="2">No single capacity building grant shall exceed fifty thousand dollars ($50,000); and </section><section prefix="3">At least forty percent (40%) of funds awarded as capacity building grants shall be provided to newly established or emerging qualified community foundations, county-specific component funds, or affiliate community foundations that specifically seek to address the needs of rural areas of the Commonwealth; </section></section><section prefix="b">Establish a challenge grant program, through which it may provide qualified community foundations, county-specific component funds, and affiliate community foundations with grants from the fund for the purpose of building community-based unrestricted endowment funds by encouraging individuals, businesses, and other organizations to provide endowment gifts, subject to the following restrictions: <section prefix="1">No qualified community foundation, county-specific component fund, or affiliate community foundation may receive more than one (1) challenge grant during any fiscal year; </section><section prefix="2">Challenge grants may be provided in amounts not to exceed fifty percent (50%) of the amount of privately donated endowment gifts provided to the receiving qualified community foundation, county-specific component fund, or affiliate community foundation during the one (1) year period preceding the grant award. However, no single challenge grant shall exceed five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); and </section><section prefix="3">At least forty percent (40%) of funds awarded as challenge grants shall be provided to newly established or emerging qualified community foundations, county-specific component funds, or affiliate community foundations that specifically seek to address the needs of rural areas of the Commonwealth; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to administer this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the establishment of any grant program under this section, the Department for Local Government shall provide an annual report to the commission, which shall include: <section prefix="a">The total number of grant requests submitted during the year, along with the amount of funds requested and the identity of the foundation making the request; and </section><section prefix="b">Information regarding all grants actually awarded during the year. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  References to the "Governor's Office for Local Development" in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5, have been changed in codification to the "Department for Local Government" to reflect the renaming of that agency in Executive Order 2009-540, which was confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 90. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1669</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>