<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-858</section_number><catch_line>Registration -- Letter of approval. </catch_line><order_by>50-858</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless exempted by KRS 224.50-854 or as authorized by KRS 224.50-856(4) and (5), no person shall accumulate more than twenty-five (25) waste tires at a time for processing, transport more than fifty (50) waste tires at a time, or accumulate more than one hundred (100) waste tires at a time without first registering and receiving a letter of approval from the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">To register, the following shall be submitted: <section prefix="a">The person's name and address; </section><section prefix="b">The address where the waste tires are to be accumulated or transferred; </section><section prefix="c">A statement of the purpose for accumulating, transporting, or processing the waste tires; </section><section prefix="d">A statement of the maximum number of waste tires to be accumulated, transported, or processed, and their passenger tire equivalents, as calculated under KRS 224.50-862; </section><section prefix="e">The rate at which waste tires are to be accumulated, transported, or processed; </section><section prefix="f">A certification stating that the person has read and understood the requirements of the waste tire program and will comply with those requirements; </section><section prefix="g">Financial assurance to pay for closure and corrective action as required by KRS 224.50-864 and 224.50-866; and </section><section prefix="h">A disclosure statement required by KRS 224.40-330(2). </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall approve the registration when the registration requirements have been met. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>