<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="424" order_by="424">LEGAL NOTICES </unit></structure><section_number>424.190</section_number><catch_line>Alternatives to newspaper publication abolished -- Exception -- Information required to be sent to Department for Local Government. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a statute gives discretion to a public officer or agency or governmental body as to the method of making an advertisement required by the statute, and if a statute provides that an advertisement may be made either by posting or by newspaper publication, the advertisement shall be made by newspaper publication in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Any city may, when the cost of the newspaper publication exceeds the cost of postage, supplies, and reproduction for the alternative method of publication, in lieu of newspaper publication of advertisement, substitute delivery of a copy of the advertisement by first class mail to each residence within the publication area. Any city electing to use the alternative publication methods authorized by this section shall forward three (3) copies of its audit report or one (1) copy of its financial statement, whichever is applicable, to the Department for Local Government in accordance with KRS 91A.040 and 424.220. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 89, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 94, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 78, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18255</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>