<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="359" order_by="359">WAREHOUSES AND WAREHOUSEMEN </unit></structure><section_number>359.070</section_number><catch_line>Inspector, weigher and registrar for grain warehouses in city having board of trade -- Inspection standards and fees. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commissioner of Agriculture shall appoint an inspector, a weigher and a registrar for the grain warehouses of each city containing grain warehouses and having a board of trade, and shall fix their duties, and the amount and kind of bond to be given by them. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be appointed as such an inspector, weigher or registrar unless he is a citizen of Kentucky, is at least twenty-five (25) years of age, has been for at least one (1) year next preceding his appointment a resident of the city for which he is chosen, and is not a member of the city board of trade, or interested in any warehouse. </section><section prefix="3">No such inspector, weigher or registrar shall have stored in, or offer for sale in, any warehouse under his supervision any commodity owned by him or any commodity in which he is interested, or be a purchaser at any sale made by the warehouse of any commodity inspected, weighed or registered by him. </section><section prefix="4">The Circuit Court may, upon complaint and proof of malfeasance or neglect, remove any inspector, weigher or registrar and declare him ineligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="5">The board of trade shall, at least once each year, establish standard grades of the various kinds of grain to govern the inspector in his inspection. </section><section prefix="6">The Commissioner shall fix the inspection fees to be paid by sellers of grain, but any warehouseman, seller, buyer or person in interest may, on summary complaint made to the Circuit Court obtain a reduction of any fee, if the court finds it exorbitant. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4791. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>