<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.215</section_number><catch_line>.   Pharmacy board's powers as to drugs -- Regulations on prescription records and on refilling prescriptions in emergency. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Board of Pharmacy, its agents and inspectors shall have the same powers of inspection and enforcement as the cabinet under KRS 217.005 to 217.215 , insofar as it relates to drugs in licensed pharmacies. </section><section prefix="2">The board of pharmacy may establish regulations relating to the storage and retrieval of prescription records in licensed pharmacies, including regulations regarding computerized recordkeeping systems. </section><section prefix="3">No prescription for any drug may be refilled by a pharmacist unless authorized by the prescribing practitioner, except that the board of pharmacy may promulgate rules and regulations to permit a pharmacist to: <section prefix="a">Dispense up to a seventy-two (72) hour supply of maintenance medication in emergency situations in which such authorization may not be readily or easily obtained from the practitioner; and </section><section prefix="b">Dispense up to a thirty (30) day supply of maintenance medication in emergency situations as authorized by KRS 315.500. </section></section><section prefix="4">Such emergency refills shall not be authorized for any controlled substance or for any drug which is not essential to maintenance of life or continuation of therapy in chronic disease conditions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 22, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9323</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>