<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.5623</section_number><catch_line>Department's powers in providing program benefits. </catch_line><order_by>5623</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In providing program benefits, the department may: <section prefix="a">Enter into a contract with one (1) or more prescription drug plans to coordinate the prescription benefits of the program and the federal law; </section><section prefix="b">Preliminarily enroll beneficiaries into a preferred Medicare Part D plan, with an opt-out provision for individuals. Individuals who opt out of the preferred PDP shall remain enrolled in the program unless they choose to disenroll from the program; </section><section prefix="c">Prescribe the application and enrollment procedures for prospective enrollees; </section><section prefix="d">Select, in accordance with applicable state law, a contractor to assist in the administration of the program or negotiate program administrative functions with a preferred PDP plan; </section><section prefix="e">Determine which drugs will be covered by the plan; and </section><section prefix="f">Negotiate with manufacturers for rebates. </section></section><section prefix="2">Program benefits shall begin January 1, 2006. </section><section prefix="3">For persons meeting eligibility requirements, the program may pay all or some of the deductibles, coinsurance payments, premiums, and copayments required under the Medicare Part D pharmacy benefit program. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>