<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.031</section_number><catch_line>Hate crimes -- Finding -- Effect. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person may be found by the sentencing judge to have committed an offense specified below as a result of a hate crime if the person intentionally because of race, color, religion, sexual orientation, or national origin of another individual or group of individuals violates a provision of any one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">KRS 508.010, 508.020, 508.025, or 508.030; </section><section prefix="b">KRS 508.050 or 508.060; </section><section prefix="c">KRS 508.100 or 508.110; </section><section prefix="d">KRS 509.020; </section><section prefix="e">KRS 510.040, 510.050, 510.060, 510.070, 510.080, 510.090, 510.100, or 510.110; </section><section prefix="f">KRS 512.020, 512.050, or 512.060; </section><section prefix="g">KRS 513.020, 513.030, or 513.040; or </section><section prefix="h">KRS 525.020, 525.050, 525.060, 525.070, or 525.080. </section></section><section prefix="2">At sentencing, the sentencing judge shall determine if, by a preponderance of the evidence presented at the trial, a hate crime was a primary factor in the commission of the crime by the defendant. If so, the judge shall make a written finding of fact and enter that in the court record and in the judgment rendered against the defendant. </section><section prefix="3">The finding that a hate crime was a primary factor in the commission of the crime by the defendant may be utilized by the sentencing judge as the sole factor for denial of probation, shock probation, conditional discharge, or other form of nonimposition of a sentence of incarceration. </section><section prefix="4">The finding by the sentencing judge that a hate crime was a primary factor in the commission of the crime by the defendant may be utilized by the Parole Board in delaying or denying parole to a defendant. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 541, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 51, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20031</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>