<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.025</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for plugging and abandoning wells -- Request for hearing -- Exception -- Rights of coal interest holder. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Prior to the abandonment of a coalbed methane well drilled through a workable coalbed, the well operator shall notify, by certified mail, return receipt requested, or by registered mail, all the coal interest holders of the workable coalbed and the department of the operator's intention to plug and abandon the well. The notice shall give the number of the well and its location, and fix the time at which the work of plugging and filling will be commenced. The time shall not be less than fifteen (15) days after the day on which the notice was received, or in due course should be received, by the department. The department shall prescribe the form of notice to be used. A representative of any coal interest holder, at his or her own expense and liability, and of the department may be present at the plugging and filling of the well. Regardless of whether representatives appear, the well operator may proceed, at the time fixed, to plug and fill the well. When the well is plugged and filled, an affidavit setting forth the time and manner in which the well was plugged shall be made in triplicate by two (2) persons experienced in plugging and filling wells who participated in the work. The affidavit shall be made on forms furnished by the department. One (1) copy of the affidavit shall be retained by the well operator, one (1) provided to each coal interest holder, and one (1) provided to the department. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to the notification required under subsection (1) of this section, prior to the abandonment of a coalbed methane well the operator shall submit a plugging plan which is subject to approval by the department. The proposed plugging plan shall be designed to allow coal mining to occur through the well after the well is plugged. </section><section prefix="3">If a coalbed methane well ceases to produce in paying quantities and no dewatering operations are being conducted for a period of fifteen (15) consecutive months, any coal interest holder or any record oil or gas lessor or lessee of any tract being penetrated by the coalbed methane well, may file a request for hearing pursuant to KRS 349.060, to determine whether the well has been abandoned and should be plugged in accordance with this section. However, nothing in this subsection shall require the plugging and abandonment of a coalbed methane well that is being temporarily shut in by the coalbed methane well operator. Simultaneously with the filing of a request for a hearing with the department, the person requesting the hearing shall send a copy of the request to the coalbed methane well operator. </section><section prefix="4">Any coal interest holder shall have the following rights with respect to a coalbed methane well to be plugged and abandoned: <section prefix="a">To convert the coalbed methane well to a vent hole or otherwise take the coalbed methane well. In this event the department, upon determination that the coal interest holder has placed the coalbed methane well under a mining permit, shall release the coalbed methane well operator's bond and the coalbed methane well operator shall be relieved of further responsibility for the coalbed methane well; and </section><section prefix="b">To file an objection concerning the proposed manner or method of plugging with the department, within fifteen (15) days after receipt of notice of intent to plug. The department shall consider any objection and may issue an order specifying the manner and method of plugging and reclamation consistent with this section. </section></section><section prefix="5">All coalbed methane wells shall be plugged and abandoned in accordance with this section. The department shall promulgate regulations specifying the manner and method of plugging vertical and horizontal coalbed methane wells and in so doing, or in entering any order for such plugging and abandonment, shall give consideration to the ability to mine any affected coal seam safely and the protection of any affected coal seam for future mining. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>