<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.190</section_number><catch_line>Public health services to be provided by the cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>The cabinet shall provide public health services including: <section prefix="1">Administrative, consultative, technical, professional, and other services needed to assist local health departments in the effective maintenance and operation of their departments; </section><section prefix="2">Administrative, investigative, and clerical services required by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and may upon request provide these services to any other agency of this Commonwealth authorized to control the practice of any other healing art; </section><section prefix="3">Administration of grants, gifts, or contributions from the federal government, or from other sources, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of Pub. L. No. 725 (79th Congress, 2nd Session, chapter 958), or any other acts for the same or similar purposes; </section><section prefix="4">Central registrations of births, deaths, and other vital records and the furnishing of copies thereof to the general public in the manner prescribed by law; </section><section prefix="5">Statistical services, including the compilation, analysis, and maintenance of statistics on matters related to public health, and may provide these services to organizations and persons interested in public health; </section><section prefix="6">Education of the public concerning all matters relating to health, including the publication and dissemination of health information, and the stimulation of citizen support for the promotion and maintenance of high standards of public health throughout the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="7">Survey and study of the needs of medical and hospital facilities in the interest of the health of the general public; </section><section prefix="8">Establishment, maintenance, and operation of public health laboratories and such branches thereof as may be needed; </section><section prefix="9">Establishment, maintenance, and operation of training facilities and schools for employees of the cabinet and of local health departments; </section><section prefix="10">Tabulating, duplicating, and other ancillary services as are necessary to the operation of the cabinet, including the keeping of adequate financial, personnel, and other records; and </section><section prefix="11">Establishment, maintenance, monitoring, and enforcement of water fluoridation programs for the protection of dental health. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 347, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 291, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(17); and ch. 308, sec. 39. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8362</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>