<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.666</section_number><catch_line>Management of single-county emergency services board -- Board appointments -- Terms of board members -- Residency requirement -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>666</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The affairs of the emergency services board composed of one (1) county shall be controlled and managed by a board of directors appointed by the county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2">The county judge/executive shall appoint: <section prefix="a">One (1) member from each magisterial district of the county; and </section><section prefix="b">One (1) additional member from the county at large. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">If the board is composed of a number evenly divisible by four (4): <section prefix="1">One-fourth (1/4) of the board members' initial terms shall be one (1) year; </section><section prefix="2">One-fourth (1/4) of the board members' initial terms shall be two (2) years; </section><section prefix="3">One-fourth (1/4) of the board members' initial terms shall be three (3) years; and </section><section prefix="4">One-fourth (1/4) of the board members' initial terms shall be four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the board is composed of a number unevenly divisible by four (4), then the county judge/executive shall appoint the remainder for a term of four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="4">After the initial appointment, terms of the board members shall be for four (4) years. </section><section prefix="5">Board members may be reappointed, and they may succeed themselves. </section><section prefix="6">Each board member shall reside in the county. </section><section prefix="7">A majority of the membership of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="8">A member of the board of directors may be removed from office as provided in KRS 65.007. </section><section prefix="9">The county judge/executive shall serve as an ex officio member of the board. </section><section prefix="10">No elected official shall serve as a member of the board. </section><section prefix="11">The board shall be appointed within thirty (30) days after the creation of the emergency services board. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23441</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>