<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.340</section_number><catch_line>Overtaking vehicles -- Traffic lanes -- Following vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Vehicles overtaking other vehicles proceeding in the same direction shall pass to the left of them and shall not again drive to the right until reasonably clear of those vehicles. Vehicles overtaking streetcars may pass either to the right or left when so directed by a police officer, when on a one (1) way street or where the location of the tracks prevents compliance with this section, with regard for other traffic. </section><section prefix="2">The operator of a vehicle may overtake and pass upon the right of another vehicle only under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">When the vehicle overtaken is making or about to make a left turn; </section><section prefix="b">Upon a roadway with unobstructed pavement of sufficient width for two (2) or more lines of vehicles moving lawfully in the direction being traveled by the overtaking vehicle. </section></section><section prefix="3">The operator of a vehicle may overtake and pass another vehicle upon the right only under conditions permitting such movements in safety. Such movement shall not be made by driving off the roadway unless passing vehicle comes to a complete stop and such movement may be made safely. </section><section prefix="4">No vehicle shall be driven to the left side of the center of the roadway in overtaking and passing another vehicle proceeding in the same direction unless the left side is clearly visible and free of oncoming traffic for a sufficient distance ahead to permit overtaking and passing to be completely made without interfering with the safe operation of any vehicle approaching from the opposite direction or any vehicle overtaken. In every event, the overtaking vehicle must return to the right-hand side of the roadway before coming within two hundred (200) feet of any vehicle approaching from the opposite direction. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner of highways is hereby authorized to determine those portions of any highway where overtaking and passing or driving to the left of the roadway would be especially hazardous and may by appropriate signs or markings on the roadway indicate the beginning and end of such zones, and when such signs or markings are in place and clearly visible to an ordinarily observant person, every driver of a vehicle shall obey the directions thereof. </section><section prefix="6">Whenever any roadway has been divided into three (3) clearly marked lanes for travel, the following additional rules shall apply: <section prefix="a">A vehicle shall be driven as nearly as may be practical entirely within a single lane and shall not be moved from that lane until the driver has first ascertained that the movement can be made with safety; </section><section prefix="b">A vehicle shall not be driven in the center lane except when overtaking and passing another vehicle where the roadway is clearly visible and the center lane is clear of traffic within a safe distance, or in preparation for a left turn or where a center lane is at the time allocated exclusively to traffic moving in the direction in which the vehicle is proceeding and is signposted to give notice of the allocation; and </section><section prefix="c">Official signs may be erected directing slow-moving traffic to use a designated lane or allocating specified lanes to traffic moving in the same direction and operators of vehicles shall obey the directions of such signs. </section></section><section prefix="7">A vehicle shall not be driven in the left lane of any limited access highway of four (4) lanes or more with a posted speed limit of at least sixty-five (65) miles per hour, except in overtaking a slower vehicle, yielding to traffic coming onto such a highway, or when traffic conditions exist which would prohibit safe use of the right or center lanes. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">The operator of a motor vehicle shall not follow another vehicle more closely than is reasonable and prudent, having regard for the speed of the vehicle and the traffic upon and condition of the highway. </section><section prefix="b">The operator of any motor truck, semitrailer truck, bus, or heavy construction equipment unit, when traveling upon a highway outside of a business or residential district, shall not follow within two hundred fifty (250) feet of another such vehicle or equipment unit. This subsection shall not prevent overtaking and passing, nor shall it apply to any lane specially designated for use of motor trucks or semitrailer trucks, buses or heavy construction equipment units. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 17, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(4). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-40. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>