<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.775</section_number><catch_line>Educational programs on investigation and prosecution of crimes against the elderly. </catch_line><order_by>775</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Prosecutors Advisory Council shall develop, in conjunction with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, educational programs on the investigation and prosecution of abuse, neglect, and exploitation of the elderly and other crimes against the elderly. </section><section prefix="2">A program not less than four (4) hours in length shall be made available to each Commonwealth's attorney, county attorney, assistant Commonwealth's attorney, assistant county attorney, Commonwealth's detective, and county detective within six (6) months of the person's initial taking of office or beginning of employment. Successful completion of the program shall be required for each officer specified, except for the elected Commonwealth's attorney and county attorney. The program shall also include the use of a multidisciplinary team in the investigation of crimes specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Each assistant Commonwealth's attorney, assistant county attorney, Commonwealth's detective, and county detective shall successfully complete a two (2) hour update on the subjects specified in subsection (1) of this section at least once every five (5) years. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>