<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.364</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities of Motorcycle Safety Education Commission. </catch_line><order_by>364</order_by><text>The Motorcycle Safety Education Commission shall have the following responsibilities: <section prefix="1">Approve any administrative regulation relating to the motorcycle safety education program promulgated by the cabinet prior to the administrative regulation being filed with the Legislative Research Commission pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="2">Approve any proposal by the cabinet to contract for services pursuant to KRS Chapter 45A or any interagency agreement for services relating to the motorcycle safety education program prior to the issuance of the contract or the agreement; </section><section prefix="3">Approve all expenditures of money relating to the motorcycle safety education program which has not been specifically authorized in the biennial budget; </section><section prefix="4">Establish for the cabinet the short-range and long-range goals to promote the continued growth and expansion of the motorcycle safety education program; </section><section prefix="5">Make recommendations regarding the administration of the motorcycle safety education program; </section><section prefix="6">Ensure that the cabinet and the motorcycle safety education program is informed on the views and philosophies of interested parties; and </section><section prefix="7">Act as a communication channel between the relevant state agencies and motorcyclists and the general public. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 55, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 8, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(7/1/2005).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h), during codification a manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected. In subsection (2) of 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 8, the phrase "motorcycle education program" has been corrected to read "motorcycle safety education program" as it is clear from the context that the word "safety" was erroneously omitted. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1080</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>