<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.011</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>011</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context thereof requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means Kentucky Board of Nursing; </section><section prefix="2">"Delegation" means directing a competent person to perform a selected nursing activity or task in a selected situation under the nurse's supervision and pursuant to administrative regulations promulgated by the board in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="3">"Nurse" means a person who is licensed or holds the privilege to practice under the provisions of this chapter as a registered nurse or as a licensed practical nurse; </section><section prefix="4">"Nursing process" means the investigative approach to nursing practice utilizing a method of problem-solving by means of: <section prefix="a">Nursing diagnosis, a systematic investigation of a health concern, and an analysis of the data collected in order to arrive at an identifiable problem; and </section><section prefix="b">Planning, implementation, and evaluation based on nationally accepted standards of nursing practice; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Registered nurse" means one who is licensed or holds the privilege under the provisions of this chapter to engage in registered nursing practice; </section><section prefix="6">"Registered nursing practice" means the performance of acts requiring substantial specialized knowledge, judgment, and nursing skill based upon the principles of psychological, biological, physical, and social sciences in the application of the nursing process in: <section prefix="a">The care, counsel, and health teaching of the ill, injured, or infirm; </section><section prefix="b">The maintenance of health or prevention of illness of others; </section><section prefix="c">The administration of medication and treatment as prescribed by a physician, physician assistant, dentist, or advanced practice registered nurse and as further authorized or limited by the board, and which are consistent either with American Nurses' Association Scope and Standards of Practice or with standards of practice established by nationally accepted organizations of registered nurses. Components of medication administration include but are not limited to: <section prefix="1">Preparing and giving medications in the prescribed dosage, route, and frequency, including dispensing medications only as defined in subsection (17)(b) of this section; </section><section prefix="2">Observing, recording, and reporting desired effects, untoward reactions, and side effects of drug therapy; </section><section prefix="3">Intervening when emergency care is required as a result of drug therapy; </section><section prefix="4">Recognizing accepted prescribing limits and reporting deviations to the prescribing individual; </section><section prefix="5">Recognizing drug incompatibilities and reporting interactions or potential interactions to the prescribing individual; and </section><section prefix="6">Instructing an individual regarding medications; </section></section><section prefix="d">The supervision, teaching of, and delegation to other personnel in the performance of activities relating to nursing care; and </section><section prefix="e">The performance of other nursing acts which are authorized or limited by the board, and which are consistent either with American Nurses' Association Standards of Practice or with Standards of Practice established by nationally accepted organizations of registered nurses; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Advanced practice registered nurse" or "APRN" means a certified nurse practitioner, certified registered nurse anesthetist, certified nurse midwife, or clinical nurse specialist, who is licensed to engage in advance practice registered nursing pursuant to KRS 314.042 and certified in at least one (1) population focus; </section><section prefix="8">"Advanced practice registered nursing" means the performance of additional acts by registered nurses who have gained advanced clinical knowledge and skills through an accredited education program that prepares the registered nurse for one (1) of the four (4) APRN roles; who are certified by the American Nurses' Association or other nationally established organizations or agencies recognized by the board to certify registered nurses for advanced practice registered nursing as a certified nurse practitioner, certified registered nurse anesthetist, certified nurse midwife, or clinical nurse specialist; and who certified in at least one (1) population focus. The additional acts shall, subject to approval of the board, include but not be limited to prescribing treatment, drugs, devices, and ordering diagnostic tests. Advanced practice registered nurses who engage in these additional acts shall be authorized to issue prescriptions for and dispense nonscheduled legend drugs as defined in KRS 217.905 and to issue prescriptions for but not to dispense Schedules II through V controlled substances as classified in KRS 218A.060, 218A.070, 218A.080, 218A.090, 218A.100, 218A.110, 218A.120, and 218A.130, under the conditions set forth in KRS 314.042 and regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Nursing on or before August 15, 2006. <section prefix="a">Prescriptions issued by advanced practice registered nurses for Schedule II controlled substances classified under KRS 218A.060 shall be limited to a seventy-two (72) hour supply without any refill. Prescriptions issued under this subsection for psychostimulants may be written for a thirty (30) day supply only by an advanced practice registered nurse certified in psychiatric-mental health nursing who is providing services in a health facility as defined in KRS Chapter 216B or in a regional services program for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability as defined in KRS Chapter 210. </section><section prefix="b">Prescriptions issued by advanced practice registered nurses for Schedule III controlled substances classified under KRS 218A.080 shall be limited to a thirty (30) day supply without any refill. Prescriptions issued by advanced practice registered nurses for Schedules IV and V controlled substances classified under KRS 218A.100 and 218A.120 shall be limited to the original prescription and refills not to exceed a six (6) month supply. </section><section prefix="c">Limitations for specific controlled substances which are identified as having the greatest potential for abuse or diversion, based on the best available scientific and law enforcement evidence, shall be established in an administrative regulation promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Nursing. The regulation shall be based on recommendations from the Controlled Substances Formulary Development Committee, which is hereby created. The committee shall be composed of two (2) advanced practice registered nurses appointed by the Kentucky Board of Nursing, one (1) of whom shall be designated as a committee co-chair; two (2) physicians appointed by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, one (1) of whom shall be designated as a committee co-chair; and one (1) pharmacist appointed by the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. The initial regulation shall be promulgated on or before August 15, 2006, and shall be reviewed at least annually thereafter by the committee. </section></section> Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as requiring an advanced practice registered nurse designated by the board as a certified registered nurse anesthetist to obtain prescriptive authority pursuant to this chapter or any other provision of law in order to deliver anesthesia care. The performance of these additional acts shall be consistent with the certifying organization or agencies' scopes and standards of practice recognized by the board by administrative regulation; <section prefix="9">"Licensed practical nurse" means one who is licensed or holds the privilege under the provisions of this chapter to engage in licensed practical nursing practice; </section><section prefix="10">"Licensed practical nursing practice" means the performance of acts requiring knowledge and skill such as are taught or acquired in approved schools for practical nursing in: <section prefix="a">The observing and caring for the ill, injured, or infirm under the direction of a registered nurse, advanced practice registered nurse, physician assistant, licensed physician, or dentist; </section><section prefix="b">The giving of counsel and applying procedures to safeguard life and health, as defined and authorized by the board; </section><section prefix="c">The administration of medication or treatment as authorized by a physician, physician assistant, dentist, or advanced practice registered nurse and as further authorized or limited by the board which is consistent with the National Federation of Licensed Practical Nurses or with Standards of Practice established by nationally accepted organizations of licensed practical nurses; </section><section prefix="d">Teaching, supervising, and delegating except as limited by the board; and </section><section prefix="e">The performance of other nursing acts which are authorized or limited by the board and which are consistent with the National Federation of Practical Nurses' Standards of Practice or with Standards of Practice established by nationally accepted organizations of licensed practical nurses; </section></section><section prefix="11">"School of nursing" means a nursing education program preparing persons for licensure as a registered nurse or a practical nurse; </section><section prefix="12">"Continuing education" means offerings beyond the basic nursing program that present specific content planned and evaluated to meet competency based behavioral objectives which develop new skills and upgrade knowledge; </section><section prefix="13">"Nursing assistance" means the performance of delegated nursing acts by unlicensed nursing personnel for compensation under supervision of a nurse; </section><section prefix="14">"Sexual assault nurse examiner" means a registered nurse who has completed the required education and clinical experience and maintains a current credential from the board as provided under KRS 314.142 to conduct forensic examinations of victims of sexual offenses under the medical protocol issued by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet in consultation with the Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee pursuant to KRS 216B.400(4); </section><section prefix="15">"Competency" means the application of knowledge and skills in the utilization of critical thinking, effective communication, interventions, and caring behaviors consistent with the nurse's practice role within the context of the public's health, safety, and welfare; </section><section prefix="16">"Credential" means a current license, registration, certificate, or other similar authorization that is issued by the board; </section><section prefix="17">"Dispense" means: <section prefix="a">To receive and distribute noncontrolled legend drug samples from pharmaceutical manufacturers to patients at no charge to the patient or any other party; or </section><section prefix="b">To distribute noncontrolled legend drugs from a local, district, and independent health department, subject to the direction of the appropriate governing board of the individual health department; </section></section><section prefix="18">"Dialysis care" means a process by which dissolved substances are removed from a patient's body by diffusion, osmosis, and convection from one (1) fluid compartment to another across a semipermeable membrane; </section><section prefix="19">"Dialysis technician" means a person who is not a nurse, a physician assistant, or a physician and who provides dialysis care in a licensed renal dialysis facility under the direct, on-site supervision of a registered nurse or a physician; </section><section prefix="20">"Population focus" means the section of the population within which the advanced practice registered nurse has targeted to practice. The categories of population foci are: <section prefix="a">Family and individual across the lifespan; </section><section prefix="b">Adult gerontology; </section><section prefix="c">Neonatal; </section><section prefix="d">Pediatrics; </section><section prefix="e">Women's health and gender-related health; and </section><section prefix="f">Psychiatric mental health; and </section></section><section prefix="21">"Conviction" means but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">An unvacated adjudication of guilt; </section><section prefix="b">Pleading no contest or nolo contendere or entering an Alford plea; or </section><section prefix="c">Entering a guilty plea pursuant to a pretrial diversion order; </section></section> Regardless of whether the penalty is rebated, suspended, or probated. </text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 112, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 52, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 101, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 296, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective June 1, 2007; and ch. 5, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec.2 effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 80, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 391, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 342, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. --Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44647</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>