<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.300</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 335.300 to 335.399. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text>As used in KRS 335.300 to 335.399, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Licensure of Marriage and Family Therapists; </section><section prefix="2">"Licensed marriage and family therapist" means a person who has completed all of the requirements set out in KRS 335.330 and who holds a license issued by the board; </section><section prefix="3">"Marriage and family therapy associate" means a person who has completed all requirements set out in KRS 335.330 and who holds a permit issued by the board to practice marriage and family therapy under the conditions set out in KRS 335.332 and the corresponding administrative regulations promulgated by the board; and </section><section prefix="4">"The practice of marriage and family therapy" means the identification and treatment of cognitive, affective, and behavioral conditions related to marital and family dysfunctions that involve the professional application of psychotherapeutic and systems theories and techniques in the delivery of services to individuals, couples, and families. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize any licensed marriage and family therapist or marriage and family therapy associate to administer or interpret psychological tests in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 319. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31938</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>