<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261">STOCKYARDS </unit></structure><section_number>261.375</section_number><catch_line>License required -- Renewal, records of transactions -- Violations -- License revocation or suspension. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in the business of being a livestock dealer without having first obtained a license from the department. Application for a license shall be made on a form provided by the department and accompanied by a fee of ten dollars ($10), payable to the Kentucky State Treasurer. The license shall expire on December 31 and shall be renewed annually. </section><section prefix="2">Any livestock dealer shall maintain records of all transactions conducted by him for the next preceding two (2) year period, including the names and addresses of persons from whom he has purchased or to whom he has sold livestock and the date of the transactions, and make the records available to department representatives upon request, but shall not be required to maintain or furnish records or information as to the amount paid or received for any head of livestock. </section><section prefix="3">The following acts by any livestock dealer shall be violations of this chapter and may result in a license being revoked or suspended by the Commissioner of Agriculture: <section prefix="a">Failing to maintain the records required under subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Failing to provide access to department representatives of records; </section><section prefix="c">Buying or selling livestock under an assumed name or address; and </section><section prefix="d">Violating of any valid administrative regulation or statute governing disease control. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the Commissioner has reasonable cause to believe any provision of this chapter is being or has been violated by any livestock dealer, the Commissioner shall notify the livestock dealer that his license may be suspended or revoked. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 183, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 1. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification> KRS 257.530. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12703</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>