<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.580</section_number><catch_line>Joint ad hoc committee on transitioning from children's services systems to adult services systems -- Membership -- Duties -- Report. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with an Intellectual Disability and Other Developmental Disorders established in KRS 210.575, and the Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports to Individuals with Mental Illness, Alcohol and Other Drug Disorders, and Dual Diagnoses established in KRS 210.502 shall, by August 1, 2004, establish a joint ad hoc committee on transitioning from children's services systems to adult services systems for children who will continue to need services or supports after reaching age twenty-one (21). </section><section prefix="2">The co-chairpersons of each commission shall each designate a joint ad hoc committee chairperson and appoint up to ten (10) members for the joint ad hoc committee. At least seventy-five percent (75%) of the membership shall be composed of family members of consumers of adult or child services, advocates, and nonprofit and community-based providers of adult and child services and supports. Members of the commissions may serve as a chairperson and may be appointed to the ad hoc committee. </section><section prefix="3">The joint ad hoc committee shall develop recommendations for implementation of specific plans of action to meet the needs of children who transition to adult services systems. </section><section prefix="4">The joint ad hoc committee shall make a preliminary report by October 30, 2004, and shall make a final report by December 30, 2004, to both commissions and to the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 24, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8302</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>