<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.780</section_number><catch_line>Termination of contract by teacher or superintendent -- Resignation binding as of date of acceptance. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No teacher shall be permitted to terminate his or her contract within fifteen (15) days prior to the first instructional day of the school term at a school to which the teacher is assigned or during the school term without the consent of the superintendent. No superintendent shall be permitted to terminate his or her contract within thirty (30) days prior to the beginning of the school term or during the school term without the consent of the employing board of education. A teacher shall be permitted to terminate his or her contract at any other time when schools are not in session by giving two (2) weeks written notice to the employing superintendent. A superintendent shall be permitted to terminate his or her contract at any other time when schools are not in session by giving two (2) weeks written notice to the employing board of education. Upon complaint by the employing board or superintendent to the Education Professional Standards Board, the certificate of a teacher or superintendent terminating his contract in any manner other than provided in this section may be suspended for not more than one (1) year, pursuant to the hearing procedures set forth in KRS 161.120. </section><section prefix="2">If a teacher voluntarily resigns his contract during the school term, the resignation shall be in writing and shall become binding on the date the resignation is accepted by the superintendent. No further action by the employing board is necessary. The resignation is effective on the date specified in the letter of resignation. A resignation, once accepted, may be withdrawn only with the approval of the employing board of education. Nothing in this subsection shall release the teacher from liability to the local board of education for breach of contract. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 7, effective April 14, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. IV, se 248, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> April 14, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3999</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>