<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.780</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited handling practices. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text>It shall be unlawful for a handler of milk in this state to: <section prefix="1">Receive or buy milk from permitted producers or their agents without obtaining a license for each location where milk is received or handled; </section><section prefix="2">Receive milk that is paid for on the basis of weight or volume without having it sampled and weighed or measured by a licensed sampler-weigher; </section><section prefix="3">Manipulate weights, measurements, or tests that are to be used as a basis to purchase milk; </section><section prefix="4">Use false or incorrect records of weights or tests as a basis for payment; </section><section prefix="5">Receive milk purchased from permitted producers by a milk handler that does not have a license to handle; </section><section prefix="6">Use weighing, mixing, sampling, or testing equipment which is inaccurate or nonstandard; </section><section prefix="7">Fail to comply with administrative regulations for weighing, measuring, sampling, and testing milk issued by the director; </section><section prefix="8">Fail to keep records of weights and tests as required by administrative regulation or fail to make such records available for inspection by the director; </section><section prefix="9">Receive milk which is paid for on the basis of tests without having it tested by a licensed tester; </section><section prefix="10">Fail to notify the director in writing of any knowledge of an inaccurately calibrated bulk milk tank; or </section><section prefix="11">Hinder or obstruct any authorized person in the performance of his or her duties under KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 10, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>