<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.318</section_number><catch_line>Board's disciplinary powers -- Reasons for sanctions -- Appeal to Franklin Circuit Court. </catch_line><order_by>318</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue a license or suspend, revoke, impose probationary conditions upon, impose an administrative fine, issue a written reprimand, or any combination thereof regarding any licensee upon proof that the licensee has: <section prefix="a">Been convicted of a crime as described in KRS 335B.010(4) or an offense that otherwise directly relates to the occupation of interpreter. A plea of "no contest" may be treated as a conviction for purposes of disciplinary action; </section><section prefix="b">Knowingly misrepresented or concealed a material fact in obtaining a license or in reinstatement thereof; </section><section prefix="c">Committed any fraudulent act or practice; </section><section prefix="d">Been incompetent or negligent in the practice of interpreting; </section><section prefix="e">Violated any state statute or administrative regulation governing the practice of interpreting; </section><section prefix="f">Violated the code of ethics of the national organization issuing the licensee's certification as incorporated in administrative regulation; or </section><section prefix="g">Violated any federal or state law considered by the board to be applicable to the practice of interpreting. </section></section><section prefix="2">When the board issues a written reprimand to the licensee, a copy of the reprimand shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to submit a response within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have that response filed in the permanent file. </section><section prefix="3">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may accept an assurance of voluntary compliance from the licensee which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="4">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its probation, suspensions, or other disciplinary action. </section><section prefix="5">Five (5) years from the date of a revocation, any person whose license has been revoked may petition the board for reinstatement. The board shall investigate the petition and may reinstate the license upon a finding that the individual has complied with any terms prescribed by the board and is again able to competently engage in the practice of interpreting. </section><section prefix="6">Any party aggrieved by a disciplinary action of the board may bring an action in Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30360</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>