<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="327" order_by="327">PHYSICAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>327.030</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Physical Therapy -- Membership -- Qualifications -- Vacancies. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>There is hereby established a Board of Physical Therapy which shall consist of seven (7) members who shall be appointed by the Governor. <section prefix="1">One (1) board member shall be a resident of Kentucky who is not affiliated with or does not have more than five percent (5%) financial interest in any health care profession or business. </section><section prefix="2">All other board members shall: <section prefix="a">Be residents of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Have engaged in the practice of physical therapy in Kentucky for the past five (5) years; and </section><section prefix="c">Not have been disciplined by the board, or have been under any disciplinary action, in the past two (2) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">All vacancies shall be filled by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons per position submitted by the Kentucky Physical Therapy Association or as provided by KRS 12.070. </section><section prefix="4">For appointments to the board after December 31, 2008, the first two (2) appointments shall be for a term of two (2) years. The third appointment shall be for a term of three (3) years. All other subsequent appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years. All members shall serve until their successors are appointed and qualify. No member shall serve for more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="5">The Governor may remove any member of the board for misconduct, incompetence, or neglect of duty. </section><section prefix="6">The board may request the removal of a board member by the Governor. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall annually elect a chair and chair-elect. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall provide orientation to all new board members regarding the duties of the board. </section><section prefix="9">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no action for damages against, any current or former board member, representative, agent, or employee of the board, when the person is functioning within the scope of board duties, acting without malice and with the reasonable belief that the actions taken by him or her are warranted by law. </section><section prefix="10">Each board member shall receive, in addition to travel, lodging, and other actual and necessary expenses, a per diem not to exceed one hundred twenty dollars ($120) for each day the member is actually engaged in the discharge of official duties approved by the board. The board shall, by promulgation of administrative regulations, set the amount of the per diem. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 23. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 3. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>