<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.050</section_number><catch_line>Amendments to articles.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The articles of incorporation may be amended as provided in this section at any regular or special meeting of the members of the corporation duly called upon notice of the specific purpose. The amendment shall first be approved by two-thirds (2/3) of the directors and then adopted by a vote representing not less than a majority of the votes entitled to be cast by the members present in person, or by proxy (if permitted by the bylaws) and voting at such meeting. The president of the corporation shall make triplicate originals of the amendments so adopted, each satisfying the requirements of KRS 14A.2-010 to 14A.2-150 and the secretary of the corporation shall attest each triplicate original. Each triplicate original shall be acknowledged by the president and the secretary before an officer authorized to take acknowledgments of deeds, and the president shall then cause them to be filed, approved and recorded in the same manner as is provided by KRS 279.040 for original articles of incorporation, and the amendments shall take effect upon filing by the Secretary of State. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 82, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 4, effective June 21, 1974. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 883j-10. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>