<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.0736</section_number><catch_line>Logo and service signs -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>0736</order_by><text>The commissioner of the Department of Highways shall promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, to provide for the erection of specific service signs on fully controlled access highways or at interchanges on partially controlled access highways. The administrative regulations shall conform to the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD), and shall include, but not be limited to, criteria for the following: <section prefix="1">Distances to eligible businesses; </section><section prefix="2">Selection of eligible businesses; </section><section prefix="3">Acceptance of logo signs that conform to the MUTCD; </section><section prefix="4">Removing or covering logo signs during off seasons for eligible businesses operated on a seasonal basis; </section><section prefix="5">Defining the circumstances in which specific service signs are erected; and </section><section prefix="6">Determining the costs to eligible businesses for initial installation, annual maintenance, and removal of logo signs. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5257</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>