<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.4909</section_number><catch_line>Operator to provide protection notification center access to excavators -- Kentucky Contact Center -- Rejection of design information request -- Color coding for temporary underground facility markers -- Operator's inability to comply due to extraordinary circumstances -- Underground facilities installed after January 1, 2013.     </catch_line><order_by>4909</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each operator shall provide protection notification center access to excavators. </section><section prefix="2">Voluntary operator membership in the Kentucky Contact Center shall satisfy the requirement of subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Each operator member of the Kentucky Contact Center shall provide and update as needed to the Kentucky Contact Center the general location of its underground facilities, the operator identity and business address, and emergency notification telephone numbers. </section><section prefix="4">An operator shall respond to facility locate requests as follows: <section prefix="a">To a normal excavation locate request within two (2) working days after receiving notification from an excavator, excluding large projects. </section><section prefix="b">To an emergency locate request as quickly as possible but not to exceed forty-eight (48) hours after receiving notification from an excavator; </section><section prefix="c">To a design information request within ten (10) working days after receiving notification from the person making the request; and </section><section prefix="d">To a large project request within five (5) working days from the later of receiving notification from an excavator or the scheduled excavation start date for that location. </section></section><section prefix="5">An operator shall, upon receiving an emergency locate request or a normal excavation locate request: <section prefix="a">Inform the excavator of the approximate location and description of any of the operator's facilities that may be damaged or pose a safety concern because of excavation or demolition; </section><section prefix="b">Inform the excavator of any other information that would assist in locating and avoiding contact with or damage to underground facilities; </section><section prefix="c">Unless permanent facility markers are provided, provide temporary markings to inform the excavator of the ownership and approximate location of the underground facility; and </section><section prefix="d">Notify the requesting party if underground facilities are not in conflict with the excavation or demolition. </section></section><section prefix="6">Upon receiving a design information request, an operator shall contact the person making the request within the time period specified in subsection (4) of this section. The operator shall: <section prefix="a">Designate with temporary underground facility markers the location of all underground facilities owned by the operator within the area of the design information request as defined in KRS 367.4903; </section><section prefix="b">Provide to the person making the design information request a description of all underground facilities owned by the operator in the area of the design information request and the location of the facilities, which may include drawings marked with a scale, dimensions, and reference points for underground utilities already built in the area or other facility records that are maintained by the operator; or </section><section prefix="c">Allow the person making the design information request or an authorized person to inspect the drawings or other records for all underground facilities with the proposed area of excavation at a location that is acceptable to the operator. </section></section><section prefix="7">An operator may reject a design information request based upon security considerations or if producing the information will place the operator at a competitive disadvantage, pending the operator obtaining additional information confirming the legitimacy of the notice. The operator shall notify the person making the design information request and may request additional information. </section><section prefix="8">Temporary underground facility markers shall consist of paint, chalk, flags, stakes, or any combination thereof and shall conform to the following standards of the American Public Works Association uniform color code: <section prefix="a">Electric power distribution and transmission  Safety Red </section><section prefix="b">Municipal electric systems  Safety Red </section><section prefix="c">Gas distribution and transmission  High visibility safety yellow </section><section prefix="d">Oil distribution and transmission  High visibility safety yellow </section><section prefix="e">Dangerous materials, product lines  High visibility safety yellow </section><section prefix="f">Telecommunication systems and cable television Safety alert orange </section><section prefix="g">Temporary survey markings  Safety pink </section><section prefix="h">Police and fire communications  Safety alert orange </section><section prefix="i">Water systems   Safety precaution blue </section><section prefix="j">Sewer and storm drainage systems  Safety green </section><section prefix="k">Proposed excavation or construction boundaries  White </section><section prefix="l">Reclaimed water, slurry, and irrigation facilities  Purple </section></section><section prefix="9">If extraordinary circumstances exist, an operator shall notify the excavator of the operator's inability to comply with this section. Extraordinary circumstances include extreme weather conditions, force majeure, disasters, or civil unrest that make timely response difficult or impossible. </section><section prefix="10">All underground facilities installed after January 1, 2013, shall include a means to accurately identify and locate the underground facilities from the surface. This subsection does not apply to the repair of existing facilities. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 425, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44309</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>