<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.130</section_number><catch_line>President -- Administrative divisions -- Employees and agents -- Contracts with management corporation. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Fair Board may employ or contract with a president who shall not be one of their number. The president shall be the chief executive officer for the board. The employment or contract of a president shall be on the basis of training, ability, and experience. A president shall hold his position during the pleasure of the board, but may be removed only by an affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the board and upon thirty (30) days written notice. A president shall be responsible for the administration of the policies set by the board and shall devote his entire time and attention to the performance of such duties and work as may be required of him by law or be assigned to him by the board. The board shall determine the term, conditions, and compensation of its president, provided such term does not exceed four (4) years. </section><section prefix="2">The president may organize such administrative divisions as may be necessary and may designate chiefs of such divisions who, under his control and supervision, shall have the duties of direction of such divisions. The president shall organize a Division for Personnel Management and Staff Development which shall manage all personnel matters, including staff development and training and programs for affirmative action. The director of this division shall be appointed, with the prior written approval of the Governor, by the president. The president may employ such other employees and agents as he deems necessary for the carrying out of the policies of the board and to conduct the affairs of the State Fair, and may fix the duties and compensation of any employees or agents with the approval of the board. </section><section prefix="3">The board may employ or contract with such other persons, firms, or corporations as the board may deem necessary or desirable to accomplish its duties and functions; may fix the compensation and the terms of employment or contract of those employed or contracted with; and may assign to them such duties and responsibilities as the board may determine, including the responsibility of actual operation of any or all of the facilities under the control of the board. </section><section prefix="4">The president and any persons employed under this section shall not be subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 18A. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 485, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 509, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 32, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 2. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 48; and ch. 80, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618i-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts which conflict and cannot be compiled together. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the later enactment prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>