<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="251" order_by="251">GRAIN WAREHOUSES </unit></structure><section_number>251.430</section_number><catch_line>License required -- Exception -- Renewal -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text>Any person, firm, or corporation who accepts grain for storage in this state shall first procure a license from the department as required by the board before transacting any business. This shall not apply to the storage of grain by an establishment bonded and licensed under the provisions of a federal law to the extent that the stored grain is covered by a federal bond and law; otherwise, the establishments shall comply with the provisions of this chapter. Any establishment that has unpaid-for grain thirty (30) days after delivery of the last load by a producer shall be considered in the grain storage business. The license shall expire on June 30, and shall be renewed annually by August 1. The fee for each license shall be according to the following schedule, and shall be used for carrying out the provisions of this chapter: Total annual volume handled: <section prefix="1">Under two million (2,000,000) bushels, three hundred dollars ($300); </section><section prefix="2">Two million (2,000,000) to five million nine hundred ninety-nine thousand nine hundred ninety-nine (5,999,999) bushels, four hundred fifty dollars ($450); </section><section prefix="3">Six million (6,000,000) to nine million nine hundred ninety-nine thousand nine hundred ninety-nine (9,999,999) bushels, six hundred dollars ($600); or </section><section prefix="4">Ten million (10,000,000) bushels and up, seven hundred fifty dollars ($750). </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 2. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (4/24/2006). For the sake of consistency with the numbering system used throughout the Kentucky Revised Statutes, the designations "(a)," "(b)," "(c)," and "(d)" in this statute have been changed to "(1)," "(2)," "(3)," and "(4)." See KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>