<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.390</section_number><catch_line>General duties as to condition of schools -- Responsibilities -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The superintendent shall devote himself exclusively to his duties. He shall exercise general supervision of the schools of his district, examine their condition and progress, and keep himself informed of the progress in other districts. He shall prepare or have prepared all budgets, salary schedules, and reports required of his board by the Kentucky Board of Education. He shall advise himself of the need of extension of the school system of the district, shall receive and examine reports from teachers and other school officers, and shall make reports from time to time as required by the rules of his board or as directed by the board. He shall be responsible to the board for the general condition of the schools. He shall be responsible for all personnel actions including hiring, assignments, transfer, dismissal, suspension, reinstatement, promotion, and demotion and reporting the actions to the local board. </section><section prefix="2">All personnel actions by the superintendent as described in subsection (1) shall be recorded in the minutes of the local board of education at the next meeting after the action is taken and shall not be effective prior to receipt of written notice of the personnel action by the affected employee from the superintendent. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 90, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-34. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>