<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.840</section_number><catch_line>Procedure to acquire title under KRS 171.836. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After the provisions of KRS 171.836(1) or (2) have been met, a museum may initiate proceedings pursuant to this section to cause title to the property to vest in the museum. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The museum shall attempt to notify the owner, pursuant to this subsection, of its intention to gain title to the property. </section><section prefix="b">The museum shall rely on its own records to determine the most recent address of the last known owner. The property owner shall have the responsibility of notifying the museum in writing of the property owner's change of address or a change in ownership of the property. <section prefix="1">Except as provided in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, the museum shall mail, by certified mail, return receipt requested, the notice, described in paragraph (d) of this subsection, to the last known owner's last known address. </section><section prefix="2">If the museum is unable to identify either a last known owner or an address for that person, the museum shall follow the procedures in paragraph (c) of this subsection to provide notice. </section></section><section prefix="c">If the museum is unable to locate the owner of the property pursuant to paragraph (b) of this subsection, the museum shall follow the publication requirements of this paragraph. The museum shall publish the notice, described in paragraph (d) of this subsection, at least twice each week for two (2) consecutive weeks: <section prefix="1">In a newspaper published in Kentucky with statewide circulation; </section><section prefix="2">In a newspaper published, and with statewide circulation, in the state of the last known address of the last known owner, if that state is known. If the last known address of the last known owner is in Kentucky, the notice shall still be published in two (2) newspapers of statewide circulation; and </section><section prefix="3">In a newspaper of less than statewide circulation published in the local area from which the museum acquired the property. </section></section><section prefix="d">The notices referred to in this subsection shall contain: <section prefix="1">The museum's name, address, and telephone number; </section><section prefix="2">A detailed description of the property; </section><section prefix="3">The last known owner's name, if that information is available; </section><section prefix="4">The last known owner's last known address, if that information is available; </section><section prefix="5">A request that all persons who may have any knowledge of the whereabouts of the owner contact the museum and provide the information; and </section><section prefix="6">A statement that if written assertion of title is not presented to the museum within six (6) months from the date of the final published notice, the title to the property shall vest in the museum, subject to KRS 171.843. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4874</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>