<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="333" order_by="333">MEDICAL LABORATORIES </unit></structure><section_number>333.190</section_number><catch_line>Denial, revocation, or suspension of laboratory license.   </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>A medical laboratory license may be denied, revoked, suspended, limited, annulled, or renewal thereof denied for any of the following reasons: <section prefix="1">Making false statements on an application for medical laboratory license or any other documents required by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">Permitting unauthorized persons to perform technical procedures or to issue or sign reports. </section><section prefix="3">Demonstrating incompetence or making frequent errors in the performance or reporting of medical laboratory examinations and procedures. </section><section prefix="4">Performing a test and rendering a report thereon to a person not authorized by law to receive such services. </section><section prefix="5">Reporting the results determined on a specimen by a medical laboratory which has not been licensed or exempted under this chapter. </section><section prefix="6">Rendering a report on medical laboratory work actually performed in another medical laboratory without designating the name of the director and the name and address of the medical laboratory in which the test was performed. </section><section prefix="7">Knowingly having professional connection with or knowingly lending the use of the name of the licensed medical laboratory or its director to an unlicensed medical laboratory. </section><section prefix="8">Violating or aiding and abetting in the violation of any provision of this chapter or the rules or regulations promulgated hereunder. </section><section prefix="9">Failing to submit to the cabinet any report required by the provisions of this chapter or the reasonable rules and regulations promulgated hereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 24, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 14, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 23. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44627</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>