<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="454" order_by="454">MISCELLANEOUS CIVIL PRACTICE PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>454.350</section_number><catch_line>Time within which judge, commissioner or hearing officer must issue judgment or report -- Certification of reason when delay occurs. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every Circuit and District Judge shall, when at all possible, issue a written judgment or order in all civil actions which have been submitted for final adjudication within ninety (90) days from the date the action was taken under submission. </section><section prefix="2">Where a report, findings, or recommendations of a commissioner or hearing officer are required by statute or rule as a prerequisite to an order or judgment by the Circuit or District Court the same shall be filed within ninety (90) days of the conclusion of the trial or hearing at which the commissioner or hearing officer presided. </section><section prefix="3">Every Circuit and District Judge shall at the end of every month certify in writing to the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court all cases which have been submitted for final adjudication for longer than ninety (90) days and have not been adjudicated and certify in writing to the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court the reason for the delay. </section><section prefix="4">Any District or Circuit Judge who knowingly violates any of the provisions of this section shall be subject to removal by the Judicial Retirement and Removal Commission. </section></text><history>Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>