<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.131</section_number><catch_line>Inspection of records -- Public records. </catch_line><order_by>131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To protect the integrity of vital records, to insure their proper use, and to insure the efficient and proper administration of the system of vital statistics, it shall be unlawful for any person to permit inspection of, or to disclose information contained in vital records or to copy or issue a copy of all or part of any record except as authorized by this chapter, by regulation, or by order of a court of competent jurisdiction. Administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet shall provide for adequate standards of security and confidentiality of vital records and shall conform to subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The state registrar shall prepare annually an alphabetical list of all persons registered as born in the preceding year. The list shall show the person's name, the mother's maiden name, and the date and county of birth. This list shall be an open record subject to inspection by the public upon request. </section><section prefix="3">The state registrar shall prepare annually an alphabetical list of all persons registered who die in the Commonwealth. This list shall show the name of the deceased and the date and county of death and shall be an open record subject to inspection by the public upon request. </section><section prefix="4">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may authorize by regulation the disclosure of information contained in vital records for research and official administrative purposes, if: <section prefix="a">All information identifying persons named on the certificate is withheld or removed; </section><section prefix="b">The information is requested by a federal, state, county, or municipal agency of government which needs the data or information in the conduct of official duties; or </section><section prefix="c">The cabinet has prepared, in writing, a statement of the conditions under which the data or records will be used and received an agreement signed by a responsible agent of the research organization agreeing to meet with and conform to the conditions. </section></section><section prefix="5">If one hundred (100) years have elapsed after the date of birth, or fifty (50) years have elapsed after the date of death, the records of these events in the custody of the state registrar shall become public records and information shall be made available in accordance with regulations which shall provide for continued safekeeping of the records. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 441, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 390, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 25, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>