<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.460</section_number><catch_line>Applications for bonus. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All applications for the bonus shall be submitted to the adjutant general, Commonwealth of Kentucky, in writing, upon forms made available for that purpose, and shall be accompanied by the documentary evidence prescribed by appropriate administrative regulations. Every application shall be certified under the penalties of perjury, and shall contain representations of the claimant or, if he shall have been adjudged incompetent, or be an infant, of his committee or guardian, that: <section prefix="a">The facts therein stated are true to the best of his knowledge and belief; </section><section prefix="b">All documents submitted in support of the application are believed by the claimant to be genuine originals or copies, as the case may be, and that the claimant has no knowledge that the document has been superseded or cancelled; </section><section prefix="c">The claimant has not received from another state a bonus or compensation of a like nature as provided by KRS 40.410 to 40.560; </section><section prefix="d">The claimant has not received the Kentucky veterans' bonus provided under KRS 40.005 to 40.230 and 40.990; </section><section prefix="e">The claimant has neither paid nor agreed to pay, directly or indirectly, any compensation for assistance received in preparing and tendering the application; and </section><section prefix="f">The claimant has knowledge of the fine and forfeiture provisions of KRS 40.410 to 40.560; </section></section><section prefix="2">The application form shall contain provision for, and each claimant shall elect, one (1) of the following choices: <section prefix="a">The claimant is eligible for and desires to receive a bonus payment; or </section><section prefix="b">The claimant is eligible for a bonus payment but requests that his payment be deposited into a veterans' program trust fund, which is hereby established, the proceeds and interest therefrom to be used for veterans' programs. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4, effective March 1, 1991. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>