<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.27-070</section_number><catch_line>Sales and use tax incentives. </catch_line><order_by>27-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding KRS 134.580(3) and 139.770, on or after January 1, 2008, an approved company is eligible for an incentive in an amount up to one hundred percent (100%) of the Kentucky sales and use tax paid, reduced by the vendor compensation provided under KRS 139.570, on the purchase of tangible personal property, including but not limited to materials, machinery, and equipment used to construct, retrofit, or upgrade an eligible project. </section><section prefix="2">The incentive shall not include tangible personal property purchased before the activation date or purchases of operating supplies, or repair, replacement, or spare parts as defined in KRS 139.010. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the activation date, an approved company may be eligible for the incentive offered under this section. The approved company shall file a request for the incentive payment with the department as provided in KRS 139.517. </section><section prefix="4">The incentive provided in this section shall expire upon the completion of the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the eligible project, or five (5) years from the activation date, whichever is earlier. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 19, effective August 1, 2008. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>