<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.73-100</section_number><catch_line>Sewage treatment company may condemn rights-of-way -- Approval required -- Objections. </catch_line><order_by>73-100</order_by><text>Any corporation authorized to do business in this state and organized for the purpose of constructing, maintaining and operating sewer lines and sewage treatment facilities may, if it is unable to contract or agree with the owner after a good faith effort to do so, condemn rights-of-way necessary for constructing, maintaining and operating its pipelines and, if necessary, pumping stations; and the necessary ingress and egress to examine, alter, repair and maintain such pipelines. The condemnation proceedings shall be conducted in the manner provided in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky. Provided, however, that before any corporation shall be authorized to use the provisions of this section, it shall have presented plans and specifications to the Energy and Environment Cabinet and received from said cabinet a permit to operate and maintain said sewage treatment facilities together with an approval of the discharge of the treated effluent from said facilities to a specific point of the waters of this Commonwealth. Provided, further, that any person wishing to object to a pipeline or plant location subject to the provisions of this section shall have the right to have his objections heard by said cabinet pursuant to the provisions of KRS 224.10-440. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 381, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 94, effective June 19, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(2), effective June 21, 1974. -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 46, effective January 1, 1973. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 196, secs. 1 to 3, effective March 21, 1964. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.130, and also previously codified as KRS 220.660. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10532</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>