<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="163" order_by="163">VOCATIONAL EDUCATION AND REHABILITATION </unit></structure><section_number>163.506</section_number><catch_line>Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing -- Membership -- Terms -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing shall consist of: <section prefix="a">Seven (7) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="1">One (1) audiologist chosen from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Speech and Hearing Association; </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) hard of hearing or deaf persons chosen from a list of six (6) names submitted by the Kentucky Association of the Deaf; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) deaf or hard of hearing person chosen from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Chapter of the Alexander Graham Bell Association for the Deaf, the initial appointment to be for a one (1) year term; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) hard of hearing or deaf person chosen from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky members of Self Help for Hard of Hearing People, the initial appointment to be for a two (2) year term; and </section><section prefix="5">One (1) deaf, late-deafened, or hard of hearing person chosen from a list of three (3) names submitted by the American Association of Retired Persons, the initial appointment to be for a two (2) year term; </section></section><section prefix="b">One (1) representative of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services appointed by the secretary; </section><section prefix="c">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or his designee; </section><section prefix="d">The president of the Kentucky Association for the Deaf or his designee; </section><section prefix="e">The president of the Kentucky Registry of Interpreters for the Deaf or his designee; and </section><section prefix="f">Three (3) persons appointed by the Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing as constituted in subsections (1)(a) through (1)(e) of this section, appointed as follows: <section prefix="1">One (1) parent of a hard of hearing or deaf child; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) representative of a public or private organization providing consistent services to the deaf and hard of hearing; and </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member at large. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">All members shall serve three (3) year terms except state officials or their designees who shall serve during their terms of office. Of the members appointed pursuant to subsection (1)(a)2. through (1)(a)5. and subsection (1)(f) of this section, no more than three (3) of those members shall have terms beginning in the same year. Any person who is a member of the commission on July 13, 1990, shall serve until he resigns or until his term expires. </section><section prefix="3">Each member of the commission shall be reimbursed for his necessary travel and other expenses actually incurred in the discharge of his duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 54, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 98, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 23, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 119, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 32 and 426. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 426, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4149</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>