<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.4475</section_number><catch_line>Assessment to be levied and collected by agency conducting referendum.   </catch_line><order_by>4475</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If, in the referendum called under the provisions of KRS 247.4451 to 247.4483, a majority of the producers eligible to participate and voting therein, shall vote in the affirmative and in favor of the levying and collection of the assessment proposed in the referendum on the agricultural commodity, then the assessment shall be collected in the manner determined and announced by the agency conducting the referendum. </section><section prefix="2">Any agricultural cooperative association organized under KRS Chapter 272 or 272A, any foreign agricultural cooperative association, or any foreign limited cooperative association that has received a certificate of authority to conduct business in the Commonwealth in the same manner as a domestic agricultural cooperative association, on application to an approval by the Commissioner, may by an alternate procedure, not in conflict with the purposes of KRS 247.4451 to 247.4483, handle the collection and disbursement of the assessments of its members. The purchaser of the agricultural commodity of the members of the association shall be relieved of the collecting and reporting requirements of KRS 247.4477 with respect to the members. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 136, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41110</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>