<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.197</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of individual employed as a Trooper R Class or a commercial vehicle enforcement officer R Class.   </catch_line><order_by>197</order_by><text>An individual employed as a Trooper R Class or a commercial vehicle enforcement officer R class shall: <section prefix="1">Be a retired officer who prior to retirement was commissioned as an officer under this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Be a retired member of the State Police Retirement System established by KRS 16.505 to 16.652 or the Kentucky Employees Retirement System established by KRS 61.510 to 61.705, who retired with at least twenty (20) years of service credit; </section><section prefix="3">Upon appointment to Trooper R Class or commercial vehicle enforcement officer R class, have been separated from the service of the Department of Kentucky State Police for a period no less than one (1) month nor greater than sixty (60) months following the individual's effective retirement date from the State Police Retirement System or the Kentucky Employees Retirement System; </section><section prefix="4">Have retired willingly with no administrative charges against the officer pending under KRS 16.140 or 16.192; and </section><section prefix="5">Have retired with no pre-existing agreement between the employee and the department prior to the employee's retirement for the employee to return to work with the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42234</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>