<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.170</section_number><catch_line>Reporting of assaults, threats, and menacing conduct against client or staff -- Information system to track threats and violent incidents against staff -- Safety liaisons. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each staff member of the department shall report to his or her supervisor any physical or verbal conduct of a client or an individual associated with a client that appears to be threatening or menacing, and any incident of assault, attempted assault, or physical contact that appears to be threatening to any staff member. Any use or threat of use of any type of weapon shall be reported. The supervisor shall report threat or incident information to the commissioner of the department or his or her designee. An employee who reports under this subsection shall be protected from reprisals pursuant to KRS 61.102. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall establish and maintain an information system and track all reports of threats or incidents involving violence against department staff as required by subsection (1) of this section. The department shall provide, upon request, the number and type of reports received and any information available regarding civil or criminal action or changes to policies and procedures resulting from threats or incidents of violence upon staff. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall designate or establish a safety liaison position within its central office and in each regional office. The regional administrator may designate or establish a safety liaison position in each county office. The duties of the central office safety liaison shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Development and implementation of policies and procedures related to the prevention of violence in the office and in community settings; </section><section prefix="b">Screening and assessment of the level of threat for professional-client interactions; </section><section prefix="c">Facilitation of safety training and safety and first alert protocols with all law enforcement agencies that work with each county office. Existing multidisciplinary teams may be utilized in the development of local safety protocols; and </section><section prefix="d">Administration of a Web-based social worker safety site and a threat and violence incident database. </section></section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 3, effective April 5, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> April 5, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20127</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>