<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="326" order_by="326">OPHTHALMIC DISPENSERS </unit></structure><section_number>326.070</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions from chapter. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in the provisions of this chapter relating to ophthalmic dispensing shall be construed to limit or restrict, in any respect, the practice of medicine by duly licensed physicians, the practice of osteopathy by duly licensed osteopaths, or the practice of optometry by duly licensed optometrists. A licensed physician, osteopath, or optometrist shall have all the rights and privileges of ophthalmic dispensers licensed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall not be construed to prohibit an unlicensed person from performing mechanical work upon inert matter in an optical office, laboratory, or shop. </section><section prefix="3">Persons, firms, and corporations that sell completely assembled eyeglasses or spectacles without advice or aid as to their selection, as merchandise, from permanently located or established places of business shall not be subject to this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">Physicians, osteopaths, optometrists, and their employees while working under their regulation and supervision shall have the right to practice ophthalmic dispensing without qualifying under this chapter and shall not be subject to any of the provisions of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 27, secs. 6 to 9, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>