<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="134" order_by="134">PAYMENT, COLLECTION, AND REFUND OF TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>134.546</section_number><catch_line>Cause of action on certificates of delinquency -- Sale and deed on foreclosure -- No redemption -- Additional rights if owner is a taxing unit. </catch_line><order_by>546</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any action to collect any amount due on a certificate of delinquency or personal property certificate of delinquency may be brought at any time after the passage of one (1) year from the date the taxes became delinquent, and shall be brought within eleven (11) years of the date when the taxes became delinquent. </section><section prefix="2">A third-party purchaser may: <section prefix="a">Institute an action against the delinquent taxpayer to collect the amount of the certificate of delinquency and any other certificates of delinquency subsequently issued to the same third-party purchaser against the same delinquent, and shall have all the remedies available for the enforcement of a debt; </section><section prefix="b">Institute an action to enforce the lien provided in KRS 134.420, represented by the certificate of delinquency and those certificates subsequently held by the same third-party purchaser against the same delinquent or property; or </section><section prefix="c">Institute one (1) action including both types of actions mentioned in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection, and the joinder of actions shall not be defeated if the delinquent taxpayer has disposed of any property covered by the lien, but the purchaser of the property shall be made a defendant if the judgment is to affect his or her interest in the property, and as between them the delinquent taxpayer shall be responsible. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the state, county, or a taxing district is the owner of a certificate of delinquency or personal property certificate of delinquency, it shall have, in addition to the remedies provided in subsection (1) of this section, the right to distrain and sell any property owned by the delinquent taxpayer, including that on which the lien provided in KRS 134.420 has attached. Any property sold under distraint proceedings shall be sold in the same manner as provided in KRS 131.500, except that the exercise of the power shall be vested in the county attorney. </section><section prefix="4">Any property while owned by a delinquent taxpayer shall be subject to foreclosure or execution in satisfaction of a judgment pursuant to an action in rem or an action in personam, or both, to enforce the obligation. </section><section prefix="5">If property is sold pursuant to a judgment of foreclosure, it shall be appraised pursuant to the provisions of KRS 426.520, and there shall be a right of redemption as provided in KRS 426.530. If there is no purchaser at a foreclosure sale, the master commissioner shall make a deed to the person or persons shown by record to be the owner of the certificate or certificates of delinquency, and that person or persons shall have a pro rata interest in accordance with the amount of their respective certificates. </section><section prefix="6">The department may provide to a third-party purchaser factual information related to the owner or lessee of the coal, oil, gas reserves, or any other mineral resources assessed under KRS 132.820(1) pursuant to an order entered in a foreclosure action involving a certificate of delinquency for unmined coal, oil, gas, or any other mineral resources. The department may promulgate an administrative regulation establishing a fee schedule for the provision of the information described in this subsection. Any fee imposed shall not exceed the greater of the actual cost of providing the information or ten dollars ($10). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 10, effective April 7, 2010. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 16, effective January 1, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> April 7, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28449</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>