<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-702</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of partner's transferable interest. </catch_line><order_by>2-702</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A transfer, in whole or in part, of a partner's transferable interest in the limited partnership: <section prefix="a">Is permissible; </section><section prefix="b">Does not by itself cause the partner's dissociation or a dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership's activities; and </section><section prefix="c">Does not, as against the other partners or the limited partnership, entitle the transferee to participate in the management or conduct of the limited partnership's activities, to require access to information concerning the limited partnership's transactions except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, or to inspect or copy the required information or the limited partnership's other records. </section></section><section prefix="2">A transferee has a right to receive, in accordance with the transfer: <section prefix="a">Distributions to which the transferor would otherwise be entitled; and </section><section prefix="b">Upon the dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership's activities the net amount otherwise distributable to the transferor. </section></section><section prefix="3">In a dissolution and winding up, a transferee is entitled to an account of the limited partnership's transactions only from the date of dissolution. </section><section prefix="4">Upon transfer, the transferor retains the rights of a partner other than the interest in distributions transferred and retains all duties and obligations of a partner. </section><section prefix="5">A limited partnership need not give effect to a transferee's rights under this section until the limited partnership has notice of the transfer. </section><section prefix="6">A transfer of a partner's transferable interest in the limited partnership in violation of a restriction on transfer contained in the partnership agreement is ineffective as to a person having notice of the restriction at the time of transfer. </section><section prefix="7">A transferee that becomes a partner with respect to a transferable interest is liable for the transferor's obligations under KRS 362.2-502 and 362.2-509. However, the transferee is not obligated for liabilities unknown to the transferee at the time the transferee became a partner. </section><section prefix="8">Limitations upon transfer set forth in KRS 362.2-701 to 362.2-704 or adopted by the partners in accordance with this subchapter are enforceable notwithstanding KRS 355.9-406 and 355.9-408. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 146, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>