<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any county engineer who fails to comply with the provisions of subsection (3) of KRS 179.040 shall be fined five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who fails to perform the duties imposed by KRS 179.220 and 179.230 shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="3">Any county engineer who fails to publish the notices required by KRS 179.230 shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25), nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates subsection (2) of KRS 179.240 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="5">Any railroad company that fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 179.290 within the specified time, shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each failure. </section><section prefix="6">Any county engineer who willfully fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 179.320 for sixty (60) days after the fiscal court has ordered the guideboards to be erected, shall be fined not more than twenty-five dollars ($25). </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates subsection (4) of KRS 179.330, shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense. </section><section prefix="8">Any owner of a toll bridge who fails to repair the bridge when ordered to do so under the provisions of KRS 179.360 shall be fined fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates subsection (4) of KRS 179.370 shall be fined not less than five dollars ($5) nor more than twenty-five dollars ($25). </section><section prefix="10">Any person who violates subsection (2) of KRS 179.380 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="11">Any county engineer who violates KRS 179.460 shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense. </section><section prefix="12">Any county engineer who fails to perform the duties of his office shall, unless a different penalty is prescribed, be fined not over one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="13">Any county engineer who fails to cause contractors for county road and bridge work to perform their duties shall be fined not over one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="14">Any county engineer who fails to prosecute for any penalty provided in KRS Chapters 178 and 179, knowing that the penalty has been incurred, shall be fined twenty-five dollars ($25) for each failure to prosecute. </section><section prefix="15">If a fiscal court or county judge/executive willfully fails to perform any duty required of it by the provisions of this chapter, except KRS 179.230 and 179.320, every member of the court concurring in the failure shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) by the Circuit Court of the county. </section><section prefix="16">All fines imposed by this chapter shall be paid into the county road fund. </section><section prefix="17">No fine imposed by this chapter shall bar an action for damages for breach of contract. </section><section prefix="18">Any person, subdivider, builder, contractor or developer of any construction project who violates subsection (2) of KRS 179.070 shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each offense. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 320, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 348, sec. 2. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 25. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4320, 4324-1, 4327, 4342a-3, 4343, 4346, 4349, 4350, 4353a-2, 4356b, 4356c, 4356e, 4356f, 4356h, 4356n, 4356o, 4356q. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><lrc-note> (9/2/92).  The former reference to subsection (13) of KRS 179.070 contained in subsection (18) of this statute has been changed to subsection (2) because of the internal renumbering of KRS 179.070.  </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5531</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>