<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5507Administrative</section_number><catch_line>enforcement of orders.   </catch_line><order_by>5507Administrative</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A party or support enforcement agency seeking to enforce a support order or an income-withholding order, or both, issued in another state or a foreign support order may send the documents required for registering the order to a support enforcement agency of this state. </section><section prefix="2">Upon receipt of the documents, the support enforcement agency, without initially seeking to register the order, shall consider and, if appropriate, use any administrative procedure authorized by the law of this state to enforce a support order or an income-withholding order, or both. If the obligor does not contest administrative enforcement, the order need not be registered. If the obligor contests the validity or administrative enforcement of the order, the support enforcement agency shall register the order pursuant to KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 39, effective June 24, 2015. -- Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered as KRS 407.5507, 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 14, effective March 23, 1998. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 45, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 407.5502. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>