<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-540</section_number><catch_line>Exemption of agricultural wastes -- Producer of hazardous waste in amounts not deemed harmful not considered as generator of hazardous waste. </catch_line><order_by>46-540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No hazardous waste management provision of this chapter shall be construed to apply to any agricultural wastes, including manures and crop residues which are returned to the soil as fertilizers or soil conditioners. A farmer disposing of waste pesticides, herbicides or fertilizers from his own use which are hazardous wastes is not required to comply with the hazardous waste management provisions of this chapter for those wastes, provided he triple rinses each emptied container and disposes of the waste residues on his own farm in a manner consistent with the disposal instructions on the container label. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who produces hazardous waste in amounts not determined to be harmful to public health or the environment by regulation of the cabinet consistent with the Federal Resource Conservation and Recovery Act, as amended, and regulations issued pursuant thereto shall not be a generator of hazardous waste or considered to be engaged in the generation of hazardous waste for purposes of this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.869. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10450</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>