<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.160</section_number><catch_line>Plans and specifications for buildings -- Boards of education must offer to lease buildings before construction contract is made. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any city desires to construct a school building, under the provisions of KRS 162.150, the governing body of the city shall, by ordinance, cause plans and specifications for the building to be duly made and filed in the office of the city clerk. The plans and specifications shall give a full description of the building to be constructed, the details thereof and the manner of construction. The plans and specifications shall be prepared by an architect selected by the city and approved by the board of education of the school district, and shall be submitted to the board of education of the school district and to the chief state school officer for approval. </section><section prefix="2">If the plans and specifications are approved, and if the board of education of the school district offers to lease the building under a lease of the kind provided in KRS 162.140, the city governing body shall cause the city clerk to advertise for bids, and thereafter the city governing body, through the mayor, may contract for the construction of the building. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 255, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4421-12. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4042</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>