<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.030</section_number><catch_line>Functions of Office for Agricultural Marketing and Product Promotion. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office for Agricultural Marketing and Product Promotion shall: <section prefix="a">Promote and develop markets for Kentucky agricultural products, assist in setting up farm cooperatives, and assist in coordinating feasibility studies, loans, grants, and funding activities for producers and cooperatives; </section><section prefix="b">Gather and disseminate information concerning supply, demand, prevailing prices, and commercial movement, including common and cold storage of food products, and maintain market news service for the purpose of disseminating this information; </section><section prefix="c">Foster and encourage the inspection, grading, standardizing, labeling, and branding of farm products; provide standards of excellence and brands for the use of producers and consumers in the marketing of Kentucky-grown products; and promote the standardization of packages and containers for those purposes; </section><section prefix="d">Promulgate administrative regulations for the grading, packing, hauling, storing, and sale of farm products if the administrative regulations are authorized by statutes, and enforce those administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="e">Act as mediator or arbitrator, when invited, in any issue that may arise between producers and distributors of agricultural products; </section><section prefix="f">Encourage the establishment of public markets and direct dealing between producer and consumer; </section><section prefix="g">Promote the sale of Kentucky-grown products locally, and in domestic and international markets; </section><section prefix="h">Encourage the development of a market for the commercial production of earthworms; </section><section prefix="i">Negotiate and enter into cooperative agreements with the United States Department of Agriculture or any other appropriate federal agency for carrying out the provisions of this section; </section><section prefix="j">Develop opportunities for the diversification of Kentucky agriculture, including additional crops and enterprises for tobacco growers; and </section><section prefix="k">Establish an Organic Agricultural Product Certification Program. </section></section><section prefix="2">The functions of the office shall be supplementary to, and not in duplication of, the educational activities of the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">In accomplishing its purposes, the office shall not compete with business operated by private capital. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42a-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>