<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.675</section_number><catch_line>Cancellation of license -- Precipitation of taxes -- Cancellation of bond. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a licensee at any time files a false quarterly report of the information required or fails or refuses to file the quarterly report or to pay the full amount of the tax or violates any other provisions of KRS 138.655 to 138.725, inclusive, without a showing that such failure was due to reasonable cause, the cabinet may cancel his license. </section><section prefix="2">Upon voluntary surrender of the license certificate or upon receipt of a written request by a licensee, the cabinet may cancel his license, effective sixty (60) days from the date of the request, but no such license shall be canceled upon surrender or request unless the licensee has, prior to the date of cancellation, paid to this state all taxes, penalties, interest and fines that are due or have accrued, and unless the licensee has surrendered to the cabinet his license certificate. </section><section prefix="3">If upon investigation the cabinet ascertains that any motor carrier or heavy equipment motor carrier to whom a license has been issued is no longer engaged as such and has not been so engaged for a period of six (6) months, the cabinet may cancel such license by giving the motor carrier or heavy equipment motor carrier sixty (60) days' notice of cancellation mailed to his last known address in which event the license certificate shall be surrendered to the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Whenever a licensee ceases to engage in business within this state, he shall notify the cabinet in writing within fifteen (15) days after discontinuance. All taxes that have accrued under KRS 138.655 to 138.725, inclusive, whether or not then due, shall become due and payable concurrently with such discontinuance. The licensee shall make a report and pay all such taxes and any interest and penalties thereon, and shall surrender to the cabinet his license certificate. </section><section prefix="5">If the license of a motor carrier or heavy equipment motor carrier is canceled by the cabinet as provided in this section and if the licensee has paid to this state all of the taxes, interest and penalties due under KRS 138.655 to 138.725 and 138.990(14) and (15), the cabinet shall cancel the bond filed by the licensee. </section></text><history>Amended 1956 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 19. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28798</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>