<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.506</section_number><catch_line>Use of state aircraft. </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, state aircraft, including air charters, shall be used only for official business. </section><section prefix="2">State aircraft shall not be used for personal business, except when the Governor or Lieutenant Governor, for reasons of security, protocol, ceremonial functions, or overall demands of time, require travel considerations not accorded to other officials. In recognition of these realities, flights that may be solely for personal business, or partly for official business or partly for personal business, may be scheduled for the Governor or the Lieutenant Governor and their immediate families. <section prefix="a">The cost of flights scheduled solely for personal business of the Governor or Lieutenant Governor shall be charged to that officer in accordance with the rate schedule set forth in the administrative regulations authorized by KRS 174.504. </section><section prefix="b">If a particular flight is in part official business and part personal business, the Governor or the Lieutenant Governor shall make a reasonable allocation of the flight time between official and personal business and be responsible for paying with nonstate funds to the Capital City Airport Division the charge for the part of the flight that is allocable to personal business. The rate charged shall be calculated using costs that would be considered in a rate developed by a commercial air charter company. In these cases, the allocation made and the basis for the allocation shall be indicated on the aircraft request form. </section></section><section prefix="3">Constitutional officers, other elected state officials, members of the General Assembly, officers and employees of the cabinets, departments, and agencies of state government, officers and employees of other governmental units, and other persons traveling under the auspices of a state agency or in connection with state business deemed desirable by an agency head, including dependents of state officials, and news media representatives and other persons having an interest in the official purpose of the trip may be authorized to use state aircraft. Charges for travel in state aircraft shall be paid by the requesting state agency in accordance with the rate schedule established in administrative regulations authorized by KRS 174.504. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 19, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 605, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification>KRS 36.415. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5033</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>