<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.400</section_number><catch_line>Effect of KRS 15.380 to 15.404 on officers employed before or after December 1, 1998 -- Exception to Open Records Act. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The effective date of KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall be December 1, 1998. All peace officers employed as of December 1, 1998, shall be deemed to have met all the requirements of KRS 15.380 to 15.404 and shall be granted certified status as long as they: <section prefix="a">Remain in continuous employment of the agency by which they were employed as of December 1, 1998, and are employed within one hundred (100) days by another law enforcement agency subject to the provisions of KRS 15.380 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="b">Retired from employment with certified status on or after July 1, 2008, and are reemployed no later than one hundred (100) days from March 15, 2011, by a law enforcement agency subject to KRS 15.380 to 15.404; or </section><section prefix="c">Have successfully completed an approved basic training course approved and recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council pursuant to KRS 15.440(1)(d) when seeking employment with another law enforcement agency. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any peace officers employed after December 1, 1998, shall comply with all minimum standards specified in KRS 15.380 to 15.404. Persons newly employed or appointed after December 1, 1998, shall have one (1) year within which to gain certified status or they shall lose their law enforcement powers. </section><section prefix="3">The Open Records Act notwithstanding, the person's home address, telephone number, date of birth, Social Security number, background investigation, medical examination, psychological examination, and polygraph examination conducted for any person seeking certification pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall not be subject to disclosure. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1, effective March 15, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002; and ch.137, sec.2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 109, effective December 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 15, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  The amendment to this section in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007, is retroactive to July 1, 2004. See 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39485</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>