<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.601</section_number><catch_line>County and multicounty 2020 water management planning councils.   </catch_line><order_by>601</order_by><text><section prefix="1">2020 water management planning councils shall be established for each county with the assistance of the appropriate area development district. Two (2) or more counties may form a multicounty 2020 water management planning council. The planning councils shall, as a minimum, be comprised of the following: <section prefix="a">Each county judge-executive or mayor of an urban-county government, or his or her authorized representative; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) representative selected by each community public water system, as defined in 401 KAR 8:010 sec. 1(71)(a), that provides water to persons in the county; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative selected by a local health department in the county; and </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative selected by each city with a population equal to or greater than one thousand (1,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census that is not a water supplier or distributor, unless that city chooses to be represented by another member of the planning council. </section></section><section prefix="2">If, after the 2020 water management planning council appointments have been made, a county judge/executive or mayor of an urban-county government determines that any areas of the county or urban county government remain unrepresented on the planning council, the county judge/executive or mayor of the urban-county government may appoint an individual to represent that area. </section><section prefix="3">The county judge/executive or mayor of an urban-county government or the county judge/executive or the mayor's designated representative shall serve as the chair of the 2020 water management planning council of which either the county judge/executive or the mayor is a member. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the 2020 water management planning councils shall serve without pay but may be reimbursed by counties or appointing agencies for reasonable expenses incurred to carry out the work of the councils. </section><section prefix="5">The area development districts shall develop a forum for the chairpersons of the 2020 water management planning councils or multicounty planning councils to meet on at least a quarterly basis for the purpose of developing regional service strategies consistent with the findings and purpose set out in KRS 224A.300. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 221, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>