<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.5-040</section_number><catch_line>Right of member to information.   </catch_line><order_by>5-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Not later than ten (10) business days after receipt of a demand made in a record, a limited cooperative association shall permit a member to obtain, inspect, and copy in the association’s principal office required information listed in KRS 272A.1-120(1)(a) to (h) during regular business hours. A member need not have any particular purpose for seeking the information. The association is not required to provide the same information listed in KRS 272A.1-120(1)(b) to (h) to the same member more than once during a six (6) month period. </section><section prefix="2">On demand made in a record received by the limited cooperative association, a member may obtain, inspect, and copy in the association’s principal office required information listed in KRS 272A.1-120(1)(i), (j), (l), (m), (p), and (r) during regular business hours, if: <section prefix="a">The member seeks the information in good faith and for a proper purpose reasonably related to the member’s interest; </section><section prefix="b">The demand includes a description with reasonable particularity of the information sought and the purpose for seeking the information; </section><section prefix="c">The information sought is directly connected to the member’s purpose; and </section><section prefix="d">The demand is reasonable. </section></section><section prefix="3">Not later than ten (10) business days after receipt of a demand pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, a limited cooperative association shall provide, in a record, the following information to the member that made the demand: <section prefix="a">If the association agrees to provide the demanded information: <section prefix="1">What information the association will provide in response to the demand; and </section><section prefix="2">A reasonable time and place at which the association will provide the information; or </section></section><section prefix="b">If the association declines to provide some or all of the demanded information, the association’s reasons for declining. </section></section><section prefix="4">A person dissociated as a member may obtain, inspect, and copy information available to a member under subsection (1) or (2) of this section by delivering a demand in a record to the limited cooperative association in the same manner and subject to the same conditions applicable to a member under subsection (2) of this section if: <section prefix="a">The information pertains to the period during which the person was a member in the association; and </section><section prefix="b">The person seeks the information in good faith. </section></section><section prefix="5">A limited cooperative association shall respond to a demand made pursuant to subsection (4) of this section in the manner provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Not later than ten (10) business days after receipt by a limited cooperative association of a demand made by a member in a record, but not more often than once in a six (6) month period, the association shall deliver to the member a record stating the information with respect to the member required by KRS 272A.1-120(1)(q). </section><section prefix="7">A limited cooperative association may impose reasonable restrictions, including nondisclosure restrictions, on the use of information obtained under this section. Except as to limitations set forth in organic rules to which a member requesting inspection has assented, in a dispute concerning the reasonableness of a restriction under this subsection, the association has the burden of proving reasonableness. </section><section prefix="8">A limited cooperative association may charge a person that makes a demand under this section the reasonable costs of copying, limited to the costs of labor and material. </section><section prefix="9">A person that may obtain information under this section may obtain the information through an attorney or other agent. A restriction imposed on the person under subsection (7) of this section or by the organic rules applies to the attorney or other agent. </section><section prefix="10">The rights stated in this section do not extend to a person as transferee. </section><section prefix="11">The organic rules may require a limited cooperative association to provide more information than required by this section, and the organic rules may establish conditions and procedures for providing the information. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 33, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). The reference to "paragraph (q) of subsection (1)(a) of Section 12" in subsection (6) of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 33, has been changed in codification to "KRS 272A.1-120(1)(q)." This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>