<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.045</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations for restoration of civil rights to eligible felony offenders. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Corrections shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement a simplified process for the restoration of civil rights to eligible felony offenders. As part of this simplified process, the Department of Corrections shall: <section prefix="a">Inform eligible offenders about the process for restoration of civil rights and provide a standard form which individuals may sign upon their release to formally request that the Department of Corrections initiate the process; </section><section prefix="b">Generate a list on a monthly basis of eligible offenders who have been released by the Department of Corrections or discharged by the Parole Board and who have requested that their civil rights be restored; </section><section prefix="c">Conduct an investigation and compile the necessary information to ensure that all restitution has been paid and that there are no outstanding warrants, charges, or indictments; </section><section prefix="d">Provide notice to the Commonwealth's attorney in the county of commitment and to the Commonwealth's attorney in the offender's county of residence, setting out in the notification the criminal case number and charges for which the offender was convicted; and </section><section prefix="e">Forward information on a monthly basis of eligible felony offenders who have requested restoration of rights to the Office of the Governor for consideration of a partial pardon. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in this section, "eligible felony offender" means a person convicted of one (1) or more felonies who: <section prefix="a">Has reached the maximum expiration of his or her sentence or has received final discharge from the Parole Board; </section><section prefix="b">Does not have any pending warrants, charges, or indictments; and </section><section prefix="c">Had paid full restitution as ordered by the court or the Parole Board. </section></section><section prefix="3">As used in this section, "civil rights" means the ability to vote, serve on a jury, obtain a professional or vocational license, and hold an elective office. It does not include the right to bear arms. </section><section prefix="4">Any eligible offender not provided for under subsection (2) of this section may submit an application directly to the Department of Corrections to initiate the process outlined in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6784</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>