<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.176</section_number><catch_line>Probative value of DNA test -- Submission of evidence by parties in case -- Fees and costs.   </catch_line><order_by>176</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the requirements specified in KRS 422.285, any evidence submitted for testing and analysis pursuant to KRS 422.285 or 422.287 shall be of probative value. When the motion is filed with the court requesting testing and analysis of evidence pursuant to this section, the applicant shall include sufficient information about the evidence, the necessity for its testing and analysis, and its applicability to the proceeding for a court to make a determination of the probative value of the evidence proposed to be tested and analyzed. </section><section prefix="2">The prosecution, with a court order issued pursuant to this section, may submit not more than five (5) items of evidence for testing and analysis by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory or another laboratory selected by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory. In capital cases, the tests shall be performed without charge to the prosecution. The cost of testing and analysis of any items of evidence in excess of the five (5) initial items to be tested and analyzed shall be borne by the agency or person requesting the testing and analysis. Any additional item of evidence submitted for testing and analysis shall be accompanied by the court order specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The defense, with a court order issued pursuant to this section, may submit not more than five (5) items of evidence for testing and analysis by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory or another laboratory selected by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory. In capital cases, the tests shall be performed without charge to the defense. The cost of testing and analysis of any item of evidence in excess of the five (5) initial items to be tested and analyzed shall be borne by the agency or person requesting the testing and analysis. Any additional item of evidence submitted for testing and analysis shall be accompanied by the court order specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Any other party in a criminal case, with permission of the court after a specific showing of necessity for testing and analysis, together with the items specified in subsection (1) of this section, may submit an item of evidence for testing and analysis by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory or another laboratory selected by the Department of Kentucky State Police forensic laboratory for testing and analysis. The cost of testing and analysis of any item of evidence permitted to be submitted by the court shall be borne by the person or organization requesting the testing and analysis. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate by administrative regulation a uniform schedule of fees to be charged for testing and analysis conducted pursuant to KRS 422.285 or 422.287. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 93, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in the second sentences of subsections (2) and (3) of this section by inserting "of" after the first appearance of "analysis" in each of those sentences. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42299</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>