<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.381</section_number><catch_line>Duties and functions of council -- Duties of state historic preservation officer. </catch_line><order_by>381</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Heritage Council shall be dedicated to the preservation and protection of all meaningful vestiges of Kentucky's heritage for succeeding generations, and in pursuit of this dedication it shall engage in and concern itself with worthy projects and other matters related to the conservation and continuing recognition of buildings, structures, sites, and other landmarks associated with the archaeological, cultural, economic, military, natural, political, or social aspects of Kentucky's history. </section><section prefix="2">The duties and functions of the council shall be to: <section prefix="a">Review and recommend appropriate projects and programs to insure the proper recognition, preservation, and protection of matters related to Kentucky's heritage, particularly those in the nature of or associated with real property; </section><section prefix="b">Advise, consult, and cooperate generally with state, local, and national officials and agencies to accomplish the purposes to which the council is dedicated, and specifically with the Kentucky Department of Parks and Historical Society in matters of common concern; </section><section prefix="c">Encourage, promote, and coordinate historic preservation programs being conducted in Kentucky by other agencies or groups, public and private; </section><section prefix="d">Prepare and maintain an inventory or survey of Kentucky's resource of historic buildings, sites, structures, and other landmarks, and list in an official roll those landmarks which possess statewide or national significance; and </section><section prefix="e">Conduct a survey and maintain a catalog of Kentucky's historic drylaid and historic mortared rock fences as defined in KRS 171.391. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council may: <section prefix="a">Accept grants or other funds or property from any available source, public or private; </section><section prefix="b">Employ, with the approval of the Governor, staff as may be necessary. Any member of the staff shall be entitled to compensation under KRS Chapter 18A, and may be reimbursed for necessary and actual expenses in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 44 and 45; </section><section prefix="c">Enter into contractual relationships as may be necessary; </section><section prefix="d">Acquire real property, by gift or devise or by purchase pursuant to the provisions of KRS 45A.045, and hold the same in the name of the Commonwealth for the use and benefit of the council; </section><section prefix="e">Initiate its own projects of an appropriate nature, and undertake or otherwise engage in joint projects with other agencies or groups, public or private; and </section><section prefix="f">Adopt rules and regulations as may be necessary and incidental to the performance of the council's duties and functions. </section></section><section prefix="4">The receipt, control, and expenditure of funds shall be subject to the general provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes governing financial administration of all state agencies. </section><section prefix="5">No provision of this section shall be construed as repealing any of the laws of the Commonwealth relating to the preservation, protection, and recognition of historical matters, but shall be held and construed as ancillary and supplemental thereto. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall receive applications, interview and recommend to the Governor three (3) persons as nominees for appointment as the director of the Heritage Division, Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. The director of the Heritage Division shall be the state historic preservation officer. </section><section prefix="7">The responsibilities of the state historic preservation officer shall include: <section prefix="a">Development for the State Historic Preservation Program; </section><section prefix="b">Direction of a comprehensive statewide survey of historic properties; </section><section prefix="c">Nomination of historic properties to the National Register of Historic Places; </section><section prefix="d">Cooperation in the development of effective working relationships with federal, state, and local agencies that participate in the management of historic properties and in project planning that may affect historic properties; </section><section prefix="e">Cooperation in the integration of historic preservation planning with all levels of planning; </section><section prefix="f">Cooperation in the development and maintenance of a review procedure for publicly funded, assisted, and licensed undertakings that may affect historic properties within the state; </section><section prefix="g">Participation in the review of federal, federally assisted, and federally licensed undertakings that may affect historic properties included in or eligible for inclusion in the National Register under Section 106 of the National Historic Preservation Act and Executive Order 11593; </section><section prefix="h">Assisting federal agencies in fulfilling their historic preservation responsibilities under federal law and regulations; </section><section prefix="i">Liaison with organizations of professional archaeologists, historians, architects, architectural historians, planners, and others concerned with historic preservation; </section><section prefix="j">Development and operation of a program of public information and education concerning the preservation program; </section><section prefix="k">Administration of the grants program within the state; </section><section prefix="l">Preparation and maintenance of a comprehensive statewide historic preservation plan; and </section><section prefix="m">The immediate transmittal to the Department of Parks and to the Commonwealth's Railtrail Development Office in the Department for Local Government of any information received from a railroad or other person having an ownership interest in a railroad corridor pertaining to a proposed or pending action or proceeding to obtain federal authority for the regulatory abandonment of that railroad corridor. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 76, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 46, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 47, sec. 80, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 110, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 54, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4804</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>