<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.710</section_number><catch_line>Awarding of grants -- Criteria. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall award grants to community corrections programs in accordance with the policies established by KRS 196.700 to 196.735 and in accordance with any laws enacted or promulgated for that purpose, including any branch budget bill and appropriation provisions. </section><section prefix="2">Grants shall be awarded to community corrections programs whose community corrections program plans meet the requirements set forth in KRS 196.720 and which, in the commission's judgment, promise to meet the goals set forth in KRS 196.700 to 196.735. Grants shall be awarded to encourage a range of services in each judicial circuit. </section><section prefix="3">Grants may be awarded only to community corrections programs which have established community corrections boards as provided in KRS 196.725 unless the commission determines that the community corrections program is governed by a board which will serve the same functions as described in KRS 196.700 to 196.735, and that establishment of a new or additional board as described in KRS 196.725 would impose an administrative burden upon or pose a conflict of interest for the program. </section><section prefix="4">Grants shall not be awarded to programs that have failed to accomplish the goals set forth in KRS 196.702(4) and that show no promise of doing so in the future, as determined pursuant to KRS 196.735. </section><section prefix="5">Preference in funding may be given to judicial circuits in which programs and services do not exist or are largely inadequate. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6850</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>