<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.080</section_number><catch_line>Special boiler inspectors -- State salary prohibited -- Duties -- Report.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the boiler inspectors authorized by KRS 236.070, the department shall, upon the request of any company authorized to insure against loss from explosion of boilers and pressure vessels in this state, issue to any boiler inspectors of said company commissions as special boiler inspectors, provided that each such special boiler inspector before receiving such commission, shall satisfactorily pass the examination provided for in KRS 236.090, or, in lieu of such examination, shall hold a commission or certificate of competency as an inspector of boilers and pressure vessels for a state that has a standard of examination substantially equal to that of this Commonwealth or a commission as an inspector of boilers and pressure vessels issued by the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors. </section><section prefix="2">Such special boiler inspectors shall receive no salary from, nor shall any of their expenses be paid by, the state and the continuance of a special inspector's commission shall be conditioned upon his or her continuing in the employ of an insurance company duly authorized as aforesaid and upon his or her maintenance of the standards imposed by this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">Such special boiler inspectors shall inspect all boilers and pressure vessels insured by their respective companies, and, when so inspected and reported as required, the owners and users of such insured boilers and pressure vessels shall be exempt from the payment to the state of the inspection fees as provided for in KRS 236.120 and 236.130. </section><section prefix="4">Each company employing such special boiler inspectors shall within thirty (30) days following each certificate inspection made by such inspectors, file a report of such inspection with the division upon appropriate forms prescribed by the division. Other than the certificate inspection report, no reporting of other inspections shall be required except when such inspections disclose that the boiler or pressure vessel is in a dangerous condition. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 521, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40111</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>