<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.691</section_number><catch_line>Adjudicatory proceedings -- Action by commission -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>691</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure and the Kentucky Rules of Evidence shall apply to all commission adjudicatory hearings. All testimony in a commission adjudicatory proceeding shall be under oath. All parties shall have the right to call and examine witnesses, to introduce exhibits, to cross-examine witnesses, to submit evidence, and to be represented by counsel and any other due process rights, privileges, and responsibilities of a witness appearing before the courts of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Before testifying, all witnesses shall be given a copy of the regulations governing commission proceedings. All witnesses shall be entitled to be represented by counsel. </section><section prefix="2">Any person whose name is mentioned during adjudicatory proceedings of the commission and who may be adversely affected thereby may appear personally before the commission on the person's own behalf, with or without attorney, to give a statement in opposition to such adverse mention or file a written statement of that opposition for incorporation into the record of proceeding. </section><section prefix="3">All adjudicatory proceedings of the commission carried out pursuant to the provisions of this section shall be public, unless the members vote to go into executive session in accordance with KRS 61.810. </section><section prefix="4">Within thirty (30) days after the end of an adjudicatory proceeding pursuant to the provisions of this section, the commission shall meet in executive session for the purpose of reviewing the evidence before it. Within thirty (30) days after completion of deliberations, the commission shall publish a written report of its findings and conclusions which shall be based on whether the person accused has complied with the statute as written. </section><section prefix="5">No penalty provided for in this section shall be imposed except as the result of an adjudicatory proceeding held upon the filing of a complaint. Notwithstanding the administrative penalties provided for in KRS 6.797, 6.807, and 6.821, the commission, upon a finding pursuant to an adjudicatory proceeding that there has been clear and convincing proof of a violation of this code, may: <section prefix="a">Issue an order requiring the violator to cease and desist the violation; </section><section prefix="b">Issue an order requiring the violator to file any report, statement, or other information as required by this code; </section><section prefix="c">In writing, publicly reprimand the violator for potential violations of the law and provide a copy of the reprimand to the presiding officer of the house in which the alleged violator serves; </section><section prefix="d">In writing, recommend to the house in which the violator serves that the violator be sanctioned as recommended by the commission, which may include a recommendation for censure or expulsion; </section><section prefix="e">Issue an order requiring the violator to pay a civil penalty of not more than two thousand dollars ($2,000); or </section><section prefix="f">Revoke the registration of any legislative agent or employer for a period not to exceed five (5) years. During the period of the revocation, the agent or employer or any other entity which constitutes nothing more than the legislative agent or employer operating under a different name or identity shall not be permitted to register as a legislative agent or employer. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commission may refer to the Attorney General, county attorney, or Commonwealth's attorney of the appropriate jurisdiction, for prosecution evidence of criminal violations of this code. The Attorney General shall have responsibility for all prosecutions under the law and may request from the commission all evidence collected in its investigation. </section><section prefix="7">Findings of fact or final determinations by the commission that a violation of this code has been committed, or any testimony related to the commission's findings of fact or final determinations, shall not be admissible in criminal proceedings in the courts of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Evidence collected by the commission may be used in a criminal proceeding if otherwise relevant. </section><section prefix="8">Any person found by the commission to have committed a violation of this code may appeal the action to the Franklin Circuit Court. The appeal shall be initiated within thirty (30) days after the date of the final action of the commission by filing a petition with the court against the commission. The commission shall transmit to the clerk of the court all evidence considered by the commission at the public hearing. The court shall hear the appeal upon the record as certified by the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 479, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 40, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>