<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.280</section_number><catch_line>Temporary custody orders. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A party to a custody proceeding may move for a temporary custody order. The motion must be supported by an affidavit as provided in KRS 403.350. The court may award temporary custody under the standards of KRS 403.270 after a hearing, or, if there is no objection, solely on the basis of the affidavits. </section><section prefix="2">If a proceeding for dissolution of marriage or legal separation is dismissed, any temporary custody order is vacated unless a parent or the child's custodian moves that the proceeding continue as a custody proceeding and the court finds, after a hearing, that the circumstances of the parents and the best interests of the child require that a custody decree be issued. </section><section prefix="3">If a custody proceeding commenced in the absence of a petition for dissolution of marriage or legal separation under KRS 403.822(1)(a) or (b) is dismissed, any temporary custody order is vacated. </section><section prefix="4">If a court determines by clear and convincing evidence that a person is a de facto custodian, the court shall join that person in the action, as a party needed for just adjudication under Rule 19 of the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 43, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>