<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1414</section_number><catch_line>Trafficking in controlled substance in third degree -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>1414</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of trafficking in a controlled substance in the third degree when he or she knowingly and unlawfully traffics in: <section prefix="a">Twenty (20) or more dosage units of a controlled substance classified in Schedules IV or V; or </section><section prefix="b">Any quantity of a controlled substance specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection in an amount less than the amount specified in that paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any person who violates the provisions of subsection (1)(a) of this section shall be guilty of: <section prefix="1">A Class A misdemeanor for a first offense involving one hundred twenty (120) or fewer dosage units; </section><section prefix="2">A Class D felony for a first offense involving more than one hundred twenty (120) dosage units; and </section><section prefix="3">A Class D felony for a second or subsequent offense. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates the provisions of subsection (1)(b) of this section shall be guilty of: <section prefix="1">A Class A misdemeanor for the first offense, subject to the imposition of presumptive probation; and </section><section prefix="2">A Class D felony for a second or subsequent offense, except that KRS Chapter 532 to the contrary notwithstanding, the maximum sentence to be imposed shall be no greater than three (3) years. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 16, effective March 25, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 11, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44012</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>