<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.840</section_number><catch_line>District health departments -- Boundaries -- Costs. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall delineate and define geographical boundaries within which district health departments may be established. The fiscal courts of all counties within the boundaries delineated by the cabinet may, by resolution of each respective court, duly passed by a majority vote of the members present, unite all the counties into a district for the purpose of creating, establishing, maintaining, and operating a district health department. The resolution of each court shall be in effect for two (2) years awaiting the action of other fiscal courts to unite in the formation of a district health department. Each court, at the time of passing the resolution, shall provide for its proportion of the cost of the creation, establishment, maintenance and operation of the department, to be paid for by the county. </section><section prefix="2">The cost of creating and establishing the district health department shall be paid by the counties comprising the district in proportion to the taxable property of each county as shown by their respective county assessments. The annual expense of maintaining and operating the district health department shall be borne by each county reasonably and equitably in proportion to the amount of the taxable property in each county, in amounts determined by the standards of the cabinet. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8688</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>