<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-110</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of commission. </catch_line><order_by>1-110</order_by><text>The Environmental Quality Commission shall have the power, duty and authority to: <section prefix="1">Establish such advisory committees as may be necessary and convenient. </section><section prefix="2">Advise the secretary on any matter within his responsibility which it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="3">Advise the Governor on any matter covered by the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">Serve as a working public forum for the exchange of views, concerns, ideas, information, and recommendations relating to the quality of the natural environment. </section><section prefix="5">Recommend adoption or rejection by a majority of its membership present and voting of any proposal by the cabinet to adopt, modify or revoke: <section prefix="a">Any positions proposed to be taken by the cabinet on behalf of the state before interstate and federal agencies or federal legislative bodies on matters relating to or affecting the quality of the environment of the state; </section><section prefix="b">Any rule or regulation pertaining to the procedural aspects of hearings, appeals, the filing of reports, the issuance of orders, the issuance of permits, and the application for and the granting of exemptions; or </section><section prefix="c">Any procedures for the financial assistance grants proposed to be given to municipal, regional, county, or state organizations for environmental purposes. </section></section><section prefix="6">Recommend adoption or rejection after public hearing by a majority of its membership present and voting of any proposal by the cabinet to adopt, modify, or revoke: <section prefix="a">Any comprehensive environment quality plan, program or policy proposed for adoption as a state plan or policy pertaining to an environmental management activity; or </section><section prefix="b">Any rule or regulation pertaining to the prevention, abatement, and control of existing or threatened air or water pollution, disposal of waste, control of noise, or the use of air, land, or water resources, or strip mining and reclamation. </section></section><section prefix="7">Establish an advisory committee on noise control, which shall consist of a sound engineer, an audiologist, and one (1) representative from each of the following: transportation industry, manufacturing industry, labor, citizenry, and the General Assembly. Such members shall be appointed with the approval of the secretary, who shall be an ex officio member. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 184, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, secs. 1 and 13(2), effective June 21, 1974; and ch. 99, sec. 21, effective June 21, 1974. -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.045. KRS 224.01-110. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-110</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41584</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>