<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.577</section_number><catch_line>Mutiny or sedition.   </catch_line><order_by>577</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person subject to this code shall be punished as a court-martial may direct who: <section prefix="a">With intent to usurp or override lawful military authority, refuses, in concert with any other person, to obey orders or otherwise do his or her duty or creates any violence or disturbance is guilty of mutiny; </section><section prefix="b">With intent to cause the overthrow or destruction of lawful civil authority, creates, in concert with any other person, revolt, violence, or other disturbance against that authority is guilty of sedition; or </section><section prefix="c">Fails to do his or her utmost to prevent and suppress a mutiny or sedition being committed in his or her presence, or fails to take all reasonable means to inform his or her superior commissioned officer or commanding officer of an offense of mutiny or sedition which he or she knows or has reason to believe is taking place, is guilty of a failure to suppress or report a mutiny or sedition. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person who is found guilty of attempted mutiny, mutiny, sedition, or failure to suppress or report a mutiny or sedition shall be punished as a court-martial may direct. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 98, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 63. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 92, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 35.465. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41979</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>