<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.243</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of all election laws -- Duties of Attorney General -- Toll-free line for report of violations -- Random inquiry for irregularities -- Initiation of prosecutions. </catch_line><order_by>243</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the other duties and powers of the Attorney General, he shall enforce all of the state's election laws by civil or criminal processes. </section><section prefix="2">The Attorney General shall: <section prefix="a">Devise and administer programs to observe the conduct of elections; </section><section prefix="b">Hold public hearings; </section><section prefix="c">Establish a toll-free telephone service for the purpose of receiving reports of election law violations. The service shall be operated during regular business hours throughout the year and during the hours which any poll in the state is open on the day of any primary, special election or regular election; </section><section prefix="d">Initiate investigations or investigate alleged violations of election laws at the request of a registered voter or on his own motion; </section><section prefix="e">Issue subpoenas for the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memoranda or other records, and compel the attendance of witnesses that he deems relevant to the purposes of any investigation; </section><section prefix="f">Present evidence of alleged violations to a grand jury; and </section><section prefix="g">File appropriate complaints in any court of competent jurisdiction. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Attorney General shall be required to begin an independent inquiry for any potential irregularities that may have occurred in each election in not fewer than five percent (5%) of Kentucky's counties, to be selected at random in a public process, within twenty (20) days following each primary or regular election. No county shall be subject to inquiry under this subsection in two (2) consecutive elections. </section><section prefix="b">The Attorney General shall report his findings to the grand jury of each county involved and to the chief circuit judge for the circuit in which the county is located. </section></section><section prefix="4">When the Registry of Election Finance concludes there is probable cause to believe a violation of election laws has occurred, it shall forward the matter to the Attorney General for prosecution. In the event the Attorney General or local prosecutor fails to prosecute the matter in a timely fashion, the registry's attorney may petition the Circuit Court to be appointed as a special prosecutor. Upon such motion timely filed, for good cause shown, the court shall enter an order to that effect. </section><section prefix="5">When requested by the Attorney General, all state and local agencies and officials, including the Auditor of Public Accounts, Commonwealth's attorneys, county attorneys, Registry of Election Finance, Department of Kentucky State Police, sheriffs' departments and local police shall give all possible assistance to the Attorney General in the performance of his duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 14, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>