<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.150</section_number><catch_line>Game and fish fund -- Funds for hunger relief -- Accounting and report -- Contribution to Becoming an Outdoors-Woman Program. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in this chapter, all moneys derived from the sale of licenses or from any other source connected with the administration of this chapter shall be promptly paid over to the State Treasurer, who shall deposit such moneys in a special fund, known as the game and fish fund, except that the moneys shall be entered under separate restricted fund accounts, not commingled, and maintained according to generally accepted accounting principles. Moneys derived from the sale of licenses issued under this chapter shall be under separate restricted fund account from any other proceeds derived from this chapter or from proceeds obtained under any other chapter. The game and fish fund shall be used to carry out the purposes of this chapter and any law or regulation for the protection of wildlife and for no other purpose. </section><section prefix="2">All funds received under KRS 150.110 and 150.520 shall be used by the department for the purpose of enforcing those sections and for the protection and propagation of mussel beds. Any surplus remaining in the fund at the close of each calendar year shall be turned into the general fund of the department. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the funds derived pursuant to KRS 186.050(15), the department shall, beginning August 1, 2006, and each fiscal year thereafter, set aside not less than twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) from the game and fish fund for the purpose of promoting hunger relief through specific wildlife management and conservation efforts. The department shall provide for a separate accounting of these funds and shall, by October 1, 2007, and annually thereafter, report on the expenditures made pursuant to this subsection to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall prescribe a method to allow any applicant for a license required under KRS 150.175 to make, at the time of application, a voluntary contribution in the amount of two dollars ($2) for the Becoming an Outdoors-Woman Program or other hunter and angler recruitment and retention program. The voluntary contribution shall be deposited into a separate, restricted account within the game and fish fund. The Becoming an Outdoors-Woman Program shall encourage women in developing skills for outdoor recreational activities including but not limited to hunting and angling. The voluntary contribution shall be automatically added to the cost of the license at the time of sale. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 413, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 33, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 6 -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 22 -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 15 -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1954d-10, 1954d-48. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>