<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.245</section_number><catch_line>Powers of local health departments. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text>County, city-county, and district health departments may: <section prefix="1">Utilize available services, facilities, equipment, and personnel of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or of the United States Public Health Service upon such terms of payment or reimbursement as are agreed on by the department and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the United States Public Health Service; </section><section prefix="2">Contract for services not otherwise available; </section><section prefix="3">Provide for the public health training and instruction of employees and compensate and defray the reasonable expenses of said employees while they are pursuing public health training courses approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="4">Establish or contribute to a retirement system or fund for employees of the department, including any retirement system for state employees; </section><section prefix="5">Issue and require the heads of families and other persons to execute such orders as it considers expedient to prevent the outbreak and spread of communicable diseases, and to this end bring the infected population under prompt and proper treatment; </section><section prefix="6">Issue written orders directed to the owner or occupant of any property, or to any person, firm, or corporation whatever, commanding, within the time and manner specified in the order, compliance with applicable public health laws of this state and all regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the county board of health. Notwithstanding the provisions of this section and KRS 212.210, any health officer may institute and maintain mandatory or prohibitory injunction proceedings in the appropriate Circuit Courts of this state to abate nuisances that are or may be a menace to the health of the people of the state or community, and to compel compliance with the public health laws of this state and the rules and regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the county board of health and the orders described in this section or in KRS 212.210; </section><section prefix="7">Through its health officers, representatives, and agents, enter upon any premises when necessary for the purpose of making inspections and investigations and view evidence and interrogate persons to the extent required in the performance of their duties and responsibilities. The department or the health officer thereof may issue subpoenas, subpoena duces tecum, and all necessary process in proceedings brought before or initiated by the department or board, and such process shall extend to all parts of the Commonwealth. Service of process may be made by certified mail, return receipt requested, or in the manner prescribed by the Rules of Civil Procedure; </section><section prefix="8">Provide administrative, investigative, and clerical services required by the local board of health; </section><section prefix="9">Cooperate with other health departments, agencies, and organizations in matters relating to public health; </section><section prefix="10">Elect coverage under the state's workers' compensation laws with the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; or </section><section prefix="11">Except as otherwise provided by law, do all other things reasonably necessary to protect and improve the health of the people. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 405, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 356, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1).and (11); and ch. 315, sec. 29 -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective June 19, 1958. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8593</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>