<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.210</section_number><catch_line>Definitions used in KRS 146.210 to 146.360. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>As used in KRS 146.210 to 146.360, the words listed herein shall have the following respective meanings, unless another or different meaning or intent shall be clearly indicated by the context: <section prefix="1">"Stream or watercourse" shall mean a flowing body of water or a section or portion thereof, including rivers, streams, and creeks. </section><section prefix="2">"Free flowing" shall mean existing or flowing in a natural condition without impoundment, diversion, straightening, riprapping, or other modification of the waterway. The existence, however, of low dams, diversion works, and other minor structures at the time any stream is proposed for inclusion in the Wild Rivers System shall not automatically bar its consideration for such inclusion; provided, that this shall not be construed to authorize or to be intended to encourage future construction of such structures within components of the Wild Rivers System. </section><section prefix="3">"Road" shall mean a highway, a hard-surfaced road, or an improved or unimproved dirt road. The existence, however, of unimproved roads at the time any stream is proposed for inclusion in the Wild Rivers System shall not automatically bar its consideration for such inclusion; provided, that this shall not be construed to authorize or to be intended to encourage future construction of such roads where this would be contrary to the provisions of KRS 146.200 to 146.360. </section><section prefix="4">"Wilderness type recreation" shall mean activities such as fishing, hunting, canoeing, camping, hiking, horseback riding, exploring, archaeological and scientific investigation, and scenic and aesthetic enjoyment, which utilizes and protects to the highest degree the primitive and natural values of the area. </section><section prefix="5">"Visual horizon" shall mean the normal distance to which land and vegetative features can be unobstructedly viewed from the center of the stream. </section><section prefix="6">"Access point" shall mean an area along the stream under public ownership, or under easement acquired by agreement with a private landowner. This area would be available for public recreational use including, but not limited to, the launching of boats, picnicking, and camping. </section><section prefix="7">"Secretary" shall mean the secretary for energy and environment or the successor to that office. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 123, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(9). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29303</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>