<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.790</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for services -- Design -- Payment. </catch_line><order_by>790</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Only a person with a disability who is a resident of Kentucky or whose family or guardian is a resident of Kentucky is eligible to apply for a Hart-Supported Living Program grant. The person may be living with a family member, independently, or be in a congregate setting and be eligible to apply for a grant. If funded, the applicant must maintain Kentucky residency as a condition of receiving grant funds or for the duration of the grant. </section><section prefix="2">Any eligible person with a disability who wants to apply for a Hart-Supported Living Program grant may design and request a set of services in the amount, kind, frequency, and duration which is dependent upon the person's individual needs, and is consistent with the definition of a Hart-Supported Living Program grant under KRS 210.770. </section><section prefix="3">Payments for Hart-Supported Living Program grants may be made directly to the person with a disability to enable the person to purchase a service, to the guardian of the person with a disability, to a fiscal representative, to a service provider agency, or to any combination of these parties. </section><section prefix="4">A license shall not be required for any supported living housing arrangement provided on a contractual basis. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8322</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>