<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.120</section_number><catch_line>Indemnity for destruction or slaughter of animal. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Indemnities shall be paid by the state or federal government for animals mandated to be destroyed or slaughtered on account of a reportable or United States Department of Agriculture (USDA) program disease. The indemnities shall be based on fair market value as determined by the USDA or independent appraisal. </section><section prefix="2">No state-funded indemnity shall be paid for any animal unless it was the property of the person claiming indemnity, and was within the state, for a period of at least six (6) months prior to the time of the first test, except when animals are destroyed or slaughtered on account of a foreign animal or zoonotic disease. </section><section prefix="3">No indemnity shall be paid for any animal: <section prefix="a">Owned by the United States, the state or any county or city; </section><section prefix="b">Brought into this state in violation of the law or any regulation of the board; </section><section prefix="c">When the owner at the time of coming into possession of the animal had any reason to believe that it was infected; or </section><section prefix="d">When the board or its authorized agents have satisfactory evidence that the owner has been guilty of negligence in permitting the animal to become exposed to the communicable disease. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 63c-7. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>