<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-660</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Recycling and Marketing Assistance Program -- Advisory committee -- Report. </catch_line><order_by>10-660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Recycling and Marketing Assistance Program, referred to in this section as the "program," is created to develop a recycling infrastructure within the Commonwealth. The program shall: <section prefix="a">Encourage the collection, processing, and marketing of recovered materials; </section><section prefix="b">Provide assistance for the development of community and regional recycling; </section><section prefix="c">Identify resources to help market recyclables; and </section><section prefix="d">Promote the development of the market for recyclables. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall administer the program and assist local governments and commercial businesses seeking to recycle materials. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall create a Kentucky Recycling and Marketing Assistance Advisory Committee to act in an advisory capacity to the cabinet. In addition to its other duties, this committee shall develop and submit an annual report by October 1 to the Interim Joint Committee on Natural Resources and Environment. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 358, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 135, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 135, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10333</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>