<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.510</section_number><catch_line>Charges for sewer service -- Collection by action -- Cutting off water service if sewer service charges not paid -- Contracts with large users -- Administration of revenue. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors shall, by resolution, determine the rates and compensation or rentals to be charged for the use of the sanitary works. The board of directors may provide for a sewer service charge to be imposed and collected, beginning at the time the plan for the improvement has been approved by the Energy and Environment Cabinet and work is begun on plans and specifications for the improvement. The rates shall at all times be reasonable, taking into account the cost of the works, the cost of operation and maintenance, and the amount necessary for the amortization of the bonds issued to finance the works. The same schedule of rates and charges shall apply to all users of the same class. The rates shall be binding upon all users of the system. The board may alter and revise the rates in its discretion. In case of failure of any user to pay for services rendered, the board may compel payment and may enjoin further use until the payment is made, or it may institute an action in any court having jurisdiction for the recovery of charges for services rendered, or the board may, by a notice in writing, signed by its chairman or any member of said board, notify the municipality, or person, firm, or corporation, which furnishes water to the user's premises, to shut off the water service to said user's premises, until such time as all delinquent charges, plus a reasonable charge for turning off and on the water service, against said user, are paid in full. Upon receipt of such notice in writing, the municipality, or the person, firm, or corporation, which furnishes water to the said user's premises shall immediately shut off and discontinue the water service to the said user's premises. Upon full payment of such account, plus a reasonable charge for turning off and on the water service, the chairman, or any member of said board, shall notify the said municipality, person, firm, or corporation, which furnishes water to said user, that the account is paid in full, including such reasonable charge for turning off and on the water service, and that the said water service can again be provided to said user's premises. The board of directors shall promptly pay to such municipality, person, firm, or corporation, such fee or charge collected for turning off and on such water service. The board may enter into contracts with public corporations or other large users of sewer services. The board may provide by resolution any provisions and stipulations it deems necessary for the administration of the revenue of the district, and for the security of the bondholders. </section><section prefix="2">No moneys received on account of the existence or operation of construction subdistricts shall be used for the payment of district obligations, and no other moneys received by the district shall be used for the payment of construction subdistrict bonds or obligations. Except as provided in the preceding sentence the use of all moneys of the district received from any and all sources is hereby limited exclusively and shall be devoted solely to the payment of all obligations of the district and board created by KRS 220.010 to 220.540, and no funds from any sources authorized by KRS 220.010 to 220.540 shall be diverted to any other purposes than those in KRS 220.010 to 220.540 set forth, except that the district shall pay from district area revenues an equitably allocable share of the cost of constructing and operating any nondistrict area facilities to which sewage from the district area is diverted in order to relieve district facilities from excessive sewage and costs described in KRS 220.561 but otherwise paid for. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 334, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(2). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 36. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2062g-29, 2062g-53. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9823</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>