<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.056</section_number><catch_line>Certificate contents -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The certificate referred to in this chapter shall be in the form prescribed by the cabinet. The certificate shall state that the respondent has been examined by each of the qualified mental health professionals making the certificate within twenty-four (24) hours (excluding weekends and holidays) prior to the date of the certificate.  It shall state the facts and circumstances upon which the judgment of the examining physician is based and shall be sworn to before a notary or the clerk or judge of the court.  </section><section prefix="2">The examiner shall be entitled to a fee for such examination and certification, to be paid by the county in which the petition is filed, upon a certified copy of an order of allowance made by the court holding the hearing.  </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 19, effective July 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><lrc-note> (11/23/93). A prior reference to the "department" in this statute was changed to "cabinet" pursuant to 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 50(5), and KRS 7.136(2). .  This section was enacted in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7452</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>