<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLI" order_by="41">LAWS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="446" order_by="446">CONSTRUCTION OF STATUTES </unit></structure><section_number>446.120</section_number><catch_line>References to sections, subsections, and paragraphs -- Citation of Acts of General Assembly. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"KRS" may be used as an abbreviation of "Kentucky Revised Statutes." </section><section prefix="2">Wherever in the statute laws of this state a reference is made to several sections and the section numbers given in the reference are connected by the word "to," the reference includes both the sections whose numbers are given and all intervening sections. </section><section prefix="3">Wherever in the Kentucky Revised Statutes a reference is made to a subsection without stating the section of which the subsection referred to is a part, the reference is to the subsection of the section in which the reference is made. </section><section prefix="4">Wherever in the Kentucky Revised Statutes a reference is made to a paragraph without stating the section and subsection of which the paragraph referred to is a part, the reference is to the paragraph of the subsection in which the reference is made. </section><section prefix="5">Material in the official edition of the Acts of the General Assembly shall be cited in the following manner: <section prefix="a">For acts of regular sessions, 19xx Ky. Acts ch. xxx, sec. xxx, e.g., 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 1; and </section><section prefix="b">For acts of extraordinary sessions, 19xx (xxx Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. xxx, sec. xxx, e.g., 1991 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 101. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, to clarify chapter. </history><metadata><effective>  July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>