<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.210</section_number><catch_line>Employees' representatives to select plant physician or surgeon. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a plan or custom exists in any industry under which the employees contribute to the payment of any physician or surgeon for furnishing treatment, by deductions from their wages through the office of the employer, a meeting of such employees may be called by any ten (10) of them, as they consider best to bring to the notice of all employees affected that the meeting is to be held. Those at the meeting, by a majority determination, shall authorize two (2) of their number to represent all employees in that plant so affected, and when the management of the plant is notified by the employees of their action, it shall forthwith select two (2) persons to represent it. </section><section prefix="2">The persons selected shall meet and select a physician or surgeon for the plant. If no selection is made within three (3) days, all questions before them shall be referred to the secretary, who shall act as umpire. His or her decision shall be final. No physician or surgeon shall be employed and paid by deductions from the wages of employees except as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="3">Any physician or surgeon selected under this section shall be employed for a definite term, not to exceed four (4) years, and may be removed at any time for gross inefficiency or misconduct in the same manner in which he or she was selected. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1724, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32021</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>