<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.340</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Homeless Veterans Program -- Homeless Veterans Service Coordinating Committee. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Homeless Veterans Program is hereby created in the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs and shall be attached to the office of the commissioner for administrative purposes. The program shall develop a statewide network of: <section prefix="a">Services that provide treatment for addictions, including but not limited to alcohol, drug use, and gambling; </section><section prefix="b">Services that lead to permanent housing; </section><section prefix="c">Services that lead to employment; and </section><section prefix="d">Concerned citizens and nonprofit agencies that provide shelter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The mission of the Kentucky Homeless Veterans Program shall be to work toward the elimination of homelessness and the prevention of the threat of homelessness and its causes in the veteran population of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">The program shall provide assistance to persons who served in the United States Armed Forces or in forces incorporated as part of the United States Armed Forces, and who were discharged under conditions other than dishonorable. </section><section prefix="4">The program shall provide assistance to persons whose need for services is based upon homelessness, or other circumstances as prescribed by administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="5">The primary components of the program shall be: <section prefix="a">Advocacy and public awareness. The program shall be an advocate for homeless veterans, and work to increase public awareness about the issue of homelessness among veterans and its root causes. The program shall advocate legislation and policies on the local, state, and national level to address these issues; </section><section prefix="b">Information services. The program shall monitor and research issues relating to homeless veterans and disseminate information and opportunities throughout its network; </section><section prefix="c">Technical assistance. The program, through conferences and training workshops with federal and state agencies, shall provide guidance and direction in applying for grants and benefits for homeless veterans. The program shall provide peer-to-peer consulting and on-site technical support; and </section><section prefix="d">Facilities. The program, through grants and other sources of funding, shall provide facilities as appropriate in support of the program. </section></section><section prefix="6">A Homeless Veterans Service Coordinating Committee shall be established. The committee's membership shall be comprised of representatives of public and private agencies who provide services that may be used by homeless veterans. The commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs shall designate the agencies represented on the committee. The committee shall discuss and research ways in which the services that it offers can be made more easily available and better focused to serve homeless veterans. </section><section prefix="7">The program is authorized to accept and expend moneys as may be appropriated from time to time by the General Assembly, and any moneys that may be received from any source including donations and grants. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21853</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>