<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.040</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations governing dental hygienists.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to dental hygienists. The administrative regulations may include at a minimum the classification of and licensure of dental hygienists, by examination or credentials, general supervision privileges, anesthesia registration, retirement of a license, reinstatement of a license, and charity licenses. </section><section prefix="2">Renewal programs shall be organized to include continuing education approved by the board. </section><section prefix="3">A licensed dental hygienist shall practice under the supervision, order, control, and full responsibility of a dentist licensed under this chapter and may practice: <section prefix="a">In a dental office, public or private school, health care facility, or government institution with a dentist on staff; </section><section prefix="b">Without the physical presence of a supervising dentist as provided in administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to subsections (6), (7), and (8) of this section; or </section><section prefix="c">Without a supervising dentist if providing screening services in accordance with subsection (9) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="4">It shall be unlawful for a person or corporation to practice dental hygiene in a manner that is separate or independent from the dental practice of a supervising dentist or to establish or maintain an office or practice that is primarily devoted to the provision of dental hygiene services. </section><section prefix="5">A dental hygienist may be employed by the supervising dentist or under contract with a dentist licensed under this chapter who is one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">The employer of the supervising dentist; </section><section prefix="b">A shareholder in a professional association formed under KRS 274.015 of which the supervising dentist is a shareholder; </section><section prefix="c">A member or manager of a limited liability company formed under KRS 275.005 of which the supervising dentist is a member or manager; </section><section prefix="d">A shareholder in a corporation formed under KRS Chapter 271B of which the supervising dentist is a shareholder; </section><section prefix="e">A partner or employee of a partnership of which the supervising dentist is a partner or employee; or </section><section prefix="f">A government entity that employs the dental hygienist to provide dental hygiene services in a public school in connection with other programs the government entity administers. </section></section><section prefix="6">A dental hygienist may provide the following procedures in a volunteer community health setting without the supervision of a dentist: <section prefix="a">Dental health education; </section><section prefix="b">Nutritional counseling; </section><section prefix="c">Preparing a generalized oral screening with subsequent referral to a dentist; </section><section prefix="d">Applying fluoride on patients; </section><section prefix="e">Demonstration of oral hygiene technique; and </section><section prefix="f">Sealants. </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">A dental hygienist may provide, for not more than fifteen (15) consecutive full business days, dental hygiene services to a patient when the supervising dentist is not physically present at the location at which the services are provided if all the following requirements are met: <section prefix="1">The dental hygienist has at least two (2) years with a minimum of three thousand (3,000) hours of experience in the practice of dental hygiene; </section><section prefix="2">The dental hygienist has successfully completed a course approved by the board in the identification and prevention of potential medical emergencies with reregistration in this course every two (2) years; </section><section prefix="3">The dental hygienist complies with written protocols for emergencies the supervising dentist establishes; </section><section prefix="4">The dental hygienist does not examine or provide dental health services to a patient who has not been examined by the supervising dentist within the previous seven (7) months. The supervising dentist shall have completed and evaluated a medical and dental history of the patient and shall have placed a written order for treatment in the patient's file. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to determine guidelines for the written order; and </section><section prefix="5">A patient is notified in advance of an appointment for dental hygiene services when the supervising dentist will be absent from the location. The patient shall be required to sign an informed consent form, prior to treatment by the hygienist, acknowledging the dentist's absence. </section></section><section prefix="b">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to determine procedures the dental hygienist shall not be allowed to perform while the supervising dentist is absent from the work site. </section></section><section prefix="8">A dental hygienist licensed by the board may practice as a public health hygienist and may provide dental hygiene services if: <section prefix="a">The services are provided as part of a dental health program; </section><section prefix="b">The program for which the hygienist works is operated through the Department for Public Health or a governing board of health; and </section><section prefix="c">The hygienist performs only accepted standardized protocols which are contained within the scope of practice of dental hygiene and which are reviewed and approved by the Board of Dentistry and either the Department for Public Health or the dentist member of the governing board of health, as set out in administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="9">A dental hygienist may provide screening services in any setting without the supervision of a dentist if: <section prefix="a">The screening is conducted to fulfill the requirements of KRS 156.160(1)(j); and </section><section prefix="b">Patients are informed that the service being provided is a screening and that only a dentist is licensed to make a definitive diagnosis of the need for dental care. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 18, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 6. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2636-3, 2636-10, 2636-19. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40141</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>