<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.687</section_number><catch_line>Registration of nonresident mail order contact lens sellers with Attorney General. </catch_line><order_by>687</order_by><text>The Attorney General shall require and provide for the annual registration of all mail order contact lens sellers located outside of the Commonwealth that dispense contact lenses to Kentucky residents, including those providing contact lenses via the Internet. A mail order contact lens seller's registration shall be granted upon the disclosure and certification by the seller of all of the following: <section prefix="1">The seller is licensed or registered to distribute contact lenses in the state in which the dispensing facility is located and from which the contact lenses are dispensed; </section><section prefix="2">The location, names, and titles of all owners, partners, corporate officers, and the person who is responsible for overseeing the dispensing of contact lenses to residents of this state; </section><section prefix="3">The seller has complied with and shall continue to comply with all lawful directives and appropriate requests for information from the appropriate agency of each state in which the seller is licensed or registered; </section><section prefix="4">The seller shall respond to all requests for information from the Attorney General within thirty (30) days from receipt of the request; </section><section prefix="5">The seller shall maintain records of contact lenses dispensed to residents of this state for a period of ten (10) years, and that the records shall be readily available for inspection by the Attorney General upon demand; </section><section prefix="6">The seller shall provide a toll-free telephone service during its regular hours of operation for the sole purpose of responding to the patients in this state concerning questions and complaints. All questions relating to eye care shall be referred to the doctor prescribing the contact lenses; </section><section prefix="7">The seller shall provide a toll-free telephone service during its regular hours of operation solely for optometrists, osteopaths, and physicians. </section><section prefix="8">The seller shall provide the following or a substantially equivalent written notification to the patient whenever contact lenses are supplied: WARNING: IF YOU ARE HAVING ANY OF THE FOLLOWING SYMPTOMS REMOVE YOUR CONTACT LENSES IMMEDIATELY AND CONSULT YOUR EYE CARE PRACTITIONER BEFORE WEARING YOUR LENSES AGAIN: UNEXPLAINED EYE DISCOMFORT, WATERING, VISION CHANGE, OR REDNESS; and </section><section prefix="9">The seller's license or registration, in the state in which the seller is licensed or registered, has not been suspended or revoked, but should the seller be the subject of any investigation undertaken by the licensing or registering state, or should the seller's license or registration be suspended or revoked, then the seller shall immediately notify the Attorney General of such actions. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>