<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-143</section_number><catch_line>Policies issued on or after the operative date of the valuation manual -- Application of KRS 304.6-130(2) minimum standard of valuation.   </catch_line><order_by>6-143</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For policies issued on or after the operative date of the valuation manual, the standard prescribed in the valuation manual shall be the minimum standard of valuation required under KRS 304.6-130(2), except as provided by subsection (5) or (7) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The operative date of the valuation manual shall be January 1 of the first calendar year following the first July 1, at which time all of the following have occurred: <section prefix="a">The valuation manual has been adopted by the NAIC by an affirmative vote of at least forty-two (42) members, or three-fourths (3/4) of the members voting, whichever is greater; </section><section prefix="b">The Standard Valuation Law, as amended by the NAIC in 2009, or legislation including substantially similar terms and provisions, has been enacted by states representing greater than seventy-five percent (75%) of the direct premiums written as reported in the following annual statements submitted for 2008: <section prefix="1">Life, accident and health insurance; </section><section prefix="2">Health insurance; or </section><section prefix="3">Fraternal benefit societies, as defined in KRS 304.29-011, insurance; and </section></section><section prefix="c">The Standard Valuation Law, as amended by the NAIC in 2009, or legislation including substantially similar terms and provisions, has been enacted in by at least forty-two (42) of the fifty-five (55) jurisdictions, including: <section prefix="1">The fifty (50) states of the United States; </section><section prefix="2">American Samoa; </section><section prefix="3">The American Virgin Islands; </section><section prefix="4">The District of Columbia; </section><section prefix="5">Guam; and </section><section prefix="6">Puerto Rico. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Unless a change in the valuation manual specifies a later effective date, changes to the valuation manual shall be effective on January 1 following the date when all of the following have occurred: <section prefix="1">The change to the valuation manual has been adopted by the NAIC by an affirmative vote representing: <section prefix="a">At least three-fourths (3/4) of the members of the NAIC voting, but not less than a majority of the total membership; and </section><section prefix="b">Members of the NAIC representing jurisdictions totaling greater than seventy-five percent (75%) of the direct premiums written as reported in the following annual statements most recently available prior to the vote required by subparagraph 1. of this paragraph: i. Life, accident and health insurance; ii. Health insurance; or iii. Fraternal benefit societies, as defined in KRS 304.29-011, insurance; or </section></section></section><section prefix="b">The valuation manual becomes effective pursuant to an order by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="4">The valuation manual shall specify the following: <section prefix="a">Minimum valuation standards for and definitions of the policies or contracts subject to KRS 304.6-130(2). The minimum valuation standards shall be: <section prefix="1">The commissioner's reserve valuation method for life insurance contracts, other than annuity contracts; </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner's annuity valuation method for annuity contracts; and </section><section prefix="3">Minimum reserves for all other policies or contracts. </section></section><section prefix="b">Which policies or contracts or types of policies or contracts that are subject to the requirements of a principle-based valuation, required by KRS 304.6-151(1), and the minimum valuation standards consistent with those requirements; </section><section prefix="c">For policies and contracts subject to a principle-based valuation under KRS 304.6-151(2)(c): <section prefix="1">Requirements for the format of the reports to the commissioner, including information necessary to determine if the valuation is appropriate and in compliance with KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180; </section><section prefix="2">Assumptions to be prescribed for risks over which the company does not have significant control or influence; and </section><section prefix="3">Procedures for corporate governance and oversight of the actuarial function, and a process for appropriate waiver or modification of the procedures; </section></section><section prefix="d">For policies not subject to a principle-based valuation under KRS 304.6-151, the minimum valuation standard shall either: <section prefix="1">Be consistent with the minimum standard of valuation prior to the operative date of the valuation manual; or </section><section prefix="2">Develop reserves that quantify the benefits and guarantees, and the funding associated with the contracts and their risks at a level of conservatism that reflects conditions that include unfavorable events that have a reasonable probability of occurring; </section></section><section prefix="e">Other requirements, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Those relating to reserve methods; </section><section prefix="2">Models for measuring risk; </section><section prefix="3">Generation of economic scenarios; </section><section prefix="4">Assumptions; </section><section prefix="5">Margins; </section><section prefix="6">Use of company experience; </section><section prefix="7">Risk measurement; </section><section prefix="8">Disclosure; </section><section prefix="9">Certifications; </section><section prefix="10">Reports; </section><section prefix="11">Actuarial opinions and memorandums; </section><section prefix="12">Transition rules; and </section><section prefix="13">Internal controls; and </section></section><section prefix="f">The data and form of the data required by KRS 304.6-133 and with whom the data shall be submitted, and may specify other requirements including data analyses and reporting of analyses. </section></section><section prefix="5">In the absence of a specific valuation requirement or if a specific valuation requirement in the valuation manual is not, in the opinion of the commissioner, in compliance with KRS 304.6-151, the company shall, with respect to the requirements, comply with minimum valuation standards prescribed by the commissioner by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner may engage a qualified actuary, at the expense of the company, to perform an actuarial examination of the company and to opine on the appropriateness of a reserve assumption or method used by the company, or to review and opine on a company's compliance with any requirement set forth in KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180. The commissioner may rely upon the opinion of a qualified actuary, regarding KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180, who is engaged by the commissioner of another state, district, or territory of the United States. As used in this subsection, the term "engage" includes employment or contracting. </section><section prefix="7">The commissioner may require a company to change any assumption or method that in the opinion of the commissioner is necessary to comply with the requirement of the valuation manual or KRS 304.6-130 to 304.6-180. The company shall adjust the reserves as required by the commissioner. The commissioner may take other disciplinary action as permitted under this subtitle. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44429</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>