<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.840</section_number><catch_line>Steering committee to assist in promotion -- Recommendation -- Reports -- Termination. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Parks shall establish a steering committee which shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or a designee; </section><section prefix="b">The Commissioner of Agriculture, or a designee; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Department of Parks, or a designee; </section><section prefix="d">The director of the Agriculture Development Board, or a designee; </section><section prefix="e">The coordinator of the Kentucky State University Aquaculture Program, or a designee; </section><section prefix="f">The chairperson of the horticulture department at the University of Kentucky, or a designee; and </section><section prefix="g">Two (2) members of organizations and associations representing the Kentucky farming community, appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture. </section></section><section prefix="2">The steering committee shall plan and assist in the implementation of the promotion program identified in KRS 148.830 and 148.835. </section><section prefix="3">The steering committee shall recommend by October 1, 2011, the structure and objectives of the promotion program identified in KRS 148.830 and 148.835. </section><section prefix="4">Upon implementation of the promotion program identified in KRS 148.830 and 148.835, the steering committee shall evaluate the promotion program and submit an initial report to the Governor, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the Legislative Research Commission no later than July 1, 2012, and subsequent annual reports no later than July 1 of each year thereafter. </section><section prefix="5">The steering committee shall continue to meet at least once each year at a date and location to be determined by its members to ensure the continuation of the promotion program. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39636</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>