<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.080</section_number><catch_line>Harassing communications. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of harassing communications when, with intent to intimidate, harass, annoy, or alarm another person, he or she: <section prefix="a">Communicates with a person, anonymously or otherwise, by telephone, telegraph, mail, or any other form of written communication in a manner which causes annoyance or alarm and serves no purpose of legitimate communication; </section><section prefix="b">Makes a telephone call, whether or not conversation ensues, with no purpose of legitimate communication; or </section><section prefix="c">Communicates, while enrolled as a student in a local school district, with or about another school student, anonymously or otherwise, by telephone, the Internet, telegraph, mail, or any other form of electronic or written communication in a manner which a reasonable person under the circumstances should know would cause the other student to suffer fear of physical harm, intimidation, humiliation, or embarrassment and which serves no purpose of legitimate communication. </section></section><section prefix="2">Harassing communications is a Class B misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 218, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19927</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>