<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.420</section_number><catch_line>Senior and Physically Disabled Adult Discount Program for retail goods and services. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services a statewide Senior and Physically Disabled Adult Discount Program for the purpose of making retail goods and services available at reduced rates to the Commonwealth's senior citizens. </section><section prefix="2">Program participation shall be voluntary and free. No fees, dues, or other charges shall be assessed by the cabinet nor required of the merchants or senior or physically disabled adult citizens who choose to participate. The cabinet shall invite retail merchants to participate in the program by extending discounts on their merchandise or services to physically disabled adults and citizens sixty (60) years of age and older. The conditions and rate of the discounts shall be determined by the participating businesses. Persons sixty (60) years of age and physically disabled adults shall be eligible to participate in the program by presenting valid proof of age or a statement from a licensed physician that the person is physically disabled to participating businesses. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the cabinet shall make such regulations as necessary to provide program identification for participating merchants and senior citizens lacking proof of age, informational brochures, directories of participating businesses, and other printed materials essential to the implementation and promotion of the program. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 296, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 241, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 406, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8204</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>