<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.020</section_number><catch_line>Purposes and construction of chapter -- Effect. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The general purposes of this chapter are: <section prefix="a">To provide for execution within the state of the policies embodied in the Federal Civil Rights Act of 1964 as amended (78 Stat. 241), Title VIII of the Federal Civil Rights Act of 1968 (82 Stat. 81), the Fair Housing Act as amended (42 U.S.C. 360), the Federal Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (81 Stat. 602), the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (P.L. 101-336), and the Civil Rights Act of 1991 as amended (P.L. 102-166, amended by P.L. 102-392); </section><section prefix="b">To safeguard all individuals within the state from discrimination because of familial status, race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age forty (40) and over, or because of the person's status as a qualified individual with a disability as defined in KRS 344.010 and KRS 344.030; thereby to protect their interest in personal dignity and freedom from humiliation, to make available to the state their full productive capacities, to secure the state against domestic strife and unrest which would menace its democratic institutions, to preserve the public safety, health, and general welfare, and to further the interest, rights, and privileges of individuals within the state; </section><section prefix="c">To establish as the policy of the Commonwealth the safeguarding of the rights of an individual selling or leasing his primary residence through private sale without the aid of any real estate operator, broker, or salesman and without advertising or public display. </section></section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall be construed to further the general purposes stated in this section and the special purposes of the particular provision involved. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as indicating an intent to exclude local laws on the same subject matter not inconsistent with this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing contained in this chapter shall be deemed to repeal any other law of this state relating to discrimination because of familial status, race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age forty (40) and over, or because of the person's status as a qualified individual with a disability as defined in KRS 344.030. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 2. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 1, sec. 101, Art. 6, sec. 604(a), and Art. 7, sec. 707. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32602</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>