<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.030</section_number><catch_line>Major organizational units of cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The cabinet consists of the following major organizational units, which are hereby created: <section prefix="1">Office of the Secretary. Within the Office of the Secretary, there shall be an Office of Communications and Administrative Review, an Office of Legal Services, an Office of Inspector General, an Office of the Ombudsman, and the Governor's Office of Electronic Health Information. <section prefix="a">The Office of Communications and Administrative Review shall include oversight of administrative hearings and communications with internal and external audiences of the cabinet. The Office of Communications and Administrative Review shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. </section><section prefix="b">The Office of Legal Services shall provide legal advice and assistance to all units of the cabinet in any legal action in which it may be involved. The Office of Legal Services shall employ all attorneys of the cabinet who serve the cabinet in the capacity of attorney, giving legal advice and opinions concerning the operation of all programs in the cabinet. The Office of Legal Services shall be headed by a general counsel who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050 and 12.210. The general counsel shall be the chief legal advisor to the secretary and shall be directly responsible to the secretary. The Attorney General, on the request of the secretary, may designate the general counsel as an assistant attorney general under the provisions of KRS 15.105. </section><section prefix="c">The Office of Inspector General shall be responsible for: <section prefix="1">The conduct of audits and investigations for detecting the perpetration of fraud or abuse of any program by any client, or by any vendor of services with whom the cabinet has contracted; and the conduct of special investigations requested by the secretary, commissioners, or office heads of the cabinet into matters related to the cabinet or its programs; </section><section prefix="2">Licensing and regulatory functions as the secretary may delegate; </section><section prefix="3">Review of health facilities participating in transplant programs, as determined by the secretary, for the purpose of determining any violations of KRS 311.1911 to 311.1959, 311.1961, and 311.1963; and </section><section prefix="4">The notification and forwarding of any information relevant to possible criminal violations to the appropriate prosecuting authority. </section></section> The Office of Inspector General shall be headed by an inspector general who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor. The inspector general shall be directly responsible to the secretary. <section prefix="d">The Office of the Ombudsman shall provide professional support in the evaluation of programs, including but not limited to quality improvement and information analysis and reporting, contract monitoring, program monitoring, and the development of quality service delivery, and a review and resolution of citizen complaints about programs or services of the cabinet when those complaints are unable to be resolved through normal administrative remedies. The Office of the Ombudsman shall place an emphasis on research and best practice and program accountability and shall monitor federal compliance. The Office of the Ombudsman shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050. </section><section prefix="e">The Governor's Office of Electronic Health Information shall provide leadership in the redesign of the health care delivery system using electronic information technology as a means to improve patient care and reduce medical errors and duplicative services. The Governor's Office of Electronic Health Information shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; </section></section><section prefix="2">Department for Medicaid Services. The Department for Medicaid Services shall serve as the single state agency in the Commonwealth to administer Title XIX of the Federal Social Security Act. The Department for Medicaid Services shall be headed by a commissioner for Medicaid services, who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. The commissioner for Medicaid services shall be a person who by experience and training in administration and management is qualified to perform the duties of this office. The commissioner for Medicaid services shall exercise authority over the Department for Medicaid Services under the direction of the secretary and shall only fulfill those responsibilities as delegated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="3">Department for Public Health. The Department for Public Health shall develop and operate all programs of the cabinet that provide health services and all programs for assessing the health status of the population for the promotion of health and the prevention of disease, injury, disability, and premature death. This shall include but not be limited to oversight of the Division of Women's Health. The Department for Public Health shall be headed by a commissioner for public health who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. The commissioner for public health shall be a duly licensed physician who by experience and training in administration and management is qualified to perform the duties of this office. The commissioner shall advise the head of each major organizational unit enumerated in this section on policies, plans, and programs relating to all matters of public health, including any actions necessary to safeguard the health of the citizens of the Commonwealth. The commissioner shall serve as chief medical officer of the Commonwealth. The commissioner for public health shall exercise authority over the Department for Public Health under the direction of the secretary and shall only fulfill those responsibilities as delegated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="4">Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities. The Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities shall develop and administer programs for the prevention of mental illness, intellectual disabilities, brain injury, developmental disabilities, and substance abuse disorders and shall develop and administer an array of services and support for the treatment, habilitation, and rehabilitation of persons who have a mental illness or emotional disability, or who have an intellectual disability, brain injury, developmental disability, or a substance abuse disorder. The Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities shall be headed by a commissioner for behavioral health, developmental and intellectual disabilities who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. The commissioner for behavioral health, developmental and intellectual disabilities shall be by training and experience in administration and management qualified to perform the duties of the office. The commissioner for behavioral health, developmental and intellectual disabilities shall exercise authority over the department under the direction of the secretary, and shall only fulfill those responsibilities as delegated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="5">Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs. The duties, responsibilities, and authority set out in KRS 200.460 to 200.490 shall be performed by the commission. The commission shall advocate the rights of children with disabilities and, to the extent that funds are available, shall provide the services and facilities for children with disabilities as are deemed appropriate by the commission. The commission shall be composed of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor to serve a term of office of four (4) years. The commission may promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A as may be necessary to implement and administer its responsibilities. The duties, responsibilities, and authority of the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs shall be performed through the office of the executive director of the commission. The executive director shall be appointed by the Governor under KRS 12.040, and the commission may at any time recommend the removal of the executive director upon filing with the Governor a full written statement of its reasons for removal. The executive director shall report directly to the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs and serve as the commission's secretary; </section><section prefix="6">Office of Health Policy. The Office of Health Policy shall lead efforts to coordinate health care policy, including Medicaid, behavioral health, developmental and intellectual disabilities, mental health services, services for individuals with an intellectual disability, public health, certificate of need, and health insurance. The duties, responsibilities, and authority pertaining to the certificate of need functions and the licensure appeal functions, as set out in KRS Chapter 216B, shall be performed by this office. The Office of Health Policy shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor pursuant to KRS 12.050; </section><section prefix="7">Department for Family Resource Centers and Volunteer Services. The Department for Family Resource Centers and Volunteer Services shall streamline the various responsibilities associated with the human services programs for which the cabinet is responsible. This shall include, but not be limited to, oversight of the Division of Family Resource and Youth Services Centers and the Kentucky Commission on Community Volunteerism and Services. The Department for Family Resource Centers and Volunteer Services shall be headed by a commissioner who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. The commissioner for family resource centers and volunteer services shall be by training and experience in administration and management qualified to perform the duties of the office, shall exercise authority over the department under the direction of the secretary, and shall only fulfill those responsibilities as delegated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="8">Office of Administrative and Technology Services. The Office of Administrative and Technology Services shall develop and maintain technology, technology infrastructure, and information management systems in support of all units of the cabinet. The office shall have responsibility for properties and facilities owned, maintained, or managed by the cabinet. The Office of Administrative and Technology Services shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor under KRS 12.050. The executive director shall exercise authority over the Office of Administrative and Technology Services under the direction of the secretary and shall only fulfill those responsibilities as delegated by the secretary; </section><section prefix="9">Office of Human Resource Management. The Office of Human Resource Management shall coordinate, oversee, and execute all personnel, training, and management functions of the cabinet. The office shall focus on the oversight, development, and implementation of quality personnel services; curriculum development and delivery of instruction to staff; the administration, management, and oversight of training operations; health, safety, and compliance training; and equal employment opportunity compliance functions. The office shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; </section><section prefix="10">The Office of Policy and Budget shall provide central review and oversight of budget, contracts, legislation, policy, grant management, boards and commissions, and administrative regulations. The office shall provide coordination, assistance, and support to program departments and independent review and analysis on behalf of the secretary. The office shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; </section><section prefix="11">Department for Community Based Services. The Department for Community Based Services shall administer and be responsible for child and adult protection, violence prevention resources, foster care and adoption, permanency, and services to enhance family self-sufficiency, including child care, social services, public assistance, and family support. The department shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; </section><section prefix="12">Department for Income Support. The Department for Income Support shall be responsible for child support enforcement and disability determination. The department shall serve as the state unit as required by Title II and Title XVI of the Social Security Act, and shall have responsibility for determining eligibility for disability for those citizens of the Commonwealth who file applications for disability with the Social Security Administration. The department shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050; and </section><section prefix="13">Department for Aging and Independent Living. The Department for Aging and Independent Living shall serve as the state unit as designated by the Administration on Aging Services under the Older Americans Act and shall have responsibility for administration of the federal community support services, in-home services, meals, family and caregiver support services, elder rights and legal assistance, senior community services employment program, the state health insurance assistance program, state home and community based services including home care, Alzheimer's respite services and the personal care attendant program, certifications of adult day care and assisted living facilities, the state Council on Alzheimer's Disease and other related disorders, the Institute on Aging, and guardianship services. The department shall also administer the Long-Term Care Ombudsman Program and the Medicaid Home and Community Based Waivers Consumer Directed Option (CDO) Program. The department shall serve as the information and assistance center for aging and disability services and administer multiple federal grants and other state initiatives. The department shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. ch. 146, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2012; and 158, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 28, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 181, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 25, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 146, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.(4/19/2007).  A manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes in the second full sentence of subsection (2) of this section pursuant to KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40936</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>