<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.230</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of county, city-county, and district health boards. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">County, city-county, and district boards of health shall: <section prefix="a">Appoint a health officer and fix his salary subject to the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">Hold a regular meeting at least once every three (3) months, except that county or city-county boards whose counties are members of a district health department shall hold a regular meeting at least once every twelve (12) months, and other special or regular meetings as desired and keep full minutes of all the proceedings in a book provided for this purpose; </section><section prefix="c">Adopt, except as otherwise provided by law, administrative regulations not in conflict with the administrative regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services necessary to protect the health of the people or to effectuate the purposes of this chapter or any other law relating to public health; </section><section prefix="d">Act in a general advisory capacity to the health officer on all matters relating to the local department of health; </section><section prefix="e">Provide information regarding the cabinet's ombudsman to all applicants; </section><section prefix="f">Hear and decide appeals from rulings, decisions, and actions of the local health department or health officer, in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, if the aggrieved party makes written request therefor to the board within thirty (30) days after the ruling, decision, or action complained of. In hearing appeals regarding on-site wastewater permitting, the local health board shall utilize the expertise of the regional on-site wastewater consultants employed by the Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="g">Provide all information on on-site wastewater systems to the cabinet for incorporation into the statewide database as provided for in KRS 211.350(1); and </section><section prefix="h">Perform all other functions necessary to carry out the provisions of law and the regulations adopted pursuant thereto, relating to local boards of health; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (1), all powers and authority of the local board of health under existing statutes are transferred to the county department of health. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 403, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 354, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 117, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (3) and (11). -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2054a-10, 2054a-15, 2055. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>