<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.180</section_number><catch_line>Renewal or transfer -- Application for endorsement. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person applying for renewal or transfer of a commercial driver's license from another issuing jurisdiction, shall complete an application as required by KRS 281A.140, providing updated information, testing, and required certifications. </section><section prefix="2">If a person applies for a renewal or transfer of a commercial driver's license or seeks to add an endorsement, or has a hazardous materials endorsement and applies to retain the endorsement, he shall provide the required medical certificate and take the knowledge test for a hazardous materials endorsement again, unless he provides proof that he has taken and passed the hazardous materials knowledge test within the preceding two (2) years. </section><section prefix="3">Every person applying to add an endorsement to his existing commercial driver's license shall complete an application as required by KRS 281A.140, providing updated information and certifications. If the endorsement originally would have required a special knowledge or skills test, he shall successfully complete the test or tests prior to the endorsement being added to his commercial driver's license. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 10, effective April 5, 2002. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 18, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> April 5, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>