<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.529Synchronization</section_number><catch_line>of multiple prescriptions for treatment of a chronicillness.  </catch_line><order_by>529Synchronization</order_by><text>(1)The Department for Medicaid Services or a managed care organizationcontracted to provide services pursuant to this chapter shall provide a programfor synchronization of medications when it is agreed among the member, aprovider, and a pharmacist that synchronization of multiple prescriptions for thetreatment of a chronic illness is in the best interest of the patient for themanagement or treatment of a chronic illness provided that the medications:(a)Are covered by the Department for Medicaid Services or a managed careorganization contracted to provide services pursuant to this chapter;(b)Are used for treatment and management of chronic conditions that aresubject to refills;(c)Are not a Schedule II controlled substance or a Schedule III controlledsubstance containing hydrocodone;(d)Meet all prior authorization criteria specific to the medications at the timeof the synchronization request;(e)Are of a formulation that can be effectively split over required short fillperiods to achieve synchronization; and(f)Do not have quantity limits or dose optimization criteria or requirementsthat would be violated in fulfilling synchronization.(2)When applicable to permit synchronization, the Department for MedicaidServices or a managed care organization contracted to provide servicespursuant to this chapter shall apply a prorated daily cost-sharing rate to anymedication dispensed by a network pharmacy pursuant to this section.(3)Any dispensing fee shall not be prorated and shall be based on an individualprescription filled or refilled.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>