<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.2-316</section_number><catch_line>Exclusion or modification of warranties. </catch_line><order_by>2-316</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Words or conduct relevant to the creation of an express warranty and words or conduct tending to negate or limit warranty shall be construed wherever reasonable as consistent with each other; but subject to the provisions of this article on parol or extrinsic evidence (KRS 355.2-202) negation or limitation is inoperative to the extent that such construction is unreasonable. </section><section prefix="2">Subject to subsection (3), to exclude or modify the implied warranty of merchantability or any part of it the language must mention merchantability and in case of a writing must be conspicuous, and to exclude or modify any implied warranty of fitness the exclusion must be by a writing and conspicuous. Language to exclude all implied warranties of fitness is sufficient if it states, for example, that "There are no warranties which extend beyond the description on the face hereof." </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding subsection (2) <section prefix="a">unless the circumstances indicate otherwise, all implied warranties are excluded by expressions like "as is," "with all faults" or other language which in common understanding calls the buyer's attention to the exclusion of warranties and makes plain that there is no implied warranty; and </section><section prefix="b">when the buyer before entering into the contract has examined the goods or the sample or model as fully as he desired or has refused to examine the goods there is no implied warranty with regard to defects which an examination ought in the circumstances to have revealed to him; and </section><section prefix="c">an implied warranty can also be excluded or modified by course of dealing or course of performance or usage of trade; and </section><section prefix="d">with respect to the sale of bovine, porcine, ovine, and equine animals, or poultry there shall be no implied warranty that the animals are free from disease or sickness. This exemption shall not apply when the seller knowingly sells animals which are diseased or sick. </section></section><section prefix="4">Remedies for breach of warranty can be limited in accordance with the provisions of this article on liquidation or limitation of damages and on contractual modification of remedy (KRS 355.2-718 and 355.2-719). </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2-316, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33276</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>