<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.2960</section_number><catch_line>Pilot projects for twenty-four hour health coverage -- Authority for administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>2960</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By January 1, 1995, the Department of Insurance shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A authorizing the establishment by March 1, 1995, of pilot projects for twenty-four (24) hour health coverage. The total number of participants in the pilot projects cannot exceed five percent (5%) of all insured persons who are covered both by workers' compensation and general health insurance. The administrative regulations for the pilot projects shall provide that: <section prefix="a">A twenty-four (24) hour policy may cover general health care for purposes of general health insurance, auto insurance, workers' compensation, or health care normally covered by any line of insurance written in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">A twenty-four (24) hour coverage policy shall not contain deductibles or copayments for medical services or treatment for work-related injuries or diseases; and </section><section prefix="c">There shall be no transfer of liabilities or expenses between or among particular lines of insurance whose medical or health components have been combined into a twenty-four (24) hour coverage for health care. </section></section><section prefix="2">No policy for twenty-four (24) hour coverage shall become effective until it is reviewed and approved by the Department of Insurance. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes to the contrary, each insurer authorized or licensed to write insurance in the Commonwealth shall provide any information requested by the department for the purpose of developing a twenty-four (24) hour health policy. </section><section prefix="4">The purchase of a twenty-four (24) hour health policy shall not constitute an exemption from statutory provisions which require other nonmedical insurance coverage. However, an insurance carrier shall reduce its premium for insurance coverage written without the medical or health care component. Notwithstanding the provisions of Subtitle 13 of KRS Chapter 304, the premium reduction required in this subsection shall be subject to the approval of the commissioner of the Department of Insurance. </section><section prefix="5">If an employer obtains a twenty-four (24) hour health insurance policy, pursuant to this section, to secure payment of compensation for medical care and treatment under KRS Chapter 342, the employer shall also procure an insurance policy which shall provide indemnity benefits to ensure that the total coverage afforded by both the twenty-four (24) hour insurance policy and the policy providing indemnity benefits, shall provide the total compensation required by KRS Chapter 342. </section><section prefix="6">The participants in a pilot project for twenty-four (24) hour health coverage shall comply with periodic reporting requirements of the Department of Insurance. </section><section prefix="7">Each insurer authorized or licensed to write insurance in the Commonwealth shall cooperate with the department and shall provide any information requested by the department for the purpose of studying twenty-four (24) hour health policy. </section><section prefix="8">Each agency of state government shall cooperate with the department if requested to provide information for the purposes of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 320, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, Pt. 6, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9001</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>