<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.040</section_number><catch_line>Service for which no allowance shall be made. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>No compensation shall be paid for time in service, of: <section prefix="1">Any civilian officer or employee of any branch of the Armed Forces, contract surgeon, cadet of the United States Military Academy, midshipman of the United States Naval Academy or of the Coast Guard, member of the Reserve Officers Training Corps, member of the Students' Army Training Corps (except an enlisted man detailed to a training detachment of any of the foregoing), Philippine Scout, member of the Philippine Guard, member of the Philippine Constabulary, member of the Puerto Rico Regiment of Infantry, member of the National Guard of Hawaii, member of the Insular Forces of the Navy, member of the Samoan Native Guard, and Band of the Navy, or Indian Scout, in each case, for the period of service as such; </section><section prefix="2">Any member of the Public Health Service, for any period during which he or she was not detailed for active duty with the Armed Forces; </section><section prefix="3">Any person granted a farm or industrial furlough, for the period of such furlough; </section><section prefix="4">Any person detailed for work in the Spruce Production Division of the Air Service, for the period during which his pay was equalized to conform to the pay of civilian employees in the same or like employment. </section></text><history>Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 4, effective February 20, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>: February 20, 1960</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21824</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>