<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7053</section_number><catch_line>Contents of ordinance establishing a development area -- Agency to oversee and administer implementation of ordinance -- Termination date. </catch_line><order_by>7053</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An ordinance establishing a development area shall include the following provisions: <section prefix="a">A legal description of the boundaries of the development area, and geographic reference points; </section><section prefix="b">The establishment date; </section><section prefix="c">The termination date, including a provision that allows the termination date to be extended as provided in KRS 65.7045(35); </section><section prefix="d">A name for the development area for identification purposes; </section><section prefix="e">A finding that the conditions in the development area meet the criteria described in KRS 65.7049; </section><section prefix="f">A finding supporting the need to employ redevelopment assistance in the development area; </section><section prefix="g">A provision adopting the development plan required by KRS 65.7051(1); </section><section prefix="h">Approval of any agreements relating to the development area, including any local participation agreements; </section><section prefix="i">A provision establishing a special fund for the development area or any project within the development area; </section><section prefix="j">A requirement that any entity other than the governing body that receives financial assistance under the development area ordinance, whether in the form of a grant, loan, or loan guarantee, shall make periodic accounting to the governing body; </section><section prefix="k">A provision for periodic analysis and review by the governing body of the development activity in the development area, a review of the progress in meeting the stated goals of the development area, and a requirement that the review and analysis be forwarded to the authority if the development activity includes projects subject to a tax incentive agreement; </section><section prefix="l">Designation of the agency or agencies responsible for oversight, administration, and implementation of the development ordinance; and </section><section prefix="m">Any other provisions, findings, limitations, rules, or procedures regarding the proposed development area or a project within the development area and its establishment or maintenance deemed necessary by the city or county. </section></section><section prefix="2">An ordinance establishing a development area may designate an existing agency to oversee and administer implementation of a development area ordinance or a portion thereof. </section><section prefix="3">Unless the ordinance establishing a development area requires an earlier date, a development area shall cease to exist on the termination date. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 59, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 7, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>