<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4015</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for licensure prior to July 1, 2012.  </catch_line><order_by>4015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure as an elevator contractor under KRS 198B.4011 or as an elevator mechanic under KRS 198B.4013 who applies to the department prior to July 1, 2012, shall be licensed by the department without completing the licensure requirements as established in KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540, if the applicant is currently licensed, certified, or registered as an elevator contractor or elevator mechanic in another state whose standards are substantially equal to those in KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to July 1, 2012, an applicant who does not qualify for licensure under KRS 198B.4011 or 198B.4013 or subsection (1) of this section shall qualify for licensure by showing a minimum of three (3) years of verifiable experience engaging in business as an elevator contractor or elevator mechanic in this state. </section><section prefix="3">After July 1, 2012, licensure under this section shall cease. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 7, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 7, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36590</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>