<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.508</section_number><catch_line>Approval of requests for use of state aircraft. </catch_line><order_by>508</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All requests for use of state aircraft shall be approved in advance by the: <section prefix="a">Constitutional officer; </section><section prefix="b">Program cabinet secretary or his designee in writing; </section><section prefix="c">For the judicial branch, the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court or the director of the Administrative Office of the Courts; or </section><section prefix="d">For the legislative branch, the co-chairs of the Legislative Research Commission or the director of the Legislative Research Commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">Verbal requests for state aircraft transportation may be honored. However, all requests for state aircraft shall be provided in writing to the Capital City Airport Division within five (5) working days of the date of the flight. </section><section prefix="3">Approving officials shall be responsible for determining that a trip is for official business, that use of state aircraft is the most appropriate means of transportation, and that the proposed passenger complement conforms to the requirements of KRS 174.506(3). In determining the passenger complement, requesting agencies shall weigh the benefit to the agency of the inclusion of additional passengers against the increased costs that might be incurred if a larger aircraft is required to accommodate additional passengers on a trip. </section><section prefix="4">All requests for use of state aircraft shall be submitted on a form prescribed by the Capital City Airport Division and shall contain at a minimum the following information: <section prefix="a">Cabinet or agency name; </section><section prefix="b">Department name with appropriate billing account number; </section><section prefix="c">Purpose of the trip; </section><section prefix="d">Destination, including any planned stopovers and the reason for them; </section><section prefix="e">Names of all passengers on the flight; and </section><section prefix="f">Identification of any percentage of the flight that is for personal business in cases of the Governor or Lieutenant Governor as allowed under KRS 174.506. </section></section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 20, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 605, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification>KRS 36.420. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5034</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>