<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Desecrate" means defacing, damaging, polluting, or otherwise physically mistreating in a way that the actor knows will outrage the sensibilities of persons likely to observe or discover his action. </section><section prefix="2">"Public" means affecting or likely to affect a substantial group of persons. </section><section prefix="3">"Public place" means a place to which the public or a substantial group of persons has access and includes but is not limited to highways, transportation facilities, schools, places of amusements, parks, places of business, playgrounds, and hallways, lobbies, and other portions of apartment houses and hotels not constituting rooms or apartments designed for actual residence. An act is deemed to occur in a public place if it produces its offensive or proscribed consequences in a public place. </section><section prefix="4">"Transportation facility" means any conveyance, premises, or place used for or in connection with public passenger transportation by air, railroad, motor vehicle, or any other method. It includes aircraft, watercraft, railroad cars, buses, and air, boat, railroad, and bus terminals and stations and all appurtenances thereto. </section><section prefix="5">"Riot" means a public disturbance involving an assemblage of five (5) or more persons which by tumultuous and violent conduct creates grave danger of damage or injury to property or persons or substantially obstructs law enforcement or other government function. </section><section prefix="6">"Service animal" includes a: <section prefix="a">"Bomb detection dog," which means a dog that is trained to locate bombs or explosives by scent; </section><section prefix="b">"Narcotic detection dog," which means a dog that is trained to locate narcotics by scent; </section><section prefix="c">"Patrol dog," which means a dog that is trained to protect a peace officer and to apprehend a person; </section><section prefix="d">"Tracking dog," which means a dog that is trained to track and find a missing person, escaped inmate, or fleeing felon; </section><section prefix="e">"Search and rescue dog," which means a dog that is trained to locate lost or missing persons, victims of natural or man-made disasters, and human bodies; </section><section prefix="f">"Accelerant detection dog," which means a dog that is trained for accelerant detection, commonly referred to as arson canines; </section><section prefix="g">"Cadaver dog," which means a dog that is trained to find human remains; </section><section prefix="h">"Assistance dog," which means any dog that is trained to meet the requirements of KRS 258.500; </section><section prefix="i">Any dog that is trained in more than one (1) of the disciplines specified in paragraphs (a) to (h) of this subsection; or </section><section prefix="j">"Police horse," which means any horse that is owned, or the service of which is employed, by a law enforcement agency for the principal purpose of aiding in detection of criminal activity, enforcement of laws, and apprehension of offenders. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 211, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19919</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>