<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.080</section_number><catch_line>Boundary of proposed district -- Investigation -- Change -- Inclusion of city property restricted.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the petition is filed with the commissioner, he shall investigate at once the boundary of the district proposed to be organized, and may, at the cost of the petitioners, cause to be made surveys necessary to establish with reasonable accuracy a boundary that will, in his judgment, accomplish the purpose sought by the creation of the district in a practicable and workable manner, and that will be sufficiently comprehensive to avoid confusion or interference with any other similar district then existing or that may be created. The boundary established by the commissioner need not follow the boundary proposed by the petitioners, but if the boundary established by the commissioner results in a material change from that proposed in the original petition the petitioners shall secure, in case of a larger or smaller area, the signatures of sixty percent (60%) of the freeholders or owners in the area as established by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">None of the provisions of KRS 220.010 to 220.520 shall be applicable within the corporate boundary of any city of the first class, nor shall they be binding upon such city or any part thereof, or any land or property within the boundary of such city. The governing body of any city of the first class shall determine by ordinance whether city property lying outside the corporate boundary shall be included in any sanitation district, and whether the city shall bind itself to pay the charges for the services of the district furnished to such land or property. </section><section prefix="3">Should it be found desirable to include in a sanitation district all or a portion of a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) but less than one hundred thousand (100,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, the governing body of such city shall determine by ordinance whether the city or portion thereof shall be included in the district, or whether the city shall bind itself to pay the charges for the services of the district furnished in such area. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 277, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-8. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>