<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.215</section_number><catch_line>Workers' Compensation Board -- Authority -- Appointment -- Qualifications -- Term -- Vacancies -- Retirement system coverage. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Workers' Compensation Board is hereby created and established. The board shall rule on appeals of decisions rendered by administrative law judges under this chapter. The board shall rule on an appeal of a decision of an administrative law judge no later than sixty (60) days following the date on which the last appeal brief was filed. </section><section prefix="2">The Workers' Compensation Board shall consist of three (3) members appointed by the Governor. Each member shall hold no other public office and shall devote his or her full time to the duties of his or her office. </section><section prefix="3">Of the members of the board appointed under this section, one (1) shall serve a term that shall expire on January 4, 2002; one (1) shall serve a term that shall expire on January 4, 2003; and one (1) shall serve a term that shall expire on January 4, 2004, as designated by the Governor at the time of appointment. Thereafter, each term of a board member shall run for four (4) years from the date of expiration of the term for which the member's predecessor was appointed, except that a person appointed to fill a vacancy prior to the expiration of a term shall be appointed for the remainder of the term. The Governor shall not appoint a member of the board to fill the unexpired term of another board member, nor shall the Governor reappoint a member of the board who has been removed from his or her position prior to the expiration of his or her term. The members of the board shall have the qualifications required of appeals court judges, except for residence in a district, and shall receive the same salary and shall be subject to the same standards of conduct. The Governor shall designate a member of the board to serve as chairman. Any vacancy in the chairmanship shall be filled by the Governor. The Governor may at any time remove any member for cause after furnishing the member with a written copy of the charges against him or her and giving the member a public hearing if he or she requests it. </section><section prefix="4">A decision concurred in by any two (2) of the three (3) members shall constitute a decision of the board. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the Workers' Compensation Board and the administrative law judges shall be members of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="6">The Workers' Compensation Board shall be attached to the Department of Workers' Claims in the Labor Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1798, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 8, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 3, sec. 10, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 23, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 36, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 29. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 15. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1; and ch. 77 sec. 15. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4618-112, 4920. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32442</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>