<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.724</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth Office of Technology.   </catch_line><order_by>724</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created within the Finance and Administration Cabinet an agency of state government known as the Commonwealth Office of Technology. </section><section prefix="2">The Commonwealth Office of Technology shall be headed by an executive director, also known as the chief information officer, appointed by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. Duties and functions of the executive director shall include serving on the Governor's Executive Cabinet and those established in KRS 42.730. </section><section prefix="3">The Commonwealth Office of Technology shall consist of the following five (5) offices, each headed by an executive director and organized into divisions headed by a division director: <section prefix="a">Office of Enterprise Technology, consisting of the: <section prefix="1">Division of IT Governance; and </section><section prefix="2">Division of Enterprise Architecture; </section></section><section prefix="b">Office of Infrastructure Services, consisting of the: <section prefix="1">Division of Technical Services; </section><section prefix="2">Division of Communications; </section><section prefix="3">Division of IT Operations; and </section><section prefix="4">Division of Field Services; </section></section><section prefix="c">Office of Application Development, consisting of the: <section prefix="1">Division of Revenue Application Development; </section><section prefix="2">Division of Agency Application Development; </section><section prefix="3">Division of Development Support Services; </section><section prefix="4">Division of Geographic Information Systems; and </section><section prefix="5">Division of Data Management Services; </section></section><section prefix="d">Office of Chief Information Security Officer. The office shall ensure the efficiency and effectiveness of information technology security functions and responsibilities; and </section><section prefix="e">Office of Information Technology Service Management. </section></section><section prefix="4">Executive directors and division directors appointed under this section shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 138, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 22, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000.. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.505. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 89, sec. 10, and 138, sec. 3, which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>