<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.109</section_number><catch_line>Duties and responsibilities. </catch_line><order_by>109</order_by><text>The Transportation and Tourism Interagency Committee shall have but not be limited to the following duties and responsibilities: <section prefix="1">Review Kentucky's signage laws, administrative regulations, and policies implementing the federal "Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices" and submit any proposed revisions to the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">Seek public comment on Kentucky's signage laws, administrative regulations, and policies; </section><section prefix="3">Advise the Transportation Cabinet on the scenic byways and highways program; </section><section prefix="4">Review and make recommendations on requests for highway signage from tourism-related entities; </section><section prefix="5">Coordinate development of the tourism information potential of welcome centers and rest areas through such means as interactive videos, information kiosks, and highway advisory radio transmitters, as well as other innovative methods which may be identified by the committee; </section><section prefix="6">Monitor developments across the United States relating to billboards and official signs; </section><section prefix="7">Report to the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet and to the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet on issues of mutual interest to the cabinets; </section><section prefix="8">Serve as an advisory committee on issues identified by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet and secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="9">Report committee recommendations to the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, and the secretary of the Executive Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 59, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 56, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 115, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 42, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  This section was amended by 2009 Ky. Acts chs. 11 and 16, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5283</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>