<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.060</section_number><catch_line>Licensure for practice of professions governed by KRS Chapter 319B -- "Grandfather" provisions for licensure. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On and after January 1, 2013, no person shall practice any profession governed by this chapter, or hold himself or herself out as being able to practice any such profession, or dispense a custom orthosis, prosthesis, or pedorthic device, unless that person is licensed by the board. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Until January 1, 2013, a person certified by the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), with the title of Certified Orthotist (CO), Certified Prosthetist (CP), or Certified Prosthetist/Orthotist (CPO), or by the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC) with the title of Board of Certification-Orthotist (BOCO), Board of Certification-Prosthetist (BOCP), or Board of Certification-Prosthetist/Orthotist (BOCPO), or holding similar certifications from other accrediting bodies with equivalent educational requirements and examination standards, may apply for and may be granted orthotic or prosthetic licensure by the board, upon payment of the required fee and after the board has completed a review of the applicant's work history. The board shall complete its review for the purposes of this section within six (6) months of the date of application. The review may include but is not limited to completion by the applicant of a questionnaire regarding the applicant's work history and scope of practice. </section><section prefix="b">Until January 1, 2013, an orthotist or prosthetist certified by either the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), or the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), shall be held to the standards of practice enforced by the board that has certified the orthotist or prosthetist. For these purposes, certification by either board shall be considered equally valid and enforceable regarding pedorthist certification and standards of practice. </section><section prefix="c">After December 31, 2012, any applicant for licensure as an orthotist or a prosthetist shall meet the requirements of this chapter regarding the applicable license. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Until January 1, 2013, a person certified as a Certified Pedorthist (C.Ped) by the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), or certified as a Board of Certification-Pedorthist (BOCPD) by the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), or holding similar certifications from other accrediting bodies with equivalent educational requirements and examination standards, may apply for and may be granted pedorthic licensure under this chapter, upon payment of the required fee and after the board has completed a review of the applicant's work history. The board shall complete its review for the purposes of this section within six (6) months of the date of application. The review may include but is not limited to completion by the applicant of a questionnaire regarding the applicant's work history and scope of practice. </section><section prefix="b">Until January 1, 2013, a pedorthist certified by either the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), or the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), shall be held to the standards of practice enforced by the board that has certified the pedorthist. For these purposes, certification by either board shall be considered equally valid and enforceable regarding pedorthist certification and standards of practice. </section><section prefix="c">After December 31, 2012, any applicant for licensure as a pedorthist shall meet the requirements of the board regarding licensure. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, as an alternative mechanism for those in practice who are not currently certified, a person who has practiced full-time for a minimum of the past four (4) years in a prosthetic/orthotic/pedorthic facility as an orthotist, prosthetist, or pedorthist, may file an application with the board before January 1, 2013, in order to continue to practice orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics, and may be issued a license to practice orthotics, prosthetics, or pedorthics by the board without examination, upon the board's receipt of payment of the required licensing fee and after the board has completed a review of the applicant's work history. The board shall complete its review for the purposes of this section within six (6) months of the date of application. The review may include but is not limited to completion by the applicant of a questionnaire regarding the applicant's work history and scope of practice. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Until January 1, 2013, a person certified as a Certified Fitter-orthotics (CFo) by the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), or certified as a Certified Orthotic Fitter (COF) by the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), or holding similar certifications from other accrediting bodies with equivalent educational requirements and examination standards, may apply for and may be granted licensure as an orthotic fitter under this chapter, upon payment of the required fee and after the board has completed a review of the applicant's work history. The board shall complete its review for the purposes of this section within six </section></section><section prefix="6">months of the date of application. The review may include but is not </section>limited to completion by the applicant of a questionnaire regarding the applicant's work history and scope of practice. (b) Until January 1, 2013, an orthotic fitter certified by either the American Board for Certification in Orthotics, Prosthetics and Pedorthics, Inc. (ABC), or the Board of Certification/Accreditation, International (BOC), shall be held to the standards of practice enforced by the board that has certified the orthotic fitter. For these purposes, certification by either board shall be considered equally valid and enforceable regarding orthotic fitter certification and standards of practice. (c) After December 31, 2012, any applicant for licensure as an orthotic fitter shall meet the requirements of the board regarding licensure. (6) Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, a person who has practiced full-time for a minimum of the past four (4) years in a prosthetic/orthotic facility as an orthotic fitter, may file an application with the board before January 1, 2013, in order to continue to practice as an orthotic fitter, and shall be issued a license to practice as an orthotic fitter by the board without examination, upon the board's receipt of payment of the required licensing fee and after the board has completed a review of the applicant's work history. The board shall complete its review for the purposes of this section within six (6) months of the date of application. The review may include but is not limited to completion by the applicant of a questionnaire regarding the applicant's work history and scope of practice. </text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31282</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>