<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="165" order_by="165">A PROPRIETARY EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>165A.490</section_number><catch_line>Suspension or revocation of, or refusal to issue or renew, license.   </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text>The commission shall, upon receipt of satisfactory evidence, suspend, revoke, refuse to issue, or refuse to renew the license of a CDL driver training school or a CDL driver training instructor if: <section prefix="1">The licensee fails or refuses to comply with the provisions of this chapter or any administrative regulation adopted hereunder; </section><section prefix="2">The licensee has made a false material statement or has concealed a material fact in connection with his or her application; </section><section prefix="3">The licensee or any partner or other person directly interested in the CDL driver training school held a license issued under this chapter which was revoked or suspended and not reinstated; </section><section prefix="4">The licensee has been guilty of a fraudulent practice in attempting to obtain for himself or another a license to operate a motor vehicle; or </section><section prefix="5">Written notice of the cancellation of insurance required by KRS 165A.475 is received by the commission, and the licensee does not present satisfactory evidence of insurance to the secretary prior to the effective date of the cancellation. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 9, effective April 9, 2002. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(2). -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2002).  The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered the subsections of this section under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><former-codification>KRS 332.060. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40330</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>