<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.560</section_number><catch_line>Fire protection sprinkler contractor's license or certificate required -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, no person other than a certificate holder or an employee of a certificate holder shall engage in the preparation of technical drawings, installation, repair, alteration, extension, maintenance or inspection of a fire protection sprinkler system or use any title, sign, card or device indicating, or intending to indicate, or represent in any manner that he is a certified fire protection sprinkler contractor without first obtaining the fire protection sprinkler contractor's license or certificate under the provisions of KRS 198B.570 or 198B.580; it being the purpose of KRS 198B.550 to 198B.630 to safeguard life, health, property, and welfare of the public. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 198B.550 to 198B.630 shall not apply to state or local building officials, fire marshals, fire inspectors, or insurance inspectors when acting in their official capacities. </section><section prefix="3">This chapter shall not apply to professional engineers in the preparation of plans or construction inspection pursuant to KRS Chapter 322. </section><section prefix="4">This chapter shall not apply to limited area sprinkler systems served by a domestic water supply consisting of ten (10) sprinkler heads or less in one (1) structure. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41124</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>