<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.836</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction declined by reason of conduct. </catch_line><order_by>836</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 403.828, or by other law of this state, if a court of this state has jurisdiction under KRS 403.800 to 403.880 because a person seeking to invoke its jurisdiction has engaged in unjustifiable conduct, the court shall decline to exercise its jurisdiction unless: <section prefix="a">The parents and all persons acting as parents have acquiesced in the exercise of jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="b">A court of the state otherwise having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826 determines that this state is a more appropriate forum under KRS 403.834; or </section><section prefix="c">No court of any other state would have jurisdiction under the criteria specified in KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a court of this state declines to exercise its jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, it may fashion an appropriate remedy to ensure the safety of the child and prevent a repetition of the unjustifiable conduct, including staying the proceeding until a child custody proceeding is commenced in a court having jurisdiction under KRS 403.822, 403.824, and 403.826. </section><section prefix="3">If a court dismisses a petition or stays a proceeding because it declines to exercise its jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, it shall assess against the party seeking to invoke its jurisdiction necessary and reasonable expenses including costs, communication expenses, attorney's fees, investigative fees, expenses for witnesses, travel expenses, and child care during the course of the proceedings, unless the party from whom fees are sought establishes that the assessment would be clearly inappropriate. The court shall not assess fees, costs, or expenses against this state unless authorized by law other than KRS 403.800 to 403.880. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 19, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>