<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-270</section_number><catch_line>Examination report of domestic insurer -- Confidential nature -- Limited disclosure. </catch_line><order_by>2-270</order_by><text>The report of examination of a domestic insurer, although filed in the department as provided in KRS 304.2-260, shall nevertheless not be for public inspection except as to those portions of the report showing the insurer's current financial condition. The examination workpapers shall be deemed confidential information and shall not be available for public inspection, except that the commissioner may in his discretion disclose the content of an examination report, preliminary examination report, examination results, or any other matter relating to an examination report, to the department of insurance of any other state or country, or to law enforcement officials of this or any other state, or to an agency of this or any other state or the federal government at any time, if the agency or office receiving the report or matters relating to the report agrees in writing to hold it confidential and in a manner consistent with this section and KRS 304.2-260. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 944, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 27, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16678</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>