<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.400</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text>As used in KRS 223.405 to 223.460, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Alteration or repair of a water well" means any maintenance, addition, or change of well or pitless adapter, but does not include replacement or repair of a water pump or associated piping. </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the Kentucky Water Well Certification Board; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">"Certificate" means a certificate of competency issued by the secretary stating that the water well driller has met all the requirements for the appropriate classification set forth in KRS 223.405 to 223.460 or by regulation; </section><section prefix="5">"Person" means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, municipality, state and federal government, or other public body or other legal entity, or any officer, employee, or agent of any of the foregoing. </section><section prefix="6">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="7">"Water well" or "well" means any excavation or opening in the surface of the earth that is drilled, cored, bored, washed, driven, jetted, or otherwise constructed when the actual or intended use in whole or part of an excavation is the removal of water for any purpose, including but not limited to culinary and household purposes, animal consumption, food manufacture, use of geothermal resources for domestic heating purposes and industrial, irrigation, and dewatering purposes, but not including wells to be used for watering stock or for general farmstead use if the wells do not provide water for human consumption; </section><section prefix="8">"Water well driller" means a person who is qualified to engage in the drilling, alteration, or repair of a water well as defined in this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 343, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>