<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.371</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 61.371 to 61.379. </catch_line><order_by>371</order_by><text>As used in KRS 61.371 to 61.379, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Public employee" means a person appointed to a position in public service for which he is compensated on a full-time basis, excluding elected officers; </section><section prefix="2">"Public service" means employment by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or by any county, city, or political subdivision or by any department, board, agency, or commission thereof; </section><section prefix="3">"Employer" means the officer, employee, board, commission or agency authorized by law to make appointments to a position in public service; </section><section prefix="4">"Position" means an office or employment in the public service, excluding an office filled by popular election; </section><section prefix="5">"Military duty" means training and service performed by an inductee, enlistee, or reservist or any entrant into a temporary component of the armed forces of the United States, and time spent in reporting for and returning from such training and service, or if a rejection occurs, from the place of reporting therefor. "Military duty" shall not include voluntary active duty for training of an individual as a reservist in the armed forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the personnel board established by KRS Chapter 18A; </section><section prefix="7">"Seniority" means the increase in compensation, status, and responsibility resulting from promotion or step progression within a class of a classified service or promotion or increase in compensation, status, and responsibility in the unclassified service. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22927</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>