<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.635</section_number><catch_line>Extension board -- Membership, appointment, term, vacancy, removal of member. </catch_line><order_by>635</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Appointment of the six (6) members, other than the county judge/executive, to the extension board shall be made by the county judge/executive of the county in which the extension district is located. These appointments shall be made, with the approval of the fiscal court, from nominations submitted by the extension council in the county in which said district is located. Said council, to be eligible to submit nominations, shall be organized and functioning in accordance with procedures approved by the director of extension.  </section><section prefix="2">On or before November 1 of each year the extension council shall submit to the county judge/executive a list of two (2) nominees for each member to be appointed to the extension board. On or before December 1 of each year the county judge/executive shall from this list appoint the required board members. If for any reason the county judge/executive fails to appoint the required members by December 15 of the year in question, they may be appointed by the director of extension. On the first board two (2) members shall be appointed for terms of three </section><section prefix="3">years, two (2) for terms of two (2) years and two (2) for terms of one (1) year. </section>Thereafter, all appointments shall be for terms of three (3) years and shall become effective on the first of January following appointment. Each member shall serve until his successor is appointed and qualified. Appointment of members to fill vacancies shall be in the same manner as those for other members. Board members may be appointed and the first board organized immediately after June 14, 1962. In this case the period served in 1962 shall be in addition to the regular terms of the members which start on January 1, 1963. Each board member shall, by virtue of his membership on the board, become a member of the extension council. This membership on the extension council may be in addition to the maximum of forty (40) as listed in subsection (2) of KRS 164.625.  (3) A board member may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4369</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>