<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-901</section_number><catch_line>Governing law. </catch_line><order_by>2-901</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The laws of the state or other jurisdiction under which a foreign limited partnership is organized govern its organization and internal affairs, including the inspection of books, records, and documents, and the liability of its partners as partners. </section><section prefix="2">A foreign limited partnership shall not be denied a certificate of authority by reason of any difference between the laws of the jurisdiction under which the foreign limited partnership is organized and the laws of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">A certificate of authority does not authorize a foreign limited partnership to engage in any business or exercise any power that a limited partnership may not engage in or exercise in this Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 158, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 158, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 161, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34623</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>