<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7065</section_number><catch_line>Service payment agreement -- Power of city, county, or issuer to enter into agreement -- Liens, priority, validity, enforceability, and termination. </catch_line><order_by>7065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A city, county, or issuer may enter into a service payment agreement. </section><section prefix="2">The service payment agreement may provide that the city, county, or issuer shall have a lien on property described in the service payment agreement equal to the amount of periodic payments due under the service payment agreement. The service payment agreement may further provide that any lien created pursuant to this section shall be governed by the provisions set forth in KRS 91A.280, provided that a lien created pursuant to this section shall not have the priority established in KRS 91A.280 in relation to an existing lien on the property covered by the agreement unless, prior to recording the service payment agreement, the lien holder under the service payment agreement provides notice of the lien created by the service payment agreement to the holder of the existing lien, and the holder of the existing lien consents to the priority in writing. If written consent is not obtained, the priority of the lien created under this subsection in relation to the prior lien shall be determined in the same manner as a mortgage lien under KRS 382.280. </section><section prefix="3">A lien authorized by this section shall not be valid and enforceable until evidence of the lien has been recorded in the office of the county clerk. The lien shall commence upon the issuance of increment bonds or other obligations and shall continue until other funding sources pledged to and derived from the project that is the subject of the service payment agreement are sufficient to make, when due, all payments on the increment bonds or other obligations identified in the service payment agreement. Upon termination of a lien authorized by this section, a release shall be filed by the city, county, or issuer with the county clerk. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 13, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> March 23, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23482</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>