<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.125</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against possession of loaded firearm in room where alcoholic beverages are being sold by the drink. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, no person shall be in possession of a loaded, as defined in KRS 237.060, firearm while actually within the room where alcoholic beverages are being sold by the drink of a building on premises licensed to sell distilled spirits and wine at retail by the drink for consumption on the licensed premises pursuant to KRS Chapter 243. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not apply to the owner manager, or employee of licensed premises, law enforcement officers, or special local peace officers commissioned pursuant to KRS 61.360. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to a bona fide restaurant open to the general public having dining facilities for not less than fifty (50) persons and which receives less than fifty percent (50%) of its annual food and beverage receipts from the dining facilities by the sale of alcohol. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed as permitting the carrying of a concealed deadly weapon in violation of KRS 527.020. </section><section prefix="5">Any firearm possessed in violation of this section shall be subject to forfeiture and shall be disposed of pursuant to KRS 237.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective October 1, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>