<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="134" order_by="134">PAYMENT, COLLECTION, AND REFUND OF TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>134.131</section_number><catch_line>County clerk to annually provide department with list of certificates of delinquency received from sheriff -- Publication on department's Web site. </catch_line><order_by>131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before May 15, 2013, and each May 15 thereafter, each county clerk shall provide or shall arrange to provide to the department a list of all certificates of delinquency received by the county clerk from the sheriff for that year, and that are in the possession of the clerk on the day the information is provided. The list shall include, at a minimum, the property owner name, property address, and parcel number or lot number if available. To the extent possible, the list shall be provided to the department in an electronic format. </section><section prefix="2">On or before June 1, 2013, and on or before each June 1 thereafter, the department shall publish on its Internet Web site a consolidated list of certificates of delinquency by county. To the extent possible, within each county, the list shall be in alphabetical order by property owner name, and shall include at a minimum the property owner name, property address, and parcel number or lot number if available. </section><section prefix="3">The information required by this section shall be provided by the county clerks and department as a public service. The department, the county clerk, and the employees thereof shall be held harmless regarding the content or any omission relating to information provided. </section><section prefix="4">If the tax collection schedule is delayed in any county, that county shall provide the information required by subsection (1) of this section to the department within thirty (30) days of receipt from the sheriff, and the department shall publish the information on its Web site within fifteen (15) days of receipt from the county clerk. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 14, effective April 23, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> April 23, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40091</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>