<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.160</section_number><catch_line>Supervisors to present application to Secretary of State and file statement of committee. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The three (3) supervisors appointed under KRS 262.150 shall present to the Secretary of State an application signed by them, which shall set forth the following: <section prefix="a">Recitals that a petition for the creation of the district was filed with the commission pursuant to this chapter and that the proceedings were taken pursuant to the petition; that the application is being filed in order to complete the organization of the district as a governmental subdivision and a public body under this chapter; and that the commission has appointed them as supervisors. </section><section prefix="b">The name and official residence of each of the supervisors, together with a certified copy of the appointments evidencing their right to office. </section><section prefix="c">The term of office of each of the supervisors. </section><section prefix="d">The name which is proposed for the district. </section><section prefix="e">The location of the principal office of the supervisors of the district. </section></section><section prefix="2">The application shall be subscribed and sworn to by each of the supervisors before an officer authorized to take and certify oaths, who shall certify upon the application that he personally knows the supervisors and knows them to be the officers as affirmed in the application, and that each has subscribed to the application in the officer's presence. </section><section prefix="3">The application shall be accompanied by a statement by the committee, which shall certify by mere recitals, that: <section prefix="a">A petition was filed, notice was issued and hearing was held. </section><section prefix="b">The commission determined that there was need, in the interest of the public health, safety and welfare, for a district to function in the proposed territory and defined the boundaries of the territory. </section><section prefix="c">Notice was given and a referendum held on the question of the creation of the district and the result of the referendum showed a majority of the votes cast in the referendum to be in favor of the creation of the district. </section><section prefix="d">The commission determined that the operation of the proposed district was administratively practicable and feasible. </section></section><section prefix="4">The statement shall set forth the boundaries of the district as they have been defined by the commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 3, effective June 21, 1974. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42i-5. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>