<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.660</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for providing assistance for education technology. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>The School Facilities Construction Commission shall be governed by the following procedures in making an offer of assistance to local public school districts for providing education technology: <section prefix="1">The base level of assistance to each eligible district shall be determined by dividing the total amount available for education technology by the total of the prior year's statewide average daily attendance of the eligible districts times the district's prior year's average daily attendance. </section><section prefix="2">The funds shall be applied to the projects listed in the district's technology plan, and the funds shall be applied to projects in the priority order listed on the plan except as provided in KRS 157.655(2). The first priority for the expenditure of each new offer of assistance shall be to meet the previous obligations of bonds, leases, or other financial agreements made for education technology by the district. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall establish administrative regulations by which a district that receives an offer of assistance but does not have the local match shall be able to accumulate a credit for the state offer of assistance for a period not to exceed three (3) years. </section><section prefix="4">All unused state funds allocated according to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be reallocated by the commission. The reallocation shall follow the process and intent as set forth in this section with eligible districts being those districts which have the available local matching funds and have not completely implemented the Kentucky Education Technology System. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 3, effective April 3, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>April 3, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 28, (3) at 623.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (16) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>