<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.821</section_number><catch_line>Board of Trustees of University of Louisville -- Membership -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>821</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The government of the University of Louisville is vested in a board of trustees appointed for a term set by law pursuant to Section 23 of the Constitution of Kentucky. The board shall consist of seventeen (17) members appointed by the Governor; one (1) member of the teaching faculty of the University of Louisville who shall be the chief executive of the ranking unit of faculty government; a member of the permanent staff of the University of Louisville who shall be the chief executive of the staff senate; and a student member who shall be the president of the student body during the appropriate academic year. <section prefix="a">All persons appointed after May 30, 1997, shall be required to attend and complete an orientation program prescribed by the council under KRS 164.020 as a condition of their service. </section><section prefix="b">Board members may be removed by the Governor for cause, which shall include neglect of duty or malfeasance in office, after being afforded a hearing with counsel before the Council on Postsecondary Education and a finding of fact by the council. </section><section prefix="c">New appointees to the board shall not serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. Board members serving as of May 30, 1997, may be reappointed at the end of their existing terms and may serve two (2) additional full consecutive terms. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the student member does not maintain his position as student body president or his status as a full-time student at any time during that academic year a special election shall be held to select a full-time student member. The student member shall serve for a term of one (1) year beginning with the first meeting of the fiscal year which contains that academic year. </section><section prefix="3">The faculty member, staff member, and student body member shall cease to be eligible for membership on the board of trustees upon termination of their respective relationships with the university, and vacancies occurring for this reason shall be filled for the remainder of the respective terms in the same manner. The seventeen (17) citizen members of the board shall annually elect one (1) of their number to serve as chairperson of the board. </section><section prefix="4">The gubernatorial appointments shall serve a term of six (6) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified, except the initial terms shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members shall serve one (1) year terms; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members shall serve two (2) year terms; </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall serve three (3) year terms, one (1) of whom shall be a graduate of the university, selected from a list of three (3) names submitted by the alumni of the university in the manner and according to rules prescribed by the board of trustees; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) members shall serve four (4) year terms; </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) members shall serve five (5) year terms; and </section><section prefix="f">Three (3) members shall serve six (6) year terms, one (1) of whom shall be a graduate of the university, selected as under paragraph (c) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Governor shall make his at-large appointments so as to divide the citizen representation upon the board to reflect proportional representation of the two (2) leading political parties in the Commonwealth based on the state's voter registration and shall reflect no less than proportional representation of the minority racial composition of the Commonwealth. The membership may include one (1) graduate of the institution who resides outside the Commonwealth, but he shall not be reimbursed for out-of-state travel. </section><section prefix="6">Vacancies among the citizen members of the board occurring by death, resignation, or any other cause shall be filled by appointments made by the Governor for the expiration of the term, subject to the qualifications set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="7">Unless specifically approved by the board of trustees under the provisions of KRS 164.367, no member of the teaching or administrative staff of the university shall be directly or indirectly interested in any contract with the university for the sale of property, materials, supplies, equipment, or services, with the exception of compensation to the faculty, staff, and student members. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 125, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4468</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>