<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.261</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Health Care Infrastructure Authority -- Responsibilities -- Funding -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>261</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville shall jointly establish and operate a Kentucky Health Care Infrastructure Authority. The purposes of the authority are to improve the quality of health care and reduce the cost of health care. </section><section prefix="2">The responsibilities of the authority include but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Providing leadership in the redesign of the health care delivery system using information technology to ensure that all Kentuckians receive care that is safe, effective, patient-centered, timely, efficient, and equitable; </section><section prefix="b">Serving as a forum for the exchange of ideas and consensus building regarding the advancement of health information infrastructure and health care applications; </section><section prefix="c">Conducting research to identify innovative health care applications using information technology and systems to improve patient care and reduce cost of care, including applications to support electronic disease management and evidence-based medicine; </section><section prefix="d">Implementing pilot projects to determine the impact of various health care applications using information technology and systems on the quality of patient care and the cost of health care; </section><section prefix="e">Facilitating the transfer of the authority's research findings into clinical practice; </section><section prefix="f">Facilitating the development of the Kentucky e-Health Network created under KRS 216.267; </section><section prefix="g">Supporting the development of the Kentucky e-Health Network created under KRS 216.267 as a framework for the national health information infrastructure; </section><section prefix="h">Facilitating the integration of the health information infrastructure with other information infrastructure development; </section><section prefix="i">Recommending policies and practices to ensure the security and confidentiality of health information; </section><section prefix="j">Providing recommendations on standards for software and communication among networks; </section><section prefix="k">Seeking funding from federal and private foundations for research, pilot projects conducted by the authority, development of health information capacity, and administrative and faculty expenses incurred by the authority; </section><section prefix="l">Collaborating with federal agencies and seeking funding for the implementation of pilot projects that can serve as models for the national electronic health information infrastructure; </section><section prefix="m">Serving as a national resource for health information science; and </section><section prefix="n">Providing educational programs and stimulating interest in health information science. </section></section><section prefix="3">The authority may receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, revolving funds, fees for services, federal funds, and any other public and private funds. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall submit an annual report of its activities to the Governor, secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Legislative Research Commission, Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare, and Interim Joint Committee on Banking and Insurance. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective March 8, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> March 8, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8971</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>