<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">JUDICIAL RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>21.345</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of KRS 21.350 to 21.510, "retirement" means a voluntary resignation or a failure of reelection, but does not include a removal for cause. </section><section prefix="2">The word "service" as used in KRS 21.370 to 21.480 means service transferred from the Kentucky Retirement Systems pursuant to KRS 21.370(2), service as a city police judge purchased pursuant to KRS 21.370(3), and service as a Justice of the Supreme Court, as a Judge of the Court of Appeals created by Section 111 of the Constitution of Kentucky, as a regular Circuit Judge, or as a regular Judge of the District Court, including service in one (1) and then another of those capacities. It also includes service as a special Circuit Judge under the conditions described in subsection (3) of this section, as a Judge or commissioner of the former Court of Appeals, or as director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, prior to January 1, 1976, and service continuing beyond that date, in any capacity in or for the Court of Justice, by any person who held the office of commissioner of the former Court of Appeals, or director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, on December 31, 1975. The word "service" embraces only service performed while a member of the retirement system established by KRS 21.350 to 21.510, except that service in any of the positions mentioned, before the Judicial Retirement System was made applicable to that category of position, and service transferred from the Kentucky Retirement Systems pursuant to KRS 21.370(2), shall be included. </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of KRS 21.345 to 21.510, a "year" of service means a total of twelve (12) months of service, which need not be in the same calendar year. Service for any part of the calendar month in which the member's term of service begins or ends shall be deemed to constitute a month of service. </section><section prefix="4">The term "accumulated employer credit" as used in KRS 21.345 to 21.580 means the employer pay credit deposited to the member's account and interest credited on such amounts as provided by KRS 21.402. </section><section prefix="5">The term "accumulated contributions" as used in KRS 21.345 to 21.580, means: <section prefix="a">For a member who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014, the contributions made by the member to the Judicial Retirement Plan; and </section><section prefix="b">For a member who begins participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, in the hybrid cash balance plan, the contributions made by the member to the Judicial Retirement Plan and interest credited on such amounts as provided by KRS 21.402. </section></section><section prefix="6">The term "accumulated account balance" as used in KRS 21.345 to 21.580 means: <section prefix="a">For members who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014, the member's accumulated contributions; or </section><section prefix="b">For members who begin participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, in the hybrid cash balance plan as provided by KRS 21.402, the combined sum of the member's accumulated contributions and the member's accumulated employer pay credit. </section></section><section prefix="7">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any director of the Administrative Office of the Courts appointed after January 1, 1976, nor shall they apply to any commissioner of the Court of Appeals not appointed prior to January 1, 1976. The administrative director of the courts and commissioners of the Court of Appeals appointed prior to January 1, 1976, shall continue to be members of the system so long as they continue to render service in any capacity in or for the Court of Justice. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 19, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 14. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 2 (last sentence) -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Art. III, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 21.390. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42647</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>