<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.261Qualifications</section_number><catch_line>for licensure as certified public accountant.   </catch_line><order_by>261Qualifications</order_by><text>The license of "certified public accountant" shall be granted by the board to any person who satisfies the following requirements: <section prefix="1">Is no less than eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="2">Is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="3">Has a baccalaureate degree or master's degree conferred by a college or university recognized by the board with a major or concentration in accounting or its equivalent, as defined in administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="4">Passes a board-approved examination in accounting, auditing, and other related subjects as the board deems appropriate. To be eligible to apply for the examination, a person shall first satisfy the requirement of subsections (1) to (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="5">Completes one hundred fifty (150) college semester hours that include a baccalaureate or masters degree conferred by a college or university recognized by the board with a major or concentration in accounting or its equivalent, as defined in administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="6">Obtains one (1) year of accounting or attest experience while employed in an accounting or auditing position in public practice, industry, or government that shall be verified by a certified public accountant who, during the time being verified, held an active license to practice from any state. The one (1) year of experience required under this subsection shall be obtained: <section prefix="a">After the completion of the education requirements established in subsection (3) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">Within five (5) years from the date the candidate successfully completed the examination; </section></section><section prefix="7">At the time of applying for a license is a United States citizen, a citizen of a foreign country who is legally residing in the United States, or is an employee of a public accounting firm, company, or an institution of postsecondary education located outside the United States, but which has an office or campus located in the United States; and </section><section prefix="8">Submits a complete application for a license to practice as a certified public accountant in accordance with KRS 325.330. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 156, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 3. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 15. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44594</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>