<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.430</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Barbering -- Membership -- Terms -- Compensation.   </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created an independent agency of the state government to be known as the Kentucky Board of Barbering, which shall have complete supervision over the administration of the provisions of this chapter relating to barbers, barbering, barber shops, independent contract owners, barber schools, and the teaching of barbering. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Barbering, hereinafter referred to as the barber board or board, shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the Governor. Four (4) members shall be barbers holding a valid license and practicing in Kentucky. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in barbering. At all times in the filling of vacancies of membership on the barber board, this balance of representation shall be maintained. </section><section prefix="3">The two (2) members appointed to fill the terms beginning on February 1, 2008, shall serve until February 1, 2011, and the three (3) members appointed to fill the terms beginning on February 1, 2007, shall serve until February 1, 2010. All subsequent appointments shall be for a term of three (3) years, with terms ending on February 1. </section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall not remove any member of the barber board except for cause. </section><section prefix="5">The barber board shall elect from its members one (1) to serve as chairman, one (1) to serve as vice chairman, and a third to serve as secretary. </section><section prefix="6">Three (3) members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="7">In addition to the other qualifications specified in this section, barber members of the barber board shall be at least twenty-three (23) years of age, citizens of the United States, residents of Kentucky, and must have engaged in the practice of barbering in this state for a period of at least five (5) years. </section><section prefix="8">No member of the barber board shall be financially interested in, or have any financial connection with, any barber or cosmetology school, wholesale cosmetic or barber supply or equipment business, nor shall any member of the barber board teach barbering, cosmetology, or manicuring for monetary considerations. </section><section prefix="9">Each member of the barber board shall receive a compensation of one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day of attendance at a meeting of the board, and shall be reimbursed for necessary traveling expenses. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall hold its meetings within the state and when deemed necessary by the board to discharge its duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 11. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 3, effective June 30, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42130</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>