<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-802</section_number><catch_line>Partnership continues after dissolution. </catch_line><order_by>1-802</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, a partnership continues after dissolution only for the purpose of winding up its business. The partnership is terminated when the winding up of its business is completed. </section><section prefix="2">At any time after the dissolution of a partnership and before the winding up of its business is completed, all of the partners, including any dissociating partner other than a wrongfully dissociating partner, may waive the right to have the partnership's business wound up and the partnership terminated. In that event: <section prefix="a">The partnership resumes carrying on its business as if dissolution had never occurred, and any liability incurred by the partnership or a partner after the dissolution and before the waiver is determined as if dissolution had never occurred; and </section><section prefix="b">The rights of a third party accruing under KRS 362.1-804(1) or arising out of conduct in reliance on the dissolution before the third party has notice of the waiver shall not be adversely affected. </section></section><section prefix="3">The dissolution of a partnership that is or was a limited liability partnership shall not abate or suspend KRS 362.1-306(3). </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 150, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 150, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 55, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34504</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>