<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.720</section_number><catch_line>Application procedures -- Granting of funds -- Priorities in funding -- Targeting of funds -- Services to be provided.   </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The corporation shall issue a public notice to eligible recipients of the availability of trust funds at least twice each calendar year and provide for reasonable opportunity for the filing of applications. </section><section prefix="2">The corporation shall approve or deny properly submitted and completed applications within ninety (90) days of their receipt. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall grant as many applications as will effectively use available funds. </section><section prefix="4">The corporation shall grant or deny applications by ranking the applications competitively using criteria established by the corporation in consultation with the advisory committee for the trust fund created under KRS 198A.725. The corporation shall give priority to: <section prefix="a">Applications for projects submitted by nonprofit organizations or local governments for new construction for families; </section><section prefix="b">Applications for projects using existing privately owned housing stock, including stock purchased by nonprofit public development authorities; </section><section prefix="c">Applications for projects using existing publicly owned housing stock; and </section><section prefix="d">Applications from local governments for projects that demonstrate effective zoning, conversion, or demolition controls for single room occupancy units. </section></section><section prefix="5">The corporation shall limit funds to be used for administrative costs to no more than seven and one-half percent (7.5%) of available funds, and shall disapprove any project in which more than seven and one-half percent (7.5%) of available funds shall be used for administrative costs. </section><section prefix="6">The corporation shall require at least forty percent (40%) of all funds received to be used for rural areas of the Commonwealth, which shall periodically be defined by the board of directors of the corporation. </section><section prefix="7">Funds targeted under this section that are not expended or set-aside within twenty-four (24) months from allocation may be reallocated in nontargeted communities for very low-income persons. The corporation may extend the twenty-four (24) month period for good cause; however, an extension shall not exceed an additional twelve (12) month period. </section><section prefix="8">The corporation shall provide technical assistance to eligible recipients seeking to construct, rehabilitate, or finance housing-related services for very low-income persons. The corporation may contract with nonprofit organizations to provide the technical assistance required by this subsection. </section><section prefix="9">The corporation shall provide or contract for the following services: <section prefix="a">Financial planning and packaging for housing projects including alternative ownership programs and bridge financing; </section><section prefix="b">Project design, architectural planning, siting, and compliance with planning requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Securing matching resources for project development; </section><section prefix="d">Maximizing local government contributions to project development in the form of land donations, infrastructure improvements, waivers of development fees, local and state managed funds, zoning variances, density bonuses for low rise-multifamily projects, or creative local planning; </section><section prefix="e">Coordination with local planning, economic development, environmental, technical assistance, and recreational activities; </section><section prefix="f">Construction and material management; and </section><section prefix="g">Project maintenance and management. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>