<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.360</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local public agency may adopt regulations, not inconsistent with KRS 45A.345 to 45A.460, governing the following: <section prefix="a">Conditions and procedures for delegations of purchasing authority; </section><section prefix="b">Prequalification, suspension, debarment, and reinstatement of prospective bidders; </section><section prefix="c">Modification and termination of contracts; </section><section prefix="d">Conditions and procedures for the purchase of perishables and items for resale; </section><section prefix="e">Conditions, including emergencies, and procedures under which purchases may be made by means other than competitive sealed bids; </section><section prefix="f">Rejection of bids, consideration of alternate bids, and waiver of informalities in offers; </section><section prefix="g">Confidentiality of technical data and trade secrets information submitted by actual and prospective bidders or offerors; </section><section prefix="h">Partial, progressive, and multiple awards; </section><section prefix="i">Supervision of store rooms and inventories, including determination of appropriate stock levels and the management, transfer, sale, or other disposal of government-owned property; </section><section prefix="j">Definitions and classes of contractual services and procedures for acquiring them; </section><section prefix="k">Procedures for the verification and auditing of local public agency procurement records; </section><section prefix="l">Annual reports from those vested with purchasing authority as may be deemed advisable in order to insure that the requirements of this chapter are complied with; and </section><section prefix="m">Such other regulations as may be deemed advisable to carry out the purposes of KRS 45A.345 to 45A.460 or otherwise fulfill the local public agency's procurement responsibilities. </section></section><section prefix="2">All local public agency ordinances and regulations pertaining to procurement, whether promulgated under KRS 45A.345 to 45A.460 or otherwise, shall be maintained by the local public agency and shall be available to the public upon request at a cost not to exceed the cost of reproduction. </section><section prefix="3">Local school districts may adopt policies, not inconsistent with KRS 45A.345 to 45A.460, governing the conditions and procedures under which purchases of supplies may be made elsewhere. These policies shall include a provision that supplies purchased under this section shall meet any applicable contract specifications and not exceed two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500). </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 10, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 73, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22406</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>