<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3">GRANTS TO UNITED STATES OF LANDS AND RIGHTS TO ACQUIRE </unit></structure><section_number>3.050</section_number><catch_line>Perryville battlefield to be conveyed to the United States. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the United States Congress enacts a law authorizing the United States to take over the Perryville battlefield, now in the hands of the Division of Parks, the Governor shall appoint a commissioner who shall make and execute on behalf of Kentucky, a deed conveying fee simple title to the United States for national cemetery or park purposes, in conformity with the provisions of the Act of Congress when enacted, seventeen and three-fourths (17.75) acres of land, more or less, in Boyle County, Kentucky, now owned and held by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, together with all improvements thereon and appurtenances thereunto belonging. The conveyance shall be made free of any cost or charge to the United States for the property conveyed. The commissioner may ascertain by survey or otherwise the metes and bounds of the land conveyed and include in the deed an appropriate description of the land. The deed shall contain a clause to the effect that, when the United States shall cease to use or maintain the land conveyed as a national cemetery or park, upon demand of the Governor of Kentucky, it shall revert to Kentucky, and complete jurisdiction over it shall be again vested in Kentucky. The deed shall be in a form agreeable to the provisions of the Act of Congress, when enacted. </section><section prefix="2">When the conveyance to the United States is made, the jurisdiction of Kentucky shall thereby be ceded to and vested in the United States over the land conveyed. The jurisdiction hereby ceded shall continue no longer than the United States of America shall own the land. </section></text><history>  Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739f-8. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=87</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>