<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.015</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Registry" means the Kentucky Registry of Election Finance; </section><section prefix="2">"Election" means any primary, regular, or special election to fill vacancies regardless of whether a candidate or slate of candidates is opposed or unopposed in an election. Each primary, regular, or special election shall be considered a separate election; </section><section prefix="3">"Committee" includes the following: <section prefix="a">"Campaign committee," which means one (1) or more persons who receive contributions and make expenditures to support or oppose one (1) or more specific candidates or slates of candidates for nomination or election to any state, county, city, or district office, but does not include an entity established solely by a candidate which is managed solely by a candidate and a campaign treasurer and whose name is generic in nature, such as "Friends of (the candidate)," and does not reflect that other persons have structured themselves as a committee, designated officers of the committee, and assigned responsibilities and duties to each officer with the purpose of managing a campaign to support or oppose a candidate in an election; </section><section prefix="b">"Caucus campaign committee," which means members of one (1) of the following caucus groups who receive contributions and make expenditures to support or oppose one (1) or more specific candidates or slates of candidates for nomination or election, or a committee: <section prefix="1">House Democratic caucus campaign committee; </section><section prefix="2">House Republican caucus campaign committee; </section><section prefix="3">Senate Democratic caucus campaign committee; and </section><section prefix="4">Senate Republican caucus campaign committee; </section></section><section prefix="c">"Political issues committee," which means three (3) or more persons joining together to advocate or oppose a constitutional amendment or public question which appears on the ballot if that committee receives or expends money in excess of one thousand dollars ($1,000); </section><section prefix="d">"Permanent committee," which means a group of individuals, including an association, committee or organization, other than a campaign committee, political issues committee, inaugural committee, caucus campaign committee, or party executive committee, which is established as, or intended to be, a permanent organization having as a primary purpose expressly advocating the election or defeat of one (1) or more clearly identified candidates, slates of candidates, or political parties, which functions on a regular basis throughout the year; </section><section prefix="e">An executive committee of a political party; and </section><section prefix="f">"Inaugural committee," which means one (1) or more persons who receive contributions and make expenditures in support of inauguration activities for any candidate or slate of candidates elected to any state, county, city, or district office; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Contributing organization" means a group which merely contributes to candidates, slates of candidates, campaign committees, caucus campaign committees, or executive committees from time to time from funds derived solely from within the group, and which does not solicit or receive funds from sources outside the group itself. However, any contributions made by the groups in excess of one hundred dollars ($100) shall be reported to the registry; </section><section prefix="5">"Testimonial affair" means an affair held in honor of a person who holds or who is or was a candidate for nomination or election to a political office in this state designed to raise funds for any purpose not charitable, religious, or educational; </section><section prefix="6">"Contribution" means any: <section prefix="a">Payment, distribution, loan, deposit, or gift of money or other thing of value, to a candidate, his agent, a slate of candidates, its authorized agent, a committee, or contributing organization. As used in this subsection, "loan" shall include a guarantee, endorsement, or other form of security where the risk of nonpayment rests with the surety, guarantor, or endorser, as well as with a committee, contributing organization, candidate, slate of candidates, or other primary obligor. No person shall become liable as surety, endorser, or guarantor for any sum in any one (1) election which, when combined with all other contributions the individual makes to a candidate, his agent, a slate of candidates, its agent, a committee, or a contributing organization, exceeds the contribution limits provided in KRS 121.150; </section><section prefix="b">Payment by any person other than the candidate, his authorized treasurer, a slate of candidates, its authorized treasurer, a committee, or a contributing organization, of compensation for the personal services of another person which are rendered to a candidate, slate of candidates, committee, or contributing organization, or for inauguration activities; </section><section prefix="c">Goods, advertising, or services with a value of more than one hundred dollars ($100) in the aggregate in any one (1) election which are furnished to a candidate, slate of candidates, committee, or contributing organization or for inauguration activities without charge, or at a rate which is less than the rate normally charged for the goods or services; or </section><section prefix="d">Payment by any person other than a candidate, his authorized treasurer, a slate of candidates, its authorized treasurer, a committee, or contributing organization for any goods or services with a value of more than one hundred dollars ($100) in the aggregate in any one (1) election which are utilized by a candidate, slate of candidates, committee, or contributing organization, or for inauguration activities; </section></section><section prefix="7">Notwithstanding the foregoing meanings of "contribution," the word shall not be construed to include: <section prefix="a">Services provided without compensation by individuals volunteering a portion or all of their time on behalf of a candidate, a slate of candidates, committee, or contributing organization; </section><section prefix="b">A loan of money by any financial institution doing business in Kentucky made in accordance with applicable banking laws and regulations and in the ordinary course of business; or </section><section prefix="c">An independent expenditure by any individual or permanent committee; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Candidate" means any person who has received contributions or made expenditures, has appointed a campaign treasurer, or has given his consent for any other person to receive contributions or make expenditures with a view to bringing about his nomination or election to public office, except federal office; </section><section prefix="9">"Slate of candidates" means any two (2) persons who have filed a joint notification and declaration pursuant to KRS 118.127, received contributions or made expenditures, appointed a campaign treasurer, designated a campaign depository, or given their consent for any other person to receive contributions or make expenditures with a view to bringing about their nomination for election to the offices of Governor and Lieutenant Governor. Unless the context requires otherwise, any provision of law that applies to a candidate shall also apply to a slate of candidates; </section><section prefix="10">"Knowingly" means, with respect to conduct or to a circumstance described by a statute defining an offense, that a person is aware or should have been aware that his conduct is of that nature or that the circumstance exists; </section><section prefix="11">"Fundraiser" means an individual who directly solicits and secures contributions on behalf of a candidate or slate of candidates for a statewide-elected state office or an office in a jurisdiction with a population in excess of two hundred thousand (200,000) residents; </section><section prefix="12">"Independent expenditure" means the expenditure of money or other things of value for a communication which expressly advocates the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate or slate of candidates, and which is made without any coordination, consultation, or cooperation with any candidate, slate of candidates, campaign committee, or any authorized person acting on behalf of any of them, and which is not made in concert with, or at the request or suggestion of any candidate, slate of candidates, campaign committee, or any authorized person acting on behalf of any of them; </section><section prefix="13">"Electronic reporting" means the use of technology, having electrical, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities, by which an individual or other entity submits, compiles, or transmits campaign finance reports to the registry, or by which the registry receives, stores, analyzes, or discloses the reports; </section><section prefix="14">"Security procedure" means a procedure employed for the purpose of verifying that an electronic signature, record, or performance is that of a specific person or for detecting changes or errors in the information in an electronic record. The term includes a procedure that requires the use of algorithms or other codes, identifying words or numbers, encryption, or callback or other acknowledgment procedures; </section><section prefix="15">"Electronic signature" means an electronic sound, symbol, or process attached to or logically associated with a record and executed or adopted by a person with the intent to sign the record; </section><section prefix="16">"Filer" means any candidate, a slate of candidates, committee, or other individual or entity required to submit financial disclosure reports to the registry; and </section><section prefix="17">"Filer-side software" means software provided to or used by the filer that enables transmittal of financial reports to the registry. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 2, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 179, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 178. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27846</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>