<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.120</section_number><catch_line>Retail premises not to be disorderly -- Acts constituting disorderly behavior.   </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A retail licensee, a patron, or the licensee's agents, servants, or employees shall not cause, suffer, or permit the licensed premises to be disorderly. </section><section prefix="2">Acts which constitute disorderly premises consist of causing, suffering, or permitting patrons, the licensee, or the licensee's servants, agents, or employees to cause public inconvenience, annoyance, or alarm, or create a risk through: <section prefix="a">Engaging in fighting or in violent, tumultuous, or threatening behavior; </section><section prefix="b">Making unreasonable noise; </section><section prefix="c">Refusing to obey an official order to disperse issued to maintain public safety in dangerous proximity to a fire, hazard, or other emergency; </section><section prefix="d">Creating a hazardous or physically offensive condition by any act that serves no legitimate purpose; </section><section prefix="e">Creating a public nuisance; </section><section prefix="f">Engaging in criminal activity that would constitute a capital offense, felony, or misdemeanor; or </section><section prefix="g">Failing to maintain the minimum health, fire, safety, or sanitary standards established by the state or a local government, or by state administrative regulations, for the licensed premises. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 85, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 20, effective June 17, 1978. -- Repealed in part 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 25; and ch. 173, sec. 15. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, secs. 8 and 17. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-180, 3490-14. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42520</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>