<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.100</section_number><catch_line>Construction, improvement or extension of sewer and drainage system -- Contracts -- Contractors' bonds. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>It shall be the duty of the district as promptly as possible, to rehabilitate, construct, improve, and extend, any sewer and drainage system taken over and controlled by it, which shall include, but is not limited to, disconnection of storm water drains and constructing outlets therefor, where such work is necessary to relieve existing sanitary sewers of storm water loads, in order to permit the efficient operation of such sanitary sewers. The district may make rules and regulations for the submission of bids and the construction of such additions, betterments, and extensions, or any part thereof. No contract shall be entered into for construction work or for the purchase of materials, unless the contractor shall give an undertaking with corporate surety in an amount approved by the board for the faithful performance of the contract. As to contracts entered into for construction, such undertaking shall provide, among other things, that the person or corporation entering into such contract with the district will pay for all materials furnished and services rendered in the performance of the contract, and that any person or corporation furnishing such materials or rendering such services, may maintain an action thereon to recover for the same against the obligor in the undertaking and the surety, as though such person or corporation was named therein. </text><history>Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 8. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24484</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>