<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.631</section_number><catch_line>Certification of results of preference primary. </catch_line><order_by>631</order_by><text>Upon completion of the official canvass of the results of the primary by the State Board of Elections, the Secretary of State shall certify to the state chairman of each political party participating in the presidential preference primary the following: <section prefix="1">The names of the candidates entitled to delegate votes under provisions of KRS 118.641; </section><section prefix="2">The total vote received by each; </section><section prefix="3">A declaration that the results of the presidential preference primary, in accordance with the division of votes reflected by the official canvass, shall be the official vote cast by each political party at its national convention, on the first ballot only, and shall be designated by KRS 118.551 to 118.651 as an automatic vote, expressing the will of the people of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="4">After the vote on the first ballot by the political party at its national convention, as required by this section, all responsibility under KRS 118.551 to 118.651 shall terminate and further balloting shall be the prerogative of the political parties as might be prescribed by the rules of such political parties. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>