<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.100</section_number><catch_line>Care, treatment, and rehabilitation of committed children -- Validated needs and risk assessment. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall arrange for a program of care, treatment, and rehabilitation of the children committed to it, which program shall be designed to provide for classification, segregation, and specialized treatment of children according to their respective problems, needs, and characteristics, as identified through a validated needs and risk assessment, and to provide a coordinated system of probation and parole services that includes a continuum of graduated sanctions. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall be responsible for the operation, management, and development of the existing state facilities for the custodial care and rehabilitation of children committed to the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet under provisions of this chapter. The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall further be responsible for the development of such facilities as are necessary to provide an adequate and modern program for the care, treatment, and rehabilitation of such children. </section><section prefix="3">The facilities and programs under the control of the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall be designed and operated in such a manner as to rehabilitate, train, develop, and educate the children to become good citizens and useful members of society. </section><section prefix="4">Suitable programs of vocational education and training shall be carried on in the facilities and programs, with the view of preparing the children for future self-support. </section><section prefix="5">The children in each facility and program shall be employed so far as practicable in labor incident to the maintenance and operation of the facility and program, and in suitable industries conducted by the facilities and programs as a part of the vocational training program. </section><section prefix="6">The superintendent or managing officer of each facility may use, for the maintenance of the facility, the products of farms, dairies, and other departments and industries of the facility or may sell or exchange such products for the benefit of the facility. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 31, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1997. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 8, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 13, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43504</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>