<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.035</section_number><catch_line>Corporate contributions to aid candidates for public office prohibited -- Aid to support a constitutional amendment or a public issue permitted. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No corporation organized or authorized to do business in this state or in another state shall, by itself or by or through an officer, agent, attorney, or employee, subscribe, give, procure or furnish, or afterwards reimburse or compensate in any way any person who has subscribed, given, procured, or furnished, any money, privilege, favor, or other thing of value to any political or quasi-political organization, or any officer or member thereof, to be used by such organization for the purpose of aiding, assisting, or advancing any candidate for public office in this state in any way whatever. </section><section prefix="2">No officer, agent, attorney, or employee of any corporation organized or authorized to do business in this state or in another state, or person acting for or representing any such corporation, shall disburse, distribute, pay out, or in any way handle any money, funds, or other thing of value that belongs to or has been or is being furnished by any such corporation or any officer, agent, attorney, or employee thereof to be used or employed in any way for the purpose of aiding, assisting, or advancing any candidate for public office in this state in any way whatever. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit a corporation from making contributions in support of a constitutional amendment, a public question which appears on the ballot, or position on an issue of public importance. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit a not-for-profit corporation, which does not derive a substantial portion of its revenue from for-profit corporations, from making independent expenditures. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 179. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27850</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>