<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.200</section_number><catch_line>Constables in counties of over 250,000 population. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In counties containing a population of over 250,000, for the performance of the duties of his office, each constable shall be exclusively compensated by a salary of nine thousand six hundred dollars ($9,600) per annum to be paid in equal monthly installments out of the county treasury. </section><section prefix="2">Each constable and deputy constable shall daily deliver or cause to be delivered to the recorder for the justice's district in which he holds office all moneys received or collected by him by virtue of his office, or the recorder may receive such moneys for the officer, and in either event the recorder shall daily issue to each officer a receipt for moneys received from or for him. Each recorder shall keep such records of each daily transaction, in such manner and form, and showing such information, as the fiscal court of the county requires. </section><section prefix="3">All moneys received or collected on account of or resulting from the performance of the duties or the exercise of the powers incident to the offices of constable and deputy constable shall be paid into the county treasury. </section><section prefix="4">Before the tenth day of each calendar month the recorder for each justice's district shall prepare a sworn statement showing the correct amounts of money received or collected during the next preceding calendar month from the administration of the offices of constable and deputy constable. The statement shall be in the form and shall disclose the information required by the fiscal court. Each monthly statement, and as many copies thereof as the fiscal court may require, shall be subscribed and sworn to by the recorder. On or before the tenth day of each calendar month each recorder shall deliver one (1) or more copies of the monthly statement to the fiscal court, or such person as the fiscal court designates, and at the same time deliver by certified check, payable to the order of the county treasurer, the total sum of money received by the recorder under the provisions of this section during the next preceding calendar month. During the interims between such monthly statements each recorder shall safely preserve the funds coming into his hands by virtue of this section in a bank designated by the justice of the peace, which bank shall duly execute a depository bond in a sufficient amount to cover monthly balances. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 180, secs. 8 and 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1083a-2, 1083a-6, 1083a-7, 1083a-9. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>