<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.330</section_number><catch_line>Articles of incorporation.   </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The articles of incorporation of a corporation formed under KRS 279.310 to 279.600 shall be entitled "Articles of Incorporation of .... Corporation" and the title may include the word "Cooperative." The articles shall satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.2-010 to 14A.2-150, recite that they are executed pursuant to KRS 279.310 to 279.600 and shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation. </section><section prefix="b">The address of its principal office. </section><section prefix="c">The names and addresses of the incorporators. </section><section prefix="d">The names and addresses of its trustees. </section><section prefix="e">A general description of the territory in which it proposes to operate. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a cooperative desires to issue nonvoting shares of stock, its articles of incorporation, in addition to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, shall state: <section prefix="a">The total number of such shares of stock which may be issued and the par value of each share; </section><section prefix="b">The fixed or maximum rate of dividends on the par value of such shares of stock, in either case not exceeding four percent (4%) per annum, and whether dividends shall be cumulative or noncumulative; </section><section prefix="c">Whether such shares of stock may be issued to members only or to members and nonmembers; </section><section prefix="d">The maximum number of such shares of stock which may be owned by any person; </section><section prefix="e">The terms and conditions on which such shares of stock may be transferred, redeemed or retired. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 84, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1973. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 3, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>