<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">B LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39B.040</section_number><catch_line>Mutual aid arrangements with special districts and public and private agencies. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local director of each local emergency management agency in the Commonwealth may develop or cause to be developed mutual aid arrangements with special districts and other public and private agencies within this Commonwealth for reciprocal disaster and emergency response aid and assistance in case of disaster or other emergency too great to be dealt with unassisted. The arrangements shall be consistent with the Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan, the local emergency operations plan, and the comprehensive emergency management program of the Commonwealth, and in time of emergency it shall be the duty of each local disaster and emergency services organizational unit, including each special district, and each public or private agency, to render assistance in accordance with the provisions of these mutual aid arrangements. </section><section prefix="2">The local director of each local emergency management agency in the Commonwealth may assist the division, acting on behalf of the Governor, in negotiation of reciprocal mutual aid agreements between the Commonwealth and other states, including foreign states or provinces, or their political subdivisions, and shall carry out the arrangements or any agreements relating to the local political subdivision. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21742</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>