<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.400</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 194A.400 and 194A.410. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text>As used in this section and KRS 194A.410: <section prefix="1">"Bioterrorism" means the intentional use, to cause or attempt to cause death, disease, or other biological malfunction in any living organism, of any of the following: <section prefix="a">Microorganism; </section><section prefix="b">Virus; </section><section prefix="c">Infectious substance; or </section><section prefix="d">Biological product that may be engineered as a result of biotechnology or any naturally occurring or bioengineered component of any microorganism, virus, infectious substance, or biological product; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department for Public Health within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department for Public Health within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="4">"Disaster location" means any geographical location where a bioterrorism attack, terrorist attack, catastrophic event, natural disaster, or emergency occurs; and </section><section prefix="5">"Emergency responder" means state or local law enforcement personnel, fire department personnel, corrections officers, and emergency medical personnel who may be deployed to a bioterrorism attack, terrorist attack, catastrophic event, natural disaster, or emergency. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 159, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 3, effective March 18, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6668</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>