<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.365</section_number><catch_line>Governing boards to have exclusive control of employment, tenure, and official relations of employees -- Payroll deduction of employee membership organization dues for KCTCS employees. </catch_line><order_by>365</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Anything in any statute of the Commonwealth to the contrary notwithstanding, the power over and control of appointments, qualifications, salaries, and compensation payable out of the State Treasury or otherwise, promotions, and official relations of all employees of Eastern Kentucky University, Western Kentucky University, Murray State University, Northern Kentucky University, and Morehead State University, as provided in KRS 164.350 and 164.360, and of Kentucky State University and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, shall be under the exclusive jurisdiction of the respective governing boards of each of the institutions named. </section><section prefix="2">The board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall develop personnel rules for the governing of its members, officers, agents, and employees by June 30, 1998. The board shall adopt interim policies to govern employees hired from July 1, 1997, until the permanent rules are adopted. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receipt of a written authorization from an employee of the Kentucky Community and  Technical College System, the board shall deduct dues from the employee's paycheck for employee membership organizations. Dues shall be deducted at a rate established by the organization, and shall be discontinued upon written notification by an employee to both the system and the employee organization. On a quarterly basis, the Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall provide to each employee membership organization an updated list that includes the names and home addresses of the employees who are having dues deducted from their paychecks for the purpose of maintaining membership in that organization. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 105, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4277</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>