<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="248" order_by="248">TOBACCO </unit></structure><section_number>248.717</section_number><catch_line>Creation and implementation of board's programs. </catch_line><order_by>717</order_by><text>Programs that shall be created by the board and overseen and implemented by the board or committees include: <section prefix="1">Programs that receive direct funding from the board: <section prefix="a">A Farm Market Development and Infrastructure Program to develop regional, integrated farm markets, and regional or community capital projects. The board may authorize moneys to the Department of Agriculture for each year of the biennium to be used for agriculture market development and infrastructure; and </section><section prefix="b">An Agricultural Entrepreneurship Program overseen by the board to support small farm agricultural diversification through technical assistance, business mentoring, and financial incentives. </section></section><section prefix="2">Programs that receive direct authorization for moneys from the agricultural development fund by the General Assembly may include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">An Environmental Stewardship Program to provide cost-share assistance to farmland owners for compliance with the state agriculture water quality plan and other environmental compliance requirements; and </section><section prefix="b">A Rural Water Line Extension Program to provide municipal water in areas of high agricultural activity or need. Priority shall be given to the tobacco-impacted communities most adversely affected by tobacco losses. The General Assembly shall authorize the issuance of bonds through the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority for this program. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board may create and fund other agricultural assistance programs in addition to those created under subsection (1) of this section, including an environmental cleanup program for cost-share assistance to tobacco warehouse operators for demolition and abatement of environmental hazards associated with tobacco warehouse structures. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 530, sec. 9, effective April 26, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> April 26, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11976</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>