<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.480</section_number><catch_line>Compliance with workers' compensation insurance and unemployment insurance laws required -- Foreign entity to obtain certificate of authority -- Penalty.   </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">No state contract for building, construction, reconstruction, renovation, demolition, or maintenance, or for any activity related to building, construction, reconstruction, renovation, demolition, or maintenance shall be awarded by any agency, department, or office of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to any person until that person assures, by affidavit, that all contractors and subcontractors employed, or that will be employed, under the provisions of the contract shall be in compliance with Kentucky requirements for workers' compensation insurance according to KRS Chapter 342 and unemployment insurance according to KRS Chapter 341. </section><section prefix="b">An agency, department, office, or political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall not award a state contract to a person that is a foreign entity unless that foreign entity, on the records of the Secretary of State, holds a certificate of authority or a statement of foreign qualification. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person who fails to comply with the requirements of subsection (1) of this section during the term of the state contract, upon such finding by a court of competent jurisdiction, shall be fined an amount not to exceed four thousand dollars ($4,000), or an amount equal to the sum of uninsured and unsatisfied claims brought under the provisions of KRS Chapter 342 and unemployment insurance claims for which no wages were reported as required by KRS Chapter 341, whichever is greater. </section><section prefix="3">The penalty imposed in subsection (2) of this section shall be enforced by the county attorney for the county in which the violation occurred. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 86, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40425</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>