<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.057</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties as to research on controlled substances. </catch_line><order_by>057</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall conduct research into all aspects of controlled substances as defined in KRS 218A.010 in coordination with the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. </section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may authorize persons engaged in research on the use and effects of dangerous substances to withhold the names and other identifying characteristics of persons who are subjects of such research. Persons who obtain this authorization may not be compelled in any state civil, criminal, administrative, legislative, or other proceeding to identify the subjects of research for which such authorization was obtained. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may authorize the possession and distribution of controlled dangerous substances by persons engaged in research. Persons who obtain this authorization shall be exempt from state prosecution for possession and distribution of dangerous substances to the extent authorized by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 305, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 250, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 200, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (9). -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8231</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>