<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.075</section_number><catch_line>Absentee ballots for voters with disabilities. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any qualified voter who has not been declared mentally disabled by a court of competent jurisdiction, and who, on account of age, disability or illness, is not able to appear at the polls on election day may vote in the following manner. At least seven (7) days prior to the date of the election and prior to the close of normal business hours, he shall present to the clerk by mail or in person his application for an absentee ballot containing a verified statement that his inability to appear is due to age, disability, or illness. The request for the application may be made by telephone, facsimile machine, mail, or in person. Within three (3) days of receipt of the request, the clerk shall mail to the voter an absentee ballot and envelopes, and the voter shall cast his vote in accordance with KRS 117.086. The ballot shall be returned by the voter to the county clerk by mail. </section><section prefix="2">Ballots furnished pursuant to the provisions of this section shall include the names of all candidates for which the voter is entitled to vote. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 4, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 405, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective March 19, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 470, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 56, effective July 1, 1982; and ch. 360, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 394, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 61 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>