<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.886</section_number><catch_line>Appointment and commissioning of peace officers for the Breaks Interstate Park Commission and the Tennessee Valley Authority. </catch_line><order_by>886</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 61.886 to 61.892: <section prefix="a">"Commission" means the Breaks Interstate Park Commission created in KRS 148.220; and </section><section prefix="b">"TVA" means the Tennessee Valley Authority. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Tennessee Valley Authority or the Breaks Interstate Park Commission may apply to the Governor for the appointment and commissioning of peace officers. Such persons shall be selected from a list submitted by TVA or the commission to the Governor. The Governor, upon such application being made and upon the payment to him or her of a one (1) time fee of five dollars ($5) for each officer to be appointed, shall appoint, for annually renewable terms of one (1) year, such persons or as many thereof as he or she deems proper to be such peace officers and shall give commissions to those appointed. Appointments and annual renewals of appointments under this subsection shall be subject to approval by the sheriff of each county in which the peace officer will normally operate, not including counties into which he or she may pursue and arrest persons under KRS 61.887. </section><section prefix="3">Such commissions shall be recorded in the office of Secretary of State. No person shall be eligible for appointment and commission as a TVA or commission peace officer unless he or she has established to the satisfaction of the Governor that, except for county residency requirements, he or she possesses the qualifications prescribed for nonelective peace officers by KRS 61.300 and, in addition, that he or she is a resident of Kentucky, or an adjoining state in which TVA or the commission operates, and has been for at least two (2) years at the time of his or her appointment. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39851</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>