<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.318</section_number><catch_line>Network of regional training centers for preschool and early childhood education established. </catch_line><order_by>318</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a network of regional training centers for preschool and early childhood education as specified in the 1987 state preschool grant application for Public Law 99-457. The purpose of the regional training centers shall be to provide peer to peer training, consultation, technical assistance, and materials to personnel from local school districts and other agencies operating programs for disabled and at-risk preschool children. </section><section prefix="2">The regional training centers shall receive federal funds from Public Law 99-457, Education of the Handicapped Act, Part B, and may receive state appropriations, gifts, and grants. No additional centers shall be established unless the existing centers receive at least the same level of funding as in the 1988 fiscal year. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate such regulations as may be needed in the administration of the regional training centers. In administering this section, the chief state school officer shall consult with the regional training centers and the districts and agencies served by this program. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>