<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="519" order_by="519">OBSTRUCTION OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>519.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Governmental function" means any activity which a public servant is legally authorized to undertake on behalf of the governmental unit which he serves; </section><section prefix="2">"Public record" includes all books, papers, maps, photographs, cards, tapes, discs, diskettes, recordings, magnetic or electronic images, optical images or other documentary materials regardless of physical form or characteristics, which are prepared, owned, used, in the possession of, received or retained by a public agency. "Public record" shall not include any records owned by a private person or corporation that are not related to functions, activities, programs, or operations funded by state or local authority; </section><section prefix="3">"Public servant" means: <section prefix="a">Any public officer or employee of the state or of any political subdivision thereof or of any governmental instrumentality within the state; </section><section prefix="b">Any person exercising the functions of any such public officer or employee; </section><section prefix="c">Any person participating as advisor, consultant or otherwise in performing a governmental function, but not including witnesses; or </section><section prefix="d">Any person elected, appointed or designated to become a public servant although not yet occupying that position; </section></section><section prefix="4">As used in this chapter, "benefit" means gain or advantage to the beneficiary or to a third person pursuant to the desire or consent of the beneficiary. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 163, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19858</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>