<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for manufactured homes manufactured under the federal act, any person who violates any provision of this chapter or any provision of a lawful order, rule, or regulation made under the provisions of this chapter, or who induces another to violate any provisions of this chapter or of any lawful order, rule, or regulation made thereunder, upon conviction thereof shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or confined in the county jail for not more than sixty (60) days, or both. Each day such violations exist shall, in the discretion of the courts, be considered as a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who, for manufactured homes manufactured under the federal act, violates any provision of the federal act or of KRS 227.550 to 227.660 or any regulation or final order issued thereunder shall be liable for a civil penalty not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each such violation. Each violation of a provision of KRS 227.550 to 227.660 or of the federal act or any regulation or order issued thereunder shall constitute a separate violation with respect to each manufactured home or mobile home or with respect to each failure or refusal to allow or perform an act required thereby, except that the maximum civil penalty may not exceed one million dollars ($1,000,000) for any related series of violations occurring within one (1) year from the date of the first violation. </section><section prefix="3">Any individual, or a director, officer, or agent of a corporation who knowingly and willfully violates the federal act or KRS 227.550 to 227.660 in a manner which threatens the health or safety of any purchaser shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisoned not more than one (1) year in the county jail, or both. </section><section prefix="4">Any person violating the provisions of KRS 227.702 to 227.750, the regulations issued thereunder, or any order issued thereunder, or who knowingly induces another, directly or indirectly, to violate the provisions of those sections, shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or imprisoned in the county jail for not more than thirty (30) days, or both. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 200, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 4, effective May 12, 1979. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 16, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 22, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><former-history> -- Repealed 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 23 -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 762b-24, 1376L-2. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 227.990</former-history-former-name><catchline-at-repeal>  Penalties. </catchline-at-repeal><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>