<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.200</section_number><catch_line>Contents of bill of sale. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The bill of sale provided for by KRS 186.190 shall contain the date, the purchaser's name and post office address, seller's name and post office address, and the information provided for in KRS 186.030 and shall be subscribed and sworn to before any officer authorized to administer an oath. </section><section prefix="2">No person for himself or his employee or agent or as an officer of any court, shall sell, trade, transfer or deliver any motor vehicle without at the same time making a bill of sale in quadruplicate and delivering the original and two (2) copies thereof to the county clerk. The county clerk shall retain one (1) copy of the bill of sale and shall deliver the original copy to the purchaser together with the registration receipt or transfer of registration, and attach the other copy to the Revenue Cabinet's copy of the registration receipt of transfer of registration. No person shall sign a bill of sale until the purchaser's name is shown thereon. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 14, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 11, effective June 19, 1976. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 13, effective January 1, 1963. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-14. </history><metadata><effective> June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6023</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>