<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.795</section_number><catch_line>Determinations to be made in reviewing projects -- Request for Legislative Research Commission to seek injunction. </catch_line><order_by>795</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In reviewing a project, the committee shall determine whether the project has met all the relevant requirements of: <section prefix="a">KRS 45.750 to 45.816; </section><section prefix="b">KRS 56.800 to 56.823; and </section><section prefix="c">Any other statutes relating to the committee's oversight of: <section prefix="1">Capital projects; </section><section prefix="2">The allotment and expenditure of funds from the emergency repair, maintenance, and replacement account and the capital construction and equipment purchase contingency account; </section><section prefix="3">The state's acquisition of capital assets, including the lease of real property; </section><section prefix="4">The issuance of bonds by the Commonwealth, and the related individual projects; and </section><section prefix="5">Bonds issued by or on behalf of local school districts. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">If the committee determines that any of the requirements in subsection (1) of this section have not been met, the committee may, by majority vote, request that the Legislative Research Commission file a civil court proceeding to seek an injunction to prohibit further action on the capital project, the acquisition of the capital asset, the initiation or modification of the lease of real property, the bond issue, or the allotment or expenditure of funds from the capital construction emergency or contingency accounts. </section><section prefix="3">The committee may take action requesting the Legislative Research Commission to seek an injunction before, during, or after its compliance with the provisions of KRS 45.800(2) or KRS 45.810(3), where applicable. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 1, (5) at 655. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22313</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>