<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">B KENTUCKY PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175B.020</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of state authority -- Participation as a developing or issuing authority -- Oversight function -- Legislative ratification required for certain actions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state authority's primary purpose shall be to facilitate the construction, financing, operation, and oversight of projects by entering into bi-state agreements and by creating bi-state authorities and project authorities. To accomplish these purposes, the state authority shall have the power and duty to: <section prefix="a">Take the following actions relating to a bi-state authority authorized pursuant to KRS 175B.030: <section prefix="1">To enter into a bi-state agreement; </section><section prefix="2">To review and approve project financing plans and development agreements; and </section><section prefix="3">To monitor agreements entered into by bi-state authorities; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Take the following actions relating to a project authority authorized pursuant to KRS 175B.035: <section prefix="1">To request establishment of a project authority; </section><section prefix="2">To review and approve project financing plans and development agreements; </section><section prefix="3">To monitor activities of project authorities; and </section><section prefix="4">To enter into an agreement with the project authority. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The state authority, when authorized pursuant to subsection (4) of this section, may participate as a developing or issuing authority, or both, in the development, construction, or financing of a project by a bi-state or project authority, if necessary. If the state authority participates as a developing or issuing authority, the state authority shall have the powers and duties established in KRS 175B.025 as they apply to that project. </section><section prefix="3">The state authority, as a function of its oversight of any other authority created pursuant to this chapter, shall report before the first issuance of bonds and no less than semiannually thereafter to the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee and to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue of the Legislative Research Commission, on any projects currently proposed or under development by each authority. Current and proposed levels of bonding for each project shall be reviewed by the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee in accordance with KRS 45.794 before the bonds shall be issued. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the following actions shall not take effect until ratified by the General Assembly: <section prefix="1">The creation of a bi-state authority; </section><section prefix="2">The creation of a project authority; </section><section prefix="3">The modification or amendment of the scope of any project; and </section><section prefix="4">The development of any project undertaken entirely by the state authority. </section></section><section prefix="b">If any action described in paragraph (a) of this subsection is not ratified by the General Assembly, the creation, approval, or modification shall be considered void. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 78, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5137</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>