<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-109</section_number><catch_line>Scope. </catch_line><order_by>9-109</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, this article applies to: <section prefix="a">A transaction, regardless of its form, that creates a security interest in personal property or fixtures by contract; </section><section prefix="b">An agricultural lien; </section><section prefix="c">A sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes; </section><section prefix="d">A consignment; </section><section prefix="e">A security interest arising under KRS 355.2-401, 355.2-505, 355.2-711(3), or 355.2A-508(5), as provided in KRS 355.9-110; and </section><section prefix="f">A security interest arising under KRS 355.4-210 or 355.5-118. </section></section><section prefix="2">The application of this article to a security interest in a secured obligation is not affected by the fact that the obligation is itself secured by a transaction or interest to which this article does not apply. </section><section prefix="3">This article does not apply to the extent that: <section prefix="a">A statute, regulation, or treaty of the United States preempts this article; </section><section prefix="b">Another statute of this Commonwealth expressly governs the creation, perfection, priority, or enforcement of a security interest created by this Commonwealth or a governmental unit of this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">A statute of another state, a foreign country, or a governmental unit of another state or a foreign country, other than a statute generally applicable to security interests, expressly governs creation, perfection, priority, or enforcement of a security interest created by the state, country, or governmental unit; or </section><section prefix="d">The rights of a transferee beneficiary or nominated person under a letter of credit are independent and superior under KRS 355.5-114. </section></section><section prefix="4">This article does not apply to: <section prefix="a">A landlord’s lien, other than an agricultural lien; </section><section prefix="b">A lien, other than an agricultural lien, given by statute or other rule of law for services or materials, but KRS 355.9-333 applies with respect to priority of the lien; </section><section prefix="c">An assignment of a claim for wages, salary, or other compensation of an employee, or for workers' compensation benefits payable to an individual; </section><section prefix="d">A sale of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes as part of a sale of the business out of which they arose; </section><section prefix="e">An assignment of accounts, chattel paper, payment intangibles, or promissory notes which is for the purpose of collection only; </section><section prefix="f">An assignment of a right to payment under a contract to an assignee that is also obligated to perform under the contract; </section><section prefix="g">An assignment of a single account, payment intangible, or promissory note to an assignee in full or partial satisfaction of a preexisting indebtedness; </section><section prefix="h">A transfer of an interest in or an assignment of a claim under a policy of insurance, other than an assignment by or to a health-care provider of a health-care-insurance receivable and any subsequent assignment of the right to payment, but KRS 355.9-315 and 355.9-322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds; </section><section prefix="i">An assignment of a right represented by a judgment, other than a judgment taken on a right to payment that was collateral; </section><section prefix="j">A right of recoupment or set-off, but: <section prefix="1">KRS 355.9-340 applies with respect to the effectiveness of rights of recoupment or set-off against deposit accounts; and </section><section prefix="2">KRS 355.9-404 applies with respect to defenses or claims of an account debtor; </section></section><section prefix="k">The creation or transfer of an interest in or lien on real property, including a lease or rents thereunder, except to the extent that provision is made for: <section prefix="1">Liens on real property in KRS 355.9-203 and 355.9-308; </section><section prefix="2">Fixtures in KRS 355.9-334; </section><section prefix="3">Fixture filings in KRS 355.9-501, 355.9-502, 355.9-512, 355.9-516, and 355.9-519; and </section><section prefix="4">Security agreements covering personal and real property in KRS 355.9-604; </section></section><section prefix="l">An assignment of a claim arising in tort, other than a commercial tort claim, but KRS 355.9-315 and 355.9-322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds; </section><section prefix="m">An assignment of a deposit account in a consumer transaction, but KRS 355.9-315 and 355.9-322 apply with respect to proceeds and priorities in proceeds; </section><section prefix="n">A claim or right to receive compensation for injuries or sickness as described in 26 U.S.C. sec. 104(a)(1) or (2), as amended from time to time; </section><section prefix="o">A claim or right to receive benefits under a special needs trust as described in 42 U.S.C. sec. 1396p(d)(4), as amended from time to time; </section><section prefix="p">A right to receive money under a structured settlement as defined by KRS 454.430; or </section><section prefix="q">A public-finance transaction or a transfer by a government or governmental unit. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective April 2, 2002. -- Repealed and reenacted 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 3, effective July 1, 2001. -- Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 29, effective July 1, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 478, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-109, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> April 2, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33736</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>