<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152">ENERGY DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>152.720</section_number><catch_line>Strategy for production of transportation fuels and synthetic natural gas from fossil energy resources and biomass resources.   </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text>To ensure that Kentucky will lead the states in securing the energy independence of the United States and will consequently benefit from economic growth and stabilization of the Commonwealth's coal industry and agriculture, the Department for Energy Development and Independence shall develop and implement a strategy for production of alternative transportation fuels and synthetic natural gas from fossil energy resources and biomass resources. The strategy shall address: <section prefix="1">Technologies available or in use for producing alternative transportation fuels and synthetic natural gas from fossil energy resources and biomass resources and the relative advantages of these in terms of process efficiencies, environmental performance, and marketable products, including chemicals, industrial feedstocks, and electricity; </section><section prefix="2">Research, demonstration, and commercial-scale construction and operation of one (1) or more technologies, and follow-up expansion; </section><section prefix="3">The essential nature of efficient cooperation, coordination, and synergy between the efforts of the Department for Energy Development and Independence and those of Kentucky's public and private colleges and universities in order to maximize Kentucky's opportunities to access federal funds and to receive research grants and awards from federal and other sources to fund the development of clean coal technology, coal-to-liquid-fuel conversion, synthetic natural gas, alternative transportation fuels, and biomass resources; </section><section prefix="4">The identification of federal funds available for research, development, construction, and operation of alternative transportation fuels or synthetic natural gas plants at laboratory, demonstration, and commercial scale; </section><section prefix="5">Establishment of a major federal energy research laboratory in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="6">Industry participation, both by single firms and by consortia, in research, development, construction, and operation of alternative transportation fuels or synthetic natural gas plants; </section><section prefix="7">Establishment or expansion of Kentucky state government incentives for development, construction, or operation of alternative transportation fuels and synthetic natural gas production facilities, including but not limited to financial incentives, tax incentives, mandating or providing incentives for use of alternative transportation fuels and synthetic natural gas by state government, school districts, or utilities, authority to issue bonds, and acquisition and preliminary environmental assessment of industrial sites; and </section><section prefix="8">Development of incentives to encourage energy conservation and renewable fuel and energy use and deployment of renewable energy, including solar power, wind power, hydropower, and other sources. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 188, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 39, effective August 30, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42405</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>