<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.270Examination</section_number><catch_line>for certified public accountant -- Fees -- Reciprocity -- Cancellation of examination scores for failure to apply for license.   </catch_line><order_by>270Examination</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Examinations provided for in this chapter shall be authorized by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board may by administrative regulation adopt standards and fees governing the application and all examination policies and procedures. </section><section prefix="3">The board may accept examination results from other states if: <section prefix="a">It is established that the examination is the same or substantially similar to the one adopted by the board; and </section><section prefix="b">The candidate has met the prerequisite examination requirements of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="4">An examination candidate who passes all sections of the examination shall apply for a license within five (5) years from the date the candidate successfully completed the examination. Failure to apply for a license prior to the expiration of the five (5) year period shall result in cancellation of the examination scores. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 6. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 1. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 3(5). </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44595</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>