<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.375</section_number><catch_line>On-site sewage disposal manuals -- Fees -- Training of personnel. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall solicit and collect technical information relating to improved methods for construction, use, and rehabilitation of septic tanks and drain fields and use of alternative on-site sewage disposal systems and technologies.  </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall compile such information in manual form so as to identify common on-site sewage disposal problems and a range of alternative solutions to such problems.  Such manuals shall be made available upon request to local boards of health, local departments of health, other agencies, and interested persons.  </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall further update the information contained in the manual on an annual basis or as necessary and disseminate the updated information to such local boards of health, local departments of health, other agencies, and interested persons.  </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall develop a nontechnical manual for use by the homeowner to be disseminated upon request to interested agencies and persons containing information on the proper operation, use and maintenance of septic tanks and drain fields and other on-site sewage disposal systems.  </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may establish by regulation a fee or schedule of fees for on-site sewage disposal manuals based on the cost of publication and dissemination of such manuals.  </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall provide training and continuing education programs to field personnel relating to on-site sewage disposal.  </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted as KRS 211.375, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><former-codification> KRS 318.330 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8391</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>