<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="201" order_by="201">JEFFERSON COUNTY CHILDREN'S HOME </unit></structure><section_number>201.110</section_number><catch_line>Duration of commitment -- Discharge -- Parole. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All children received into the home's care by commitment of any court or officer having jurisdiction shall remain under the home's care for the period of their commitment, not to exceed their minority, unless sooner paroled or discharged. </section><section prefix="2">The board may discharge any child received under KRS 201.080(1) at any time it deems it for the best interest of the child or the other children under the home's care, or for the best interests of the home. The discharge may be absolute, conditional, temporary or on parole, in the discretion of the board. Before discharge notice must be given to the committing court and to such other parties as required in KRS Chapter 208. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall discharge any child accepted for care under KRS 201.080(2) on written request of the parent, or other party as specified in said section, making the application for care, within five (5) calendar days, unless during said period the board shall have filed a petition for commitment under KRS 201.100 or KRS Chapter 620, 630, or 645 and such commitment, or a temporary order of custody under KRS Chapter 620, 630, or 645, shall have been ordered by the court. </section><section prefix="4">The board may discharge any child accepted for care under KRS 201.080(2) at any time it deems it for the best interest of the child or the other children under the home's care or for the best interests of the home. Before discharge notice must be given to the committing court or board. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 191, effective July 1, 1987. --Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 181, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1964. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 938b-9. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1987</effective><note> This section was amended by 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 149, which was to have become effective July 1, 1982. Thereafter, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284 changed the effective date of that act to July 15, 1984. Then, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 184 repealed both 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, and 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7351</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>