<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.852</section_number><catch_line>School food service director or menu planner -- Credentials and certificates -- Continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>852</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each district shall appoint a food service director who is responsible for the management and oversight of the food service program in the district, except two </section><section prefix="2">or more contiguous districts may form one (1) "school food service area" and a </section>school food service director shall be jointly selected by the participating school superintendents to oversee the school food service area. (2) (a) Any person serving as a school food service director or person otherwise responsible for menu planning in each school district on June 20, 2005, shall be credentialed as a "school food service and nutrition specialist" or certified by a Level 2 certificate issued by the American School Food Service Association within three (3) years after June 20, 2005. No school district shall be required to have more than one (1) person with a credential or certificate under this section. (b) After June 20, 2005, a person appointed to serve as school food service director or the person designated for menu planning who does not hold the "school food service and nutrition specialist" credential or the Level 2 certificate issued by the American School Food Service Association shall obtain the appropriate credential within three (3) years of his or her appointment or designation. No school district shall be required to have more than one (1) person with a credential or certificate under this section. (c) Eight (8) clock hours of the required continuing education for maintaining the appropriate credential or certificate under this subsection shall be directly related to applied nutrition and healthy meal planning and preparation. <section prefix="3">School cafeteria managers shall annually receive at least two (2) hours of continuing education in applied nutrition and healthy meal planning and preparation. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>