<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.355</section_number><catch_line>Creation of authority. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any local government, the county or independent school district within the county, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky may enter into an interlocal cooperation agreement pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300 for the purpose of establishing a land bank authority pursuant to KRS 65.350 to 65.375. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall be a public body corporate and politic with the power to sue and be sued, issue deeds in its name, and any other powers necessary and convenient to carry out these powers or that may be granted to the authority by the parties. </section><section prefix="3">The authority shall be established to acquire the tax delinquent properties of the parties in order to foster the public purpose of returning land that is in a non-revenue generating, non-tax producing status to effective utilization in order to provide housing, new industry, and jobs for the citizens of the county. The authority shall have the powers provided in KRS 65.370 and 65.375 and in the interlocal cooperation agreement. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><former-codification> KRS 91.805. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>