<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.445</section_number><catch_line>Local assessment of school safety and school discipline -- District assessment -- Local plans. </catch_line><order_by>445</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each local school shall begin an assessment of school safety and student discipline during the 1998-1999 school year including a review of the following: <section prefix="a">Reports of school incidents relating to disruptive behaviors; </section><section prefix="b">The school's behavior and discipline codes for clarity and appropriate notice to students and parents; </section><section prefix="c">The school's hierarchy of responses to discipline problems and actual disciplinary outcomes; </section><section prefix="d">Training needs for instructional staff in classroom management, student learning styles, and other specialized training to enhance teachers' capacity to engage students and minimize disruptive behavior; </section><section prefix="e">The array of school services to students at risk of academic failure, dropping out, or truancy; </section><section prefix="f">The engagement of parents at the earliest stages of problem behavior; </section><section prefix="g">Training needs for students in the development of core values and qualities of good character, anger reduction, conflict resolution, peer mediation, and other necessary skills; </section><section prefix="h">Training needs of parents; </section><section prefix="i">Existing school council policies relating to student discipline and student information; </section><section prefix="j">The school's physical environment; </section><section prefix="k">The school's student supervision plan; </section><section prefix="l">Existing components of the school improvement plan or consolidated plan that focus on school safety and at-risk students, and the effectiveness of the components; and </section><section prefix="m">Other data deemed relevant by the school council or school administration. </section></section> A school that does not complete an assessment process shall not be eligible for funds under the state school safety grant program in 1999-2000 and subsequent years. <section prefix="2">By May 15, 1999, each local school district shall complete a district-level assessment of district-level data, resources, policies and procedures, and district-wide needs as identified from the individual school assessment process. The district shall engage local community agencies including law enforcement and the courts in the assessment process. </section><section prefix="3">As a result of the district assessment and analysis of data, resources, and needs, each board of education shall adopt a plan for immediate and long-term strategies to address school safety and discipline. The development of the plan shall involve at least one (1) representative from each school in the district as well as representatives from the community as a whole, including representatives from the local juvenile delinquency prevention council if a council exists in that community. The process of planning shall be determined locally depending to a large extent on the size and characteristics of the district. </section><section prefix="4">The district plan under subsection (3) of this section shall be the basis for any request for funds under the state school safety grant program for 1999-2000 and subsequent years. The district plan shall include the local code of acceptable behavior and discipline as required under KRS 158.148 and a description of instructional placement options for threatening or violent students. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 6, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3520</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>