<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.495</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers of electrical inspectors -- Sanctions for misconduct. </catch_line><order_by>495</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Electrical inspectors shall have the authority to take immediate action to prevent further electrical work at any inspection site where, in the judgment of the electrical inspector, imminent danger to life or property exists. Actions the electrical inspector may take to address this danger are the following: <section prefix="a">Stop-work order regarding any electrical work at the inspection site; or </section><section prefix="b">Recommendations of fines or other penalties as described in KRS 227.500. </section></section><section prefix="2">The findings of the electrical inspector under subsection (1) of this section shall be presumed to be correct until the city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government, the department, or the party affected by the findings demonstrates that it is more likely than not that the electrical inspector was incorrect in his or her findings. </section><section prefix="3">The actions of an electrical inspector under this section are subject to misconduct investigation by the commissioner under KRS 227.492, and the inspector is subject to any appropriate criminal or civil penalty due to misconduct or violation of any provision of KRS 227.200 to 227.400 or 227.450 to 227.500. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 409, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 6, provides that the Act, which created this section, shall be known and may be cited as "Isaac's Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10674</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>