<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.207</section_number><catch_line>Text and map of zoning regulations -- Notice and publication. </catch_line><order_by>207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before a city or county enacts zoning regulations, as authorized by KRS 100.201, the planning commission shall prepare the text and map of all zoning regulations and shall hold at least one (1) public hearing. Notice of the public hearing shall be given in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="2">Subsequent to the public hearing, the planning commission shall submit, along with their recommendation, a copy of the approved zoning regulation text and map to the various legislative bodies and fiscal courts for adoption. A majority of the entire legislative body or fiscal court shall be required for passage of an ordinance adopting these regulations. Notwithstanding publication requirements, the ordinance by which these regulations are originally adopted may be published by stating the title and general description of the regulations and referring to the place within the unit where a copy of the complete ordinance may be examined without charge. </section><section prefix="3">The procedure for amending the zoning regulation text and map shall be as set forth in KRS 100.211. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 31. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26722</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>