<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text>Any person who shall violate or aid in the violation of any of the provisions of KRS 321.175, 321.181, 321.185, 321.190, 321.193, 321.195, 321.200, 321.201, 321.205, 321.207, 321.211, 321.221, 321.230, 321.235, 321.237, 321.240, 321.320, 321.351, 321.360, 321.441, and 321.443 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or sentenced to jail for not less than ten (10) nor more than ninety (90) days, or both so fined and imprisoned in the discretion of the jury. </text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 283, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 22, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 26. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 28. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 63b-11, 63b-13. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 321.990:</former-history-former-name><lrc-note> (7/14/92).  This statute was created in 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, which contains the enrolled text of Senate Bill 250. A committee substitute for this bill was adopted by the House with a floor amendment, and the Senate subsequently concurred in this action by the House; this amended substitute thus became the enrolled version of the bill. In drafting the House Committee Substitute, the original Section 10 of the bill was deleted in its entirety, but internal section references within the bill were not renumbered to reflect this deletion. Therefore, in codifying this statute, the internal section reference within Acts ch. 299, sec. 22, has been changed pursuant to KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31416</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>