<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.7-103</section_number><catch_line>Relation of article to treaty or statute.   </catch_line><order_by>7-103</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This article is subject to any treaty or statute of the United States or a regulatory statute of this state to the extent the treaty, statute, or regulatory statute is applicable. </section><section prefix="2">This article does not repeal or modify any law prescribing the form or contents of a document of title or the services or facilities to be afforded by a bailee, or otherwise regulating a bailee’s businesses in respects not specifically treated in this article. However, violation of these laws does not affect the status of a document of title that otherwise complies with the definition of a document of title. </section><section prefix="3">This article modifies, limits, and supersedes the federal Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act, 15 U.S.C. secs. 7001 et seq., but does not modify, limit, or supersede Section 101(c) of that Act, 15 U.S.C. sec. 7001(c), or authorize electronic delivery of any of the notices described in Section 103(b) of that Act, 15 U.S.C. sec. 7003(b). </section><section prefix="4">To the extent there is a conflict between the Uniform Electronic Transactions Act and this article, this article governs. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7-103, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40604</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>