<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-140</section_number><catch_line>Standard provisions, in general. </catch_line><order_by>14-140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Insurance contracts shall contain such standard or uniform provisions as are required by the applicable provisions of this code pertaining to contracts of particular kinds of insurance. The commissioner may waive the required use of a particular provision in a particular insurance policy form if: <section prefix="a">The commissioner finds such provision unnecessary for or unrelated to the protection of the insured and inconsistent with the purposes of the policy, and </section><section prefix="b">The policy is otherwise approved by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">No policy shall contain any provision inconsistent with or contradictory to any standard or uniform provision used or required to be used, but the commissioner may approve any substitute provision which is, in his or her opinion, not less favorable in any particular to the insured or beneficiary than the provisions otherwise required. </section><section prefix="3">In lieu of the provisions required by this code for contracts for particular kinds of insurance, substantially similar provisions required by the law of the domicile of a foreign or alien insurer may be used when approved by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="4">A policy issued by a domestic insurer for delivery in another jurisdiction may contain any provision required or permitted by the laws of such jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1153, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 14, sec. 14, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>