<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.285</section_number><catch_line>Revocation of subdivision plat. </catch_line><order_by>285</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application of all persons owning land comprising a subdivision, the planning commission may revoke the approval of a subdivision plat, including all dedications of public facilities, easements and rights-of-way. </section><section prefix="2">Before any plat shall be revoked, all owners shall, as part of their application for revocation, state under oath that no person has purchased a lot shown on the plat. </section><section prefix="3">A revocation shall become effective only upon: <section prefix="a">A notation on the margin of the recorded plat stating that such plat has been revoked and the date of such vote of revocation; such notation shall be signed by the chairman, secretary, or other duly authorized officer of the commission; and </section><section prefix="b">A written approval of such revocation filed with the commission, duly signed by each entity to which an offer of dedication of any public or private facility, easement or right-of-way was made on the plat. </section></section><section prefix="4">The remedy provided in this section is in addition to all other remedies provided by law and shall not impair the right of the commission or any interested party from filing an action in Circuit Court for such relief as may be appropriate. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>