<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1413</section_number><catch_line>Trafficking in controlled substance in second degree -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>1413</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of trafficking in a controlled substance in the second degree when: <section prefix="a">He or she knowingly and unlawfully traffics in: <section prefix="1">Ten (10) or more dosage units of a controlled substance classified in Schedules I and II that is not a narcotic drug; or specified in KRS 218A.1412, and which is not a synthetic drug, salvia, or marijuana; or </section><section prefix="2">Twenty (20) or more dosage units of a controlled substance classified in Schedule III; </section></section><section prefix="b">He or she knowingly and unlawfully prescribes, distributes, supplies, or sells an anabolic steroid for: <section prefix="1">Enhancing human performance in an exercise, sport, or game; or </section><section prefix="2">Hormonal manipulation intended to increase muscle mass, strength, or weight in the human species without a medical necessity; or </section></section><section prefix="c">He or she knowingly and unlawfully traffics in any quantity of a controlled substance specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection in an amount less than the amounts specified in that paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, any person who violates the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be guilty of a Class D felony for the first offense and a Class C felony for a second or subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates the provisions of subsection (1)(c) of this section shall be guilty of: <section prefix="1">A Class D felony for the first offense, except that KRS Chapter 532 to the contrary notwithstanding, the maximum sentence to be imposed shall be no greater than three (3) years; and </section><section prefix="2">A Class D felony for a second offense or subsequent offense. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 9, effective April 11, 2012; and ch. 156, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 10, effective June 8, 2011; and ch. 45, sec. 9, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 10, effective April 13, 2010; and ch. 160, sec. 10, effective April 26, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 64, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 108 and 156, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40032</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>