<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.640</section_number><catch_line>Employment of inspectors -- Authority of inspectors -- Access by the department -- Licensees to keep records. </catch_line><order_by>640</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commissioner may employ inspectors for the purpose of enforcing the provisions of the egg marketing law. These inspectors may examine any eggs offered or exposed for sale for human consumption at the times and places and in a manner as the Commissioner may direct. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall have free access, at all reasonable hours when the business is open to the general public, to any establishment, premises, or building where eggs are processed, stored, or offered for sale, and to any vehicle used to transport or hold eggs, for the purpose of inspecting the establishment, premises, building, or vehicle or the eggs to determine compliance with the provisions of the Kentucky egg marketing law. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall have free access at all reasonable hours when the business is open to the general public, to any restaurant kitchen, hotel kitchen, or kitchen of any other public eating place, including schools, hospitals, nursing homes, or other similar institutions, to determine compliance with the provisions of the Kentucky egg marketing law. If the inspector determines that inspected eggs fail to comply with the Kentucky egg marketing law or standards as established by USDA, the inspector shall take the necessary action and issue an advisory on proper procedures. </section><section prefix="4">All licensees shall keep a record of all eggs handled during the license year, and any other records the department shall require. These records shall be available for examination by authorized agents of the department. </section><section prefix="5">An inspector may, for the purpose of enforcing the Kentucky egg marketing law, break any form of sealing on any case or retail container. If a broken seal necessitates the repacking of the cases or containers, the original packer shall absorb all expenses involved. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 11, effective January 1, 1957. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>