<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142">MISCELLANEOUS TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>142.050</section_number><catch_line>Real estate transfer tax -- Collection on recording -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Deed" means any document, instrument, or writing other than a will and other than a lease or easement, regardless of where made, executed, or delivered, by which any real property in Kentucky, or any interest therein, is conveyed, vested, granted, bargained, sold, transferred, or assigned. </section><section prefix="b">"Value" means: <section prefix="1">In the case of any deed not a gift, the amount of the full actual consideration therefor, paid or to be paid, including the amount of any lien or liens thereon; and </section><section prefix="2">In the case of a gift, or any deed with nominal consideration or without stated consideration, the estimated price the property would bring in an open market and under the then prevailing market conditions in a sale between a willing seller and a willing buyer, both conversant with the property and with prevailing general price levels. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A tax upon the grantor named in the deed shall be imposed at the rate of fifty cents ($0.50) for each $500 of value or fraction thereof, which value is declared in the deed upon the privilege of transferring title to real property. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">If any deed evidencing a transfer of title subject to the tax herein imposed is offered for recordation, the county clerk shall ascertain and compute the amount of the tax due thereon and shall collect the amount as prerequisite to acceptance of the deed for recordation. </section><section prefix="b">The amount of tax shall be computed on the basis of the value of the transferred property as set forth in the deed. </section><section prefix="c">The tax required to be levied by this section shall be collected only once on each transaction and in the county in which the deed is required to be recorded by KRS 382.110(1). </section></section><section prefix="4">The county clerk shall collect the amount due and certify the date of payment and the amount of collection on the deed. The county clerk shall retain five percent (5%) as his fee for collection and remit the balance every three (3) months to the county treasurer, who shall deposit the money in the county general fund. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Revenue may prescribe regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Any county clerk who willfully shall record any deed upon which a tax is imposed by this section without collecting the proper amount of tax and certifying the date and amount of collection on the deed as required by this section based on the declared value indicated in the affidavit appended to the deed shall, upon conviction, be fined $50 for each offense. </section><section prefix="7">The tax imposed by this section shall not apply to a transfer of title: <section prefix="a">Recorded prior to March 27, 1968; </section><section prefix="b">To, in the event of a deed of gift or deed with nominal consideration, or from the United States of America, this state, any city or county within this state, or any instrumentality, agency, or subdivision hereof; </section><section prefix="c">Solely in order to provide or release security for a debt or obligation; </section><section prefix="d">Which confirms or corrects a deed previously recorded; </section><section prefix="e">Between husband and wife, or between former spouses as part of a divorce proceeding; </section><section prefix="f">On sale for delinquent taxes or assessments; </section><section prefix="g">On partition; </section><section prefix="h">Pursuant to: <section prefix="1">Merger or consolidation between and among corporations, partnerships, limited partnerships, or limited liability companies; or </section><section prefix="2">Any conversion of a partnership, limited partnership, corporation, or limited liability company into a partnership, limited partnership, corporation, or limited liability company; </section></section><section prefix="i">Between a subsidiary corporation and its parent corporation for no consideration, nominal consideration, or in sole consideration of the cancellation or surrender of either corporation's stock; </section><section prefix="j"><section prefix="1">Under a foreclosure proceeding; or </section><section prefix="2">Pursuant to a voluntary surrender under a mortgage in lieu of a foreclosure proceeding; </section></section><section prefix="k">Between a person and a corporation, partnership, limited partnership or limited liability company in an amount equal to the portion of the value of the real property transferred that represents the proportionate interest of the transferor of the property in the entity to which the property was transferred, if the transfer was for nominal consideration; </section><section prefix="l">Between parent and child or grandparent and grandchild, with only nominal consideration therefor; </section><section prefix="m">By a corporation, partnership, limited partnership, or limited liability company to a person as owner or shareholder of the entity, upon dissolution of the entity, in an amount equal to the portion of the value of the real property transferred that represents the proportionate interest of the person to whom the property was transferred, if the transfer was for nominal consideration; </section><section prefix="n">Between a trustee and a successor trustee; and </section><section prefix="o">Between a limited liability company and any of its members. </section></section><section prefix="8">The tax imposed by subsection (2) of this section shall not apply to transfers to a trustee, to be held in trust, or from a trustee to a beneficiary of the trust if: <section prefix="a">The grantor is the sole beneficiary of the trust; </section><section prefix="b">The grantor is a beneficiary of the trust and a direct transfer from the grantor of the trust to all other individual beneficiaries of the trust would have qualified for an exemption from the tax pursuant to one (1) of the provisions of subsection (7) of this section; or </section><section prefix="c">A direct transfer from the grantor of the trust to all other individual beneficiaries of the trust would have qualified for an exemption from the tax pursuant to one (1) of the provisions of subsection (7) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="9">As used in this section, "trust" shall have the same definition as contained in KRS 386B.1-010. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 97, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 204, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 521, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective February 29, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Pt. III, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 182, secs. 1 to 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), during codification a manifest clerical or typographical error occurring in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 204(7)(h)2. has been corrected. It is clear from the context of the Act that a comma should appear after the words "limited partnership" and before the word "corporation." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43160</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>