<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159">COMPULSORY ATTENDANCE </unit></structure><section_number>159.170</section_number><catch_line>Withdrawals and transfers -- Teachers to investigate and report -- Collection and dissemination of student records. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever any child of compulsory school age withdraws from school, the teacher of the child shall ascertain the reason. The fact of the withdrawal and the reason for it shall be immediately transmitted by the teacher to the superintendent of schools of the district in which the school is located. If the child has withdrawn because of change of residence, the next residence shall be ascertained and included in the report. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Department of Education shall ensure that the student information system facilitates the collection of student data and the transfer of education records among schools and local districts. </section><section prefix="3">A school district shall notify the Kentucky Department of Education when a new student enrolls in a school in the district. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Department of Education, upon notification of a student's enrollment in a school, shall forward within ten (10) working days all records regarding the student collected under this section to the receiving district. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 414, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4434-16. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3645</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>