<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.7524</section_number><catch_line>Statement to assist out-of-state court in determining whether orderissued under KRS 403.715 to 403.785 is entitled to full faith and credit.  </catch_line><order_by>7524</order_by><text>(1)In order to assist a court of another state in determining whether an orderissued under KRS 403.715 to 403.785 is entitled to full faith and creditpursuant to 18 U.S.C. sec. 2265:(a)All domestic violence orders shall include a statement certifying that theissuing court had jurisdiction over the parties and the matter, and thatreasonable notice and opportunity to be heard has been given to theperson against whom the order is sought sufficient to protect that person'sright to due process; and(b)All emergency protective orders shall include a statement certifying thatnotice and opportunity to be heard has been provided within the timerequired by state law, and in any event within a reasonable time after theorder is issued, sufficient to protect the respondent's due process rights.(2)The Administrative Office of the Courts shall prescribe the form to be used forthe purposes of this section.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 11, effective January1, 2016. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96; modified 1/7/98).  The KRSreferences contained in subsections (1) and (3) of this statute have beencodified as those references were enacted in 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99 (Senate Bill105), sec. 5, but it appears that these statute references may be erroneous.Subsection (1) contained a reference to Section 1 of the Act (KRS 403.725), butfrom context it appears that Section 4 of the Act (KRS 403.7521) may havebeen intended; subsection (3) contained a reference to Section 4 of the Act(KRS 403.7521), but from context it appears that Section 2 of the Act (KRS403.750) may have been intended. (Modified to correct a mistaken subsectionreference.)</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>