<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.355</section_number><catch_line>Election reports to be made by the precinct election sheriff and county board of elections -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within three (3) days after any primary or general election, the precinct election sheriff shall file a report with the chairman of the county board of elections and with the local grand jury. The report shall include any irregularities observed and any recommendations for improving the election process. </section><section prefix="2">Within ten (10) days after any primary or general election, the county board of elections shall file a report with the State Board of Elections and the local grand jury. The report shall include any irregularities of which the county board has knowledge and any recommendations for improving the election process. The report shall also include a breakdown by precinct of the number of voters requiring assistance to vote and the reasons therefor; the number of special ballots cast by category; and any other information required by the state board. </section><section prefix="3">Within thirty (30) days after any primary or general election, the county board of elections shall transmit the information required by KRS 117.275(4) to (7). </section><section prefix="4">The State Board of Elections shall issue administrative regulations to prescribe the forms required by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>