<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.685</section_number><catch_line>Misuse of electronic information prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>685</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who, with intent to defraud the issuer, the cardholder, or any other person or organization, (a) intercepts, taps or alters electronic information between an automated banking device and the issuer, or (b) originates electronic information to an automated banking device or to the issuer, via any line, wire, or any other means of electronic transmission, at any junction or terminal, or at any location within an E.F.T. system, for the purpose of obtaining money, goods, services or anything else of value, violates this subsection and is subject to the penalties set forth in subsection (2) of KRS 434.730. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who, with intent to defraud the issuer, cardholder, or any other person or organization, intercepts, taps or alters electronic information between an automated banking device and the issuer, or originates electronic information to an automated banking device or to the issuer, via any line, wire, or other means of electronic transmission, at any junction or terminal, or at any location within the E.F.T. system, and therefore causes funds to be transferred from one account to any other account, violates this subsection and is subject to the penalties set forth in subsection (2) of KRS 434.730. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>