<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.200</section_number><catch_line>Gas system restoration and development project account -- Review board -- Loan applications. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Local Government is authorized and directed to apply for and receive federal funds to be placed in a state account called the gas system restoration and development project account, and to provide staff to administer said funds. The funds in this account may be used in any gas system restoration or development project approved by the Gas System Restoration and Development Project Account Review Board. </section><section prefix="2">A Gas System Restoration and Development Project Account Review Board is established and shall consist of eight (8) members appointed by the Governor. The board shall be chaired by the commissioner of the Department for Local Government and shall include representatives of the Public Service Commission, state fire marshal, Department for Local Government, Kentucky Infrastructure Authority, banking and finance industry, commercial or industrial consumers, Kentucky Gas Association, and low-income or minority group consumers. Members shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses in attending meetings. </section><section prefix="3">The review board shall meet as necessary and shall establish rules for conducting its business. The review board shall consider applications for loans from the account and approve or disapprove loan applications. No loan shall be considered unless the applicant has complied with all construction and securities requirements of the Public Service Commission. In reviewing loan applications, the review board may request the testimony of the county judge/executive of an affected county and any other witnesses deemed appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 137, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 551, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1663</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>