<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.010</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner's authority to organize Department of Education -- Composition -- Functions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of education shall be the chief executive of the Department of Education. The commissioner shall be responsible for administering, structuring, and organizing the department and its services including, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">Technical assistance with curriculum design, school administration and finance, computer and technology services, media services, community education, secondary vocational education, education for exceptional children, and professional development; </section><section prefix="b">Compensatory education; </section><section prefix="c">Research and planning, which shall include, but not be limited to, a statewide research and development effort to identify or develop the best educational practices to be used in the public schools of the Commonwealth. Appropriations for this purpose may be used within the department or for contracting with other individuals, agencies, universities, laboratories, or organizations; </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky School for the Blind and the Kentucky School for the Deaf; </section><section prefix="e">Performance and outcome assessments; </section><section prefix="f">Monitoring the management of school districts, including administration and finance, implementation of state laws and regulations, and student performance; and </section><section prefix="g">Implementing state laws and the policies promulgated thereunder by the Kentucky Board of Education and the Education Professional Standards Board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of education may delegate to his assistants any authority to act for him in the supervision, inspection, and administration of the schools to the extent he has supervisory and administrative control. </section><section prefix="3">All employees of the Department of Education shall be reimbursed for necessary traveling expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties, and no part of the reimbursement shall be included in or accounted as a part of their salaries. </section><section prefix="4">The State Department of Education, in the operation and management of its schools and the programs at these schools, shall meet all required federal and state standards relating to facilities and personnel qualifications; however, no license or license fee shall be required for any school or program operated by the State Department of Education. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Education shall be the sole state agency for the purpose of developing and approving state plans required by state or federal laws and regulations as prerequisites to receiving federal funds for elementary and secondary education. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 45, effective July 1, 1990; ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 43, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 518, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 435, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 84, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4618-20, 4618-80. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3089</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>