<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.450</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 216B.450, 216B.455, and 216B.457. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>As used in this section and KRS 216B.455 and 216B.457: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Community-based" means a facility that is located in an existing residential neighborhood or community; </section><section prefix="3">"Freestanding" means a completely detached building or two (2) residences under one (1) roof that are clearly separate and can serve youth independently; </section><section prefix="4">"Home-like" means a residence with living space designed to accommodate the daily living needs and tasks of a family unit, with opportunity for adult-child communication, shared tasks, adult-child learning, congregate meals, and family-type routines appropriate to the ages and levels of functioning of the residents; </section><section prefix="5">"Psychiatric residential treatment facility" means either a licensed: <section prefix="a">Level I community-based, and home-like facility with a maximum of nine (9) beds which provides inpatient psychiatric residential treatment to residents age six (6) to twenty-one (21) years who have an emotional disability or severe emotional disability as defined in KRS 200.503, with an age range of no greater than five (5) years at the time of admission in a living unit; or </section><section prefix="b">Level II home-like facility that provides twenty-four (24) hour inpatient psychiatric residential treatment and habitation to persons who: <section prefix="1">Are ages four (4) to twenty-one (21) years, with an age range of no greater than five (5) years at the time of admission to the facility; </section><section prefix="2">Have a severe emotional disability as defined by KRS 200.503 in addition to severe and persistent aggressive behaviors, intellectual disability, sexually acting out behaviors, or developmental disability; and </section><section prefix="3">Do not meet the medical necessity criteria for an acute care hospital or a psychiatric hospital and whose treatment needs cannot be met in an ambulatory care setting, Level I psychiatric residential treatment facility, or other less restrictive environment; </section></section></section><section prefix="6">"Qualified mental health personnel" means a staff member who operates under the supervision of a qualified mental health professional; and </section><section prefix="7">"Qualified mental health professional" has the same meaning as in KRS 202A.011. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 510, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 455, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9255</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>