<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.460</section_number><catch_line>Levy of surcharge on tickets and on restaurant gross receipts by county containing city of first class or consolidated local government.   </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Multipurpose arena" means a facility whose principal use includes but is not limited to the exhibition of collegiate basketball competition; </section><section prefix="b">"Restaurant" means any facility operated for profit which has minimum seating capacity of fifty (50) people at tables and which receives less than fifty percent (50%) of its annual food and beverage income from the sale of alcohol. </section></section><section prefix="2">Fiscal courts in counties containing cities of the first class or consolidated local governments may levy: <section prefix="a">A ten percent (10%) surcharge on all tickets sold by a multipurpose arena located in the county and constructed after April 9, 1980; and </section><section prefix="b">A one-fourth of one percent (0.25%) tax on gross receipts from the sale of food and beverages of all restaurants located in the county. </section></section><section prefix="3">All moneys collected from the surcharge on tickets and the restaurant tax shall be placed in a fund to be used to defray operating expenses of any such multipurpose arena. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 174, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 8, effective April 9, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>