<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.676</section_number><catch_line>Provision of identifying or asset information not to be disclosed to delinquent taxpayer or debtor -- Penalty -- Financial institutions not liable -- General notice to account holders. </catch_line><order_by>676</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A financial institution furnishing a report or providing asset information about a delinquent taxpayer or debtor to the department shall not disclose to the delinquent taxpayer or debtor that the name of that person has been received from or furnished to the department. A financial institution may disclose to its depositors or account holders that, under the financial institution match system, the department has the authority to request certain identifying information on certain depositors or account holders. </section><section prefix="2">If a financial institution willfully violates the provisions of this section, the institution shall pay to the department the lesser of one thousand dollars ($1,000) or the amount on deposit or in the account of the person to whom the disclosure was made. </section><section prefix="3">A financial institution shall incur no obligation or liability to a depositor or account holder or any other person arising from the furnishing of a report or information to the department pursuant to KRS 131.670 to 131.676, or from the failure to disclose to a depositor or account holder that the name of the person was included in a list or report furnished by the financial institution to the department. </section><section prefix="4">A financial institution shall not give notice to an account holder or customer of the financial institution that the financial institution has provided information or taken any action pursuant to KRS 131.670 to 131.676 and shall not be liable for failure to provide that notice; provided, however, that a financial institution may disclose to its depositors or account holders that, under the data match system, the department has the authority to request certain identifying information on certain depositors or account holders. The department shall notify, not less than annually, affected depositors or account holders who have not otherwise received notification. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XVII, sec. 4, effective April 25, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> April 25, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28194</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>