<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="433" order_by="433">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>433.753</section_number><catch_line>Criminal littering on public highway -- Rewards for information. </catch_line><order_by>753</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any paper, waste material, litter, or other refuse is thrown or dropped from a motor vehicle, the operator thereof shall be deemed prima facie to be guilty of criminal littering. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the duty of the Department of Kentucky State Police, county sheriffs and police officers, solid waste coordinators appointed by a county or waste management district, city police officers, and all other law enforcement and peace officers within their respective jurisdictions, to enforce the criminal littering laws and the provisions of KRS 224.40-100. </section><section prefix="3">Any city or county may offer and pay rewards for the giving of information leading to the arrest and conviction of any person, firm, or corporation for commission of the offense of criminal littering. </section><section prefix="4">Violators may prepay to the Circuit Court clerk if prepayment is so noted on the citation and if the littering offense is not combined with an offense that is not prepayable. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 316, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 332. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 77. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>