<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-390</section_number><catch_line>Place of agent's business -- Display of licenses -- Records. </catch_line><order_by>9-390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every individual and business entity issued a license with Kentucky as its home state shall have and maintain in this state a place of business accessible to the public, and wherein the licensee principally conducts transactions under his or her license. This provision shall not be deemed to prohibit maintenance of this place of business in the office of an insurer, office of the employer, or in the residence of the licensee. </section><section prefix="2">The licenses of the licensee shall be conspicuously displayed in each of the places of business in a part customarily open to the public. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee shall keep at his or her place of business complete records of transactions under the license. <section prefix="a">The records shall be kept available for inspection by the commissioner for a period of at least five (5) years after completion of the respective transactions. </section><section prefix="b">For an insurance producer, the record shall show, as to each insurance policy or contract placed by or through the licensee, the names of the insurer and insured, the number and expiration date of, and premium payable as to, the policy or contract, and any other information as the commissioner may reasonably require. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1071, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 28, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 39, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>