<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">E IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL HAZARDOUS MATERIALS PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39E.080</section_number><catch_line>Administrative support by Division of Emergency Management -- Protection of federal funds -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Emergency Management shall provide administrative support to the commission within the limitation of staff resources. The division may employ staff and may acquire technical or professional assistance as determined to be necessary by the director of the division, and for whom federal, state, or other funds have been provided. </section><section prefix="2">Persons employed under this section shall report to the director of the division and shall implement policies and directives of the commission as specified by the director. Other employees of the division may also support the commission and assist in the implementation of hazardous substance planning, reporting, investigation, training, and exercising as directed by the director. In cases when the commission develops policies or directives which cannot reasonably be implemented by division staff, the director may defer implementation until sufficient resources exist. In cases when the director advises the commission, in writing, that the division cannot provide requested resources, the commission may seek assistance from other agencies of state government. </section><section prefix="3">In no case shall the director devote division resources to support the commission if that support would result in the withdrawal of federal or state funds from the division. </section><section prefix="4">The division shall, upon concurrence by the director, promulgate administrative regulations recommended by the commission and consistent with Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499. The regulations shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Substances which require inventory reporting; </section><section prefix="b">Quantities of each substance covered; and </section><section prefix="c">Emergency notification procedures and requirements. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 65, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21776</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>