<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.660</section_number><catch_line>Motor fuels tax -- Surtax -- Weight distance tax. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every motor carrier, excluding charter bus operators registered pursuant to KRS Chapter 281, shall pay a tax at the rate levied in KRS 138.220(1) and (2) on the amount of gasoline and special fuels used in operations on the public highways of this state. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to the tax imposed in subsection (1) of this section, if the motor carrier is a heavy equipment motor carrier as defined in KRS 138.655, he shall pay a surtax at the rate of two percent (2%) of the average wholesale price as provided in subsection (1) of this section, on the amount of gasoline and at the rate of four and seven-tenths percent (4.7%) on the amount of special fuels used in operations on public highways of this state. </section><section prefix="3">Every motor carrier shall pay for every motor vehicle operated upon the public highways of this state with a combined licensed weight in excess of fifty-nine thousand nine hundred and ninety-nine (59,999) pounds a weight distance tax computed at the rate of two and eighty-five hundredths cents ($0.0285) per mile. </section><section prefix="4">Those taxes levied under this section shall be computed and paid as provided in KRS 138.685 and 138.690. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 4, effective April 1, 1988; and ch. 285, sec. 32, effective August 1, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1987. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 77, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 151, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 6, effective April 1, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 3. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 7. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1958. -- Amended 1956 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 16. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>