<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.351</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary action -- Offenses subject to disciplinary action. </catch_line><order_by>351</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue a license, or may suspend, revoke, impose probationary or supervisory conditions upon, impose an administrative fine, issue a written reprimand, or any combination thereof regarding any licensee upon proof that the licensee has: <section prefix="a">Committed any act of dishonesty or corruption. If the act constitutes a crime, conviction in a criminal proceeding is not a condition precedent to disciplinary action. Upon conviction of the crime, the judgment and sentence are presumptive evidence at the ensuing disciplinary hearing of the guilt of the licensee or applicant. Conviction includes all instances in which a plea of no contest on the basis of the conviction; </section><section prefix="b">Misrepresented or concealed a material fact in obtaining a license, or in reinstatement thereof; </section><section prefix="c">Committed any unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive act or practice; </section><section prefix="d">Been incompetent or negligent in the practice of veterinary medicine; </section><section prefix="e">Violated any state statute or administrative regulation governing the practice of veterinary medicine or any activities undertaken by a veterinarian; </section><section prefix="f">Failed to comply with an order issued by the board or an assurance of voluntary compliance; </section><section prefix="g">Violated the code of ethical conduct as set forth by the board by administrative regulation; or </section><section prefix="h">Violated any applicable provision of any federal or state law or regulation regarding the dispensing of controlled or legend drugs. </section></section><section prefix="2">Five (5) years from the date of a revocation, any person whose license has been revoked may petition the board for reinstatement. The board shall investigate the petition and may reinstate the license upon a finding that the individual has complied with any terms prescribed by the board and is again able to competently engage in the practice of veterinary medicine. </section><section prefix="3">When in the judgment of the board, an alleged violation is not of a serious nature, and the evidence presented to the board after the investigation and appropriate opportunity for the licensee to respond, provides a clear indication that the alleged violation did in fact occur, the board may issue a written reprimand to the licensee. A copy of the reprimand shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to file a response to the reprimand within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have the response placed in the permanent licensure file. The licensee may alternatively, within thirty (30) days of the receipt, file a request for hearing with the board. Upon receipt of this request the board shall set aside the written reprimand and set the matter for hearing. </section><section prefix="4">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may enter into an agreed order or accept an assurance of voluntary compliance with the licensee which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="5">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its probation, suspensions, or other disciplinary action. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31403</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>