<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="316" order_by="316">EMBALMERS AND FUNERAL DIRECTORS </unit></structure><section_number>316.125</section_number><catch_line>Funeral establishment license -- Application -- Fee -- Each funeral establishment to be licensed separately -- Supervision. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall operate a full-service funeral establishment, a visitation and ceremonial funeral service establishment, or an embalming service establishment in the Commonwealth of Kentucky without first obtaining the applicable establishment license issued by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall issue the appropriate establishment license to an applicant who: <section prefix="a">Has paid to the board an establishment license fee, not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200), as set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board; and </section><section prefix="b">Has filed with the board a sworn statement that sets out the following: <section prefix="1">Name of the funeral establishment; </section><section prefix="2">Address of the funeral establishment; </section><section prefix="3">Type of funeral establishment; </section><section prefix="4">Owners of the funeral establishment, indicating which owners are licensed by the board; and </section><section prefix="5">Name and address of the Kentucky-licensed embalmer or the Kentucky-licensed funeral director who will supervise the funeral establishment pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Each funeral establishment shall be licensed separately from any other funeral establishment. </section><section prefix="4">Each funeral establishment, when in use, shall be under the supervision of a Kentucky-licensed embalmer or a Kentucky-licensed funeral director. </section><section prefix="5">A Kentucky-licensed embalmer or a Kentucky-licensed funeral director shall not supervise more than one (1) funeral establishment at the same time. </section><section prefix="6">The funeral establishment shall display in a public place in the establishment its establishment license and the license of the embalmer or funeral director who supervises the establishment pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>