<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.170</section_number><catch_line>Officers of board -- Seal -- Records -- Powers -- Compensation -- Regulations -- Resolution of complaints. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors shall, upon taking oath, elect one (1) of their members as president of the board, and shall select some suitable person as secretary, who need not be a member of the board. The secretary shall serve as treasurer of the district, or the board may select a treasurer. The selection of the secretary and treasurer shall be evidenced on the minutes of the board, with their compensation. They shall serve at the pleasure of the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall adopt a seal, and shall keep in a well-bound book a record of all proceedings, minutes of meetings, certificates, contracts, bonds given by employees, and all corporate acts, which shall be open to the inspection of any owner of property in the district as well as all other interested persons. </section><section prefix="3">The board of directors shall be the governing body of the sanitation district and shall exercise all the powers and manage and control all the affairs and property of the district. If the board of a multicounty district governed by the provisions of KRS 220.135 has an executive committee, each county shall have a member on the committee. </section><section prefix="4">The board of directors may prescribe the duties and fix the compensation of all the officers of the district, subject to the limits fixed in this section. No member of the board of directors, except the president, shall receive more than thirty-six hundred dollars ($3,600) per annum. The president shall receive not more than six hundred dollars ($600) per annum in addition to his compensation as a director. The treasurer shall receive not more than nine hundred dollars ($900) and the secretary not more than three hundred dollars ($300) per annum. </section><section prefix="5">The board may adopt all necessary rules and regulations for the proper management and conduct of the business of the board and of the corporation, and for carrying into effect the other objects for which the district was formed. All such rules or regulations shall become effective only upon posting in at least ten (10) public places within the district. </section><section prefix="6">The board of directors of an established district shall develop a procedure to hear, review, and resolve customers' complaints and grievances on any matter for which there is otherwise no requirement in this chapter for a hearing. Upon written request setting forth the basis of the complaint or grievance by the customer, mailed or delivered to the principal office of the district, the secretary of the board of directors shall schedule a hearing for the next regular board of directors' meeting if the meeting is not held within fourteen (14) days of the date of receipt of the request, and shall give the customer at least ten (10) days' written notice of the hearing by mail. If the receipt of the request is within fourteen (14) days of the next regularly scheduled meeting of the board of directors, the hearing shall be held at the regular meeting following the next scheduled meeting. The board of directors shall provide a written response to the customer concerning his complaint within seven (7) days after the conclusion of the hearing unless the customer waives his right to a written response or agrees to a delay. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 490, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1, effective May 18, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2062g-16, 2062g-18, 2062g-19, 2062g-20.</history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 307 and 490 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9786</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>