<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.601</section_number><catch_line>Notification of nominees by Secretary of State -- Order of names on ballot -- Certification of candidates. </catch_line><order_by>601</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State shall contact each person who has been nominated by petition, or who has been nominated pursuant to KRS 118.591(5) and (6), and notify him in writing by certified mail, with return receipt requested, that his name will appear as a candidate on the Kentucky presidential primary ballot of his party. </section><section prefix="2">The order in which the names of candidates for a presidential preference primary are to be printed on the ballot shall be determined by lot at a public drawing in the office of the Secretary of State at 2 p.m., standard time, on the Thursday following the last Tuesday in January preceding the presidential preference primary. </section><section prefix="3">Not later than the date set forth in KRS 118.215(1)(a) preceding the presidential preference primary, and after the order of the names has been determined as provided by subsection (2) of this section, the Secretary of State shall certify to each county clerk the name, place of residence, and party of each candidate, as specified in the notice of candidacy forms or petitions filed with him and shall designate the device with which the candidates of each party shall be printed, in the order in which they are to appear on the ballot, with precedence to be given to the party that polled the highest number of votes at the preceding election for presidential electors, followed by the political party which received the second highest number of votes. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2, effective January 29, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 54, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 431, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 470, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27666</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>