<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.070</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The board shall administer and enforce the provisions of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990, and shall evaluate applications and issue licenses to qualified applicants within forty-five (45) days of submission of the complete application packet and receipt of the official passing score report and the licensure fee. </section><section prefix="b">Within fifteen (15) days of accepting an applicant's payment and application packet, the board shall: <section prefix="1">Notify the applicant that the application packet is complete, approve the applicant to sit for the national examination, and issue a temporary permit to engage in the practice of social work; or </section><section prefix="2">Notify the applicant that the application packet is incomplete and, when all omitted application items are received, notify the applicant of receipt of the complete application packet, approve the applicant to sit for the national examination, and issue a temporary permit to engage in the practice of social work. </section></section><section prefix="c">The board shall evaluate the complete application packet and, within forty-five (45) days, notify a qualified applicant of the issuance of the permanent license pursuant to KRS 335.080, 335.090, or 335.100. </section><section prefix="d">If the board deems an applicant unqualified, the license may be denied and the temporary permit to practice social work may be revoked. </section><section prefix="e">In order to be issued a temporary permit, an applicant shall have submitted: <section prefix="1">A complete application packet as provided in this subsection, with the exception of a passing score on the required examination; and </section><section prefix="2">If applying for licensure as a certified social worker or as a licensed clinical social worker, a letter from a licensed clinical social worker, or equivalent, who will supervise the applicant while under temporary permit in accordance with administrative regulations. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The board may issue subpoenas, examine witnesses, pay appropriate witness fees, administer oaths, and investigate allegations of practices violating the provision of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990. </section><section prefix="3">The board may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the provisions of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990. </section><section prefix="4">The board may conduct hearings pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B and keep records and minutes necessary to carry out the functions of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990. </section><section prefix="5">The board may employ any other persons it deems necessary to carry on the work of the board, and shall define their duties and fix their compensation. </section><section prefix="6">The board may renew licenses and require continuing education as a condition for license renewals, and shall authorize organizations to provide continuing education programs, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Schools of social work accredited by the Council on Social Work Education; </section><section prefix="b">The National Association of Social Workers-Kentucky Chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Society of Clinical Social Workers. </section></section><section prefix="7">The board may, after a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, revoke, suspend, or refuse to issue or renew; impose probationary or supervisory conditions upon; impose administrative fines; issue written reprimands and admonishments; or any combination of actions regarding licenses and licensees. </section><section prefix="8">The board may seek injunctive relief in Franklin Circuit Court to stop the unlawful practice of social work by unlicensed persons. </section><section prefix="9">The board may establish, by promulgation of administrative regulations, the requirements for temporary permits to practice social work. </section><section prefix="10">The board may enter into agreements with any organization for the creation and implementation of a social work impairment program, as specified in the agreement. </section><section prefix="11">The board shall refund any levied administrative assessments that it has received for practice by unlicensed individuals employed by organizations exempted from the application of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and 335.990 by KRS 335.010(5). </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 79, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 352, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 1. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). In subsection (1) of this statute, an erroneous citation to a provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes has been corrected. Subsection (11) of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 79, refers to "subsection (5) of Section 1 of this Act" rather than making the clearly intended reference to "subsection (5) of Section 77 of this Act." Under KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error. The reference now reads "KRS 335.010(5)." (7/15/94). This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 14 is not in conflict with these two Acts and has been codified together with them. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40970</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>