<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.450</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers and duties of secretary as to regional programs.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>In addition to the powers and duties already conferred upon him by the law, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall: <section prefix="1">Promulgate policies and regulations governing eligibility of community programs for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability to receive state grants and other fund allocations from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, prescribing standards for qualification of personnel and quality of professional service and for in-service training and educational leave programs for personnel, governing eligibility for service so that no person will be denied service on the basis of race, color or creed, or inability to pay, providing for establishment of fee schedules which shall be based upon ability to pay, regulating fees for diagnostic services, which services may be provided for anyone without regard to his financial status, when referred by the courts, schools, or health and welfare agencies whether public or private, governing financial record keeping, prescribing standards for personnel management operations, providing for financial and program reporting requirements, and such other policies and regulations as he deems necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 210.370 to 210.460; </section><section prefix="2">Review and evaluate local programs and the performance of administrative and psychiatric personnel and make recommendations thereon to community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability and program administrators; </section><section prefix="3">Provide consultative service, by professionals qualified in the areas of mental health and intellectual disabilities by education and training, to communities to assist in ascertaining local needs and in planning and establishing community programs for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability; </section><section prefix="4">Employ necessary and qualified personnel to implement KRS 210.370 to 210.460; and </section><section prefix="5">Review annually the personnel policies, procedures, and personnel compensation plans of community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability and disapprove if not consistent with accepted standards of personnel and salary administration prescribed by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 84, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 334, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 278, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 61. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 64(3). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 203.490. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40812</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>