<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.845</section_number><catch_line>Dissolution of participating incorporated cities and special districts -- Effect.   </catch_line><order_by>845</order_by><text>The comprehensive plan for merging a participating city or cities and a county government into a charter county government under KRS 67.825 to 67.875 may provide for the corporate dissolution of incorporated cities and special districts within the county. If the participating incorporated cities and special districts within the county are dissolved, the following provisions shall apply: <section prefix="1">For purposes of all state and federal licensing and regulatory laws, statutory entitlement, gifts, grants-in-aid, governmental loan, or other governmental assistance under state or federal laws, rules, or regulations: <section prefix="a">The charter county may be deemed a county and, if so, the entire geographic area and population of the charter county shall be considered in calculating and determining the distribution basis for state or federal statutory entitlements, gifts, grants-in-aid, loans, or other forms of governmental assistance; and </section><section prefix="b">The charter county government may designate to the appropriate state or federal agency those geographic areas, portions of roads, or segments of population that shall be deemed to constitute rural or urban areas, roads, or population. </section></section><section prefix="2">The chief executive officer of the charter county government may determine and make the designations provided for in this section following a public hearing. The charter county government shall fix the time and place of the hearing and it shall be advertised pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41118</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>