<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.791</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and intent regarding reading. </catch_line><order_by>791</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds that reading proficiency is a gateway skill necessary for all of Kentucky students to achieve the academic goals established in KRS 158.6451. It is Kentucky's goal that all children learn to read well before exiting the primary program and that all middle and high school students have the skills necessary to read complex materials in specific core subjects and comprehend and constructively apply the information. </section><section prefix="2">It is the intent of the General Assembly that: <section prefix="a">Every elementary school: <section prefix="1">Provide a comprehensive schoolwide reading program; </section><section prefix="2">Provide diagnostic reading assessments and intervention services for those students who need them to learn to read at the proficient level; </section><section prefix="3">Ensure quality instruction by highly trained teachers; and </section><section prefix="4">Provide high quality library media programs; </section></section><section prefix="b">Every middle and high school: <section prefix="1">Provide direct, explicit instruction to students lacking skills in how to read, learn, and analyze information in key subjects, including language, reading, English, mathematics, science, social studies, arts and humanities, practical living skills, and career studies; and </section><section prefix="2">Ensure that teachers have the skills to help all students develop critical strategies and skills for subject-based reading; </section></section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Department of Education provide technical assistance to local school districts in the identification of professional development activities, including teaching strategies to help teachers in each subject area to: <section prefix="1">Identify and teach the skills that students need to comprehend the concepts and content of each subject area; and </section><section prefix="2">Use activities and materials that will help the students comprehend and constructively apply information based on the unique content of each subject area; and </section></section><section prefix="d">The Education Professional Standards Board review and revise when deemed necessary the teacher certification and licensure requirements to ensure that all teachers, regardless of the subject area taught, are prepared to improve students' subject reading skills. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 2, effective March 18, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, which created this section, KRS 158.791, provides that the Act shall be cited as the "Read to Achieve Act of 2005." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3588</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>