<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.596</section_number><catch_line>Pediatric Cancer Research Trust Fund Board -- Membership -- Terms -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>596</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Pediatric Cancer Research Trust Fund Board is hereby created for the purpose of administering and distributing funds from the trust created under KRS 211.595. The board shall be composed of nine (9) members to be appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">A specialist in pediatric oncology nominated by the Kosair Children’s Hospital to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">A specialist in pediatric oncology nominated by the University of Kentucky Children’s Hospital to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="c">A representative nominated by Kentucky Chapters of the Leukemia and Lymphoma Society to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="d">A representative nominated by Kentucky offices of the American Cancer Society to be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) citizens, one (1) of whom shall be a pediatric cancer survivor, or parent thereof, to be appointed by the Governor from a list of six (6) citizens nominated by Kentucky offices of the American Cancer Society; </section><section prefix="f">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or the secretary's designee; and </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of the Department for Public Health, or the commissioner's designee. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall be attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall convene the first meeting of the board within sixty (60) days of June 24, 2015. </section><section prefix="4">Board members shall serve without compensation, but may receive reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="5">The term of each appointed member shall be four (4) years. </section><section prefix="6">A member whose term has expired may continue to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member who is appointed to an unexpired term shall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member may serve two (2) consecutive four (4) year terms and shall not be reappointed for four (4) years after the completion of those terms. </section><section prefix="7">A majority of the full membership of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="8">At the first meeting, the board shall elect, by majority vote, a president who shall preside at all meetings and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The president shall be elected or reelected each calendar year thereafter. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall meet at least two (2) times annually, but may meet more frequently, as deemed necessary, subject to call by the president or by request of a majority of the board members. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 108, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This statute was created with identical text in 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 96 and 108, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together.  (6/24/2015). During codification, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected the name of the Pediatric Cancer Research Trust Fund Board in this statute from the way it appeared in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4 and 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 3, by inserting the inadvertently omitted word "Research" in subsection (1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44568</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>