<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.785</section_number><catch_line>Duties of law enforcement officers and agencies.  (Effective January1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>785</order_by><text>(1)A court issuing an order of protection shall direct the appropriate lawenforcement agency to assist the petitioner in having the provisions of theorder complied with.(2)When a law enforcement officer has reason to suspect that a person has beenthe victim of domestic violence and abuse, the officer shall use all reasonablemeans to provide assistance to the victim, including but not limited to:(a)Remaining at the location of the call for assistance so long as the officerreasonably suspects there is danger to the physical safety of individualsthere without the presence of a law enforcement officer;(b)Assisting the victim in obtaining medical treatment, including transportingthe victim to the nearest medical facility capable of providing thenecessary treatment; and(c)Advising the victim immediately of the rights available to them, includingthe provisions of this chapter.(3)Orders of protection shall be enforced in any county of the Commonwealth.(4)Officers acting in good faith under this section shall be immune from criminaland civil liability.(5)Each law enforcement agency shall report all incidents of actual or suspecteddomestic violence and abuse within their knowledge to the Cabinet for Healthand Family Services, Department for Community Based Services, withinforty-eight (48) hours of learning of the incident or of the suspected incident.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 18, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 629, effective June 20, 2005. --Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 53, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 583, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky.Acts ch. 54, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172,sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 15,effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44766</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>