<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="395" order_by="395">PERSONAL REPRESENTATIVES </unit></structure><section_number>395.430</section_number><catch_line>Application for curator for absent person -- Notice. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before any curator is appointed for an absent person under subsection (2) of KRS 395.410, a written application requesting the appointment shall be filed with the District Court Clerk. The application shall be verified and shall recite the fact of absence, the last known address of the absent person and the presence of property within this state or other ground requiring the appointment of a curator for the protection of the property or rights of the absent person. The application may be made by any relative, creditor or debtor of the absent person, or by any person in possession of or interested in any property or rights of the absent person. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the filing with the District Court Clerk of any such application, the clerk shall send by United States certified mail, return receipt requested a letter addressed to the absent person at the last known address as given in the application, stating that such application has been filed. The clerk shall publish pursuant to KRS Chapter 424 a notice to the effect that an application for the appointment of a curator has been made. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 103, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 390, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 85. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 224. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3902a-2, 3902a-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>