<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.241</section_number><catch_line>Designation of streams in Wild Rivers System. </catch_line><order_by>241</order_by><text>The streams or segments of streams to be included in this system, being classified by KRS 146.230, are as follows: <section prefix="1">The Cumberland River from Summer Shoals to the backwater of Lake Cumberland; </section><section prefix="2">The Red River from the Ky. 746 bridge to the mouth of Swift Camp Creek. Nothing in KRS 146.220 to 146.360 shall be construed to prohibit that portion of the Red River between Peck's Branch and Swift Camp Creek from being used to temporarily contain flood waters that may be impounded above the normal sustained pool level of any lake which may be created in the event a dam is constructed on the Red River near Bowen, Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">The Rockcastle River from the Ky. 80 bridge to the backwater of Lake Cumberland.  Nothing in KRS 146.220 to 146.360 shall be construed to prohibit or interfere with the relocating of Ky. 80, including the construction of a bridge at a point approximately 2.35 miles downstream from the existing Ky. 80 bridge; </section><section prefix="4">The Green River from the eastern boundary of Mammoth Cave National Park extending downstream and including only that portion of the river within the Mammoth Cave National Park; </section><section prefix="5">The Big South Fork of the Cumberland River from the Tennessee border to Blue Herron; </section><section prefix="6">Martins Fork, Cumberland River from Ky. Highway 987 bridge to the eastern boundary of Cumberland Gap National Park; </section><section prefix="7">Rock Creek from the White Oak Junction bridge to the Kentucky-Tennessee border; </section><section prefix="8">Little South Fork, Cumberland River from the backwater of Lake Cumberland (mile 4.1) to the Kentucky Highway 92 bridge (mile 14.5) in Wayne and McCreary counties; and </section><section prefix="9">Bad Branch of Poor Fork, Cumberland River from the headwaters on Pine Mountain to the Ky. 932 bridge, including the entire watershed drained by all stream segments, except for that portion above a point 0.1 mile below the existing lake on the easternmost fork. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29307</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>