<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-040</section_number><catch_line>Flexible manufacturing networks.   </catch_line><order_by>47-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Three (3) or more secondary wood products businesses may establish a flexible manufacturing network for the purposes deemed appropriate by those businesses upon application to the cabinet, and, if approved, may become eligible for business incentives and priority consideration for state economic development loans and grants. </section><section prefix="2">Information concerning the various secondary wood products requirements of state capital construction and renovation projects shall be maintained by the Finance and Administration Cabinet's Department for Facilities and Support Services. This information shall be made available to any secondary wood industry business that seeks business with state agencies. Applications of secondary wood products businesses as prescribed in subsection (1) of this section shall be approved or disapproved by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Any business firm that is a member of an approved network as set forth in this section shall be eligible for priority consideration for financial incentives, including loans, grants, and tax credits programs under the authority of the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority as set forth in this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing contained in this section shall be so construed as waiving standard eligibility requirements and sound business qualifications applicable to any business making an application to the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority for state financial assistance programs under its authority and responsibility. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42111</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>