<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.200</section_number><catch_line>Power to hear witnesses, issue subpoenas, and serve process. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the discharge of the duties imposed by this chapter members of the commission, the secretary or any duly authorized representative thereof, may administer oaths and affirmations, take depositions, certify official acts, and issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records considered necessary and relevant as evidence in connection with the administration of this chapter. Such subpoena shall be served in the same manner as a subpoena issued out of a Circuit Court, and the sheriff shall receive the same fee as provided by law for like service in civil actions. Witnesses subpoenaed shall be allowed witnesses' fees according to the rates prescribed by KRS 421.015 for each day their attendance is actually required at a hearing. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary or the commission, or any of their authorized representatives, shall have the power, in any and all counties of this Commonwealth, now granted by law to sheriffs within their respective jurisdictions, to execute and make due return of all notices, summonses, including summonses duces tecum, subpoenas, and executions in respect to all court actions instituted to enforce the provisions of this chapter. The secretary, a member of the commission, or any of their authorized representatives shall not be deemed to be an interested party in the action by reason of his official or representative capacity. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 138, effective July 12, 2006. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 425, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 268, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(31). -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 6, effective March 24, 1952. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32262</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>