<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any owner or occupant who fails to comply with an order made under the provisions of subsection (1) of KRS 212.210 shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) and each day's continuance of the nuisance, source of filth, or cause of sickness, after the owner or occupant has been notified to remove it, shall be a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 212.715 or any rule or regulation adopted by any consolidated local government, city, county, or city-county board of health, except as otherwise provided by subsection (3) of this section for counties containing cities of the first class or consolidated local government, shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each day the violation continues. </section><section prefix="3">The violation of any health regulation promulgated by the city-county board of health or of any order made by the board under KRS 212.350 to 212.620, directing the abatement of a nuisance, source of filth, or cause or probable cause of sickness, is hereby declared to be a misdemeanor, and any person, firm, or corporation, or member of a firm or officer or director of a corporation, upon conviction thereof shall be fined not less than five dollars ($5) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each such offense. If any offense is continued for more than one (1) day, each day upon which such offense occurs or is continued shall be considered and constitute a separate offense and a separate fine may be imposed therefor. </section><section prefix="4">Any physician who fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 212.343, upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="5">Failure to procure the informed consent of those required to give their consent pursuant to KRS 212.345, prior to performing a nontherapeutic sterilization shall be punishable by imprisonment in the county jail not to exceed one (1) year or a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000), or both. </section><section prefix="6">Any physician violating KRS 212.347 shall be imprisoned in the county jail not to exceed one (1) year or shall pay a fine not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000), or both. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 210, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 179, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 6. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 9, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 21. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2055, 2057. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8699</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>