<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29">A JURIES </unit></structure><section_number>29A.130</section_number><catch_line>Limitation on jury service within a twenty-four-month period. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as set out in this section, in any twenty-four (24) month period, a person shall not be required to: <section prefix="a">Serve or attend court for prospective service as a petit juror more than thirty (30) court days except when necessary to complete service in a particular case; or </section><section prefix="b">Serve on more than one (1) grand jury; or </section><section prefix="c">Serve as both a grand and petit juror. </section></section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of this section, court includes all federal courts, all other state courts, and any court of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 24, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>(8/24/2005). In 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 7, the following text was erroneously included in this statute: "At any time for cause shown, the court may excuse a grand juror either temporarily or permanently and may swear another grand juror from a current jury panel in place of the one excused. The discharge of any such grand juror shall in no way or manner affect any indictment found by the grand jury as it was composed either before or after such discharge. If it is impossible to fill the vacancy on the grand jury from a current jury panel, the Chief Circuit Judge may summon, using the procedure in KRS 29A.060(5), such number of prospective jurors as deemed necessary for the purpose."   This text was not part of the statute when the section was created in 1976, and it was never added to the statute in accordance with the requirements of KRS 446.145(1). Instead, the text was inadvertently inserted, without underlining, in the 2002 amendment to this statute (2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 7).   Acting under the authority of KRS 446.270, 446.280, and 7.136(1)(h), the Reviser of Statutes has deleted this extraneous text.   For a provision similar to the one deleted from this statute, see KRS 29A.260. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21130</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>