<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.272</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 234.270 to 234.302. </catch_line><order_by>272</order_by><text>As used in KRS 234.270 to 234.302, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="2">"Council" means the Kentucky Propane Education and Research Council created in accordance with KRS 234.290; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the state Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="4">"Education" means any action to provide information regarding propane, propane equipment, mechanical and technical practices relating to the use of propane, and propane uses to consumers and members of the propane industry; </section><section prefix="5">"Industry" means those persons involved in the production, transportation, and sale of propane and in the manufacture and distribution of propane utilization equipment; </section><section prefix="6">"Industry trade association" means an organization representing the propane industry which is exempt from tax, under Section 501(c)(3) or (c)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="7">"Odorized propane" means propane to which an odorant has been added; </section><section prefix="8">"Person" means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, cooperative, or other business entity; </section><section prefix="9">"Producer" means the owner of propane at the time it is recovered at a gas processing plant or refinery, without regard to the state in which actual production occurs; </section><section prefix="10">"Propane" means a hydrocarbon whose chemical composition is predominately C3H8, whether recovered from natural gas or crude oil, and includes liquefied petroleum gases and mixtures thereof; </section><section prefix="11">"Public member" means a member of the council representing significant users of propane, public safety officials, state regulatory officials, or other groups knowledgeable about propane; </section><section prefix="12">"Research" means any type of study, investigation, or other activity designed to advance the image, desirability, usage, marketability, efficiency, or safety of propane and to further the development of this information; </section><section prefix="13">"Retail marketer" means a person engaged primarily in the sale of odorized propane to the final user of the product or to retail propane dispensers; </section><section prefix="14">"Retail propane dispenser" means a person who sells odorized propane to the final user of the product but is not engaged primarily in the business of these sales; and </section><section prefix="15">"Supplier" means a person, other than a producer, who is the owner of propane in the Commonwealth at the time of odorization or who is the owner of odorized propane at the time it is imported into the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 503, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>