<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.120</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of commercial driver's instruction permit. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A commercial driver's instruction permit may be issued to an individual twenty-one (21) years and older who: <section prefix="a">Has complied with the criminal history background check required by KRS 281A.300; </section><section prefix="b">Holds a valid automobile driver's license; and </section><section prefix="c">Has passed the vision and knowledge tests required for a commercial driver's license of the class vehicle to be driven. Instruction permits shall be class specific. </section></section><section prefix="2">A commercial driver's instruction permit may be issued to a resident eighteen (18) years of age who: <section prefix="a">Has complied with the criminal history background check required by KRS 281A.300; </section><section prefix="b">Holds a valid automobile Class D driver's license; and </section><section prefix="c">Has passed the vision and knowledge tests required for a commercial driver's license of the class vehicle to be driven, if the individual only drives a commercial motor vehicle in intrastate commerce and does not drive a school bus or a vehicle hauling hazardous material. The instruction permit shall be class specific and shall contain an "I" restriction noting that the commercial driver is limited to Kentucky intrastate commerce. </section></section><section prefix="3">A commercial driver's instruction permit shall not be issued to a resident for a period to exceed six (6) months. Only one (1) renewal or reissuance may be granted within a two (2) year period for the same class of vehicle. The holder of a commercial driver's instruction permit may, unless otherwise disqualified, drive a commercial motor vehicle on the highways of Kentucky only when accompanied by the holder of a commercial driver's license valid for the type of vehicle driven and who occupies a seat beside the permit holder for the purpose of giving instruction in driving the commercial motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="4">A person who is not a resident who is enrolled in a program offering commercial truck driving under the Kentucky Community and Technical College System or a proprietary school licensed under KRS Chapter 165A may be issued a provisional Class D license that allows an applicant to include a commercial driver's instruction permit into a single license that shall be valid for ninety (90) days. The fee for a provisional Class D license shall be the same as for a regular Class D license. A provisional Class D license may be renewed for one (1) ninety (90) day period. A person issued a provisional Class D license under this subsection shall be required to convert the license to a regular Kentucky CDL or return to the person's state of domicile and transfer the Kentucky provisional Class D license to his or her state of domicile. A provisional Class D license issued under this subsection shall not be converted to a regular Class D license unless the applicant satisfies all Kentucky residency requirements. A commercial driver's instruction permit shall contain, in addition to other information required by the cabinet, those requirements set forth in KRS 281A.170. The commercial driver's instruction permit shall not contain the permit holder's Social Security number but shall include a color photo of the permit holder. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 4, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 481, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> April 5, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14471</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>