<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.702</section_number><catch_line>Functions of the commission.   </catch_line><order_by>702</order_by><text>The commission shall: <section prefix="1">Develop a statewide strategic plan for the development and implementation of goals and objectives, target populations, and program criteria for community corrections programs; </section><section prefix="2">Conduct, in collaboration with community corrections boards, a statewide assessment of community corrections programs; </section><section prefix="3">Award all grant moneys to community corrections programs; </section><section prefix="4">Review community correction program plans and their implementation to ensure compliance with the statewide strategic plan, including the following goals: <section prefix="a">Effectiveness of community corrections programs in maintaining public safety; </section><section prefix="b">Reduction of local commitments to the department; </section><section prefix="c">Reduction in the rate of recidivism; and </section><section prefix="d">Reduction in revocations of probation and parole; </section></section><section prefix="5">Provide technical assistance, support, and training to local boards; </section><section prefix="6">Submit an annual report no later than September 1 of each year to the commissioner, the Governor, and the General Assembly which includes at least the following information: <section prefix="a">The status of the implementation of the statewide strategic plan; </section><section prefix="b">The effectiveness of community corrections programs in achieving the goals outlined in subsection (4) of this section; and </section><section prefix="c">An accounting of the distribution of grants and other funds; </section></section><section prefix="7">Administer the provisions of KRS 196.700 to 196.735; </section><section prefix="8">Advise the Governor and the commissioner concerning correctional policy and programs, including particularly the following: <section prefix="a">The need for, and the development of, new or specialized institutions, facilities, or programs; </section><section prefix="b">The need for, and the effectuation of, collaboration and liaison within the department, and between the department and community agencies and resources, including the bench and bar, in order to promote the readjustment and rehabilitation of offenders in institutions or under parole or probation supervision in the community; and </section><section prefix="c">The need for, and the development of, useful research in penology, correctional treatment, criminal law, or in the disciplines relevant thereto; and </section></section><section prefix="9">Establish a Parole Board Nominating Committee which shall: <section prefix="a">Include five (5) ex officio members of the commission: <section prefix="1">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, who shall serve as chairperson of the committee; </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections, who shall serve as the vice chairperson of the committee; </section><section prefix="3">The director of the Division of Parole and Victim Services; </section><section prefix="4">The deputy commissioner of the Office of Adult Institutions; and </section><section prefix="5">The deputy commissioner of the Office of Community Services and Facilities; </section></section><section prefix="b">Include ten (10) other members of the commission: <section prefix="1">Two (2) Circuit Judges; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) service providers with backgrounds in mental health or education; </section><section prefix="3">A person representing the views of business and industry; </section><section prefix="4">A person representing the views of organized labor; </section><section prefix="5">A practicing attorney; and </section><section prefix="6">Three (3) at-large members; </section></section><section prefix="c">Publicize vacancies and impending term expirations on the Parole Board in accordance with standards set forth in KRS 424.180; </section><section prefix="d">Submit the names of three (3) candidates to the commission for every vacancy or expired term on the Parole Board; </section><section prefix="e">Forward a statement of qualifications of each nominee to the commission along with the nomination. This statement shall identify the experience which meets the qualifications for Parole Board membership outlined in KRS 439.320(1); and </section><section prefix="f">Maintain the statement of qualifications as a public record in accordance with KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 228, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42287</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>