<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.600</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of KRS 136.600 to 136.660 and 132.825. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds that the enactment of the tax and distribution system created by KRS 132.825 and 136.600 to 136.660: <section prefix="1">Addresses an important state interest in providing a fair, efficient, and uniform method for taxing communications services sold in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Overcomes limitations placed upon the taxation of communications service by federal legislation that has resulted in inequities and unfairness among providers and consumers of similar services in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="3">Simplifies an existing system that includes a myriad of levies, fees, and rates imposed at all levels of government, making it easier for communications providers to understand and comply with the provisions of the law; </section><section prefix="4">Provides enough flexibility to address future changes brought about by industry deregulation, convergence of service offerings, and continued technological advances in communications; and </section><section prefix="5">Enhances administrative efficiency for communications service providers, the state, and local governments by drastically reducing the number of returns that must be filed and processed on an annual basis. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 88, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>