<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.240</section_number><catch_line>Annual review -- Interdisciplinary evaluation report -- Discharge.   </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every resident admitted under the provisions of this chapter shall have an annual review conducted by an interdisciplinary team of the ICF/ID to determine the appropriateness of and the necessity for care and treatment provided the resident in the ICF/ID. On or before the anniversary date of an involuntary admission order entered for a resident pursuant to KRS 202B.190, and every year thereafter for as long as the resident resides in the ICF/ID, the ICF/ID shall file with the admitting court an interdisciplinary evaluation report on behalf of the resident whose continued placement in the ICF/ID is required. The report shall detail the social, psychological, medical, and other considerations requiring continued placement of the resident in the ICF/ID, a description of the treatment or habilitation programs which will benefit the resident as a result of such placement, and a statement that the criteria for involuntary admission set forth in KRS 202B.040 are satisfied. The interdisciplinary report shall list the name and address of the guardian or limited guardian or, if none, an immediate family member of the resident. </section><section prefix="2">The physician shall discharge a resident whose admission is pursuant to court order when it is determined by the interdisciplinary team that the resident no longer meets the criteria for involuntary admission as provided in KRS 202B.040. When a resident is discharged, the ICF/ID shall send notice of the discharge to the court. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 55, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 23, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>