<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.220</section_number><catch_line>Interference with officers prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall in any way hinder, refuse, or defeat entrance or inspection by an agent or employee of the department who is performing the duties of his office for the purpose of combating the European corn borer under subsection (1) of KRS 246.210. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall interfere in any way with the department or any of its agents or employees in the inspection of premises and livestock, or in the testing of livestock on any premises when the object of the inspection or testing is to determine the existence of, or to combat in any way, communicable disease in livestock. No person shall interfere in any way with the department or any of its agents or employees in the removal from any premises of livestock found to be infected with a communicable disease. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall hinder the efforts of the state entomologist or his agents in combating Japanese beetles under KRS 246.210. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall hinder the entomologist in the performance of any of his duties. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall interfere in any way with inspectors or assistants while they are discharging their duties under KRS 250.021 to 250.111. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall hinder, prevent, or attempt to prevent any person from discharging his duties under KRS 250.491 to 250.631. </section><section prefix="7">No person shall in any way impersonate, hinder, or obstruct the department or its inspectors in the performance of their official duties under KRS 248.280 to 248.440 or 261.220. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 10, effective March 28, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 13, effective April 8, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 230, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 218. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 3. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 31. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42c-7, 42f-3, 42g-3, 63c-5, 63d-11, 68n-11, 1376b-23, 1719a-11, 4814c-18. </history><metadata><effective> March 28, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11534</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>