<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.088</section_number><catch_line>Nonquota type 4 or NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license -- Issuance to holders of quota retail drink license, microbrewery license, small farm winery license, or other businesses selling for consumption on premises -- Permitted activities -- Sales at service stations.   </catch_line><order_by>088</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A "Nonquota type 4" or "NQ4" retail malt beverage drink license may be issued to the holder of a quota retail drink license, microbrewery license, small farm winery license, or any other business wishing to sell malt beverages by the drink for consumption on the premises only. </section><section prefix="2">An NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license shall authorize the licensee to: <section prefix="a">Sell malt beverages at retail by the drink from only the licensed premises for consumption at the licensed premises only; and </section><section prefix="b">Purchase malt beverages only from a distributor. </section></section><section prefix="3">The holder of an NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license may also hold a nonquota retail malt beverage package license. </section><section prefix="4">A nonquota retail malt beverage drink license shall not be issued to any premises from which gasoline and lubricating oil are sold or from which the servicing and repair of motor vehicles is conducted, unless there is maintained in inventory on the premises for sale at retail not less than five thousand dollars ($5,000) of food, groceries, and related products valued at cost. For purposes of this subsection, the term "food and groceries" has the meaning provided in KRS 243.280. This section shall not apply to any licensed premises that sells no fuel other than marine fuel. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 43, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>