<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="338" order_by="338">OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH OF EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>338.051</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Standards Board -- Membership -- Terms -- Chairman -- Meetings -- Quorum -- Regulations -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Standards Board consisting of the secretary and twelve (12) members equally representing industry, labor, agriculture, and the safety and health profession. The members shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of three (3) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified, from lists of nominees submitted by bona fide associations representative of industry, labor, agriculture, and the safety and health profession. Members shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for attending each meeting and shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in carrying out their duties. The secretary shall act as chairman of the board. No member of the board may have a concurrent term on the review commission. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall hold annual meetings and additional meetings as needed. A majority of the board constitutes a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall adopt and promulgate occupational safety and health rules, regulations, and standards, except that the chairman of the board may adopt established federal standards without board approval if necessary to meet federal time requirements. The board shall secure all expertise, testimony, and evidence necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall be attached to the Labor Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1754, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 37, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32124</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>