<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.713</section_number><catch_line>Contents of lease agreement. </catch_line><order_by>713</order_by><text>A lease agreement, in no smaller type than twelve (12) point font, shall be executed by the client and the assisted-living community and shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Client data, for the purpose of providing service, to include: <section prefix="a">Emergency contact person's name; </section><section prefix="b">Name of responsible party or legal guardian, if applicable; </section><section prefix="c">Attending physician's name; </section><section prefix="d">Information regarding personal preferences and social factors; and </section><section prefix="e">Advance directive under KRS 311.621 to 311.643, if desired by the client. </section></section><section prefix="2">Assisted-living community's policy regarding termination of the lease agreement; </section><section prefix="3">Terms of occupancy; </section><section prefix="4">General services and fee structure; </section><section prefix="5">Information regarding specific services provided, description of the living unit, and associated fees; </section><section prefix="6">Provisions for modifying client services and fees; </section><section prefix="7">Minimum thirty (30) day notice provision for a change in the community's fee structure; </section><section prefix="8">Minimum thirty (30) day move-out notice provision for client nonpayment, subject to applicable landlord or tenant laws; </section><section prefix="9">Provisions for assisting any client that has received a move-out notice to find appropriate living arrangements prior to the actual move-out date; </section><section prefix="10">Refund and cancellation policies; </section><section prefix="11">Description of any special programming, staffing, or training if an assisted-living community is marketed as providing special programming, staffing, or training on behalf of clients with particular needs or conditions; </section><section prefix="12">Other community rights, policies, practices, and procedures; </section><section prefix="13">Other client rights and responsibilities, including compliance with KRS 194A.705(2) and (3); and </section><section prefix="14">Grievance policies that minimally address issues related to confidentiality of complaints and the process for resolving grievances between the client and the assisted-living community. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6702</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>