<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.230</section_number><catch_line>Controlled substances -- Possession, forfeiture, disposition -- Records, inspection. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text>All controlled substances, the lawful possession of which is not established or the title to which cannot be ascertained, which have come into the custody of a peace officer, shall be forfeited and disposed of as follows: <section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the court having jurisdiction shall order such controlled substances forfeited and destroyed. A record of the place where said drugs were seized, of the kinds and quantities of drugs so destroyed, and of the time, place, and manner of destruction, shall be kept. </section><section prefix="2">The court by whom the forfeiture of controlled substances has been decreed may order the delivery of same to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for destruction. Practitioners, pharmacists, hospitals, and nursing homes may voluntarily surrender controlled substances to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for destruction. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall keep a record of all substances received and of all substances disposed of, showing the exact kinds, quantities, and forms of such substances, the persons from whom received and the time, place, and manner of destruction. </section><section prefix="4">Prescriptions, orders, and records, required by this chapter, and stocks of controlled substances, shall be open for inspection only to federal, state, county, and municipal officers, whose duty it is to enforce the laws of this state or of the United States relating to controlled substances. </section><section prefix="5">No pharmacist, practitioner, manufacturer, or wholesaler or other custodian of records, prescriptions, or orders required by this chapter shall refuse to permit the inspection thereof by any federal, state, county or municipal officer whose duty it is to enforce the laws of this state or of the United States relating to controlled substances. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 545, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 486, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, secs. 24 and  25. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>