<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="363" order_by="363">WEIGHTS, MEASURES, AND MILLERS' TOLLS </unit></structure><section_number>363.630</section_number><catch_line>Spot checks of commodities offered for sale. </catch_line><order_by>630</order_by><text>The director shall, from time to time, weigh or measure and inspect packages or amounts of commodities kept, offered, or exposed for sale, sold, or in the process of delivery, to determine whether the same contain the amounts represented and whether they be kept, offered, or exposed for sale or sold in accordance with law. When such packages or amounts of commodities are found not to contain the amounts represented, or are found to be kept, offered, or exposed for sale in violation of law, the director may order them off sale and may so mark or tag them as to show them to be illegal. In carrying out the provisions of this section, the director may employ recognized sampling procedures under which the compliance of a given lot of packages will be determined on the basis of the result obtained on a sample selected from and representative of such lot. No person shall:  <section prefix="1">Sell, or keep, offer, or expose for sale, in intrastate commerce, any package or amount of commodity that has been ordered off sale or marked or tagged as provided in this section unless and until such package or amount of commodity has been brought into full compliance with all legal requirements, or  </section><section prefix="2">Dispose of any package or amount of commodity that has been ordered off sale or marked or tagged as provided in this section and that has not been brought into compliance with legal requirements, in any manner, except with the specific approval of the director.  </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 13. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34685</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>