<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.285</section_number><catch_line>Display of choke-saving techniques posters. </catch_line><order_by>285</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each food service establishment, having an on-premises seating capacity of twenty-five (25) persons or more, shall post inside the establishment, in a location conspicuous to employees, a choke-saving techniques poster meeting the following requirements. </section><section prefix="2">The choke-saving techniques poster shall meet the following specifications: <section prefix="a">The poster shall depict through illustration and description procedures for the removal of food which is lodged in a person's throat; and </section><section prefix="b">The techniques illustrated and described shall include, but need not be limited to, the procedures whereby the choking person is grasped around the lower chest and upper abdomen and given a quick jerk, thus putting increased interabdominal pressure on the lungs and expelling the foreign matter. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall produce or requisition the production of the choke-saving techniques poster as provided in this section and shall supply the posters to the local health departments for distribution without cost to food establishments. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 515, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 459, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>