<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6917</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for agency contract. </catch_line><order_by>6917</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An agency contract must be in a record, signed or otherwise authenticated by the parties. </section><section prefix="2">An agency contract must state or contain: <section prefix="a">The amount and method of calculating the consideration to be paid by the student-athlete for services to be provided by the athlete agent under the contract and any other consideration the athlete agent has received or may receive from any other source for entering into the contract or for providing the services; </section><section prefix="b">The name of any person not listed in the application for registration or renewal of registration who will be compensated because the student-athlete signed the agency contract; </section><section prefix="c">A description of any expenses that the student-athlete agrees to reimburse; </section><section prefix="d">A description of the services to be provided to the student-athlete; </section><section prefix="e">The duration of the contract; and </section><section prefix="f">The date of execution. </section></section><section prefix="3">An agency contract must contain, in close proximity to the signature of the student-athlete, a conspicuous notice in boldface type in capital letters stating: WARNING TO STUDENT-ATHLETE IF YOU SIGN THIS CONTRACT: (1) YOU MAY LOSE YOUR ELIGIBILITY TO COMPETE AS A STUDENT-ATHLETE IN YOUR SPORT; (2) IF YOU HAVE AN ATHLETIC DIRECTOR, BOTH YOU AND YOUR ATHLETE AGENT MUST NOTIFY YOUR ATHLETIC DIRECTOR WITHIN 72 HOURS AFTER ENTERING INTO THIS CONTRACT; AND (3) YOU MAY CANCEL THIS CONTRACT WITHIN 14 DAYS AFTER SIGNING IT. CANCELLATION OF THIS CONTRACT MAY NOT REINSTATE YOUR ELIGIBILITY. </section><section prefix="4">An agency contract that does not conform to this section is voidable by the student-athlete. If a student-athlete voids an agency contract, the student-athlete is not required to pay any consideration under the contract or to return any consideration received from the athlete agent to induce the student-athlete to enter into the contract. </section><section prefix="5">The athlete agent shall give a record of the signed or otherwise authenticated agency contract to the student-athlete at the time of execution. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><former-codification>KRS 164.684. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>