<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.910</section_number><catch_line>Unification plan -- Components -- Deadline for completion -- Dissolution of commission.   </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The unification review commission shall study matters relating to the feasibility of forming a unified local government and, if unification is proposed, develop a unification plan consistent with the provisions of the Kentucky Constitution and KRS 67.900 to 67.940. A unification plan shall include: <section prefix="a">The process for establishing the unified local government; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the form, structure, functions, and powers of the proposed unified local government; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the officers of the proposed unified local government and their powers and duties; </section><section prefix="d">A procedure for the orderly and timely transition of specified services, functions, and responsibilities from each affected city and the county to the unified local government; </section><section prefix="e">A procedure for the orderly transition to the unified local government of the services, functions, and responsibilities of any special district that will be eliminated; </section><section prefix="f">A procedure for the orderly transition to the unified local government of the services, functions, and responsibilities of any board, commission, or authority that will be eliminated; </section><section prefix="g">The procedures by which the unification plan may be amended by the subsequently created unified local government; </section><section prefix="h">The procedures by which the unification plan may be amended by the participating county and city or cities as a result of contingencies arising from the failure of certain jurisdictions to vote in favor of joining the unification plan. The contingency plan shall be adopted by the participating county and city or cities by joint ordinance. The contingency plan shall be adopted by the participating county and city or cities within sixty (60) days of the certification of the election result. The contingency plan shall only address: <section prefix="1">Issues of revenue; </section><section prefix="2">Issues of indebtedness; </section><section prefix="3">Issues of service provision, service areas, or service area boundaries; </section><section prefix="4">Personnel or administration, but may not infringe upon any pre-existing collective bargaining agreements in force in participating jurisdictions; and </section><section prefix="5">Any issues directly related to the cost of government or provision of services within the unification plan. </section></section> The contingency plan shall not address issues within the plan related to paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), or (g) of this subsection; and <section prefix="i">The procedures by which the unified local government may be dissolved. The procedures drafted shall include but are not limited to: <section prefix="1">Requirements for a public petition for the dissolution of the unified local government; </section><section prefix="2">The question to be presented to voters for the dissolution of the unified local government; and </section><section prefix="3">Any administrative measures necessary to settle tax and debt issues created by the dissolution of the unified local government. </section></section> The proposed unification plan shall specify that no petition for the dissolution of the unified local government shall be valid until a period of five (5) years has passed from commencement of the first terms of the duly elected officers of the unified local government; and <section prefix="j">Such other provisions as the commission shall determine. </section></section><section prefix="2">The unification review commission may propose a unification plan under which the county and one (1) or more participating cities unite to form a single unit of local government. </section><section prefix="3">The unification plan shall be completed within two (2) years of the commission's appointment. If a majority of the commission members are unable to agree on a plan for unification within the two (2) year period, the unification review commission shall be dissolved by operation of law. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41120</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>