<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.290</section_number><catch_line>Record book to be kept by fire boss -- Report of danger -- Accessibility of records to mine inspector and miner. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text>A suitable record book shall be kept at the mine office of every mine wherein fire bosses are employed, and immediately after the examination of the mine or any portion thereof, by a fire boss, he shall enter and sign a record of the examination in the book with ink. The record shall clearly show the time taken in making the examination, the nature and location of any danger discovered in the mine, and what has been done to correct dangerous conditions. If any danger is discovered, the fire boss shall immediately report its location to the mine foreman, or in his absence to the assistant mine foreman in charge, who shall take immediate action to remove the danger. When a station is located inside a mine the fire boss shall enter and sign a report both in the record book kept there and in a record book in the mine office on the surface. The record books of the licensee shall at all times during working hours be accessible to the mine inspector and the miner or his representative. </text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 21, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 39, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 17. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 27. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-38. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>