<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.220</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for secure juvenile detention facilities -- Decertification. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each person or organization operating a facility shall register with the Department of Juvenile Justice and shall comply with the regulations issued pursuant to KRS 15A.210. </section><section prefix="2">Each organization operating or seeking to operate or expand a facility shall: <section prefix="a">Apply to the Department of Juvenile Justice in a period of time set by administrative regulation prior to the scheduled opening of the facility; </section><section prefix="b">Permit inspection of the facility by the Department of Juvenile Justice not less than thirty (30) days prior to the scheduled opening of the facility; and </section><section prefix="c">Supply to the Department of Juvenile Justice not less than thirty (30) days prior to the scheduled opening of the facility all data, plans, and other materials required by the Department of Juvenile Justice. </section></section><section prefix="3">No facility shall operate except with the approval of the Department of Juvenile Justice. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Juvenile Justice shall have the authority, upon thirty (30) days' written notice to the county judge/executive and jailer of any county that operates a juvenile detention facility and is located within an area served by a state-operated juvenile detention facility, to decertify any juvenile detention facility and that facility shall, at the expiration of the thirty (30) day period, cease detaining juveniles. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 132, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 174, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>