<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.130</section_number><catch_line>Employees may organize, bargain collectively, strike, picket -- Conduct prohibited -- Effect of violence or injury to person or property. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Employees may, free from restraint or coercion by the employers or their agents, associate collectively for self-organization and designate collectively representatives of their own choosing to negotiate the terms and conditions of their employment to effectively promote their own rights and general welfare. Employees, collectively and individually, may strike, engage in peaceful picketing, and assemble collectively for peaceful purposes. </section><section prefix="2">Neither employers or their agents nor employees or associations, organizations or groups of employees shall engage or be permitted to engage in unfair or illegal acts or practices or resort to violence, intimidation, threats or coercion. </section><section prefix="3">Except in instances where violence, personal injury, or damage to property have occurred and such occurrence is supported by an affidavit setting forth the facts and circumstances surrounding such incidents, the employees and their agents shall not be restrained or enjoined from exercising the rights granted them in subsection (1) of this section without a hearing first being held, unless the employees or their agents are engaged in a strike in violation of a "no strike" clause in their labor contract. </section><section prefix="4">Submission of a false affidavit concerning violence, personal injury, or damage to property shall constitute a violation of KRS 523.030.  In the absence of any such affidavit alleging violence, personal injury, or damage injunctions shall be issued only by a Circuit Judge or other justice or judge acting as a Circuit Judge pursuant to law. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599c-28. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32002</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>