<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.775</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </catch_line><order_by>775</order_by><text>As used in KRS 260.775 to 260.845, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Milk Handlers Advisory Board; </section><section prefix="2">"Buy" means the receiving of milk from producers or their agents and paying for the milk on the basis of volume and test, or weight and test; </section><section prefix="3">"Director" means the director of the Agricultural Experiment Station, College of Agriculture, University of Kentucky, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="4">"Handler" means any person who receives, bargains, brokers, or issues payment for or purchases milk from Kentucky permitted producers or the permitted producers' agents; </section><section prefix="5">"Laboratory" means the location or work area where milk analysis or testing takes place; </section><section prefix="6">"Laboratory license" means the license issued to a milk laboratory; </section><section prefix="7">"License to handle" means the license issued to a handler of milk; </section><section prefix="8">"License to sample and weigh" means the license issued to a milk sampler-weigher; </section><section prefix="9">"License to test" means the license issued to a milk tester; </section><section prefix="10">"Location" means each separate business place where permitted producers' milk or milk samples are received, stored, or processed, or where records pertaining to permitted producers' milk tests or payments are kept; </section><section prefix="11">"Milk" means the lacteal secretion and all of its components, obtained by the milking of animals; </section><section prefix="12">"Milk importer" means any person who delivers milk from producers outside the Commonwealth of Kentucky to processors in this state; </section><section prefix="13">"Milk processor" means any location where milk or milk products are collected, handled, processed, stored, pasteurized, bottled, or prepared for distribution by a milk handler; </section><section prefix="14">"Milk receiving station" means any location where producers' raw farm milk is collected, handled, or stored by a milk handler; </section><section prefix="15">"Permitted producer" means any producer issued a permit by the Kentucky Cabinet for Health and Family Services to offer milk for sale; </section><section prefix="16">"Person" shall mean any individual, bargaining agent, broker, processor, milk plant operator, partnership, cooperation, concern, corporation, organization, company, firm, trustee, association, or agent thereof; </section><section prefix="17">"Producer" means any person keeping animals for the production of milk; </section><section prefix="18">"Record" means any information relating to milk weights, tests, transfers, purchases, receipts, and sales; </section><section prefix="19">"Sampler-weigher" means any person who samples, weighs, or measures milk from producers and submits these samples, weights, or measurements for use in determining the price paid for milk; </section><section prefix="20">"Test" means to analyze a milk sample to determine the amount of a milk component or to determine milk quality; </section><section prefix="21">"Tester" means any person who tests milk from permitted producers to determine its components or quality, or submits these tests for use in determining the price paid for milk; </section><section prefix="22">"Transfer station" means any location where farm bulk milk is transferred directly from one (1) tank to another and producers' milk samples are collected, handled, stored, and transported to a laboratory for analysis; and </section><section prefix="23">"Transfer station license" means the license issued to operate a transfer station. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 575, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12633</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>