<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.092</section_number><catch_line>Compensation of sheriffs and other law enforcement officers or agencies for attending court and providing security services -- Rates. </catch_line><order_by>092</order_by><text>Compensation of sheriffs and other law enforcement officers or agencies for attending court shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Compensation shall be provided only for the actual time for which the sheriff or other officer is ordered to be physically present in the courtroom or is ordered to be physically present to discharge a duty ordered by the Chief Circuit Judge, Chief District Judge, or Judge of the Court of Appeals, as appropriate. </section><section prefix="2">Compensation shall not be provided for more than one (1) sheriff or other officer per courtroom unless the need for additional personnel is certified in writing by the Chief Circuit Judge, Chief District Judge, or Judge of the Court of Appeals, as appropriate, and the utilization of additional personnel is approved by the Chief Justice, or his designee. In the event of an emergency of such nature precluding contacting the Chief Justice or his designee, the Chief Circuit Judge, Chief District Judge, or Judge of the Court of Appeals may authorize such assignment of additional personnel for a period not to exceed twenty-four (24) hours. </section><section prefix="3">Where a single sheriff or other law enforcement officer serves more than one (1) court or courtroom during a single day, he shall be paid as if he had served only one (1) courtroom during that day. Dual compensation for service during a single day shall not be permitted. </section><section prefix="4">Time, for compensation purposes, shall be computed as the actual time spent in the courtroom pursuant to court direction or order and the actual time spent in other service to the court as directed or ordered by the appropriate judge. </section><section prefix="5">Time spent in court service by a sheriff or other law enforcement officer shall be certified by the judge of the court which the officer attended and by the Chief Judge of the Circuit Court, if the service was to the Circuit Court, or by the Chief Judge of the District Court, if the service was to the District Court. </section><section prefix="6">The sheriff or other law enforcement officer serving a Circuit or District Court shall be compensated at the rate of eight dollars ($8) per hour of service. If service is for a part of an hour, then compensation for such service shall be prorated for the actual number of minutes' service within a given hour. </section><section prefix="7">The sheriff shall receive the disbursements provided for in KRS 42.320(2)(i) to help defray the cost of providing security services and related activities to the court. The moneys received by the sheriff under this subsection are authorized official expenses to be considered operating expenses of the sheriff's office and shall not be considered as part of his compensation. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 10, effective August 1, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 188, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 63, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, F, 5, (2) at 640. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 64.348. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23194</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>