<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="527" order_by="527">OFFENSES RELATING TO FIREARMS AND WEAPONS </unit></structure><section_number>527.020</section_number><catch_line>Carrying concealed deadly weapon. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of carrying a concealed weapon when he or she carries concealed a firearm or other deadly weapon on or about his or her person. </section><section prefix="2">Peace officers and certified court security officers, when necessary for their protection in the discharge of their official duties; United States mail carriers when actually engaged in their duties; and agents and messengers of express companies, when necessary for their protection in the discharge of their official duties, may carry concealed weapons on or about their person. </section><section prefix="3">The director of the Division of Law Enforcement in the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, conservation officers of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, and policemen directly employed by state, county, city, or urban-county governments may carry concealed deadly weapons on or about their person at all times within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, when expressly authorized to do so by law or by the government employing the officer. </section><section prefix="4">Persons, except those specified in subsection (5) of this section, licensed to carry a concealed deadly weapon pursuant to KRS 237.110 may carry a firearm or other concealed deadly weapon on or about their persons at all times within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, if the firearm or concealed deadly weapon is carried in conformity with the requirements of that section. Unless otherwise specifically provided by the Kentucky Revised Statutes or applicable federal law, no criminal penalty shall attach to carrying a concealed firearm or other deadly weapon with a permit at any location at which an unconcealed firearm or other deadly weapon may be constitutionally carried. No person or organization, public or private, shall prohibit a person licensed to carry a concealed deadly weapon from possessing a firearm, ammunition, or both, or other deadly weapon in his or her vehicle in compliance with the provisions of KRS 237.110 and 237.115. Any attempt by a person or organization, public or private, to violate the provisions of this subsection may be the subject of an action for appropriate relief or for damages in a Circuit Court or District Court of competent jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The following persons, if they hold a license to carry a concealed deadly weapon pursuant to KRS 237.110 or 237.138 to 237.142, may carry a firearm or other concealed deadly weapon on or about their persons at all times and at all locations within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, without any limitation other than as provided in this subsection: <section prefix="1">A Commonwealth's attorney or assistant Commonwealth's attorney; </section><section prefix="2">A retired Commonwealth's attorney or retired assistant Commonwealth's attorney; </section><section prefix="3">A county attorney or assistant county attorney; </section><section prefix="4">A retired county attorney or retired assistant county attorney; </section><section prefix="5">A justice or judge of the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="6">A retired or senior status justice or judge of the Court of Justice; and </section><section prefix="7">A retired peace officer who holds a concealed deadly weapon license issued pursuant to the federal Law Enforcement Officers Safety Act, 18 U.S.C. sec. 926C, and KRS 237.138 to 237.142. </section></section><section prefix="b">The provisions of this subsection shall not authorize a person specified in this subsection to carry a concealed deadly weapon in a detention facility as defined in KRS 520.010 or on the premises of a detention facility without the permission of the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the facility, or the permission of a person authorized by the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the detention facility to give such permission. As used in this section, "detention facility" does not include courtrooms, facilities, or other premises used by the Court of Justice or administered by the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section><section prefix="c">A person specified in this section who is issued a concealed deadly weapon license shall be issued a license which bears on its face the statement that it is valid at all locations within the Commonwealth of Kentucky and may have such other identifying characteristics as determined by the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Except provided in this subsection, the following persons may carry concealed deadly weapons on or about their person at all times and at all locations within the Commonwealth of Kentucky: <section prefix="1">An elected sheriff and full-time and part-time deputy sheriffs certified pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404 when expressly authorized to do so by the unit of government employing the officer; </section><section prefix="2">An elected jailer and a deputy jailer who has successfully completed Department of Corrections basic training and maintains his or her current in-service training when expressly authorized to do so by the jailer; and </section><section prefix="3">The department head or any employee of a corrections department in any jurisdiction where the office of elected jailer has been merged with the office of sheriff who has successfully completed Department of Corrections basic training and maintains his or her current in-service training when expressly authorized to do so by the unit of government by which he or she is employed. </section></section><section prefix="b">The provisions of this subsection shall not authorize a person specified in this subsection to carry a concealed deadly weapon in a detention facility as defined in KRS 520.010 or on the premises of a detention facility without the permission of the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the facility, or the permission of a person authorized by the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the detention facility to give such permission. As used in this section, "detention facility" does not include courtrooms, facilities, or other premises used by the Court of Justice or administered by the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">A full-time paid peace officer of a government agency from another state or territory of the United States or an elected sheriff from another territory of the United States may carry a concealed deadly weapon in Kentucky, on or off duty, if the other state or territory accords a Kentucky full-time paid peace officer and a Kentucky elected sheriff the same rights by law. If the other state or territory limits a Kentucky full-time paid peace officer or elected sheriff to carrying a concealed deadly weapon while on duty, then that same restriction shall apply to a full-time paid peace officer or elected sheriff from that state or territory. </section><section prefix="b">The provisions of this subsection shall not authorize a person specified in this subsection to carry a concealed deadly weapon in a detention facility as defined in KRS 520.010 or on the premises of a detention facility without the permission of the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the facility, or the permission of a person authorized by the warden, jailer, or other person in charge of the detention facility to give such permission. As used in this section, "detention facility" does not include courtrooms, facilities, or other premises used by the Court of Justice or administered by the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section></section><section prefix="8">A loaded or unloaded firearm or other deadly weapon shall not be deemed concealed on or about the person if it is located in any enclosed container, compartment, or storage space installed as original equipment in a motor vehicle by its manufacturer, including but not limited to a glove compartment, center console, or seat pocket, regardless of whether said enclosed container, storage space, or compartment is locked, unlocked, or does not have a locking mechanism. No person or organization, public or private, shall prohibit a person from keeping a loaded or unloaded firearm or ammunition, or both, or other deadly weapon in a vehicle in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. Any attempt by a person or organization, public or private, to violate the provisions of this subsection may be the subject of an action for appropriate relief or for damages in a Circuit Court or District Court of competent jurisdiction. This subsection shall not apply to any person prohibited from possessing a firearm pursuant to KRS 527.040. </section><section prefix="9">The provisions of this section shall not apply to a person who carries a concealed deadly weapon on or about his or her person without a license issued pursuant to KRS 237.110: <section prefix="a">If he or she is the owner of the property or has the permission of the owner of the property, on real property which he or she or his or her spouse, parent, grandparent, or child owns; </section><section prefix="b">If he or she is the lessee of the property or has the permission of the lessee of the property, on real property which he or she or his or her spouse, parent, grandparent, or child occupies pursuant to a lease; or </section><section prefix="c">If he or she is the sole proprietor of the business, on real property owned or leased by the business. </section></section><section prefix="10">Carrying a concealed weapon is a Class A misdemeanor, unless the defendant has been previously convicted of a felony in which a deadly weapon was possessed, used, or displayed, in which case it is a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 14, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 329, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 17, effective March 31, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 3, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 235, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43448</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>