<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="82" order_by="82">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>82.700</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 82.700 to 82.725. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>As used in KRS 82.700 to 82.725: <section prefix="1">"Abatement costs" means a local government's costs for and associated with cleaning, preventing unauthorized entry to, or demolishing all or a portion of a structure or premises, or taking any other action with regard to a structure or premises to maintain and preserve public health, safety, and welfare in accordance with the portion of a local government's nuisance code pertaining to the condition of and maintenance of structures or premises, adopted pursuant to KRS 82.700 to 82.725 or 381.770; </section><section prefix="2">"Local government" means a consolidated local government, county, urban-county government, charter county government, unified local government, or a city of any class; </section><section prefix="3">"Hearing board" means a body established by ordinance and empowered to conduct hearings pursuant to KRS 82.710 and composed of one (1) or more persons appointed by the mayor, county judge/executive, or chief executive officer of the local government. "Hearing board" also means any hearing officers appointed by the board. Any action of a hearing officer shall be deemed to be the action of the board; </section><section prefix="4">"Owner" means a person, association, corporation, partnership, or other legal entity having a legal or equitable title in real property; </section><section prefix="5">"Nuisance code" means an ordinance or ordinances enacted by a local government pursuant to KRS 82.705 or 381.770; and </section><section prefix="6">"Premises" means a lot, plot, or parcel of land, including any structures upon it. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 97, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>