<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="338" order_by="338">OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH OF EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>338.015</section_number><catch_line>Definitions and applicability. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Employer" shall mean any entity for whom a person is employed except those employers excluded in KRS 338.021; </section><section prefix="2">"Employee" shall mean any person employed except those employees excluded in KRS 338.021; </section><section prefix="3">The term "occupational safety and health standard" means a standard which requires conditions, or the adoption or use of one (1) or more practices, means, methods, operations, or processes, reasonably necessary or appropriate to provide safe or healthful employment and places of employment. "Standard" has the same meaning as and includes the words "regulation" and "rule"; </section><section prefix="4">"Occupational safety and health hazard" means any practice or condition in a place of employment which may be deemed detrimental to the safety and health of employees; </section><section prefix="5">"Occupational injury or illness" means any abnormal condition or disorder of an employee caused by exposure to factors associated with his or her employment; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Standards Board established under this chapter; </section><section prefix="7">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards under the direction and supervision of the secretary of the Labor Cabinet; </section><section prefix="8">"Review commission" means the Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission established under this chapter; </section><section prefix="9">The term "national consensus standard" means any occupational safety and health standard or modification thereof which has been adopted and promulgated by a nationally recognized standards-producing organization; </section><section prefix="10">The term "established federal standard" means any operative occupational safety and health standard established by any agency of the United States government; </section><section prefix="11">"Department" means the Department of Workplace Standards; and </section><section prefix="12">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Labor Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1751, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 37, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>