<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.125</section_number><catch_line>Procedure and form for candidate to get name on primary ballot -- Form in which name may appear on ballot. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 118.155, any person who is qualified under the provisions of KRS 116.055 to vote in any primary for the candidates for nomination by the party at whose hands he or she seeks the nomination, shall have his or her name printed on the official ballot of his or her party for an office to which he is eligible in that primary, upon filing, with the Secretary of State or county clerk, as appropriate, at the proper time, a notification and declaration. </section><section prefix="2">The notification and declaration shall be in the form prescribed by the State Board of Elections. It shall be signed by the candidate and by not less than two (2) registered voters of the same party from the district or jurisdiction from which the candidate seeks nomination.Signatures for nomination papers shall not be affixed on the document to be filed prior to the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the office will appear on the ballot. <section prefix="a">The notification and declaration for a candidate for an office other than Governor or Lieutenant Governor shall include the following oath: </section>  "For the purpose of having my name placed on the official primary election ballot as a candidate for nomination by the ------ Party, I, ------ (name in full as desired on the ballot as provided in KRS 118.129), do solemnly swear that my residence address is ----- (street, route, highway, city if applicable, county, state, and zip code), that my mailing address, if different, is ----- (post office address), and that I am a registered ------ (party) voter in ------ precinct; that I believe in the principles of the ------ Party, and intend to support its principles and policies; that I meet all the statutory and constitutional qualifications for the office which I am seeking; that if nominated as a candidate of such party at the ensuing election I will accept the nomination and not withdraw for reasons other than those stated in KRS 118.105(3); that I will not knowingly violate any election law or any law relating to corrupt and fraudulent practice in campaigns or elections in this state, and if finally elected I will qualify for the office."  The declaration shall be subscribed and sworn to before an officer authorized to administer an oath by the candidate and by the two (2) voters making the declaration and signing the candidate's petition for office. <section prefix="b">The notification and declaration for a slate of candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor shall include the following oath: </section>  "For the purpose of having our names placed on the official primary election ballot as a slate of candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor for nomination by the ------ Party, I, ------, (name of candidate for Governor in full as desired on the ballot as provided in KRS 118.129), do solemnly swear that my residence address is ----- (street, route, highway, city if applicable, county, state, and zip code), that my mailing address, if different, is ----- (post office address), and that I am a registered ------ (party) voter in ------ precinct; and I, ------, (name of candidate for Lieutenant Governor in full as desired on the ballot as provided in KRS 118.129), do solemnly swear that my residence address is ----- (street, route, highway, city if applicable, county, state, and zip code), that my mailing address, if different, is ----- (post office address), and that I am a registered ------ (party) voter in ------ precinct; that we believe in the principles of the ------ Party, and intend to support its principles and policies; that we meet all the statutory and constitutional qualifications for the offices which we are seeking; that we will accept the nomination and not withdraw for reasons other than those stated in KRS 118.105(3); that we will not knowingly violate any election law or any law relating to corrupt or fraudulent practice in campaigns or elections in this state, and if finally elected we will qualify for our offices."  The declaration shall be subscribed and sworn to before an officer authorized to administer an oath by the candidate and by the two (2) voters making the declaration and signing the petition for office. </section><section prefix="3">When the notice and declaration has been filed with the Secretary of State or county clerk, as appropriate, and certified according to KRS 118.165, the Secretary of State or county clerk, as appropriate, shall have the candidate's name printed on the ballot according to the provisions of this chapter, except as provided in KRS 118.185. </section><section prefix="4">Titles, ranks, or spurious phrases shall not be accepted on the filing papers and shall not be printed on the ballots as part of the candidate's name; however, nicknames, initials, and contractions of given names may be acceptable as the candidate's name. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1, effective November 5, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 39, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976; and ch. 54, sec. 24, effective March 10, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 102, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27576</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>