<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.856</section_number><catch_line>Duties of supervising physician. </catch_line><order_by>856</order_by><text>A supervising physician shall: <section prefix="1">Restrict the services of a physician assistant to services within the physician assistant's scope of practice and to the provisions of KRS 311.840 to 311.862; </section><section prefix="2">Prohibit a physician assistant from prescribing or dispensing controlled substances; </section><section prefix="3">Inform all patients in contact with a physician assistant of the status of the physician assistant; </section><section prefix="4">Post a notice stating that a physician assistant practices medicine or osteopathy in all locations where the physician assistant may practice; </section><section prefix="5">Require a physician assistant to wear identification that clearly states that he or she is a physician assistant; </section><section prefix="6">Prohibit a physician assistant from independently billing any patient or other payor for services rendered by the physician assistant; </section><section prefix="7">If necessary, participate with the governing body of any hospital or other licensed health care facility in a credentialing process established by the facility; </section><section prefix="8">Not require a physician assistant to perform services or other acts that the physician assistant feels incapable of carrying out safely and properly; </section><section prefix="9">Maintain adequate, active, and continuous supervision of a physician assistant's activities to assure that the physician assistant is performing as directed and complying with the requirements of KRS 311.840 to 311.862 and all related administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="10">Review and countersign a sufficient number of overall medical notes written by the physician assistant to ensure quality of care provided by the physician assistant but, at a minimum, a supervising physician shall review and countersign at least ten percent (10%) of these overall medical notes every thirty (30) days. A countersignature shall not be required prior to orders being executed; </section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">Reevaluate the reliability, accountability, and professional knowledge of a physician assistant two (2) years after the physician assistant's original licensure in this Commonwealth and every two (2) years thereafter; and </section><section prefix="b">Based on the reevaluation, recommend approval or disapproval of licensure or renewal to the board; and </section></section><section prefix="12">Notify the board within three (3) business days if the supervising physician: <section prefix="a">Ceases to supervise or employ the physician assistant; or </section><section prefix="b">Believes in good faith that a physician assistant violated any disciplinary rule of KRS 311.840 to 311.862 or related administrative regulations. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 31, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 11, provides: "A physician assistant who is certified in Kentucky and in good standing on the effective date of this Act [July 12, 2006] shall automatically be licensed under Sections 1 to 10 of this Act [KRS 311.840, 311.842, 311.844, 311.845, 311.846, 311.848, 311.850, 311.852, 311.856, and 311.862] and shall be issued a physician assistant license upon annual renewal."  (7/15/2002).  Although 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 31, subsection (1), has a reference to "Sections 32 to 34 of this Act" (which sections were codified as KRS 311.858 and 311.862) that reference has been codified as KRS 311.840 to 311.862" as the reference to "Sections 32..." was a manifest clerical or typographical error that should have read "Sections 23..." and has been corrected in codification under KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43235</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>