<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Prosthetics, Orthotics, and Pedorthics -- Membership -- Appointment -- Terms -- Meetings and quorum -- Limitation of liability -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The Kentucky Board of Prosthetics, Orthotics, and Pedorthics is hereby established. The board shall consist of five (5) members who shall be appointed by the Governor. <section prefix="1">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is a consumer of orthotic, prosthetic, or pedorthic professional services and is not affiliated with and does not have more than five percent (5%) financial interest in any one (1) health care profession or business. </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) members shall be practicing, licensed orthotists, licensed prosthetists, or licensed pedorthists. These members may be licensed in more than one (1) discipline and at least one (1) board member shall be a licensed pedorthist. Membership of the board shall reasonably reflect representation from the geographic areas in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Each member of the board shall serve a term of three (3) years, except that of the initial appointments to the board, two (2) members shall be appointed for two (2) years, two (2) members shall be appointed for three (3) years, and one (1) member shall be appointed for one (1) year. No member of the board shall serve more than the greater of eight (8) consecutive years or two (2) full terms. The Governor may remove any member of the board for misconduct, incompetence, or neglect of duty. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall meet at least annually and may meet at other times if necessary to complete required business. A quorum of the board shall consist of a majority of board members currently appointed. The board shall annually elect a chairperson and vice chairperson who shall be licensed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">There shall be no liability on the part of, and no action for damages against, any current or former board member, representative, agent, or employee of the board, when the person is acting with ordinary care, is functioning within the scope of board duties, is acting without malice, and has the reasonable belief that the actions taken by him or her are warranted by law. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the board shall receive a per diem reimbursement of reasonable expenses incurred as determined by the board in consultation with the Office of Occupations and Professions for each day actually engaged in the duties of the office. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Division of Occupations and Professions" in subsection (6) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 3, has been changed in codification to the "Office of Occupations and Professions" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31278</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>