<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.313</section_number><catch_line>Duties as to information concerning Kentucky family cemeteries and as to gravesites of historically significant people -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>313</order_by><text>In addition to the responsibilities set forth in KRS 171.311, the Kentucky Historical Society shall: <section prefix="1">Collect, maintain, preserve, categorize, and cause to be published necessary information concerning Kentucky family cemeteries; </section><section prefix="2">Undertake a systematic program which will restore and maintain the gravesites of any of the following historically significant people who are buried within this Commonwealth: <section prefix="a">Past Governors of the Commonwealth and their spouses; </section><section prefix="b">The three (3) former Vice Presidents of the United States from the Commonwealth: Richard M. Johnson; John C. Breckinridge; and Alben W. Barkley; and </section><section prefix="c">The "First Pioneers," who were the original members in the first settlements at either Boonesboro, Harrodsburg, or Stanford in 1774-1775; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the purposes of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>