<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.329</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensed Diabetes Educators. </catch_line><order_by>329</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Board of Licensed Diabetes Educators consisting of five (5) members who shall be appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be a licensed medical physician with experience in the delivery of diabetes education appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a registered nurse with experience in diabetes education appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Board of Nursing; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a pharmacist experienced in diabetes education, licensed under KRS Chapter 315, and appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be a licensed dietitian or certified nutritionist with experience in diabetes education appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Board of Licensure and Certification for Dietitians and Nutritionists; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not employed in the health care field. </section></section> One (1) of the members appointed under paragraph (b), (c), or (d) of this subsection shall have completed either the credentialing program of the American Association of Diabetes Educators or the National Certification Board for Diabetes Educators. <section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Governor shall initially appoint one (1) member and the citizen at large to terms of four (4) years, two (2) members to terms of three (3) years, and one (1) member to a term of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="b">All reappointments to the board shall be for terms of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="c">No member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms and shall serve on the board until his or her successor is appointed. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall organize annually and elect one (1) of its members as chair and one (1) of its members as secretary. A quorum of the board shall consist of three (3) members. The board shall meet at least semiannually and upon the call of the chair, or at the request of two (2) or more members to the secretary of the board. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall be placed for administrative purposes under the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39845</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>