<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78">COUNTY EMPLOYEES' CIVIL SERVICE AND RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>78.435</section_number><catch_line>Political activities forbidden. </catch_line><order_by>435</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No officer or employee covered by the provisions of KRS 78.400 to 78.460 shall directly or indirectly solicit or receive or be in any manner whatever concerned in receiving, soliciting or publicizing any assessment, gift, subscription or contribution to or for any political party or candidate for public office. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall use or promise to use his personal influence or official authority to secure any appointment or promotion to any position of employment covered by the provisions of KRS 78.400 to 78.460, as a reward or return for personal or partisan political service. No candidate applying for original appointment or promotion to any position of employment covered by KRS 78.400 to 78.460 shall sign or execute or promise to sign or execute a resignation dated or undated in advance of such appointment or promotion. No officer or employee covered by the provisions of KRS 78.400 to 78.460 shall be suspended, laid-off, demoted, promoted, fined, disciplined or threatened, or in any way changed in rank, duty or compensation for withholding or neglecting to pay or make any contribution of any sort, or character, either in money, goods or services or anything of value for any political purpose whatsoever. </section><section prefix="3">No examination question in any examination held by the board shall relate to any political or religious opinion, belief, affiliation or service and no appointment, promotion, demotion, suspension, fine or removal shall be brought about, effected, affected or influenced by such opinions, beliefs, affiliations or services. </section><section prefix="4">No officer or employee covered by KRS 78.400 to 78.460 shall foster, promote, or be concerned with any actions involving political or religious controversies or prejudices while in uniform. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing contained in KRS 78.400 to 78.460 shall be so construed as to abridge the rights of any officer or employee with respect to his or her personal opinions or beliefs or right to vote. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 3(4) and (5), effective March 4, 1952. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>