<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.595</section_number><catch_line>Pediatric cancer research trust fund.   </catch_line><order_by>595</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The pediatric cancer research trust fund is hereby created as a separate trust fund. The fund shall be administered by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall receive amounts collected from the income tax checkoff created in KRS 141.445, and any other proceeds from grants, contributions, appropriations, or other moneys made available for the purposes of this fund. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, trust fund amounts not expended at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4">Any interest earned on moneys in the trust fund shall become a part of the trust fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="5">Trust fund moneys shall be used to support pediatric cancer research and treatment for Kentucky patients. Funds shall be administered and distributed by the Pediatric Cancer Research Trust Fund Board established by KRS 211.596 for the purposes directed in this section and KRS 211.596 and 211.597. </section><section prefix="6">Moneys transferred to the trust fund pursuant to KRS 141.445 are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in KRS 211.597. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015; and ch. 108, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This statute was created with identical text in 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 96 and 108, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together.  (6/24/2015). During codification, the Reviser of Statutes has corrected the name of the Pediatric Cancer Research Trust Fund Board in this statute from the way it appeared in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3 and 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, by inserting the inadvertently omitted word "Research" in subsection (5). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44567</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>