<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.455</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Legislative findings -- Kentucky efficient school design trust fund -- Development of guidelines -- Assistance to school districts -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>455</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Life-cycle cost analysis" means to calculate and compare different building designs to identify which is the best investment over the long term. Life-cycle costs include design and construction costs, operating costs, maintenance costs, and repair and replacement costs, adjusted for the time value of money; </section><section prefix="b">"Net zero building" means a building in which the amount of energy provided by on-site renewable energy sources is equal to the amount of energy used by the building; and </section><section prefix="c">"Efficient school design" means a school building design: <section prefix="1">That meets, at a minimum, the requirements of the United States Green Building Council's Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) for schools at the "Certified" level or certification under a comparable system with equivalent requirements or other building performance certification systems, such as the United States Department of Energy's Energy Star program; </section><section prefix="2">That ensures energy savings from a building design that equates to or exceeds ten percent (10%) over the American Society of Heating, Refrigerating, and Air Conditioning Engineers energy standard 90.1-2007; and </section><section prefix="3">For which whole building life-cycle cost analysis illustrates that the design is cost-effective. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly hereby finds that schools that are constructed or renovated using efficient school design are proven effective vehicles for accomplishing some or all of the following beneficial public purposes: <section prefix="a">Lower operating costs and increased asset value; </section><section prefix="b">Reduced waste sent to landfills; </section><section prefix="c">Conservation of energy and water; </section><section prefix="d">Reduced storm drainage runoff; </section><section prefix="e">Healthier, safer environments for occupants; </section><section prefix="f">Reduced emissions of greenhouse gases; and </section><section prefix="g">Improved student attendance and performance by: <section prefix="1">Using the building as a teaching tool; </section><section prefix="2">Using the local environment as a context for curriculum integration; </section><section prefix="3">Providing rigorous, highly relevant, and applied learning; and </section><section prefix="4">Improving productivity by making buildings healthier for occupants, especially through the increased use of natural light. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Department of Education and all school districts undertaking the construction of new school buildings or the major renovation of existing school buildings are strongly encouraged to: <section prefix="a">Meet or exceed efficient school design standards in planning and designing all new buildings and major renovation projects; </section><section prefix="b">Use life-cycle cost analysis to evaluate different design proposals; and </section><section prefix="c">Consider the possibility that each new school building or major renovation of a building could be a net zero building, either during the construction or renovation, or at a later date as resources become available. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky efficient school design trust fund is hereby created as a restricted account to be administered by the Department of Education. </section><section prefix="b">The account may receive contributions, gifts, donations, appropriations, and any other moneys made available for the account. Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the account at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse, but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section. Interest on moneys in the account shall accrue to the account. </section><section prefix="c">Moneys in the account shall be used to offset the initial additional cost, if any, associated with the construction or renovation of school buildings using efficient school design. </section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to prescribe how a local school district may qualify for and use funds from the account created by this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Department of Education shall develop and adopt guidelines for efficient school design, net zero buildings, and life-cycle cost analysis, including the identification of appropriate computer-based simulation programs for use in undertaking life-cycle cost analysis. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Education and the Department for Energy Development and Independence shall assist school districts in: <section prefix="a">Developing methods for measuring ongoing operating savings resulting from the use of efficient school design; </section><section prefix="b">Identifying sources for training for school staff and students to ensure that efficient school design features and components are fully utilized; and </section><section prefix="c">Identifying ways that efficient school design and its energy-saving components can be integrated into the school curriculum. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Department of Education and the Department for Energy Development and Independence shall, by November 1, 2010, and each year thereafter, for the fiscal year ending on June 30 of that year, prepare a report that shall be submitted to the Legislative Research Commission and the Governor. The report shall address new school buildings or building renovations and shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">An assessment of the implementation of efficient school design within Kentucky's education system; </section><section prefix="b">Documented energy savings from any buildings built using efficient school design or net zero school buildings in operation; </section><section prefix="c">A list of the new or renovated school buildings completed or identified for future construction during the prior year using efficient school design, including the name of the school district, name of the school, total project cost, additional cost or savings, if any, associated with efficient school design features, and efficient school design features included in the project; </section><section prefix="d">A list of all school buildings that operate as a net zero building, and school buildings which school districts plan to convert to net zero. The list shall include the name of the school district, the name of the school, the total cost associated with the school building becoming a net zero building, and the components that will be installed to make the building a net zero building; </section><section prefix="e">Any recommendations relating to efficient school design; and </section><section prefix="f">A list of new school buildings completed during the prior year without using efficient school design and an explanation of why efficient school design was not used. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3331</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>