<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.175</section_number><catch_line>Services by a physician assistant or advanced practice registered nurse for patient admitted to acute care or psychiatric hospital -- Transferability of history and physical examination to another licensed level of care within same hospital -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A physician assistant, credentialed under KRS Chapter 311, when those duties and responsibilities are within the scope of training received in an approved program and within the scope of the supervising physician's practice, or an advanced practice registered nurse licensed under KRS Chapter 314, may: <section prefix="a">Perform a history and physical examination for a patient admitted to an acute care or psychiatric hospital licensed under this chapter; and </section><section prefix="b">Order and review continuation of restraints and seclusion as a health care practitioner in accordance with 42 C.F.R. 482.13. </section></section><section prefix="2">A history and physical examination shall be performed no more than thirty (30) days before or twenty-four (24) hours after a patient is admitted to an acute care or psychiatric hospital licensed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The history and physical examination that has been performed in compliance with subsection (2) of this section is transferable to another licensed level of care within the same hospital. </section><section prefix="4">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish the content of the history and physical examination required by subsection (2) of this section performed in an acute or psychiatric hospital that shall be used by the licensing entity. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 39, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 506, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 422, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9232</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>