<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.105</section_number><catch_line>Sourcing of retail sales -- Communications services, digital property, and florist wire sales. </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">For purposes of the retailer's obligation to pay or collect and remit the taxes imposed by KRS 139.200 and 139.310, the retailer shall source retail sales not addressed in subsections (2), (3), and (4) of this section as follows: <section prefix="1">Over the counter. When the purchaser receives tangible personal property, digital property, or service at a business location of the retailer, the sale is sourced to that business location; </section><section prefix="2">Delivery to a specified address. When a purchaser or purchaser's donee receives tangible personal property, digital property, or service at a location specified by the purchaser, the sale is sourced to that location; or </section><section prefix="3">Address unknown. When the retailer of a product does not know the address where the tangible personal property, digital property, or service is received, the sale is sourced to the first address listed in this paragraph that is known to the retailer: <section prefix="a">The address of the purchaser; </section><section prefix="b">The billing address of the purchaser; </section><section prefix="c">The address of the purchaser's payment instrument; or </section><section prefix="d">The address from which the tangible personal property was shipped; from which the computer software delivered electronically or the digital property transferred electronically was first available for transmission by the retailer; or from which the service was provided, disregarding for these purposes any location that merely provided the actual digital transfer of the product sold. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">Nothing included in this subsection shall affect the obligation of a purchaser to remit use tax pursuant to KRS 139.310. </section></section><section prefix="2">The retailer shall source communications services as follows: <section prefix="a">A sale of mobile telecommunications services, other than air-ground radiotelephone service and prepaid wireless calling service, shall be sourced to the customer's or other purchaser's place of primary use; </section><section prefix="b">A sale of postpaid calling service shall be sourced to the origination point of the telecommunications signal as first identified by either the retailer's telecommunications system or information received by the retailer from its service provider, where the system used to transport the signals is not that of the retailer; </section><section prefix="c">A sale of prepaid calling service or a sale of a prepaid wireless calling service shall be sourced according to the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. If the sale is of a prepaid wireless calling service and the retailer does not know the address where the service is received, the sale shall be sourced to the first of the following that is known by the retailer: <section prefix="1">The address of the customer available from the business records of the retailer; </section><section prefix="2">The billing address of the customer; </section><section prefix="3">The address from which the service was provided; or </section><section prefix="4">The location associated with the mobile telephone number; </section></section><section prefix="d">A sale of a private communications service shall be sourced as follows: <section prefix="1">Service for a separate charge related to a customer channel termination point shall be sourced to each level of jurisdiction in which the customer channel termination point is located. </section><section prefix="2">Service where all customer termination points are located entirely within one (1) jurisdiction or levels of jurisdiction is sourced in the jurisdiction in which the customer channel termination points are located. </section><section prefix="3">Service for segments of a channel between two (2) customer channel termination points located in different jurisdictions and which segments of channel are separately charged shall be sourced fifty percent (50%) in each level of jurisdiction in which the customer channel termination points are located. </section><section prefix="4">Service for segments of a channel located in more than one (1) jurisdiction or levels of jurisdiction and which segments are not separately billed shall be sourced in each jurisdiction based on the percentage determined by dividing the number of customer channel termination points in the jurisdiction by the total number of customer channel termination points; </section></section><section prefix="e">A sale of an ancillary service is sourced to the customer's place of primary use; and </section><section prefix="f">A sale of other communications services: <section prefix="1">Sold on a call-by-call basis shall be sourced based on the taxing jurisdiction where the call either originates or terminates and in which the service address is also located; or </section><section prefix="2">Sold on a basis other than a call-by-call basis shall be sourced to the customer's or other purchaser's place of primary use. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Florist wire sales shall be sourced in accordance with an administrative regulation promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="4">Advertising and promotional direct mail and other direct mail shall be sourced as provided in KRS 139.777. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec 2, effective July 1, 2011. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 23, effective July 1, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005).  Under KRS 7.136(1)(h), the Reviser of Statutes has corrected the capitalization and punctuation of an amendment that was made to subsection (2)(c) of this statute in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>