<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="155" order_by="155">BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>155.080</section_number><catch_line>Membership -- Duty of members -- Loan limit formula. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any financial institution may request membership in the corporation by making application to the board of directors on such form and in such manner as said board of directors may require, and membership shall become effective upon acceptance of such application by said board. </section><section prefix="2">Except for short term loans which members may make at their discretion, each member of the corporation shall make loans to the corporation as and when called upon by it to do so on such terms and other conditions as shall be approved from time to time by the board of directors, subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">All loan limits shall be established at the thousand dollar ($1,000) amount nearest to the amount computed in accordance with the provisions of this section; </section><section prefix="b">No loan to the corporation shall be made if immediately thereafter the total amount of the obligations of the corporation would exceed twenty (20) times the amount then paid in on the outstanding capital stock of the corporation; and </section><section prefix="c">The total amount outstanding on loan to the corporation made by any member at any one (1) time when added to the amount of the investment in the capital stock of the corporation then held by such member shall not exceed the following limit, to be determined as of the time such member becomes a member on the basis of the audited balance sheet of such member at the close of its fiscal year immediately preceding its application for membership, or, in the case of an insurance company, its last annual statement to the commissioner of insurance: <section prefix="1">Two percent (2%) of the capital and surplus of commercial banks and trust companies; </section><section prefix="2">One percent (1%) of the total outstanding loans made by a building and loan association: provided, however, that any business development corporation created pursuant to this section, KRS 155.010 and 155.090 may in its articles of incorporation, or by appropriate amendment thereto, provide that the loan limit of a building and loan association member shall be only one-half of one percent (0.5%) of the total outstanding loans made by such building and loan association member; </section><section prefix="3">One percent (1%) of the capital and unassigned surplus of stock insurance companies, except fire insurance writing companies; </section><section prefix="4">One percent (1%) of the unassigned surplus of mutual insurance companies, except fire insurance writing companies; </section><section prefix="5">One-tenth of one percent (0.1%) of the assets of fire insurance writing companies; and </section><section prefix="6">Such limits as may be approved by the board of directors of the corporation for other financial institutions. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 208, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 9. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 212, ch. 2 -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 1 -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  The Reviser of Statutes has restructured subsection (2)(c) under the authority of KRS 7.136. No substantive change has been made. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>