<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.090</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on driving. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except when driving under a commercial driver's instruction permit and accompanied by the holder of commercial driver's license valid for the vehicle being driven, no person shall drive a commercial motor vehicle on the highways of this state unless the person holds a valid commercial driver's license with applicable endorsements valid for the vehicle he or she is driving. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall drive a commercial motor vehicle on the highways of this state while his or her driving privilege for a commercial or noncommercial motor vehicle is suspended, revoked, or canceled, or while he or she is subject to a disqualification, or in violation of an out-of-service order. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee shall have in his or her immediate possession at all times when operating a motor vehicle his or her commercial driver's license, and shall display the license upon demand to a circuit clerk, a license examiner, a peace officer, a State Police officer, or an inspector or officer of the Department of Vehicle Regulation. It shall be a defense to a violator of this subsection if the person so charged produces in court a commercial driver's license, issued to him or her before his or her arrest or violation and which was valid at that time. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 20, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 286, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14467</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>