<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.990Penalties.</section_number><catch_line>183.990Penalties. repealed</catch_line><order_by>990Penalties.</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person violating any of the provisions of this chapter with respect to operation of aircraft, or violating the provisions of any rule, regulation, or ordinance adopted under KRS 183.133(6), shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) or imprisoned not more than ninety (90) days or both. </section><section prefix="2">Each violation of the statutes pertaining to the state airport zoning commission or of any order, rule, or regulation promulgated pursuant thereto shall be punishable by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisonment for not more than thirty (30) days or both and each day a violation continues to exist shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 183.886 shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or shall be imprisoned in the county jail for not less than ten (10) nor more than ninety (90) days, or both. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 183.887(2) shall be guilty of: <section prefix="a">A Class A misdemeanor; or </section><section prefix="b">A Class D felony, if the violation causes a significant change of course or a serious disruption to the safe travel of the aircraft that threatens the physical safety of the passengers and crew of the aircraft. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 8(2). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 25. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 82. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 48. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 7. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 165-56. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44637</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>