<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.267</section_number><catch_line>Articles of amendment.   </catch_line><order_by>267</order_by><text>A corporation amending its articles of incorporation shall deliver to the Secretary of State for filing articles of amendment that satisfy KRS 14A.2-010 to 14A.2-150 setting forth: <section prefix="1">The name of the corporation. </section><section prefix="2">The amendment so adopted. </section><section prefix="3">If there are members entitled to vote thereon, (a) a statement setting forth the date of the meeting of members at which the amendment was adopted, that a quorum was present at such meeting, and that such amendment received at least two-thirds (2/3) of the votes which members present at such meeting or represented by proxy were entitled to cast, or (b) a statement that such amendment was adopted by a consent in writing signed by all members entitled to vote with respect thereto. </section><section prefix="4">If there are no members, or no members entitled to vote thereon, a statement of such fact, the date of the meeting of the board of directors at which the amendment was adopted, and a statement of the fact that such amendment received the vote of a majority of the directors in office. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 65, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 202, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 34. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36679</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>