<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.710</section_number><catch_line>Contract requirements. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text>In order to enable cities and counties to fulfill their obligations regarding the public health, safety, and welfare, the General Assembly does hereby allow cities and counties to contract with private persons, partnerships, or corporations for providing ambulance service to the residents of such cities and counties subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="1">These contracts must be in writing and must be approved by the city council or board of aldermen if a city is party thereto, or by the fiscal court in case a county is party thereto. </section><section prefix="2">No contract shall be made with an ambulance service or other organization or person unless the contract shall stipulate that at least one (1) person on each ambulance run shall possess currently valid emergency medical technician certification. </section><section prefix="3">All contracts made with any ambulance service or other organization or person shall stipulate that all vehicles used for operation of the service comply with vehicle and equipment administrative regulations issued by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="4">All contracts shall include the stipulation that at least two (2) trained persons, one (1) driver and one (1) attendant, shall be carried on each ambulance for each ambulance call which is covered by the contract. </section><section prefix="5">No contract shall be made for a period of time greater than one (1) year. </section><section prefix="6">The vehicle, equipment, training, and personnel requirements of subsections (2), (3), and (4) of this section shall also apply to the operation of an ambulance service by a city or a county or by a city and a county jointly. </section><section prefix="7">No provisions of this section shall be construed as to limit the power of any city or county to contract for or operate ambulance services under requirements which are stricter than those of this section, or to require insurance, or bonding of contractors, provided these provisions are not in conflict with the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 109, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 91, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>