<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.886</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of surgical assistant certificate. </catch_line><order_by>886</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall provide for the annual renewal of a surgical assistant certificate. </section><section prefix="2">At least thirty (30) days before the expiration of a person's certificate, the board shall send written notice of the impending certificate expiration to the person at the certificate holder's last known address according to the records of the board. </section><section prefix="3">If the person's certificate has been expired for ninety (90) days or less, the person may renew the certificate by paying the board one and one-half (1-1/2) times the required renewal fee. The person shall not engage in activities that require a certificate until the certificate has been renewed under this section. </section><section prefix="4">If the person's certificate has been expired for longer than ninety (90) days but less than one (1) year, the person may renew the certificate by paying the board two (2) times the required renewal fee. The person shall not engage in activities that require a certificate until the certificate has been renewed under this section. </section><section prefix="5">If the person's certificate has been expired for one (1) year or longer, the person may not renew the certificate. The person may obtain a new certificate by complying with the requirements and procedures for obtaining an original certificate. </section><section prefix="6">If the person was certified as a surgical assistant in this state, moved to another state, and is currently licensed or certified as a surgical assistant and has been in practice as a surgical assistant in the other state for the two (2) years preceding application, the person may renew an expired surgical assistant certificate without reexamination. The person shall pay the board a fee that is equal to two (2) times the required renewal fee for the license. The person shall not engage in activities that require a certificate until the certificate has been renewed under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>