<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.540</section_number><catch_line>Uniform schedule of amounts of bail in designated nonviolent Class D felonies, misdemeanors, and violations. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text>The Supreme Court may by rule or order prescribe a uniform schedule of amounts of bail in designated nonviolent Class D felonies, misdemeanors, and violations; <section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, when the amount of bail is fixed by such rule or order of the Supreme Court for a particular offense, the clerk of the court or other public officers so authorized by the court's order shall accept cash bail in the prescribed amount or the deposit authorized by KRS 431.530 and release the defendant to appear in accordance with the conditions of the bail bond. A receipt shall be delivered to the defendant for the bail so taken and within a reasonable time such bail shall be deposited with the clerk of the court having jurisdiction of the offense. </section><section prefix="2">A court may, in the exercise of its reasonable discretion, refuse to set bail in the amount prescribed by such rule or order of the Supreme Court, but, in so doing, the court must set forth in writing its reasons for such refusal. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18639</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>