<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-255</section_number><catch_line>Tax credits available to investment fund -- Application for approval as manager -- Requirements for investment fund -- Agreement -- Total qualified investments made by fund. </catch_line><order_by>20-255</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The total amount of tax credits available to any single investment fund awarded tax credits under KRS 154.20-250 to 154.20-284 shall not exceed, in aggregate, eight million dollars ($8,000,000) for all investors and all taxable years. </section><section prefix="b">The total tax credits available for all investors in all investment funds awarded under KRS 154.20-250 to 154.20-284, and all qualified investors awarded under KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240, shall not exceed a total of forty million dollars ($40,000,000). </section></section><section prefix="2">A person or entity seeking to be approved as an investment fund manager for the operation of one (1) or more investment funds shall make written application to the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-256, in addition to complying with applicable state and federal securities laws and regulations. </section><section prefix="3">Prior to the granting of any tax credits to investors of an investment fund, the committed cash contributions to an investment fund shall be not less than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). </section><section prefix="4">An investment fund shall have no less than four (4) investors, and no investor or investment fund manager, including their immediate family members, as defined in KRS 164.6011(7), and affiliates may own or have a capital interest in more than forty percent (40%) of the investment fund's capitalization. </section><section prefix="5">Subsequent to approval of the investment fund and the investment fund manager, the authority and the investment fund manager, on behalf of itself and any investors in the investment fund, shall enter into an agreement with respect to the investment fund. The terms and provisions of each agreement shall be determined by negotiations between the authority and the investment fund manager. The effective date of the agreement shall be the date of approval of the investment fund and the investment fund manager by the authority. If an investment fund manager fails to comply with any of the obligations of the agreement, the authority may, at its option, do any one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">Suspend the availability of the credits; </section><section prefix="b">Pursue any remedy provided under the agreement, including termination of the agreement; or </section><section prefix="c">Pursue any other remedy at law to which it may be entitled. </section></section><section prefix="6">Any investor shall be entitled to a tax credit as a result of its investment in an investment fund as provided in KRS 154.20-258. </section><section prefix="7">Total qualified investments made by an investment fund, including initial and subsequent investments made by an investment fund, in any single small business using approved qualified investments, shall not exceed thirty percent (30%) of the committed cash contributions to the investment fund. This restriction shall not apply to investments of money by the investment fund that are not qualified investments. </section><section prefix="8">The provisions of this section shall not prohibit an investment fund from investing in a business that is not a small business, including a business that is located outside of the Commonwealth; however, such investments shall not be eligible for the tax credit set forth in KRS 154.20-258. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 27, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>