<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.6459</section_number><catch_line>Intervention strategies for accelerated learning -- Individualized learning plan -- Retake of ACT. </catch_line><order_by>6459</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A high school student whose scores on the high school readiness examination administered in grade eight (8), on the college readiness examination administered in grade ten (10), or on the WorkKeys indicate that additional assistance or advanced work is required in English, reading, or mathematics shall have intervention strategies for accelerated learning incorporated into his or her learning plan. </section><section prefix="2">A high school student whose score on the ACT examination under KRS 158.6453 (11)(a)3. in English, reading, or mathematics is below the systemwide standard established by the Council on Postsecondary Education for entry into a credit-bearing course at a public postsecondary institution without placement in a remedial course or an entry-level course with supplementary academic support shall be provided the opportunity to participate in accelerated learning designed to address his or her identified academic deficiencies prior to high school graduation. </section><section prefix="3">A high school, in collaboration with its school district, shall develop and implement accelerated learning that: <section prefix="a">Allows a student's learning plan to be individualized to meet the student's academic needs based on an assessment of test results and consultation among parents, teachers, and the student; and </section><section prefix="b">May include changes in a student's class schedule. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Department of Education, the Council on Postsecondary Education, and public postsecondary institutions shall offer support and technical assistance to schools and school districts in the development of accelerated learning. </section><section prefix="5">A student who participates in accelerated learning under this section shall be permitted to take the ACT examination a second time prior to high school graduation at the expense of the Kentucky Department of Education. The cost of any subsequent administrations of the achievement test shall be the responsibility of the student. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 6, effective March 25, 2009. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3559</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>