<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.140</section_number><catch_line>Surplus expenditure plan to be included in each enacted branch budget bill -- Surplus in excess of two and one-half percent to accrue to surplus account. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly shall include in each enacted branch budget bill a plan for the expenditure of a general fund or road fund surplus. </section><section prefix="2">If there is a surplus, the Office of State Budget Director shall notify all branches of government. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in KRS 48.705, any surplus in the general or road fund in excess of two and one-half percent (2.5%) of the enacted estimates shall not be expended but shall accrue to the surplus account of the general fund or road fund for investment until appropriated by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="4">Unless required by the budget reduction provisions in a branch budget bill, no funds shall be transferred from one budget unit to another budget unit. </section><section prefix="5">Surplus funds in any account, unless a statute requires otherwise, shall lapse to the surplus account of the general fund for investment until appropriated by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="6">Funds in the surplus account of the general fund may be used for current expenditures as authorized by the budget reduction provisions of a branch budget bill. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1995 (3d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective November 3, 1995. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 14, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. VII, (1) at 750. See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. IX at 750. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22548</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>