<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.112</section_number><catch_line>Planning process for management and development of water resources. </catch_line><order_by>112</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall develop a comprehensive and systematic planning process for the long-range management and orderly development of the Commonwealth's water resources. The planning process shall generate over each biennium a plan for the implementation of specific goals and management objectives for the cabinet to achieve in meeting the Commonwealth's water needs. The biennial plan shall serve as the basis for the cabinet's budgeting process in allocating resources to the state's water resource programs. The planning process shall be developed to: <section prefix="a">Protect, conserve, develop, and utilize the water resource in a manner consistent with the Commonwealth's duties for management of natural resources, the public's right to clean water, and the preservation of the natural, scenic, cultural, historic, and aesthetic values of the environment; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a coordinated framework for cooperation among federal, interstate, state, and local government agencies in the planning and management of water resources, in a manner consistent with KRS Chapter 147 and KRS 224.10-100(13); </section><section prefix="c">Be both anticipatory of future needs and reactive to problems; </section><section prefix="d">Provide for public involvement in the establishment of the comprehensive and systematic planning process, in plan development and implementation, and the allocation and prioritizing of resources for water resource management and development; and </section><section prefix="e">Establish a process for the collection and coordination of data regarding surface and ground water availability and quality, including the presence of point and nonpoint sources of pollution, instream flow information, withdrawal and use information, an assessment of flood damage and storm water management problems, and an identification and assessment of future data needs. </section></section><section prefix="2">The continuous planning process shall include goals and objectives for ground and surface water quantity and quality management in order to assess the effectiveness of current programs in addressing the comprehensive water needs of the Commonwealth and to gauge the need for new or different programs to recommend to the General Assembly for legislation. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2079</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>