<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.061</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner -- Appointment -- Qualifications -- Term -- Removal -- Compensation -- Oath -- Bond -- Duties -- Annual report -- Authority to appoint additional employees if grant funds available. </catch_line><order_by>061</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall appoint a commissioner of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, who shall be a person with knowledge of and experience in the requirements for the protection, conservation and restoration of the wildlife resources of the state. The commissioner shall serve for a defined employment contract term not to exceed four (4) years and shall be subject to: <section prefix="a">Annual review by the commission in closed, executive session; </section><section prefix="b">Removal by the commission for the same cause and in the same manner in which the Governor may remove a member of the commission; and </section><section prefix="c">Reappointment by the commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall receive such compensation as the commission may determine, and shall be reimbursed for all actual and necessary travel and other expenses incurred by him in the performance of his official duties. </section><section prefix="3">Before entering upon the duties of his office, the commissioner shall take and subscribe to the constitutional oath of office, and shall, in addition thereto, swear or affirm that he holds no other public office, nor any position upon or under any political committee or party. Upon appointment by the commission, the commissioner shall execute a bond of five thousand dollars ($5,000) in favor of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, the premium on said bond to be paid out of department funds. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner shall have general supervision and control of all activities, functions, appointments, and employees of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources. He shall enforce all provisions of the laws of the state relating to wild animals, birds, fish and amphibians, and shall exercise all powers necessarily incident thereto not specifically conferred on the commission. The commissioner shall make an annual report of all receipts and disbursements and file same with the Secretary of State of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">If federal or other grant funds become available to pay their salaries, the commissioner may appoint and employ other persons that he may deem necessary or desirable to accomplish the purposes of this chapter. The commissioner shall determine the compensation, duties, and terms of employment of these employees, and grant funded, time-limited positions shall be approved by the commission as needed. Employees whose salaries are funded through federal or other grant funds shall not be counted in any tally of permanent employees made for employee cap or budgetary purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 28. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 4, effective May 18, 1956. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 8. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>