<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Business" means any corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, firm, enterprise, franchise, association, organization, self-employed individual, holding company, joint stock company, receivership, trust, or any legal entity through which business is conducted, whether or not for profit; </section><section prefix="2">"Commission" means the Executive Branch Ethics Commission; </section><section prefix="3">"Compensation" means any money, thing of value, or economic benefit conferred on, or received by, any person in return for services rendered, or to be rendered, by himself or another; </section><section prefix="4">"Family" means spouse and children, as well as a person who is related to a public servant as any of the following, whether by blood or adoption: parent, brother, sister, grandparent, grandchild, father-in-law, mother-in-law, brother-in-law, sister-in-law, son-in-law, daughter-in-law, stepfather, stepmother, stepson, stepdaughter, stepbrother, stepsister, half brother, half sister; </section><section prefix="5">"Gift" means a payment, loan, subscription, advance, deposit of money, services, or anything of value, unless consideration of equal or greater value is received; "gift" does not include gifts from family members, campaign contributions, or door prizes available to the public; </section><section prefix="6">"Income" means any money or thing of value received or to be received as a claim on future services, whether in the form of a fee, salary, expense allowance, forbearance, forgiveness, interest, dividend, royalty, rent, capital gain, or any other form of compensation or any combination thereof; </section><section prefix="7">"Officer" means all major management personnel in the executive branch of state government, including the secretary of the cabinet, the Governor's chief executive officers, cabinet secretaries, deputy cabinet secretaries, general counsels, commissioners, deputy commissioners, executive directors, principal assistants, division directors, members and full-time chief administrative officers of the Parole Board, Board of Tax Appeals, Board of Claims, Kentucky Retirement Systems board of trustees, Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System board of trustees, Public Service Commission, Worker's Compensation Board and its administrative law judges, the Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission, the Kentucky Board of Education, the Council on Postsecondary Education, and any person who holds a personal service contract to perform on a full-time basis for a period of time not less than six (6) months a function of any position listed in this subsection; </section><section prefix="8">"Official duty" means any responsibility imposed on a public servant by virtue of his or her position in the state service; </section><section prefix="9">"Public servant" means: <section prefix="a">The Governor; </section><section prefix="b">The Lieutenant Governor; </section><section prefix="c">The Secretary of State; </section><section prefix="d">The Attorney General; </section><section prefix="e">The Treasurer; </section><section prefix="f">The Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="g">The Auditor of Public Accounts; and </section><section prefix="h">All employees in the executive branch including officers as defined in subsection (7) of this section and merit employees; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Agency" means every state office, cabinet, department, board, commission, public corporation, or authority in the executive branch of state government. A public servant is employed by the agency by which his or her appointing authority is employed, unless his or her agency is attached to the appointing authority's agency for administrative purposes only, or unless the agency's characteristics are of a separate independent nature distinct from the appointing authority and it is considered an agency on its own, such as an independent department; </section><section prefix="11">"Lobbyist" means any person employed as a legislative agent as defined in KRS 6.611(23) or any person employed as an executive agency lobbyist as defined in KRS 11A.201(8); </section><section prefix="12">"Lobbyist's principal" means the entity in whose behalf the lobbyist promotes, opposes, or acts; </section><section prefix="13">"Candidate" means those persons who have officially filed candidacy papers or who have been nominated by their political party pursuant to KRS 118.105, 118.115, 118.325, or 118.760 for any of the offices enumerated in subsections (9)(a) to (g) of this section; </section><section prefix="14">"Does business with" or "doing business with" means contracting, entering into an agreement, leasing, or otherwise exchanging services or goods with a state agency in return for payment by the state, including accepting a grant, but not including accepting a state entitlement fund disbursement; </section><section prefix="15">"Public agency" means any governmental entity; </section><section prefix="16">"Appointing authority" means the agency head or any person whom he or she has authorized by law to act on behalf of the agency with respect to employee appointments; </section><section prefix="17">"Represent" means to attend an agency proceeding, write a letter, or communicate with an employee of an agency on behalf of someone else; </section><section prefix="18">"Directly involved" means to work on personally or to supervise someone who works on personally; </section><section prefix="19">"Sporting event" means any professional or amateur sport, athletic game, contest, event, or race involving machines, persons, or animals, for which admission tickets are offered for sale and that is viewed by the public; and </section><section prefix="20">"Person" means an individual, proprietorship, firm, partnership, limited partnership, joint venture, joint stock company, syndicate, business or statutory trust, donative trust, estate, company, corporation, limited liability company, association, club, committee, organization, or group of persons acting in concert. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective April 11, 2012; and ch. 81, sec. 77, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 3, effective December 1, 2000; ch. 475, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 542, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 431, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 602, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 149, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 71, effective September 16, 1993. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>