<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.252</section_number><catch_line>Title to and control of park property -- Exemption from taxation -- Use for streets -- Contracts for use of aviation fields -- Control of public ways acquired for park purposes. </catch_line><order_by>252</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The title to all property with all improvements and equipment acquired for park, airport or aviation field purposes, subject to any existing leases thereof, shall be held by the city in strict and inviolable trust for such public purposes, free from all taxation, imposts or assessments by state, county, district, municipal, or other governmental subdivision; but the city may use any portion of such property as is necessary and proper for the construction, extension, or widening of streets, boulevards, thoroughfares or other public ways, and may enter into contracts or agreements, with reference to properties acquired for airport or aviation field purposes, for the use of the field and airport for aviation purposes, with the United States government or any agency thereof, or any state government or any agency thereof, or any board of aviation established under any act of the General Assembly of this Commonwealth, or of any other commonwealth or state, or any individual, firm or corporation. However, it shall at no time and in no way enter into any contract or agreement that prevents its carrying out the main purpose of the establishment and maintenance of a public municipal aviation field and airport, for the general use of the citizens of the city as a park purpose. </section><section prefix="2">Such park property as consists of all connecting parkways and roads or drives between public parks, and all avenues, roads, ways, drives, walks, outside of or on the boundaries of public parks which were or are acquired for park purposes, shall be under the direction, control, maintenance and management of the department of public works of the city, and any such property may be declared by resolution of the board of aldermen to be a part of the public ways of the city. </section></text><history>Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 80. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26383</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>