<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280">PRIVATE TOLL BRIDGES AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>280.150</section_number><catch_line>Ownership or interest in more than one bridge forbidden. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No consolidated corporation of the type mentioned in KRS 280.140 shall at the same time own, possess, lease, control or operate more than one (1) bridge crossing any river forming a boundary line of this state. No person owning, possessing or controlling any bridge crossing a river forming a boundary line of this state, and no agent, officer or stockholder thereof, shall at the same time own, possess, lease or control any bridge constructed by a consolidated corporation of the type mentioned in KRS 280.140. No such consolidated corporation, and no agent, officer or stockholder thereof, shall make or be a party to any contract, agreement, combination or arrangement relating to tolls or fares on any bridge crossing a river forming a boundary line of this state with any person owning, possessing, controlling or operating any other such bridge, or with any agent, officer or stockholder thereof. No stock in any such consolidated corporation shall be subscribed for by, transferred to, or held, possessed or owned by any other corporation owning, possessing, controlling or operating any other bridge crossing, from any point in the same county, a river forming a boundary line of this state, or by any agent, officer or stockholder of such a corporation. Each such consolidated corporation, and its agents, officers and stockholders, are hereby made incapable of and prohibited from holding, possessing or owning stock in any other corporation owning, possessing, controlling or operating any bridge crossing, from any point in the same county, a river forming a boundary line of this state.  </section><section prefix="2">Every contract, agreement, combination or arrangement made, and every act done, in violation of any provision of this section or of KRS 280.140, shall be void.  </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 849, 851. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14252</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>