<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.650</section_number><catch_line>Civil action for relief from discriminatory housing practice or breach of conciliation agreement -- Time limitation. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An aggrieved person may file a civil action in an appropriate Circuit Court not later than two (2) years after the occurrence or the termination of an alleged discriminatory housing practice, or the breach of a conciliation agreement entered into as the result of an alleged discriminatory housing practice, whichever occurs last, to obtain appropriate relief with respect to the discriminatory housing practice or breach. </section><section prefix="2">The computation of the two (2) year period shall not include any time during which an administrative proceeding under this chapter is pending with respect to a complaint or charge of an alleged discriminatory housing practice. This subsection does not apply to actions arising from a breach of a conciliation agreement entered into as a result of an alleged discriminatory housing practice. </section><section prefix="3">An aggrieved person may file a civil action under this section whether or not a complaint has been filed under KRS 344.600, and without regard to the status of any such complaint, but: <section prefix="a">If the commission has obtained a conciliation agreement with the consent of an aggrieved person, the aggrieved person may not file an action under this section with respect to the alleged discriminatory housing practice which forms the basis for the complaint except for the purposes of enforcing the terms of the conciliation agreement; and </section><section prefix="b">An aggrieved person may not file a civil action under this section with respect to an alleged discriminatory housing practice which forms the basis of a charge issued by the commission if the commission has commenced a hearing. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 27, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32670</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>