<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.192</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Livestock Care Standards Commission -- Members. </catch_line><order_by>192</order_by><text>The Kentucky Livestock Care Standards Commission is hereby created to make recommendations to the board to establish, maintain, or revise standards governing the care and well-being of on-farm livestock and poultry. The commission shall be attached to the Department of Agriculture for administrative purposes and shall consist of sixteen (16) members as follows: <section prefix="1">The state veterinarian, who shall be a nonvoting member; </section><section prefix="2">The co-chairs of the Interim Joint Committee on Agriculture, who shall be nonvoting, ex officio members; and </section><section prefix="3">Thirteen (13) voting members as follows: <section prefix="a">The Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee, who shall serve as chair; </section><section prefix="b">The dean of the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture or the dean's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The chair of the Animal Control Advisory Board or the chair's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The director of the University of Kentucky Livestock Disease Diagnostic Center or the director of the Murray State University Breathitt Veterinary Center. Each director shall serve one (1) year terms on a rotating basis; </section><section prefix="e">Four (4) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="1">One (1) person selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Farm Bureau; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) person selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky County Judge/Executive Association; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) veterinarian selected from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association. The veterinarian's practice shall include working on one (1) or more of the species named in paragraph (f) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="4">One (1) citizen at large with an interest in food safety; and </section></section><section prefix="f">Five (5) members actively engaged in farming and appointed by the Governor with assistance by the department. The department shall contact commodity organizations named in this paragraph, collect a list of potential representatives from the organizations, and deliver the list to the Governor. The Governor shall appoint: <section prefix="1">One (1) active producer from the list submitted by Kentucky commodity organizations representing bovine species; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) active producer from the list submitted by Kentucky commodity organizations representing ovine and caprine species; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) active producer from the list submitted by Kentucky commodity organizations representing porcine species; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) active producer from the list submitted by Kentucky commodity organizations representing equine species; and </section><section prefix="5">One (1) active producer from the list submitted by Kentucky commodity organizations representing poultry species. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12362</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>