<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142">MISCELLANEOUS TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>142.301</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 142.301 to 142.363.   </catch_line><order_by>301</order_by><text>As used in KRS 142.301 to 142.363: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="2">"Charitable provider" means any provider which does not charge its patients for health-care items or services, and which does not seek or accept Medicare, Medicaid, or other financial support from the federal government or any state government. The collaboration with public hospitals, agencies, or other providers in the delivery of patient care; affiliation with public institutions to provide health-care education; or the pursuit of research in cooperation with public institutions or agencies shall not be considered as the receipt of government support by a charitable provider; </section><section prefix="3">"Dispensing" means to deliver one (1) or more doses of a prescription drug in a suitable container, appropriately labeled for subsequent administration or use by a patient or other individual entitled to receive the prescription drug; </section><section prefix="4">"Entity" means any firm, partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, company, joint stock association, trust, business trust, syndicate, cooperative, or other group or combination acting as a unit; </section><section prefix="5">"Gross revenues" means the total amount received in money or otherwise by a provider for the provision of health-care items or services in Kentucky, less the following: <section prefix="a">Amounts received by any provider as an employee or independent contractor from another provider for the provision of health-care items or services if: <section prefix="1">The employing or contracting provider receives revenue attributable to health-care items or services provided by the employee or independent contractor receiving payment; and </section><section prefix="2">The employing or contracting provider is subject to the tax imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, or 142.363 on the receipt of that revenue; </section></section><section prefix="b">Amounts received as a grant or donation by any provider from federal, state, or local government or from an organization recognized as exempt from federal income taxation under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code for: <section prefix="1">Research; or </section><section prefix="2">Administrative or operating costs associated with the implementation and operation of an experimental program; </section></section><section prefix="c">Salaries or wages received by an individual provider as an employee of a charitable provider, the federal government, or any state or local governmental entity; </section><section prefix="d">Salaries or wages received by an individual provider as an employee of a public university for the provision of services at a student health facility; and </section><section prefix="e">Amounts received by an HMO on a fixed, prepayment basis as premium payments. </section></section><section prefix="6">"Health-care items or services" means: <section prefix="a">Inpatient hospital services; </section><section prefix="b">Outpatient hospital services; </section><section prefix="c">Nursing-facility services; </section><section prefix="d">Services of intermediate-care facilities for individuals with intellectual disabilities; </section><section prefix="e">Physicians' services provided prior to July 1, 1999; </section><section prefix="f">Licensed home-health-care-agency services; </section><section prefix="g">Outpatient prescription drugs; </section><section prefix="h">HMO services; </section><section prefix="i">Regional community services for mental health and individuals with intellectual disabilities; </section><section prefix="j">Psychiatric residential treatment facility services; </section><section prefix="k">Medicaid managed care organization services; and </section><section prefix="l">Supports for community living waiver program services; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Health-maintenance organization" or "HMO" means an organization established and operated pursuant to the provisions of Subtitle 38 of KRS Chapter 304; </section><section prefix="8">"Hospital" means an acute-care, rehabilitation, or psychiatric hospital licensed under KRS Chapter 216B; </section><section prefix="9">"Hospital services" means all inpatient and outpatient services provided by a hospital. "Hospital services" does not include services provided by a noncontracted, university-operated hospital, or any freestanding psychiatric hospital, if necessary waivers are obtained by the Cabinet for Human Resources, Cabinet for Health Services, or Cabinet for Health and Family Services from the Health Care Financing Administration or Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, or hospitals operated by the federal government; </section><section prefix="10">"Health and family services secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or that person's authorized representative; </section><section prefix="11">"Inpatient hospital services," "outpatient hospital services," "intermediate-care-facility services for individuals with intellectual disabilities," "physician services," "licensed home-health-care-agency services," and "outpatient prescription drugs" have the same meaning as set forth in regulations promulgated by the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services and codified at 42 C.F.R. pt. 440, as in effect on December 31, 1993; </section><section prefix="12">"Medicaid" means the state program of medical assistance as administered by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in compliance with 42 U.S.C. sec. 1396; </section><section prefix="13">"Nursing-facility services" means services provided by a licensed skilled-care facility, nursing facility, nursing home, or intermediate-care facility, excluding services provided by intermediate-care facilities for individuals with intellectual disabilities and services provided through licensed personal care beds; </section><section prefix="14">"Person" means any individual, firm, partnership, joint venture, association, corporation, company, joint stock association, estate, trust, business trust, receiver, trustee, syndicate, cooperative, assignee, governmental unit or agency, or any other group or combination acting as a unit and the legal successor thereof; </section><section prefix="15">"Provider" means any person receiving gross revenues for the provision of health-care items or services in Kentucky, excluding any facility operated by the federal government; </section><section prefix="16">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Revenue or that person's authorized representative; </section><section prefix="17">"Total bed capacity" means the combination of licensed nursing home beds, licensed nursing facility beds, and licensed intermediate-care facility beds; </section><section prefix="18">"Regional community services programs for mental health and individuals with an intellectual disability" means programs created under the provisions of KRS 210.370 to 210.480; </section><section prefix="19">"Psychiatric residential treatment facility" has the same meaning as provided in KRS 216B.450; and </section><section prefix="20">"Supports for Community Living Waiver Program" has the same meaning as provided in KRS 205.6317. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 85, sec. 522, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 99, sec. 20, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 120, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 101, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3, effective August 1, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 96, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40749</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>