<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.303</section_number><catch_line>Library science scholarships -- Library Science Scholarship Fund Advisory Committee. </catch_line><order_by>303</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a Library Science Scholarship Fund. </section><section prefix="2">The state librarian may grant scholarships for study in library science at an institution within the Commonwealth which is accredited by the American Library Association, the National Council for the Accreditation of Teacher Education or the appropriate regional postsecondary education accrediting organization. Scholarships may also be granted for study in an accredited library education program offered via distant learning technologies. Students applying for library education programs at institutions outside the Commonwealth that are likewise accredited may apply for assistance under this program if they agree to work in a library or archival services program within the Commonwealth upon their graduation in accordance with KRS 171.306. </section><section prefix="3">The state librarian shall establish a Library Science Scholarship Fund Advisory Committee that will receive and consider all applications for scholarships for study in library science and shall advise the state librarian on the awarding of scholarships according to criteria they establish for this purpose. </section><section prefix="4">The department is authorized to receive money from any state, federal, private or other legal funding source approved by the appropriate state agency for scholarship purposes, and the amounts of individual scholarships shall be determined by the state librarian on the advice of the Library Science Scholarship Fund Advisory Committee, which shall set criteria for the assistance. Money designated for this fund shall be held in a restricted account and shall not lapse to the general fund. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. VIII, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4784</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>