<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.038</section_number><catch_line>Employer to keep record of injuries -- Reports required to be filed. </catch_line><order_by>038</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every employer subject to this chapter shall keep a record of all injuries, fatal or otherwise, received by his employees in the course of their employment. Within one (1) week after the occurrence and knowledge, as provided in KRS 342.185 to 342.200, of an injury to an employee causing his absence from work for more than one (1) day, a report thereof shall be made to the department in the manner directed by the commissioner through administrative regulations. An employer's insurance carrier or other party responsible for the payment of workers' compensation benefits shall be responsible for making the report to the Department of Workers' Claims within one week of receiving the notification referred to in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The report shall contain the name, nature, and location of the business of the employer and name, age, sex, wages, and occupation of the injured employee, and shall state the date and hour of the accident causing the injury, the nature and cause of the injury, and any other information required by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">Every employer subject to this chapter shall report to its workers' compensation insurance carrier or the party responsible for the payment of workers' compensation benefits any work-related injury or disease or alleged work-related injury or disease within three (3) working days of receiving notification of the incident or alleged incident. </section><section prefix="4">Every employer or insurer subject to this chapter shall file additional reports covering specifically voluntary payments and settlements, and any other reports required by the commissioner by administrative regulation for the determination of the promptness of voluntary payment and validity and fairness of agreements. In addition, the commissioner may require additional information as may be necessary to comply with a federal statute or regulation or any state statute. </section><section prefix="5">Upon the termination of the disability of the injured employee, or if the disability extends beyond a period of sixty (60) days, then also at the expiration of that period, the employer shall make a supplementary report to the commissioner on blanks procured from the department for the purpose. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1783, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 14, sec. 68, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32380</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>