<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.379</section_number><catch_line>Rules and regulations -- Appeals from failure to restore or discharge -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>379</order_by><text>The board shall adopt regulations to carry out the provisions of KRS 61.371 to 61.379 in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. Any public employee who is not restored to a position, or who is discharged without cause within one (1) year after restoration, may appeal to the board for review. Upon review, both the employee and the employer may be represented by counsel. Technical rules as to admission of evidence shall not apply. If the board finds that the employer has violated the provisions of KRS 61.371 to 61.379 or regulations promulgated thereunder, it shall direct the employer to comply with the provisions and to compensate the employee for loss of pay suffered by reason of the violation; except any amount received by the employee during the period from his discharge to reinstatement from other public employment, unemployment compensation, or readjustment allowances from a public agency shall be deducted from such compensation. </text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 5. </history><metadata><lrc-note> (10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, รยง 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22931</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>