<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.193</section_number><catch_line>Advanced Practice Registered Nurse Council -- Members -- Meetings -- Duties -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>193</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created an Advanced Practice Registered Nurse Council to be made up of nine (9) members, including one (1) member who shall be from the Board of Nursing, one (1) member from the Board of Medical Licensure, one (1) member from the Board of Pharmacy, and six (6) advanced practice registered nurses who shall be determined as follows: <section prefix="a">Three (3) advanced practice registered nurse members shall include one (1) certified nurse anesthetist, one (1) certified nurse midwife, and one (1) certified nurse practitioner who shall be nominated from members chosen by their respective nursing specialty groups or organizations and recommended to the Board of Nursing for appointment; and </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) advanced practice registered nurse members, at least one (1) of whom shall be a designated clinical nurse specialist, shall be nominated by the Kentucky Nurses Association, and recommended to the Board of Nursing for appointment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall meet annually or as the members designate and shall seek all available information from concerned nursing groups. The council shall have the duty of recommending standards in the performance of any acts requiring additional education which is recognized by the nursing profession. The Board of Nursing may authorize the performance of additional acts by its regulations, after seeking all available information from the groups to be regulated. The regulations shall not be inconsistent with statutory law and shall be promulgated pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The terms for the council shall be for four (4) years. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 65, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>