<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Licensure for Private Investigators; </section><section prefix="2">"Company" means a firm, association, sole proprietorship, partnership, corporation, nonprofit organization, institution, or similar enterprise; </section><section prefix="3">"Investigating company" or "company licensee" means a company engaged in private investigating that is licensed under KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090; </section><section prefix="4">"Private investigating" means the act of any individual or company engaging in the business of obtaining or furnishing information with reference to: <section prefix="a">Crime or wrongs done or threatened against the United States or any state or territory of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">The identity, habits, conduct, business, occupation, honesty, integrity, credibility, knowledge, trustworthiness, efficiency, loyalty, activity, movement, whereabouts, affiliations, associations, transactions, acts, reputations, or character of any person; </section><section prefix="c">The location, disposition, or recovery of lost or stolen property; </section><section prefix="d">The cause or responsibility for fires, losses, accidents, damages, or injuries to persons or to property; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Private investigator" or "individual licensee" means a person who is engaged in private investigating and licensed in accordance with the provisions of KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090; and </section><section prefix="6">"Qualifying agent" means a principal corporate officer, such as the chief executive officer, president, vice president, treasurer-secretary, comptroller, or any other responsible officer or executive employee, who is designated by the corporation to represent it in matters relating to KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31758</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>