<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-644</section_number><catch_line>Required disclosure of availability of Kentucky Long-Term Care Partnership Insurance Program. </catch_line><order_by>14-644</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each insurer or its agent, soliciting or offering to sell a policy that is intended to qualify as a partnership policy, shall provide each prospective applicant a Partnership Program Notice disclosing the availability of the Kentucky Long-Term Care Partnership Insurance Program as authorized in Section 6021 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 and outlining the requirements and benefits of a partnership policy. </section><section prefix="2">The manner and content of the disclosure described in subsection (1) of this section shall be established through promulgation of administrative regulations by the Department of Insurance in coordination with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1171, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> ((7/15/2008).  A reference to "42 U.S.C. sec. 6021" in subsection (1) of this section as it appears in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 3, has been replaced with "Section 6021 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005" by the Reviser of Statutes during codification to correct a manifest clerical or typographical error. Consultation with the drafter and examination of the materials in the bill folder for House Bill 259 (which became 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 16) show that the former reference was intended to have been to the amendments made by Section 6021 of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 to various sections of 42 U.S.C. secs. 1395 et seq., and not to Section 6021 of that title, an unrelated section that was repealed in 2000. This correction has been made under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17187</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>