<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.700</section_number><catch_line>General fund -- Surplus fund account. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>There is hereby created in the general fund of the State Treasury a surplus fund account subject to the following terms and conditions: <section prefix="1">It shall contain all surplus tax receipts accruing to the general fund as provided by KRS 48.140(3); </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 48.705, it shall contain all funds lapsed from general fund receipts not otherwise appropriated; </section><section prefix="3">It shall contain all receipts from the sale of surplus property purchased with general fund tax receipts and not otherwise appropriated; </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in KRS 48.705, it shall contain all general fund tax revenues in excess of estimates; </section><section prefix="5">It shall contain all moneys saved as a result of a reorganization of state government operations funded by the general fund; </section><section prefix="6">Funds in the account shall be invested at interest and the interest shall also accrue to this account; </section><section prefix="7">It shall contain any other funds which are required by law or regulation to accrue to the surplus account of the general fund; and </section><section prefix="8">No expenditures shall be made from this account unless appropriated by the General Assembly or unless required by the budget reduction provisions of a branch budget bill, or as provided by KRS 48.130. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1995 (3d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 5, effective November 3, 1995. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. III, 25 at 741. See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. VII, (1) at 750. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22574</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>