<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.120</section_number><catch_line>Renewal, expiration, suspension, and revocation of licenses -- Fees and penalties -- Trust and agency fund. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every license issued under this chapter shall expire on June 30 following the date of issuance unless sooner revoked and canceled. </section><section prefix="2">On or before June 1 of each year, the board shall send notices to all licensees, at their last known addresses, advising them that the annual renewal fee is due on July 1 of each year. Every licensee shall renew his or her license on or before July 1 of each year by the payment to the board of an annual renewal fee which shall be a reasonable fee set by administrative regulation of the board and upon submission of a statement of compliance with the continuing education regulations of the board. If this renewal fee is not paid or the statement of compliance is not submitted on or before July 1, the board shall notify the delinquent licensee by mail at his or her last known address that the fee and statement are past due and that a delinquent penalty fee is assessed, in addition to the renewal fee, and that the renewal fee and penalty must be paid and the statement of compliance submitted on or before January 1. If these fees, penalties, and statement are not submitted by January 1, it shall be the duty of the board to suspend or revoke the license for nonpayment of the annual renewal and delinquent fees or for failure to submit the statement of compliance for the current year. </section><section prefix="3">All fees collected under the provisions of this chapter, or the administrative regulations adopted pursuant to this chapter, shall be paid into the State Treasury, and credited to a trust and agency fund to be used in defraying the costs and expenses in the administration of this chapter, including but not limited to salaries and necessary travel expenses. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31288</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>