<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.16-020</section_number><catch_line>Inspection of records by shareholders. </catch_line><order_by>16-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A shareholder of a corporation shall be entitled to inspect and copy, during regular business hours at the corporation's principal office, any of the records of the corporation described in subsection (5) of KRS 271B.16-010 if he gives the corporation written notice of his demand at least five (5) business days before the date on which he wishes to inspect and copy. </section><section prefix="2">A shareholder of a corporation shall be entitled to inspect and copy during regular business hours at a reasonable location specified by the corporation any of the following records of the corporation if the shareholder meets the requirements of subsection (3) of this section and gives the corporation written notice of his demand at least five (5) business days before the date on which he wishes to inspect and copy: <section prefix="a">Excerpts from minutes of any meeting of the board of directors, records of any action of a committee of the board of directors while acting in place of the board of directors on behalf of the corporation, minutes of any meeting of the shareholders, and records of action taken by the shareholders or board of directors without a meeting, to the extent not subject to inspection under subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Accounting records of the corporation; and </section><section prefix="c">The record of shareholders. </section></section><section prefix="3">A shareholder may inspect and copy the records described in subsection (2) of this section only if: <section prefix="a">His demand is made in good faith and for a proper purpose; </section><section prefix="b">He describes with reasonable particularity his purpose and the records he desires to inspect; and </section><section prefix="c">The records are directly connected with his purpose. </section></section><section prefix="4">The right of inspection granted by this section shall not be abolished or limited by a corporation's articles of incorporation or bylaws. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not affect: <section prefix="a">The right of a shareholder to inspect records under KRS 271B.7-200 or, if the shareholder is in litigation with the corporation, to the same extent as any other litigant; </section><section prefix="b">The power of a court, independently of this chapter, to compel the production of corporate records for examination. </section></section><section prefix="6">For purposes of this section, "shareholder" includes a beneficial owner whose shares are held in a voting trust or by a nominee on his behalf. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 168, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13479</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>