<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.430</section_number><catch_line>Lien on radios, phonographs and other electrical or electronic devices, for repair. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All persons, firms and corporations engaged in the business of repairing radios, phonographs, combinations thereof, automatic music instruments, refrigerators, televisions, electrical or electronic recording devices, and any and all portable electrical or electronic instruments or appliances shall have a lien upon such articles and appliances for the agreed or reasonable charge for parts, supplies, accessories and labor performed in their repair, said lien to attach upon completion of such repairs. The lien may be enforced by legal action or as hereafter provided. </section><section prefix="2">After completion of repairs, the owner shall be notified thereof by certified mail, return receipt requested or by registered mail, and if the repaired article be not removed and all charges paid within thirty (30) days after giving the notice, the person, firm or corporation making such repairs may hold such repaired articles and sell same at public or bona fide private sale to pay all agreed or reasonable charges, including charges for storage after notice of completion of repairs, and expenses incidental to advertisement and sale, accounting to the owner for any excess of charges and expenses. </section><section prefix="3">Before any sale of the repaired article, the person, firm or corporation making the repairs shall notify the owner of the article of the time and place of the sale. The notice may be served by certified mail, return receipt requested, or by registered mail directed to the owner's last known address, or, if the owner or his address is unknown, notice of the sale shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 216. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35332</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>