<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.140</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations presumed valid -- Promulgating administrative body to bear burden of proof in court challenge. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Administrative regulations are presumed to be valid until declared otherwise by a court, but when an administrative regulation is challenged in the courts it shall be the duty of the promulgating administrative body to show and bear the burden of proof to show: <section prefix="a">That the administrative body possessed the authority to promulgate the administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">That the administrative regulation is consistent with any statute authorizing or controlling its issuance; </section><section prefix="c">That the administrative regulation is not in excess of statutory authority; </section><section prefix="d">That the administrative regulation is not beyond the scope of legislative intent or statutory authority; </section><section prefix="e">That the administrative regulation is not violative of any other applicable statute; and </section><section prefix="f">That the laws and administrative regulations relating to promulgation of administrative regulations were faithfully followed. </section></section><section prefix="2">It shall be prima facie evidence of compliance with the provisions of this section as to the holding of hearings, statements of consideration, consideration of tiering, local government impact, and fiscal impact to file with the court appropriate citations to the Administrative Register which indicate such compliance. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 14, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>April 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=741</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>