<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.440</section_number><catch_line>Computation of bonus. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person determined by the administrator to be a qualified veteran shall be paid the sum of fifteen dollars ($15) for each month and major fraction of a month of qualifying Vietnam era service, not to exceed in all the sum of three hundred dollars ($300), and the sum of twenty-five dollars ($25) for each month and major fraction of a month of such service which is qualifying Vietnam service, subject to an aggregate limit for all service in the sum of five hundred dollars ($500). Any qualified veteran who was medically evacuated from a location, service in which location constituted qualifying Vietnam service, shall receive the sum of five hundred dollars ($500), this sum to be in lieu of any other bonus for which said veteran may qualify under the provisions of KRS 40.410 to 40.560. </section><section prefix="2">If a person determined to have been a qualified veteran shall be deceased at the time payment of the bonus would otherwise be made to him, the amount of his bonus shall be paid to the first surviving beneficiary, if any, according to the order of priority defined in KRS 40.400(9) and if there be no surviving beneficiary, the bonus of such veteran shall lapse, and no payment thereof shall be made. </section><section prefix="3">A beneficiary, as defined in KRS 40.400(9), (10), (11), (12), and (13), of a person killed in the line of duty while serving in the Armed Forces of the United States during the period of eligibility, or who died of service-connected injury sustained while so serving, and who would otherwise have qualified for the bonus provided in subsection (1) of this section, shall be paid three hundred dollars ($300) if no part of the total service during the period was served outside the continental United States or five hundred dollars ($500) if any part of the total service during the period was served outside the continental United States. The provisions of subsection (1) of this section and the minimum period of service for entitlement to a bonus as established by KRS 40.400(5) or (6) shall not apply to these beneficiaries. However, this exception does not waive the respective maximums of three hundred dollars ($300) or five hundred dollars ($500) for each veteran, person killed in the line of duty while on active duty in the Armed Forces, or person who died as a result of service-connected injury sustained while on active duty in the Armed Forces. Payment shall be made to a beneficiary in the order of priority defined in KRS 40.400(9). </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (1), (2), and (3) of this section, the amount paid to a qualifying veteran or a beneficiary of a qualifying veteran shall be the amount calculated under the provisions of subsection (1), (2), or (3) of this section, less the amount received by the veteran under the provisions of KRS 40.005 or KRS 40.010 to 40.990. </section></text><history>Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 3., effective March 1, 1991. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>March 1, 1991 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>