<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.3103</section_number><catch_line>Annual report on efforts to implement evidence-based practices to reduce recidivism. </catch_line><order_by>3103</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By December 1 of each year, beginning in 2012, the department shall submit to the Governor, the General Assembly, and the Chief Justice a comprehensive report on its efforts to implement evidence-based practices to reduce recidivism. The report shall include at a minimum: <section prefix="a">The percentage of supervised individuals being supervised in accordance with evidence-based practices; </section><section prefix="b">The percentage of state moneys expended by the department for programs that are evidence based, and a list of all programs with identification of which are evidence based; </section><section prefix="c">Specification of supervision policies, procedures, programs, and practices that were created, modified, or eliminated; and </section><section prefix="d">The department’s recommendations for resource allocation, and any additional collaboration with other state, regional, or local public agencies, private entities, or faith-based and community organizations. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall make the full report and an executive summary available to the general public on its Web site. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 53, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>