<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVII" order_by="37">SPECIAL PROCEEDINGS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="416" order_by="416">EMINENT DOMAIN </unit></structure><section_number>416.675</section_number><catch_line>Public use required -- No condemnation for indirect benefit -- Exemption. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every grant of authority contained in the Kentucky Revised Statutes to exercise the power of eminent domain shall be subject to the condition that the authority be exercised only to effectuate a public use of the condemned property. </section><section prefix="2">"Public use" shall mean the following: <section prefix="a">Ownership of the property by the Commonwealth, a political subdivision of the Commonwealth, or other governmental entity; </section><section prefix="b">The possession, occupation, or enjoyment of the property as a matter of right by the Commonwealth, a political subdivision of the Commonwealth, or other governmental entity; </section><section prefix="c">The acquisition and transfer of property for the purpose of eliminating blighted areas, slum areas, or substandard and insanitary areas in accordance with KRS Chapter 99; </section><section prefix="d">The use of the property for the creation or operation of public utilities or common carriers; or </section><section prefix="e">Other use of the property expressly authorized by statute. </section></section><section prefix="3">No provision in the law of the Commonwealth shall be construed to authorize the condemnation of private property for transfer to a private owner for the purpose of economic development that benefits the general public only indirectly, such as by increasing the tax base, tax revenues, or employment, or by promoting the general economic health of the community. However, this provision shall not prohibit the sale or lease of property to private entities that occupy an incidental area within a public project or building, provided that no property may be condemned primarily for the purpose of facilitating an incidental private use. </section><section prefix="4">The exercise of the power of eminent domain for the acquisition of property financed by state road funds or federal highway funds shall be exempt from the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>