<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.030</section_number><catch_line>Deputy sheriffs -- Certified court security officers -- Nonsworn personnel -- Participation in Law Enforcement Foundation Program. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The sheriff may appoint his or her own deputies and may revoke the appointment at his or her pleasure except where that revocation is prohibited by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273. In a county containing a consolidated local government or city of the first class with a deputy sheriff merit board, the term of office of a deputy shall continue from sheriff to sheriff unless a deputy is removed according to the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273. Before any deputy executes the duties of his or her office, he or she shall take the oath required to be taken by the sheriff. </section><section prefix="2">The sheriff may appoint his or her own certified court security officers and may revoke the appointment at his or her pleasure. A certified court security officer shall take an oath to faithfully perform the duties of his or her office and that he or she possesses the minimum qualifications under KRS 15.3971. </section><section prefix="3">The sheriff may appoint nonsworn clerical, technical, professional, and support personnel to assist him or her in the performance of the duties of his or her office. All nonsworn personnel shall serve at the pleasure of the sheriff. </section><section prefix="4">No sheriff whose county has adopted a deputy sheriff merit board under KRS 70.260 shall appoint a deputy who is a member of the immediate family of the sheriff. The term "member of the immediate family" has the meaning given in KRS 70.260. </section><section prefix="5">Except for certified court security officers, a sheriff's office may, upon the written request of the sheriff, participate in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund authorized by KRS 15.410 to 15.510 without the county establishing a deputy sheriff merit board. This subsection shall not prohibit the sheriff from requesting the consolidated local government or the fiscal court to establish a deputy sheriff merit board. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 11, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 67, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 57, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 43. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 29; and ch. 196, sec. 2. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1; and ch. 84, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1762, 1763, 1763-1, 1763-2, 1779a-1, 4560. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>  This section was also amended by Acts 1978, ch. 384, sec. 159 (the reviser's bill) but Acts 1978, ch. 63, sec. 1 prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24186</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>