<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.220</section_number><catch_line>Training courses to contain instruction on behavioral characteristics and proper care of lost persons with traumatic brain injury or developmental disability.   </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each basic search and rescue course offered by or under the authority of the Division of Emergency Management shall contain not less than thirty (30) minutes of instruction in the behavioral characteristics of lost persons with a traumatic brain injury or developmental disability and the proper care of lost persons with a traumatic brain injury or developmental disability, including but not limited to autism. </section><section prefix="2">Each search and rescue management course offered by or under the authority of the Division of Emergency Management shall contain not less than one (1) hour of instruction in the behavioral characteristics of lost persons with a traumatic brain injury or developmental disability and the proper care of lost persons with a traumatic brain injury or developmental disability, including but not limited to autism. </section><section prefix="3">The Division of Emergency Management shall seek recommendations regarding the curricula for basic search and rescue training and search and rescue management training sessions from organizations with a history of, and demonstrable experience serving or advocating on behalf of, individuals with autism, intellectual and developmental disabilities, or traumatic brain injuries. </section><section prefix="4">The time allotted for the subjects required by this section for each course and the content for each course shall be specified by administrative regulations promulgated by the Division of Emergency Management. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, provides that Sections 2 to 5 of the Act, which included the creation of this statute, shall be known as the "Chase McMurray Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40537</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>