<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.837Price</section_number><catch_line>contracts for architectural, engineering, and engineering-related services -- Review procedure required.   </catch_line><order_by>837Price</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 45A.800 to 45A.835, the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the Transportation Cabinet may enter into price contracts for architectural, engineering, and engineering-related services. If the agencies choose to enter into a price contract, subsection (2) of this section shall apply. </section><section prefix="2">Price contracts shall be awarded to firms qualified by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, Department of Facilities Management or by the Transportation Cabinet, Department of Highways. The Finance and Administration Cabinet selection committee established by KRS 45A.810 shall meet at least quarterly during each fiscal year to review and make recommendations to the commissioner of the Department for Facilities Management for qualification of interested firms. The Transportation Cabinet selection committee established by KRS 45A.810 shall meet at least quarterly during each fiscal year to review and make recommendations to the commissioner of the Department of Highways for qualification of interested firms. <section prefix="a">The respective committees shall evaluate those firms submitting statements of interest in obtaining a price contract. The submitting firms shall be reviewed according to the following criteria: <section prefix="1">Qualifications; </section><section prefix="2">Ability of professional personnel; and </section><section prefix="3">Past record and experience. </section></section><section prefix="b">Firms qualified by the commissioner of the Department for Facilities Management or by the commissioner of the Department of Highways shall be awarded price contracts by the respective departments for the type of work for which they have been qualified. </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Department for Facilities Management or the commissioner of the Department of Highways may select firms to perform work under price contract for small projects for which the architectural, engineering, or engineering-related fees do not exceed seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000). However, no firm that has received more than one hundred fifty thousand dollars ($150,000) in price contract fees in any one (1) fiscal year in the contract discipline being awarded shall be selected to work under a price contract unless the secretary of finance and administration or the secretary of transportation makes a written determination that the selection is in the best interest of the Commonwealth and the determination is confirmed by the appropriate cabinet's selection committee established by KRS 45A.810. </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, no price contract shall be awarded under the provisions of this section before completion of the review procedure provided for in KRS 45A.695 and 45A.705. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 12, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 1, effective April 3, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44587</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>