<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.675</section_number><catch_line>Temporary licensure as an acupuncturist -- Notification upon cancellation of temporary license. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever, in the opinion of the executive director based upon verified information contained in the application, an applicant for a license to practice as an acupuncturist is eligible under the applicable provisions of KRS 311.671 to 311.686, the executive director may issue to the applicant, on behalf of the board, a temporary license which shall entitle the holder to practice as an acupuncturist for a maximum of six (6) months from the date of issuance unless the temporary license is canceled by the executive director. The executive director may cancel the temporary license at any time without a hearing, for reasons deemed sufficient with appropriate consultation with the board, and the executive director shall cancel the temporary license immediately upon direction by the board or upon the board's denial of the application for a license. The temporary license shall not be renewable. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall present to the board the application for licensure made by the holder of the temporary license. If the board issues a regular license to the holder of a temporary license, the fee paid in connection with the temporary license shall be applied to the regular license fee. </section><section prefix="3">If the executive director cancels a temporary license, he or she shall promptly notify, by United States certified mail, the holder of the temporary license at the last known address on file with the board. The temporary license shall be terminated and of no further force or effect three (3) days after the date the notice was sent by certified mail. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>