<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.669</section_number><catch_line>Professionals to whom KRS 311.665 to 311.669 does not apply -- Licensing boards may require continuing education and training. </catch_line><order_by>669</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 311.665 to 311.669 shall not apply to the use of an AED by: <section prefix="a">Physicians, podiatrists, or osteopaths licensed under KRS Chapter 311 or chiropractors licensed under KRS Chapter 312; </section><section prefix="b">Physician assistants as defined in KRS 311.550; </section><section prefix="c">Registered nurses, practical nurses, or advanced practice registered nurses licensed under KRS Chapter 314; </section><section prefix="d">Dentists licensed under KRS Chapter 313; or </section><section prefix="e">Paramedics licensed, or first responders or emergency medical technicians certified, under KRS Chapter 311A. </section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall preclude the licensing boards referred to in subsection (1) of this section from requiring continuing education or training on the use of an AED. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 49, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 40, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 320, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002). This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs. 211 and 320. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, under KRS 446.250, ch. 320 would prevail as the Act last enacted by the General Assembly. However, ch. 320, sec. 4, provides: "Nothing in this Act shall be construed under KRS 7.123(4) as appearing to effect any substantive change in the statute law of Kentucky, and the actions contained within this Act shall not operate under KRS 446.250 or 446.260 to defeat any amendments in other Acts of this 2002 Regular Session of the Kentucky General Assembly to the statutes contained in this Act." Accordingly, where ch. 211, sec. 40, and ch. 320, sec. 3, are in conflict, ch. 211 prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>