<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.055</section_number><catch_line>Raising of funds for certain activities permitted. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any provision of KRS Chapter 11A to the contrary notwithstanding, a state agency or a public servant may raise funds, either individually or as a department or agency, for a charitable nonprofit organization granted a tax exemption by the Internal Revenue Service under Section 501c of the Internal Revenue Code without violating the provisions of this chapter. Raising of funds shall include but not be limited to holding events for the benefit of the charitable organization, contacting potential donors, providing prizes, and engaging in other forms of fundraising and providing the funds thus raised to the charitable organization. </section><section prefix="2">Any provision of KRS Chapter 11A to the contrary notwithstanding, a state agency or a public servant may raise funds, either individually or as a department or agency, for crime prevention, drug and alcohol abuse prevention, and traffic safety programs without violating the provisions of this chapter. Raising of funds shall include but not be limited to holding events for the benefit of a program specified in this section, contacting potential donors, providing prizes, and engaging in other forms of fundraising and providing the funds thus raised to the program. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 2, effective April 9, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>