<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.5636</section_number><catch_line>Drug Management Review Advisory Board -- Membership -- Officers -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>5636</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Drug Management Review Advisory Board is hereby established and attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. The board shall consist of sixteen (16) members to be appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and shall be constituted as follows: <section prefix="a">Five (5) members shall be physicians, one (1) each from the fields of family medicine, internal medicine, pediatrics, and geriatrics. The fifth physician appointed shall be from any other recognized field of medicine. Two (2) of the above indicated physicians shall be representatives of the two (2) current medical schools in the Commonwealth, the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville Schools of Medicine; </section><section prefix="b">Five (5) members shall be pharmacists, at least one (1) of whom shall be designated as the representative of the University of Kentucky College of Pharmacy; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members shall be advanced practice registered nurses; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be an optometrist and one (1) member shall be a physician's assistant; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be a representative of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services designated to serve on an ex officio basis; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) nonvoting member shall be a member of the pharmaceutical manufacturing industry. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The physician members of the board shall be appointed from a list of three (3) qualified physicians for each vacancy submitted by the Kentucky Medical Association. </section><section prefix="b">The pharmacist members of the board shall be appointed from a list of three </section></section><section prefix="3">qualified pharmacists for each vacancy submitted by the Kentucky <section prefix="a">The clinically appropriate prescribing, utilization, and evaluation of </section><section prefix="b">The clinically appropriate dispensing and monitoring of pharmaceuticals; </section><section prefix="c">Drug utilization review, pharmacoeconomic and pharmacoepidemiological </section><section prefix="d">Medical quality assurance. </section></section>Pharmacy Association. (c) The advanced practice registered nurse members of the board shall be appointed from a list of three (3) for each vacancy, submitted by the Kentucky Nurses Association. (d) The optometrist shall be appointed from a list of three (3) qualified optometrists submitted by the Kentucky Optometric Association. (e) The physician's assistant shall be appointed from a list of three (3) qualified physicians assistants submitted by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure. (3) The secretary may appoint one (1) nonvoting industry representative to be selected from a list of three (3) members nominated from the Pharmaceutical Research and Manufacturers of America. The secretary may request additional names for appointments and current members may be considered for reappointment. All members of the board shall be licensed and actively practicing in their respective professions in the Commonwealth and shall have knowledge or expertise in at least one (1) of the following areas: pharmaceuticals; evaluation and intervention, pharmacotherapeutic intervention methods in disease management using treatment algorithms, critical paths, and other measures that have been well defined and validated; and <section prefix="4">Three (3) of the initially appointed physician members, three (3) of the initially appointed pharmacist members, and one (1) of the initially appointed advanced practice registered nurses shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year. The remaining initial members shall be appointed for a term of two (2) years. Subsequent appointments shall be for a term of two (2) years. Members shall serve for no more than three (3) consecutive terms. The board shall designate a chair and vice chair. A member shall serve no more than two (2) consecutive terms as chair. </section><section prefix="5">The first meeting of the board shall take place within thirty (30) days of the appointment of all the members of the board. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall meet at least quarterly, or upon the call of the chair or the commissioner. A majority of the voting members of the board shall constitute a quorum. All meetings shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of the Open Meetings Act, KRS 61.805 to 61.850, and all balloting shall take place by roll call vote. </section><section prefix="7">Actions of the board shall require a majority vote of the members present or participating through distance communication technology. No member may vote on a matter where a conflict of interest may exist. The chair may vote on any matter before the board unless a conflict of interest exists. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 35, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 238, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 561, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7721</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>