<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="316" order_by="316">EMBALMERS AND FUNERAL DIRECTORS </unit></structure><section_number>316.130</section_number><catch_line>Expiration date of license -- Renewal -- Continuing education required for renewal -- Fee -- License not transferable.   </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No license granted under this chapter shall be issued or renewed for a period exceeding one (1) year. Every license and renewal shall expire on July 31 following the date of its issuance unless sooner revoked, surrendered, or canceled. </section><section prefix="2">A person may renew an embalmer's license or a funeral director's license by paying to the board a renewal fee, not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100), as set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="3">Except for the first licensure renewal following the issuance of an original license by the board, as a prerequisite for license renewal, every Kentucky-licensed embalmer and every Kentucky-licensed funeral director shall attend a minimum of twelve (12) hours every two (2) years in a continuing education program or programs approved by the board. Of these twelve (12) hours, a minimum of six (6) hours shall be attained from programs attended in a live, interactive, in-person format. Upon application to the board, the board may exempt a licensee from the continuing education requirements of this section if the applicant demonstrates that meeting the continuing education requirements of this section would work an undue hardship because of disability, illness, or other clearly mitigating circumstances, or if the applicant is seventy (70) years of age or older and is not actively involved in embalming or funeral directing. The board may use a portion of the annual license renewal fees for the purpose of contracting with accredited educational institutions, professional organizations, or other qualified persons to provide educational programs that meet this continuing education requirement. </section><section prefix="4">A licensed funeral establishment may renew its license by paying to the board a renewal fee equal to the establishment license fee. </section><section prefix="5">Any renewal not received by the board prior to July 31 will be assessed a late fee, not to exceed the amount of the renewal fee, as set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="6">A license granted under this chapter shall not be transferable. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 13. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599a-9, 1599a-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>