<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 304.14-510 to 304.14-550. </catch_line><order_by>14-500</order_by><text>For the purpose of KRS 304.14-510 to 304.14-550: <section prefix="1">"Applicant" means: <section prefix="a">In the case of an individual Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the person who seeks to contract for insurance benefits; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a group Medicare supplement policy or subscriber contract, the proposed certificate holder. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Certificate" means, for the purposes of KRS 304.14-510 to 304.14-550, any certificate issued under a group Medicare supplement policy, which policy has been delivered or issued for delivery in this state. </section><section prefix="3">"Medicare supplement policy" means a group or individual policy of (accident and sickness) insurance or a subscriber contract (of hospital and medical service associations or health maintenance organizations) other than a policy issued pursuant to a contract under Section 1876 of the Federal Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. secs. 1395 et seq.) or an issued policy under a demonstration project specified in 42 U.S.C. sec. 1395ss(g)(1), which is advertised, marketed, or designed primarily as a supplement to reimbursements under Medicare for the hospital, medical, or surgical expenses of persons eligible for Medicare. Such policy does not include: <section prefix="a">Medicare Advantage plans established under Medicare Part C; </section><section prefix="b">Prescription drug plans established under Medicare Part D; or </section><section prefix="c">Health care prepayment plans that provide benefits pursuant to an agreement under 42 U.S.C. sec. 1395l(a)(1)(A). </section></section><section prefix="4">"Medicare" means the "Health Insurance for the Aged Act," Title XVIII of the Social Security Amendments of 1965, as then constituted or later amended. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 1, effective March 31, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective February 26, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17167</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>