<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.180</section_number><catch_line>Plans for storage plants -- Submission -- Approval -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For plants storing liquefied petroleum gases, and used for the dispensing of liquefied petroleum gases in liquid state into container or containers, for resale, plans shall be submitted, in duplicate, to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, and shall be approved by the department before construction is started. Plans so submitted shall show the following information as a minimum: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the owner, and the name and purpose of the plant proposed; </section><section prefix="b">Location of the proposed plant in relation to the nearest city, highways, railroads, and built up areas; </section><section prefix="c">A plot plan showing dimensions of the area proposed to be used for the plant, distances to the nearest property lines and the location and construction of any buildings which might affect the distances required under regulations adopted by the commissioner of housing, buildings, and construction; </section><section prefix="d">Construction drawings showing the arrangement and construction of all tanks, tank supports, piping, accessories, buildings, and appurtenant items of construction. These drawings shall be in sufficient detail to allow a contractor who is familiar with tank and pipe installation but not necessarily familiar with liquefied petroleum gas installations to use such drawings to satisfactorily complete the installation without further instructions; </section><section prefix="e">A copy of the original boiler inspector's report of inspection of the tank or tanks to be used or a reference to manufacturer's name and serial number of the tank so that the report may be obtained direct; </section><section prefix="f">The date of completion of the plans, the dates of any subsequent revisions and the signature of the person assuming responsibility for the correctness of the plans. </section></section><section prefix="2">For plants, installed for industrial or commercial usage, having a nominal water capacity of 150 gallons or over and serving an aggregate BTU usage of 150,000 BTUs or over and/or used for dispensing liquefied petroleum gas into other containers, not for resale, a report of installation, giving location and equipment installed, must be made to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, not later than ten (10) days after installation. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 502, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 30, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 20. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 9, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10998</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>