<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">A RECREATIONAL VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190A.100</section_number><catch_line>Recreational vehicle dealer's prohibited actions.   </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>A recreational vehicle dealer shall not do any of the following: <section prefix="1">Fail to perform any warranty service work authorized by a warrantor in a reasonably competent and timely manner if a transient customer requests service work on a recreational vehicle of a line-make that the dealer is authorized to display and sell; </section><section prefix="2">Make a fraudulent warranty claim to a warrantor; </section><section prefix="3">Misrepresent the terms of any warranty; </section><section prefix="4">Fail to perform any pre-delivery inspection functions as specified by the warrantor in a competent and timely manner; </section><section prefix="5">Fail to accurately document the time spent completing each repair, the total number of repair attempts conducted on a single recreational vehicle, and the number of repair attempts for the same repair conducted on a single recreational vehicle; </section><section prefix="6">Fail to notify the warrantor within ten (10) days subsequent to the second repair attempt on a defect which impairs the use, value, or safety of a recreational vehicle; or </section><section prefix="7">Fail to maintain written records, including a customer's signature, regarding the amount of time a recreational vehicle is stored for the consumer's convenience during a repair. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 10, effective January 1, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43557</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>