<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.555</section_number><catch_line>Service credit, creditable compensation, and other credits for military service.   </catch_line><order_by>555</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After August 1, 1998, any employee entering the Armed Forces of the United States after he first participates in the system, who joins the Armed Forces within three (3) months of the last day of paid employment, being on leave of absence from service and not withdrawing his accumulated account balance, shall be credited for retirement purposes with service credit and creditable compensation as provided in 38 U.S.C. sec. 4318 for his period of active military duty in the Armed Forces of the United States, not to exceed six (6) years, if his discharge therefrom is honorable and he returns to work with an employer participating in one (1) of the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems within two (2) years after completion of the period of active military duty, or upon the subsequent termination of any total disability which existed at the expiration of the two (2) years after discharge. A member eligible for the benefit prescribed by this subsection who participates in the hybrid cash balance plan as provided by KRS 16.583 and 61.597 shall also have his or her member account credited with employee contributions, employer pay credits, and interest credits, as provided by KRS 16.583 and 61.597, as though the member were employed during the member's period of active military duty described by this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">After August 1, 1998, any employee who, prior to the date he first participated in the system, terminated his employment with an agency participating in one (1) of the systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems and within three (3) months entered the Armed Forces of the United States and who returns to work with an employer participating in one (1) of the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems within two (2) years after completion of the period of active military duty, or upon the subsequent termination of any total disability which existed at the expiration of the two (2) years after discharge, shall be credited for retirement purposes with service credit and creditable compensation as provided in 38 U.S.C. sec. 4318 for his period of active military duty in the Armed Forces, not to exceed six (6) years. A member eligible for the benefit prescribed by this subsection who participates in the hybrid cash balance plan as provided by KRS 16.583 and 61.597 shall also have his or her member account credited with employee contributions, employer pay credits, and interest credits, as provided by KRS 16.583 and 61.597, as though the member were employed during the member's period of active military duty described by this subsection. </section><section prefix="3">Any National Guard technician involuntarily serving on active military duty during the period between January 26, 1968, and January 1, 1970, who completes his eight (8) years' service while on military duty during this period, shall have that portion of his active military duty, necessary to the completion of eight (8) years' current service, credited to his account, as current service without having to meet the reemployment criteria. </section><section prefix="4">Any employee eligible for retirement as prescribed in KRS 61.559 or any employee upon completion of five (5) years of service shall receive current service credit for a maximum of four (4) years for his period of active military duty in the Armed Forces of the United States, if his discharge therefrom is honorable and he has not been credited with the service under subsections (1) to (3) of this section if he pays thirty-five percent (35%) of the cost of the service based on the formula adopted by the board. The payment by the member shall not be picked up by the employer, as described in KRS 61.560(4), and shall be deposited to his individual member's account. The remaining sixty-five percent (65%) shall be paid by the state from funds appropriated specifically for the purpose and these payments shall be deposited to the respective retirement allowance accounts. If no funds are available in the special appropriation account, the system shall not accept employee payments until funds are available in the account. </section><section prefix="5">Any employee participating in one (1) of the retirement systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems eligible to purchase military service credit under subsection (4) of this section shall receive current service credit for active military duty as provided under subsection (4) of this section without payment of the current employee contribution ratio if the member was taken prisoner by a hostile power at any time during active military service. </section><section prefix="6">Any employee participating in one (1) of the retirement systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems age sixty-five (65) or older who has forty-eight (48) months of service, at least twelve (12) of which are current service, or if younger who has sixty (60) months of service, at least twelve (12) of which are current service shall receive current service for his period of active military duty in the Armed Forces of the United States, if his discharge therefrom is not dishonorable and he has not been credited with the service under subsections (1) to (4) of this section, by paying the retirement system a delayed contribution payment. Payment may be made by lump sum or in increments. The payment shall not be picked up by the employer as described in KRS 16.545(4), 61.560(4), or 78.610(4) and shall be deposited in the member's individual retirement account. </section><section prefix="7">Any employee participating in one (1) of the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems age sixty-five (65) or older who has forty-eight (48) months of service, at least twelve (12) of which are current service, or if younger who has sixty (60) months of service, at least twelve (12) of which are current service, shall receive one (1) month of current service for each six (6) months of service in the National Guard or the military reserves of the United States, by paying the retirement system a delayed contribution payment. The service shall be treated as service earned prior to participation in the system and shall not be included in the member's final compensation. Payment may be made by lump sum or in increments. The payment shall not be picked up by the employer, as described in KRS 16.545(4), 61.560(4), or 78.610(4) and shall be deposited in the member's individual retirement account. </section><section prefix="8">For members who begin participating in the systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems on or after January 1, 2014, in the hybrid cash balance plan prescribed by KRS 16.583 and 61.597, the provisions of subsections (4) to (7) of this section shall not apply. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 51, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 15, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, secs. 10 and 26, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 22, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. --Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. --Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 17. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1; and ch. 302, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 32; ch. 116, sec. 32; and ch. 133, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 6. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42679</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>