<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">A LICENSING OF NURSING HOME ADMINISTRATORS </unit></structure><section_number>216A.040</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensure for Long-term Care Administrators -- Membership.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>There shall be a Kentucky Board of Licensure for Long-term Care Administrators located within the Public Protection Cabinet for administrative and budgetary purposes. The board shall be composed of ten (10) members. The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or his or her designee, shall be an ex officio member of the board. The other members of the board shall be appointed by the Governor. One (1) member shall be a practicing hospital administrator, to be appointed from a list of two (2) names submitted by the Kentucky Hospital Association. One (1) member shall be a practicing medical physician, to be appointed from a list of two (2) names submitted by the Kentucky State Medical Association. One (1) member shall be an educator in the field of allied health services. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. One (1) member shall be a practicing long-term care administrator appointed from a list of two (2) names submitted by LeadingAge Kentucky. The other four (4) members shall be practicing long-term care administrators appointed from a list of two (2) names for each vacancy submitted by the Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities and duly licensed under this chapter. No person who has been disciplined in the previous five (5) years by the board, or by another state's board of licensure governing the same profession, shall be appointed to the board. </text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 58, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 503, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 447, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 83. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 129 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>