<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.195</section_number><catch_line>Compensatory time -- Payment upon leaving state service. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A state employee who is authorized to work one (1) or more hours in excess of the prescribed hours of duty shall be granted compensatory leave on an hour-for-hour basis. Upon the written request of an employee who is not exempt from the provisions of the Federal Fair Labor Standards Act, 29 U.S.C. sec. 201 et seq., an appointing authority may grant compensatory time, in lieu of overtime pay, at the rate of one and one-half (1.5) hours for each hour the employee is authorized to work in excess of forty (40) hours in a work week. An employee who is transferred or otherwise changed from the jurisdiction of one agency to another shall retain his compensatory leave in the receiving agency. </section><section prefix="2">An employee in a position listed in KRS 18A.115(1)(d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), or (k) shall not be eligible to receive any level of block payment for compensatory leave hours, except as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Any employee who leaves state service shall be paid for the balance of unused compensatory time not to exceed two hundred forty (240) hours. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 12, effective April 13, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 495, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.195, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.360. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>