<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="635" order_by="635">PUBLIC OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>635.083</section_number><catch_line>Court's continuing jurisdiction over juvenile repeat offenders. </catch_line><order_by>083</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A juvenile convicted of or adjudged delinquent of three (3) or more offenses, other than violations or status offenses, by the juvenile session of District Court, shall be retained under the jurisdiction and supervision of the court with regard to the commission of that offense until the child reaches the age of eighteen (18), except that if the child is convicted of or adjudged delinquent of a third or subsequent misdemeanor offense after the child reaches the age of seventeen (17) years and six (6) months, the court's jurisdiction and supervision shall continue for a period not to exceed one (1) year. This jurisdiction shall continue even after the service of incarceration or other court-ordered punishment in the form of conditional discharge. Violation of the terms and conditions of conditional discharge shall be punished as contempt of court. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of this section shall not apply to adjudications of delinquency for more than one (1) misdemeanor arising from the same incident. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1997 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  Under 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 67(1), this statute becomes effective July 15, 1997. (7/15/96).  Although 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 42, indicated that it was creating a new section of KRS Chapter 630, this statute has been codified in KRS Chapter 635 because the text of the statute clearly indicates that it does not apply to status offenses. See KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>