<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.190</section_number><catch_line>Development of comprehensive written search and rescue plan. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each local search and rescue coordinator shall assist local rescue squads in developing a comprehensive written search and rescue plan which shall address as a minimum: <section prefix="a">Direction and control responsibilities or incident command system procedures; </section><section prefix="b">Notification and reporting procedures and requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Call-out procedures; </section><section prefix="d">Resource identification; </section><section prefix="e">Coordination of resources; </section><section prefix="f">Mutual aid agreements; </section><section prefix="g">Training requirements for search and rescue responders and managers; </section><section prefix="h">Coordination of all on-scene operations with other local, state, and federal agencies; and </section><section prefix="i">The provision of copies of topographical maps for search team members. </section></section><section prefix="2">The local search and rescue plan shall be incorporated into the rescue services annex of the local emergency operations plan and submitted for review and adoption as part of the local emergency operations plan. </section><section prefix="3">The local search and rescue plan shall be a public record and shall be updated not less than annually. A copy of the plan shall be filed with the division not less than ten (10) days after each update or amendment. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 101, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21812</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>