<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.210</section_number><catch_line>Operating commercial vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or other controlled substance. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, a person shall not drive a commercial motor vehicle within this state while having any measurable or detectable amount of alcohol or other controlled substances in his system. </section><section prefix="2">A person who drives a commercial motor vehicle within this state while having any detectable amount of alcohol or controlled substance in his system or who refuses to submit to the test required in KRS 281A.220, shall be placed out of service for twenty-four (24) hours. </section><section prefix="3">A person who drives a commercial motor vehicle within this state with an alcohol concentration of four hundredths (0.04) or more shall be deemed to be operating a vehicle under the influence. </section><section prefix="4">A person who drives a commercial motor vehicle within this state with an alcohol concentration of four hundredths (0.04) or more, or who refused to submit to the test required in KRS 281A.220, in addition to any other sanctions that may be imposed under this chapter shall be disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle under KRS 281A.190. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 7, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 21, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective>April 7, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14482</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>