<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7701</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 65.7703 to 65.7721. </catch_line><order_by>7701</order_by><text>As used in KRS 65.7703 to 65.7721, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Governmental agency" means any county, urban-county government, consolidated local government, city, taxing district, special district, school district, or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth or body corporate or politic or any instrumentality of the foregoing. </section><section prefix="2">"Governing body" means the board, council, commission, fiscal court, or other body or group that is authorized by law to act on behalf of a governmental agency. </section><section prefix="3">"Legislation" means an order, resolution, or ordinance of the governing body. </section><section prefix="4">"Notes" means notes authorized by KRS 65.7703 to 65.7721 which may be secured by taxes or revenue or taxes and revenue. </section><section prefix="5">"Revenue" means all funds received by a governmental agency which are not taxes, including but not limited to excises, transfers, service fees, assessments, and occupational license fees. </section><section prefix="6">"State local debt officer" means the officer so designated in KRS 66.045. </section><section prefix="7">"Taxes" means taxes properly levied upon real or personal property. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 35, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23513</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>