<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="433" order_by="433">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>433.900</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 433.900 to 433.906.     </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text>As used in KRS 433.900 to 433.906, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Applicant" means a secondary metals recycler seeking an application for a certificate of registration with the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet, as provided in KRS 433.902. If the secondary metals recycler is owned by a corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, incorporated association, or any other entity organized for the purpose of engaging in business as a secondary metals recycler, "applicant" means the officers of these entities; </section><section prefix="2">"Ferrous metals" means any metal containing significant quantities of iron or steel; </section><section prefix="3">"Nonferrous metals" means metal not containing significant quantities of iron, including but not limited to copper, brass, aluminum, bronze, lead, zinc, nickel, and alloys thereof; </section><section prefix="4">"Name-based background check" means a statewide search of the centralized criminal history record information system by the Department of Kentucky State Police, utilizing the name, date of birth, and Social Security number of the applicant; </section><section prefix="5">"Restricted metals" means any of the following metal items: <section prefix="a">Manhole covers; </section><section prefix="b">Electric light poles or other utility poles; </section><section prefix="c">Guardrails; </section><section prefix="d">Street signs, traffic signs, or traffic signals; </section><section prefix="e">Whole road tiles; </section><section prefix="f">Funeral markers or funeral vases; </section><section prefix="g">Railroad equipment, including but not limited to a tie plate, signal house, control box, switch plate, e-clip, or rail tie junction; </section><section prefix="h">Condensing or evaporating coils made from copper, aluminum, or aluminum-copper, including the tubing or rods from a heating or air conditioning unit that is not from a window air conditioning unit or automobile air conditioning unit; </section><section prefix="i">Stainless steel beer kegs; </section><section prefix="j">A catalytic converter or any nonferrous part of a catalytic converter unless purchased as part of a vehicle; or </section><section prefix="k">Storm drain covers; and </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">"Secondary metals recycler" means: <section prefix="1">Any person who is engaged in the business of gathering or obtaining ferrous or nonferrous metals that have served their original economic purpose or is in the business of performing the manufacturing process by which ferrous metals or nonferrous metals are converted into raw material products consisting of prepared grades and having an existing or potential monetary value; </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has facilities for performing the manufacturing process by which ferrous metals or nonferrous metals are converted into raw material products consisting of prepared grades and having an existing or potential monetary value, other than by the exclusive use of hand tools, by methods including but not limited to processing, sorting, cutting, classifying, cleaning, baling, wrapping, shredding, shearing, or changing the physical form or chemical content thereof; or </section><section prefix="3">Any recycler, dealer in junk or metals, dealer in secondhand articles, vendor of bottles or rags, or collector of or dealer in articles found in ashes, garbage, or other refuse, whether a dealer, collector, or vendor operates an established place of business or an itinerant business. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Secondary metals recycler" shall not include a municipal solid waste department or any entity which has been issued a municipal solid waste transporter license by the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet and which gathers or obtains ferrous or nonferrous metals in a vehicle registered in Kentucky to transport solid waste. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42386</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>