<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">TURNPIKE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175.650</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 175.640 to 175.690. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>As used in KRS 175.640 to 175.690, and as applied to the financing of resource recovery roads by the Turnpike Authority of Kentucky, the following words and phrases shall have the following respective meanings, unless another or different meaning or intent shall be clearly indicated by the context. <section prefix="1">"Authority" shall mean the Turnpike Authority of Kentucky duly organized and existing pursuant to the provisions of KRS 175.410 to 175.990, inclusive. </section><section prefix="2">"Bonds" or "resource recovery road revenue bonds" shall mean resource recovery road revenue bonds of the authority issued under the provisions of KRS 175.640 to 175.690. </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" shall mean the Transportation Cabinet of Kentucky or, if said cabinet shall be abolished, the cabinet, board, body, department, or commission succeeding to the principal functions thereof or to whom the powers vested in the cabinet shall be given or transferred by law. </section><section prefix="4">"Resource recovery road project" or "project" shall mean any express highway or superhighway, or such part or parts thereof, as may be constructed and financed under the provisions of KRS 175.640 to 175.690 which shall be designed and constructed to serve as a modern, heavy-duty motorway facility capable of carrying in normal operations vehicles designed for the transportation of coal severed and produced in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, which road shall also be designed to serve the traveling public, including all bridges, tunnels, overpasses, underpasses, interchanges, entrance plazas, approaches, connecting highways, tollhouses (if any), service stations, garages, restaurants, and administration, storage, or other buildings and facilities which the authority may deem necessary for the operation of such resource recovery road project, together with all property, rights, easements, and interests which may be acquired by the authority or by the cabinet for the construction or the operation of such project. </section><section prefix="5">All words and phrases which are defined and used in KRS 175.410 to 175.990, inclusive, shall have the same meaning or meanings when used in KRS 175.640 to 175.690, except that the words and phrases "turnpike project" or "project" as used in said identified sections shall mean and refer to resource recovery road projects constructed and financed pursuant to KRS 175.640 to 175.690. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5098</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>