<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.295</section_number><catch_line>Owner to surrender title on destroyed vehicle or trailer. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Any person or entity having a motor vehicle or trailer that has been destroyed, to the extent that its repair cannot be obtained through usual commercial repair services, at a cost less than its retail value as established from a value manual approved by the Department of Revenue, or from which two (2) or more parts which typically bear a vehicle identification number placed thereon by the manufacturer have been removed, or which he removes, shall surrender the certificate of title for such vehicle for which he has a certificate of title in his or another name, to the county clerk of the county in which such vehicle is located. The clerk shall immediately forward the surrendered title to Frankfort with instructions for canceling the title. </section><section prefix="b">Any person or entity engaged in the sale of used motor vehicle or trailer parts, or the recycling or salvage of them, shall surrender the certificate of title for any vehicle in his possession, and for which he has a certificate of title, whether in his or another name, if such vehicle is destroyed within the meaning of paragraph (a) of this subsection, or from which two (2) or more parts which typically bear a vehicle identification number placed thereon by a manufacturer have been removed, or which he removes, to the county clerk of the county in which such vehicle is located. The clerk shall immediately forward the surrendered title to Frankfort with instructions for canceling the title. </section><section prefix="c">The surrender of the certificate of title pursuant to this section shall be made within ten (10) working days, next succeeding the day when such vehicle was received, destroyed, or next succeeding the day during which such second part was removed. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each county clerk shall receive without charge, a certificate surrendered in accordance with this section, cancel it, and remit it to the Department of Vehicle Regulation, and take any other action related to it, as required by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 615, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6195</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>