<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-714</section_number><catch_line>Collection of claim overpayments -- Dispute resolution. </catch_line><order_by>17A-714</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for overpayments which are a result of an error in the payment rate or method, an insurer that determines that a provider was overpaid shall, within twenty-four (24) months from the date that the insurer paid the claim, provide written or electronic notice to the provider of the amount of the overpayment, the covered person's name, patient identification number, date of service to which the overpayment applies, insurer reference number for the claim, and the basis for determining that an overpayment exists. Electronic notice includes e-mail or facsimile where the provider agreed in advance in writing to receive such notices. The insurer shall either: <section prefix="a">Request a refund from the provider; or </section><section prefix="b">Indicate on the notice that, within thirty (30) calendar days from the postmark date or electronic delivery date of the insurer's notice, if the insurer does not receive a notice of provider dispute in accordance with subsection (2) of this section, the amount of the overpayment will be recouped from future payments. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a provider disagrees with the amount of the overpayment, the provider shall within thirty (30) calendar days from the postmark date or the electronic delivery date of the insurer's written notice dispute the amount of the overpayment by submitting additional information to the insurer. </section><section prefix="3">If a provider files a dispute in accordance with subsection (2) of this section, no recoupment shall be made until the dispute is resolved. If a provider does not dispute the amount of the overpayment and does not provide a refund as required in subsection (2) of this section, the insurer may recoup the amount due from future payments. </section><section prefix="4">All disputes submitted by providers pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall be processed in accordance and completed within thirty (30) days with the insurer's provider appeals process. </section><section prefix="5">An insurer may recover an overpayment resulting from an error in the payment rate or method by requesting a refund from the provider or making a recoupment of the overpayment from the provider, subject to the provisions of subsection (6) of this section. A provider may dispute such recoupment in accordance with the provisions contained in KRS 304.17A-708. </section><section prefix="6">If an insurer chooses to collect an overpayment made to a provider through a recoupment against future provider payments, the insurer shall, within twenty-four (24) months from the date that the insurer paid the claim, and at the actual time of recoupment give the provider written or electronic documentation that specifies: <section prefix="a">The amount of the recoupment; </section><section prefix="b">The covered person's name to whom the recoupment applies; </section><section prefix="c">Patient identification number; and </section><section prefix="d">Date of service. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29336</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>