<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.043</section_number><catch_line>Special license plates for historic motor vehicles -- Permanent registration. </catch_line><order_by>043</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In enacting this section, it is the intention of the General Assembly to recognize the special value of historic vehicles to the Commonwealth, and also to recognize that historic vehicles, because of their limited use and easily identifiable characteristics, do not require the same degree of regulation as other vehicles. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires, "historic vehicle" shall mean all motor vehicles twenty-five (25) years old or older, which are used primarily for exhibition in shows, parades, tours, and other special uses, but not for general transportation. </section><section prefix="3">Historic vehicles shall be registered and licensed by the Transportation Cabinet. The registration shall be in lieu of registration and license required by KRS 186.020 to 186.270. </section><section prefix="4">Upon payment of the fee established in KRS 186.162 and an application in accordance with regulations issued by the Transportation Cabinet, the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet shall issue a certificate of registration and two (2) special license plates of a different color and design than the regular license plate, which, in the judgment of the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, will best advertise, popularize, and promote the Commonwealth of Kentucky. These plates, besides the word "Kentucky" shall have the words, "Historic Motor Vehicle" inscribed in a conspicuous manner and carry no year date. These plates shall have a serial number beginning with the number "100" and continue in a consecutive numerical sequence. </section><section prefix="5">Historic vehicles may display an authentic Kentucky license plate, twenty-five (25) years or older, or a reproduction of such a plate, if the historic motor vehicle plate and the registration receipt are kept in the vehicle at all times. </section><section prefix="6">The registration license and license plates of historic motor vehicles shall be valid without renewal as long as the vehicle is in existence. If the historic motor vehicle is sold, the registration and license shall be assigned and transferred to the new owner on the records of the Transportation Cabinet upon receipt of an application in accordance with regulations issued by the cabinet and payment of a fee of three dollars ($3). </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(9), (10). -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 14, secs. 1 to 5 and 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5928</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>