<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0551</section_number><catch_line>Boundaries of precincts. </catch_line><order_by>0551</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county board of elections shall establish election precincts so that each boundary of each precinct follows: <section prefix="a">A boundary described in KRS 117.055(1); </section><section prefix="b">The boundary of an incorporated city; </section><section prefix="c">A boundary of an urban-county legislative district established under KRS Chapter 67A; </section><section prefix="d">A boundary of a school district or school district division established under KRS Chapter 160; or </section><section prefix="e">A boundary of a census tract or census block established by the United States Bureau of the Census for the most recent decennial census of population and appearing on census block boundary maps. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a county board of elections cannot establish a precinct that complies with KRS 117.055 by using the boundaries permitted under subsection (1) of this section, the county board of elections may either: <section prefix="a">Establish the precinct boundary by using a boundary following a visible feature, including but not limited to a highway, railroad, or stream, and an extension of that visible feature to, but not across, another visible feature, nor across an extension of another feature that is used as a precinct boundary; or </section><section prefix="b">Request an exemption under KRS 117.0553 and 117.0554. </section></section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section, a "visible feature" is a physical feature shown on official maps prepared by: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">The United States Geological Survey; or </section><section prefix="c">The United States Bureau of the Census. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27353</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>