<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">A UNIFORM MILITARY AND OVERSEAS VOTERS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>117A.140</section_number><catch_line>Electronic mail address -- Standing request for electronic delivery.   </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local election official shall request an electronic mail address from each covered voter who applies to register to vote after July 1, 2014. An electronic mail address provided by any voter may not be made available to the public or any individual or organization other than an authorized agent of the local election official and is exempt from disclosure under the Kentucky Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884. The address may be used only for official communication with the voter about the voting process, including transmitting military-overseas ballots and election materials if the voter has requested electronic transmission, and verifying the voter’s mailing address and physical location. The request for an electronic mail address shall describe the purposes for which the electronic mail address may be used and include a statement that any other use or disclosure of the electronic mail address is prohibited. </section><section prefix="2">A covered voter who provides an electronic mail address may request that the voter’s application for a military-overseas ballot be considered a standing request for electronic delivery of a ballot for all elections held after the date of the application through the next regular election or December 31 of the year of the application, whichever is later, or another shorter period the voter specifies. An election official shall provide a military-overseas ballot to a voter who makes a standing request for each election to which the request is applicable. A covered voter who is entitled to receive a military-overseas ballot for a primary under this subsection is entitled to receive a military-overseas ballot for the regular election. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 15, effective July 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>