<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0863</section_number><catch_line>Assistance in voting by absentee ballot -- Form required of voter and assistant. </catch_line><order_by>0863</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for those voters who have been certified as requiring assistance in voting on a permanent or annual basis, any person voting by means of an absentee ballot by mail or on the voting machine in the county clerk's office or other place designated by the county board of elections, and approved by the State Board of Elections, as provided in this chapter who receives assistance in voting shall be required to complete the voter assistance form required by KRS 117.255. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who assists another person in voting by use of an absentee ballot by mail or on a voting machine in the county clerk's office or other place designated by the county board of elections, and approved by the State Board of Elections, shall complete the voter assistance form required by KRS 117.255. </section><section prefix="3">The detachable flap on all absentee ballot envelopes shall have printed upon it the voter assistance form required by KRS 117.255, as well as a notice of the penalty for failure to complete the form. </section><section prefix="4">The State Board of Elections shall promulgate a voter assistance form which shall be in a form acceptable to the Attorney General. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 8, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 270, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> April 1, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27374</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>