<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.826</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>826</order_by><text>A court of this state has jurisdiction to appoint a guardian or issue a protective order for a respondent if: <section prefix="1">This state is the respondent's home state; </section><section prefix="2">On the date the petition is filed, this state is a significant-connection state and: <section prefix="a">The respondent does not have a home state or a court of the respondent's home state has declined to exercise jurisdiction because this state is a more appropriate forum; or </section><section prefix="b">The respondent has a home state, a petition for an appointment or order is not pending in a court of that state or another significant-connection state, and, before the court makes the appointment or issues the order: <section prefix="1">A petition for an appointment or order is not filed in the respondent's home state; </section><section prefix="2">An objection to the court's jurisdiction is not filed by a person required to be notified of the proceeding; and </section><section prefix="3">The court in this state concludes that it is an appropriate forum under the factors set forth in KRS 387.832; </section></section></section><section prefix="3">This state does not have jurisdiction under either subsection (1) or (2) of this section, the respondent's home state and all significant-connection states have declined to exercise jurisdiction because this state is the more appropriate forum, and jurisdiction in this state is consistent with the constitutions of this state and the United States; or </section><section prefix="4">The requirements for special jurisdiction under KRS 387.828 are met. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 9, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>