<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23">A CIRCUIT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>23A.100</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction of family court.  </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>(1)As a division of Circuit Court with general jurisdiction pursuant to Section112(6) of the Constitution of Kentucky, a family court division of Circuit Courtshall retain jurisdiction in the following cases:(a)Dissolution of marriage;(b)Child custody;(c)Visitation;(d)Maintenance and support;(e)Equitable distribution of property in dissolution cases;(f)Adoption; and(g)Termination of parental rights.(2)In addition to general jurisdiction of Circuit Court, a family court division ofCircuit Court shall have the following additional jurisdiction:(a)Domestic violence and abuse proceedings under KRS Chapter 403subsequent to the issuance of an emergency protective order in accordwith local protocols under KRS 403.725;(b)Proceedings under the Uniform Act on Paternity, KRS Chapter 406, andthe Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902;(c)Dependency, neglect, and abuse proceedings under KRS Chapter 620;and(d)Juvenile status offenses under KRS Chapter 630, except whereproceedings under KRS Chapter 635 or 640 are pending.(3)Family court divisions of Circuit Court shall be the primary forum for cases inthis section, except that nothing in this section shall be construed to limit theconcurrent jurisdiction of District Court.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 38, effective January 1, 2016. --Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective June24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 517, sec. 1, effective September 1, 1998.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44786</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>