<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.908</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities of board. </catch_line><order_by>908</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The PACE board shall have the following responsibilities: <section prefix="a">Implementing a Purchase of Agricultural Conservation Easement Program in the Commonwealth as provided by this section, including the development and promulgation of any administrative regulations required; </section><section prefix="b">Making decisions in connection with each specific easement purchase to be made with Commonwealth funds from the agricultural enhancement fund; </section><section prefix="c">Evaluating, as necessary, potential sites within the Commonwealth on which agricultural conservation easements or other property interests are to be acquired, applying the criteria set forth in this section and administrative regulations; and </section><section prefix="d">Employing the staff necessary to implement the provisions of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The PACE board shall establish fair, equitable, objective, nondiscriminatory procedures for determining easement purchase priorities. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing policies and procedures for determining easement purchase priorities and for purchasing easements. </section><section prefix="c">The program criteria shall be designed to ensure that land is selected for easement purchase because it will make a significant contribution to agricultural production. </section></section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>