<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.090</section_number><catch_line>Inspectors to report violations of health and fire laws and rulings. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall be furnished with a copy of all the laws and rulings of the secretary for health and family services affecting sanitary conditions in places of employment, not covered by the labor laws of the state, and shall report in writing to the state, county, or city health authorities any violations coming under the observation of its inspectors while visiting places of employment in the regular performance of their duty. </section><section prefix="2">The inspectors shall be furnished with a copy of all the laws and rulings of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction relating to fire hazards in places of employment, and shall report in writing to the state, county, or city authorities any violations coming under their observation while visiting places of employment in the regular performance of their duty. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1708, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 606, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 557, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(1), VI, sec. 107(1). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 254. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 33a-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (4/2/90, as revised 7/14/00).  In 1974, certain responsibilities of the Department of Public Safety were transferred to the Department of Insurance through the enactment of KRS 304.2-015. See 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, art. V, § 20. This statute was renumbered as the former KRS 198B.035 (repealed 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 270, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000) in 1980 and amended to place these responsibilities in the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. See 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, § 243. Accordingly, the prior reference to the Department of Public Safety contained in subsection (2) of this section has been changed to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction by the Reviser of Statutes acting pursuant to KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31998</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>