<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLI" order_by="41">LAWS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="446" order_by="446">CONSTRUCTION OF STATUTES </unit></structure><section_number>446.030</section_number><catch_line>Computation of time. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">In computing any period of time prescribed or allowed by order of court, or by any applicable statute or regulation, the day of the act, event or default after which the designated period of time begins to run is not to be included. The last day of the period so computed is to be included, unless it is a Saturday, a Sunday, a legal holiday, or a day on which the public office in which a document is required to be filed is actually and legally closed, in which event the period runs until the end of the next day which is not one (1) of the days just mentioned. When the period of time prescribed or allowed is less than seven (7) days, intermediate Saturdays, Sundays and legal holidays shall be excluded in the computation. </section><section prefix="b">When a statute, regulation, or order of court requires an act to be done either a certain time before an event or a certain time before the day on which an event occurs, the day of the event shall be excluded in computing the time. If the day thereby computed on which or by which the act is required to be done falls on a Saturday, Sunday, legal holiday, or a day on which the public office in which the act is required to be completed is actually and legally closed, the act may be done on the next day which is none of the days just mentioned. </section></section><section prefix="2">If any proceeding is directed by law to take place, or any act is directed to be done, on a particular day of a month and that day is Sunday, the proceeding shall take place, or the act shall be done, on the next day that is not a legal holiday. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 453, 454. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19391</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>