<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="179" order_by="179">COUNTY ROAD ENGINEER AND MAINTENANCE OF PUBLIC ROADS </unit></structure><section_number>179.330</section_number><catch_line>Names of county roads -- How changed and established -- Erection of signs. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every county road shall be known by the name by which it was designated on the map or plat or record in the office of the county clerk of the county in which it is located or by the order of the court establishing the road, or by the deed conveying the right-of-way for the road to the county. </section><section prefix="2">When the name of any road has been designated as provided in subsection (1) of this section, the name of the road can only be changed by an order of the county judge/executive or the mayor of a consolidated local government. Such order may be issued on a petition and proceeding in which fifty percent (50%) or more of the property owners abutting upon the road have joined in the petition or have been summoned for a hearing upon the petition by the county judge/executive or the mayor of a consolidated local government at a day and time designated for the hearing or in counties containing a city of the first class or consolidated local government upon the recommendation of the county engineer and of the planning and zoning commission. On similar proceeding an order may be issued designating a name for any unnamed road in the county. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court or a consolidated local government may cause signs bearing the name of each road as fixed by the county judge/executive or the mayor of a consolidated local government, to be placed on the roads, or it may, by a resolution duly recorded, authorize any person or organization to erect signs, approved as to form by the fiscal court or a consolidated local government, bearing the name designated to the road by the county judge/executive or the mayor of a consolidated local government. </section><section prefix="4">No person or organization shall remove or damage any sign erected as hereinabove provided for, or erect or place or cause to be erected or placed, upon a road any sign or signs, indicating, marking, or designating a road by any other name than as hereinabove provided for. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall prohibit the Department of Highways from designating roads built under the supervision of the Department of Highways, either by name or number. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 192, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 319, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4324-1, 4324-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5505</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>