<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.8-255</section_number><catch_line>Registration with department required for mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor -- Renewals-- Continuing education requirement -- Background checks -- Originators and processors subject to other laws -- Minimum requirements -- Limitation of loan origination services. </catch_line><order_by>8-255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No natural person shall transact business in Kentucky, either directly or indirectly, as a mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor unless such mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor is registered with the department and has been issued a current certificate of registration by the department, complies with all applicable requirements of this subtitle, and maintains a valid unique identifier issued by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry. The department shall maintain a database of all mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors originating or processing mortgage loans on residential real property in Kentucky. The department shall issue a certificate of registration to all registered mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors. </section><section prefix="2">The application for registration shall: <section prefix="a">Be on a form prescribed by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="b">Be accompanied by a registration fee in the amount of fifty dollars ($50) which shall be used solely by the department to establish and maintain a database of all mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors, and any excess funds shall be retained by the department and shall not lapse to the general fund; and </section><section prefix="c">Contain such information as the commissioner deems necessary to carry out the purposes of this subtitle. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Applications for initial registrations of mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors shall be accompanied by satisfactory evidence that the applicant has successfully completed twenty (20) hours of prelicensing education courses related directly to the mortgage lending process, as approved and designated by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="b">For the purposes of paragraph (a) of this subsection, the prelicensing education courses approved and designated by the commissioner shall meet the minimum requirements set forth in Section 1505(c) of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act, Pub. L. No. 110-289, and amendments thereto, and shall be reviewed, and approved by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry. </section><section prefix="c">For the purposes of paragraph (a) of this subsection, the commissioner may accept as credit towards the completion of the prelicensing education requirements in this state, the completion of prelicensing education requirements in any other state so long as the education has met the requirements set forth in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="4">Applications for renewals of certificates of registration by registered mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors shall be accompanied by satisfactory evidence that the individual has successfully met the continuing education requirements of KRS 286.8-260 and by payment of a renewal fee in the amount of fifty dollars ($50). The renewal fee shall be used solely by the department to establish and maintain a database of all mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors and any excess funds shall be retained by the department and shall not lapse to the general fund. </section><section prefix="5">A certificate of registration issued between January 1 and October 31 of the same calendar year shall expire on December 31 of the same calendar year. A certificate of registration issued between November 1 and December 31 of the same calendar year shall expire on December 31 of the following calendar year. Any certificate of registration that has expired may be reinstated by the commissioner upon payment of the annual registration fee, and a reinstatement fee of two hundred fifty dollars ($250), within thirty (30) days of the expiration of the certificate of registration. </section><section prefix="6">The department shall provide a registrant with a duplicate copy of any certificate of registration upon satisfactory showing of its loss and payment of a ten dollar ($10) replacement fee. </section><section prefix="7">All mortgage loan originators and mortgage loan processors subject to the registration requirements of this section shall also be subject to and comply with all applicable provisions of this subtitle. </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner may require the submission of background records checks, including but not limited to checks for state, federal, and international criminal histories, civil or administrative records, and any other information as deemed necessary to comply with the minimum requirements set forth in Section 1505 of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act, Pub. L. No. 110-289, and amendments thereto, as well as the submission of an independent credit report obtained from a consumer reporting agency described in the Fair Credit Reporting Act, 15 U.S.C. sec. 1681a, as part of an application or renewal application filed under this subtitle. The cost of the background and records checks, and credit report shall be borne by the applicant. </section><section prefix="9">No mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor shall be granted or shall be entitled to maintain a certificate of registration unless he or she satisfies the following minimum standards for registration: <section prefix="a">The applicant has never had a loan originator's license or registration revoked in any governmental jurisdiction, except revocations that have been formally vacated or set aside shall not be deemed a revocation for the purposes of this section; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant has not been convicted of, pled guilty to, or pled nolo contendere to a felony in any domestic, foreign, or military court: <section prefix="1">During the seven (7) year period preceding the date of the application for registration or renewal of registration; or </section><section prefix="2">At any time preceding such date of application for registration or renewal of registration, if such felony involved an act of fraud or dishonesty, a breach of trust, or money laundering; </section></section><section prefix="c">The applicant has demonstrated financial responsibility, character, and general fitness such as to command the confidence of the community and to warrant a determination that the loan originator or loan processor will operate honestly, fairly, lawfully, and efficiently within the purposes of the subtitle; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant has completed the prelicensing education requirement set forth in subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="e">The applicant has passed a qualified written test which satisfies the minimum requirements set forth in Section 1505(d) of the S.A.F.E. Mortgage Licensing Act, Pub. L. No. 110-289, and amendments thereto; and </section><section prefix="f">If required by KRS 286.8-060, the applicant holds or is covered by a surety bond which satisfies the minimum requirements set forth in KRS 286.8-060. </section></section><section prefix="10">No mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor shall be granted a renewal certificate of registration unless he or she satisfies the following minimum standards for renewal of registration: <section prefix="a">The applicant has met and continues to meet the minimum standards set forth in subsection (9) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">The applicant has satisfied the annual continuing education requirements set forth in KRS 286.8-260. </section></section><section prefix="11">The certificate of registration of any mortgage loan originator or mortgage loan processor that fails to comply with the minimum standards for registration renewal set forth in this section shall expire and shall promptly be deemed surrendered to the commissioner without demand. The commissioner may adopt procedures and requirements for the reinstatement of expired registrations consistent with the standards established by the Nationwide Mortgage Licensing System and Registry. </section><section prefix="12">Mortgage loan originators engaging in any of the activities set forth in KRS 286.8-010(21)(a) shall provide loan origination services to not more than one (1) mortgage loan company or mortgage loan broker at a time. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 790, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 17, effective April 24, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification>KRS 294.255. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was amended in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 218. In that same session, 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 38, required that all sections of KRS Chapters 287, 288, 290, 291, 294, 366, 366A, and 368 be renumbered as sections of a single KRS chapter entitled the "Kentucky Financial Services Code." Therefore, the Statute Reviser, acting under KRS 7.136(1), has changed the number of this section and codified it as a section of KRS Chapter 286. In addition, KRS references have been adjusted to conform with the renumbering. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14888</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>