<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91">FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>91.4884</section_number><catch_line>Notice by mail to interested parties. </catch_line><order_by>4884</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The collector shall also cause to be prepared and mailed by first class mail, certified by a United States postal service certificate of mailing, within thirty (30) days after the filing of such petition, a brief notice of the filing of the suit to any taxing authority or person of record owning or holding any tax bills or claiming any right, title, or interest in or to, or lien upon, any such parcel of real estate as set out in the petition. </section><section prefix="2">The notice shall be substantially as follows: </section>To the person to whom this notice is addressed:  Public records indicate that you may own or claim some right, title, or interest in or to, or hold a lien upon a certain parcel of real estate located at (here insert the street address and the property valuation administrator's tax parcel number) and set out in count number _____ in a certain petition bearing Action No. _______ filed in the Circuit Court of ________ County, Kentucky at __________ (city) on _________, 19_____, wherein an enforcement of the liens of various delinquent tax bills is sought and a court order asked for the purpose of selling said real estate at a public sale for payment of all delinquent tax bills, together with interest, penalties, and costs. Publication of notice of such enforcement was commenced on the _____ day of ________, 19...., in __________ (here insert name of city).  Public records in the office of the county clerk or other public office indicate you may own or claim some interest in this parcel by reason of (Here insert specific reference to any public document of record as disclosed in a thorough examination of title status.).  Unless all delinquent city taxes are paid upon the parcel of real estate described in said petition and unless the owners of said real estate shall either have discharged any city tax liens or satisfied any judgment rendered on said liens in favor of the city, prior to the time of the enforcement sale of such real estate by the master commissioner, or within sixty (60) days after the sale if the purchase price at sale is less than the parcel's certified assessed value, the owner or any taxing authority or person of record claiming any right, title, or interest in or to, or lien upon, any such parcel of real estate shall be forever barred and foreclosed of all right, title and interest and equity of redemption in and to such parcel of real estate; provided, however, that any such person shall have the right to file an answer in said suit on or before the ______ day of ________, 19____, in the office of the Circuit Court clerk and copy thereof to the city of _________, in accordance with the Kentucky rules of civil procedure, setting forth in detail the nature and amount of the interest and any defense or objection to the enforcement. Dated ____________, 19____  ______________, Kentucky     (Name of city) ___________________ Attorney ___________________ ___________________ ___________________ Address ___________________ Phone </text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25511</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>