<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.441</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>441</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Intervention services" means any preventive, developmental, corrective, supportive services or treatment provided to a student who is at risk of school failure, is at risk of participation in violent behavior or juvenile crime, or has been expelled from the school district. Services may include, but are not limited to, screening to identify students at risk for emotional disabilities and antisocial behavior; direct instruction in academic, social, problem solving, and conflict resolution skills; alternative educational programs; psychological services; identification and assessment of abilities; counseling services; medical services; day treatment; family services; work and community service programs; </section><section prefix="2">"School resource officer" means a sworn law enforcement officer who has specialized training to work with youth at a school site. The school resource officer shall be employed through a contract between a local law enforcement agency and a school district; and </section><section prefix="3">"School security officer" means a person employed by a local board of education who has been appointed a special law enforcement officer pursuant to KRS 61.902 and who has specialized training to work with youth at a school site. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 2, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>