<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-050</section_number><catch_line>Secretary as chief executive officer -- Duties and responsibilities. </catch_line><order_by>10-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall be the chief executive officer of the Cabinet for Economic Development and shall possess the professional qualifications appropriate for that office as determined by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall set the salary of the secretary, which shall be exempt from state employee salary limitations as set forth in KRS 64.640. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall be responsible for the day-to-day operations of the cabinet and shall report and submit on an annual basis implementation plans to the board as provided in KRS 154.10-060; submit the strategic plan for economic development to the board in accordance with the provisions of KRS 154.10-120 and 154.10-125; submit program evaluation reports to the board in accordance with the provisions of KRS 154.10-140; carry out policy and program directives of the board; coordinate programs of the cabinet with all other agencies of state government having economic development responsibilities; hire all other personnel of the cabinet consistent with state law; and carry out all other duties and responsibilities assigned by state law. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall prepare and submit the proposed budget of the cabinet to the chairman who shall present it to the board for final approval. Upon approval, the board shall submit the proposed budget to the Governor's Office for Policy and Management. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall be reimbursed for all actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of all assigned duties and responsibilities. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary shall give highest priority consideration in marketing, targeting, and recruiting new businesses, in expanding existing businesses, and in recommending state economic development loans, grants, and incentive programs administered by the authority, to Kentucky counties which have had an average countywide rate of unemployment of fifteen percent (15%) or greater in the most recent twelve (12) consecutive months for which unemployment figures are available, on the basis of the final unemployment figures calculated by the Office of Employment and Training within the Department of Workforce Investment within the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 31, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 62, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43340</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>