<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-041</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against insurer's refusing to reissue motor vehicle liability policy or imposing additional premium because of uninsured status under certain conditions. </catch_line><order_by>20-041</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An insurer, with whom a person was most recently insured under a motor vehicle liability insurance policy, shall not refuse to issue a policy of motor vehicle liability insurance nor impose an additional premium solely because the person is uninsured at the time of reapplication, if the person demonstrates that: <section prefix="a">During the period he was without insurance, he did not own a motor vehicle, the registration on the insured motor vehicle was canceled because he was absent from the Commonwealth, the motor vehicle was out of use, or inoperable and under repair, or he was unable to pay the premium renewal due to unemployment or other bona fide economic hardship; and </section><section prefix="b">During the period the person was without insurance, he was not convicted of any traffic violation under the laws of the Commonwealth; and the reapplication was made within twenty-four (24) months of the nonrenewal of the policy. </section></section><section prefix="2">This section shall not be construed to permit the owner of the motor vehicles or any other person to operate or to permit the operation of the motor vehicle in this Commonwealth until the security has again been provided pursuant to Subtitle 39 of this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29479</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>