<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.840</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Technical Education Personnel Board.   </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Technical Education Personnel Board is hereby established to conduct personnel appeals from certified and equivalent employees in the Office of Career and Technical Education under KRS 156.800 to 156.860. Appeals shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions established in KRS Chapter 13B. The board shall be attached to the Department of Education for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Technical Education Personnel Board shall be composed of five (5) voting members, three (3) of whom shall be selected from employees within the Department of Education, except no member shall be an employee within the Office of Career and Technical Education. The remaining two (2) members shall be teachers employed by the Office of Career and Technical Education's Area Technology Centers. The election of the teacher representatives may be conducted by written ballot, Internet balloting, intranet balloting, or electronic mail. The teacher candidates may be present when the balloting is tallied. All votes cast shall be tallied by an independent entity. <section prefix="a">The Governor shall appoint the two (2) members elected by the teachers employed by the Office of Career and Technical Education's Area Technology Centers and the three (3) members selected from employees within the Department of Education. All members shall be appointed by the Governor to four (4) year terms, and each term shall end on June 30 of the fourth year. </section><section prefix="b">Terms of new members or reappointed members shall begin on July 1 of the year beginning their term. If a vacancy occurs during a term, the Governor shall appoint a replacement to serve the remainder of the unexpired term within thirty (30) days of the vacancy. The Governor shall select a replacement from the group where the vacancy occurred. The manner of selection for the replacement shall be the same as the manner of the original selection. </section><section prefix="c">The members shall possess an understanding of the personnel system established in KRS 156.800 to 156.860. </section><section prefix="d">A chair shall be elected annually by members of the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall meet as necessary to comply with time frames for conducting personnel appeals under KRS Chapter 13B and KRS 156.800 to 156.860, and at other times as deemed necessary by the chair of the board. For meetings of the board, a majority of the voting members shall be present to constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="4">The Office of Career and Technical Education shall provide administrative, budgetary and support staff services for the board. </section><section prefix="5">Pursuant to KRS 156.010, employees of the Department of Education who serve as members of the board shall not receive additional salary for serving as members on the board. However, upon approval of the commissioner of education, board members shall be entitled to reimbursement of actual and necessary expenses incurred while performing their duties as an active member of the board. </section><section prefix="6">During personnel appeals conducted by the board, both parties shall be given the opportunity to have a representative present at each step of the process. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 23, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 17, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 33, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 151B.097. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42191</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>