<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.7535</section_number><catch_line>Duty to notify court of change in foreign protective order.  </catch_line><order_by>7535</order_by><text>(1)A person who has filed a foreign protective order in a court in Kentucky isunder a continuing obligation to inform the court of any expiration, vacation,modification, or other change in the order which the person filing the order hasreceived from the issuing foreign court.(2)A person who has filed a foreign protective order in a court in Kentucky shall,within two (2) working days of the occurrence of any event specified insubsection (1) of this section, notify the clerk of the court in which the foreignprotective order was filed of the fact of the changed order and present the clerkwith a copy of the order for authentication as provided in this chapter. The clerkshall immediately notify the Law Information Network of Kentucky enteringagency of the modification.(3)No court in Kentucky and no peace officer in Kentucky shall be expected toenforce a provision of a foreign protective order which has been the subject ofany action specified in subsection (1) of this section, unless proper notice hasbeen given in accordance with this section.(4)Intentional failure of a person who has filed a foreign protective order to makethe notifications required by this section in the manner required by this sectionshall constitute contempt of court and may be grounds for an appropriate civilaction brought by any person damaged by the intentional act of omission bythe person failing to act.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 15, effective January1, 2016. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44763</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>