<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Architects; </section><section prefix="2">An "architect" is any person who engages in the practice of architecture as hereinafter defined; </section><section prefix="3">The "practice of architecture" is the rendering or offering to render certain services, hereinafter described, in connection with the design and construction of a structure or group of structures which have as their principal purpose human habitation or use, and the utilization of space within and surrounding such structures.  The services referred to in the previous sentence include planning, providing preliminary studies, designs, drawings and specifications, and administration of construction contracts; </section><section prefix="4">A "building" is a structure which has as its principal purpose human habitation or use; </section><section prefix="5">"Use group" is the classification of a building or structure based on the purpose for which it is used, as set forth in the Kentucky Building Code; </section><section prefix="6">"Consultant" is an individual, partnership, or firm acting subordinately and in a position of service to an architect engaged in the practice of architecture as defined; and </section><section prefix="7">"Administration of construction contracts" means: <section prefix="a">Conducting periodic site visits; </section><section prefix="b">Reviewing shop drawings and reviewing other submittals required of the contractor by the terms of the construction contract documents; </section><section prefix="c">Reporting to the owner any violations of applicable building codes and any substantial deviations from the contract documents that the architect observes; or </section><section prefix="d">Reporting to the building official any violations of applicable building codes that the architect observes. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31480</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>