<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.260</section_number><catch_line>Recommendation of additional stream areas by secretary for energy and environment -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for energy and environment shall study and from time to time submit to the Governor and to the General Assembly proposals for additions to the Wild Rivers System of streams and sections of streams which, in his judgment, would qualify for inclusion therein. Each proposal shall be accompanied by: <section prefix="a">A detailed map showing the boundaries of the stream or sections of streams and those adjacent lands needed to protect and administer the needed controls. </section><section prefix="b">The category of the proposed additions in accordance with KRS 146.230. </section><section prefix="c">A detailed report on the factors which make the area a worthy addition to the system. </section></section><section prefix="2">The intention of this requirement is to insure that such studies will be made; it is not intended to preclude or discourage, but rather encourage similar studies and proposals by other agencies or by citizen groups working independently. Authority for additions to the Wild Rivers System shall remain exclusively with the Kentucky General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 126, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(9). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29309</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>