<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.617</section_number><catch_line>Expansion of Medicaid coverage for screening and treatment of breast or cervical cancer or precancerous conditions -- Short title. </catch_line><order_by>617</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Medicaid Services shall expand Medicaid coverage to offer benefits to uninsured women who: <section prefix="a">Are under age sixty-five (65); </section><section prefix="b">Are not otherwise eligible for Medicaid; </section><section prefix="c">Have been screened for breast or cervical cancer or precancerous conditions, or any combination of these conditions, through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention's National Breast and Cervical Cancer Early Detection Program or through the Department for Public Health's Women's Cancer Screening Program; </section><section prefix="d">Are in need of treatment for breast or cervical cancer or precancerous conditions, or any combination of these conditions, as a result of a diagnosis of those conditions in a program identified in paragraph (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="e">Are not otherwise covered under creditable coverage, as defined in 42 U.S.C. sec. 300gg(c); and </section><section prefix="f">Meet any other eligibility-required criteria established under the Federal Breast and Cervical Cancer Prevention and Treatment Act of 2000. </section></section><section prefix="2">No later than three (3) months after April 10, 2008, the department shall submit to the secretary of the United States Department for Health and Human Services a request for approval of a plan amendment to extend coverage as authorized under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Within three (3) months following receipt of federal approval of a plan amendment, the department shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement the requirements of this section. If federal approval has not been received within six (6) months after April 10, 2008, for the plan amendment, the department shall report the status of the request for approval and the steps being taken by the department to secure federal approval. </section><section prefix="4">Medical assistance provided under the plan amendment shall be limited to medical assistance provided during the period in which a woman who meets the requirements of subsection (1) of this section requires treatment for breast or cervical cancer or precancerous conditions, or any combination of these conditions. In the case of any covered woman whose medical assistance has been terminated due to a cure or remission of a condition diagnosed under subsection (1)(c) of this section, medical assistance shall be reinstituted for any subsequent periods of recurrence or metastasis or any future conditions establishing eligibility under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall be known as the Kentucky Breast and Cervical Cancer Treatment Act of 2008. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective April 10, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> April 10, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7745</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>