<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.550</section_number><catch_line>Department to aid in enforcement -- Remedies of laborer. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any laborer, workman, or mechanic employed on public works may file a complaint of any violation of any provision of KRS 337.505 to 337.550 with the department. The department shall assist him or her in the collection of claims of wages due him or her and shall also assist to the fullest extent in the administration and enforcement of KRS 337.505 to 337.550. The commissioner shall investigate and enforce the provisions of KRS 337.505 to 337.550 to the fullest and shall bring all actions to collect wages due any laborer, workman, or mechanic and shall take action against any contractor or subcontractor to restrain violations of KRS 337.505 to 337.550. If any contractor or subcontractor is found to be in violation of any provisions of KRS 337.505 to 337.550, then the commissioner shall inform the secretary for finance and administration of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and the secretary for finance and administration shall hold such contractor or subcontractor ineligible to bid on public works until such time as that contractor or subcontractor is in substantial compliance as determined by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">A laborer, workman, or mechanic may by civil action recover any sum due him or her as the result of the failure of his or her employer to comply with the terms of KRS 337.505 to 337.550. The commissioner may also bring any legal action necessary to collect claims on behalf of any or all laborers, workmen, or mechanics. No employer shall take any punitive measure or action against an employee because such employee has made a charge, testified, assisted or participated in any manner in an investigation, proceeding, or hearing under KRS 337.505 to 337.550. The commissioner shall not be required to pay the filing fee, or other costs, in connection with such action. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1749, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 9. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2290c-6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32107</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>