<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.031</section_number><catch_line>Applicability of chapter. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the drawings and specifications are signed by the author thereof with the true titles of their occupations as may be required by law, this chapter does not apply to: <section prefix="a">Any building which is to be used for farm purposes only; </section><section prefix="b">Any residential structure that does not require the services or seal of an architect or engineer either under the Uniform State Building Code pursuant to KRS 198B.050 or under KRS 323.033; </section><section prefix="c">Any building classified by use group other than those listed under KRS 323.033 so long as the services or seal of an architect or engineer as applicable is not required for such other use group under the Uniform State Building Code pursuant to KRS 198B.050 or; </section><section prefix="d">Any structure not classified as a building by KRS 323.010(4). </section></section><section prefix="2">Provisions of this chapter shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Any individual, partnership, or firm acting solely as a consultant to an architect licensed in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">An architect or other person acting solely as an officer or employee of the United States government. </section></section><section prefix="3">A licensed professional engineer may prepare plans and specifications for and supervise the construction of structures as an incident to the practice of his own profession. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31483</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>