<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="108" order_by="108">URBAN SERVICES DISTRICTS -- AMBULANCE SERVICE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>108.020</section_number><catch_line>District's powers. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An urban services district through its council is empowered to:  <section prefix="a">Provide for police and fire protection;  </section><section prefix="b">Construct and maintain streets, sidewalks, alleys and other drives and walks;  </section><section prefix="c">Provide library services;  </section><section prefix="d">Provide for garbage and trash collection and disposal;  </section><section prefix="e">Provide for street lighting and street cleaning;  </section><section prefix="f">Acquire, maintain and operate parks and playgrounds;  </section><section prefix="g">Provide sewer, drainage and treatment services and facilities;  </section><section prefix="h">Collect fees for services performed and to levy assessments consistent with this chapter and in such amounts as the council shall deem necessary to carry out the functions of the district; and  </section><section prefix="i">Provide other services and engage in other activities, either directly or by contract with a county, a city or other districts, which contracts shall set forth what services are to be provided and how they are to be financed.  </section></section><section prefix="2">An urban services district is prohibited from providing sanitation service that is being provided in the same area by a sanitation district as of June 16, 1960.  </section></text><history>Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>