<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.790</section_number><catch_line>Penalties -- Confidentiality of information filed with tax district -- Suspension of services or payments if tax district fails to comply with KRS 67.766(1) or (2).   </catch_line><order_by>790</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A business entity subject to tax on gross receipts or net profits may be subject to a penalty equal to five percent (5%) of the tax due for each calendar month or fraction thereof if the business entity: <section prefix="a">Fails to file any return or report on or before the due date prescribed for filing or as extended by the tax district; or </section><section prefix="b">Fails to pay the tax computed on the return or report on or before the due date prescribed for payment. </section></section> The total penalty levied pursuant to this subsection shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total tax due; however, the penalty shall not be less than twenty-five dollars ($25). <section prefix="2">Every employer who fails to file a return or pay the tax on or before the date prescribed under KRS 67.783 may be subject to a penalty in an amount equal to five percent (5%) of the tax due for each calendar month or fraction thereof. The total penalty levied pursuant to this subsection shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total tax due; however, the penalty shall not be less than twenty-five dollars ($25). </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the penalties prescribed in this section, any business entity or employer shall pay, as part of the tax, an amount equal to twelve percent (12%) per annum simple interest on the tax shown due, but not previously paid, from the time the tax was due until the tax is paid to the tax district. A fraction of a month is counted as an entire month. </section><section prefix="4">Every tax subject to the provisions of KRS 67.750 to 67.790, and all increases, interest, and penalties thereon, shall become, from the time the tax is due and payable, a personal debt of the taxpayer to the tax district. </section><section prefix="5">In addition to the penalties prescribed in this section, any business entity or employer who willfully fails to make a return, willfully makes a false return, or willfully fails to pay taxes owing or collected, with the intent to evade payment of the tax or amount collected, or any part thereof, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who willfully aids or assists in, or procures, counsels, or advises the preparation or presentation under, or in connection with, any matter arising under KRS 67.750 to 67.790 of a return, affidavit, claim, or other document, which is fraudulent or is false as to any material matter, whether or not the falsity or fraud is with the knowledge or consent of the person authorized or required to present the return, affidavit, claim, or document, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="7">A return for the purpose of this section shall mean and include any return, declaration, or form prescribed by the tax district and required to be filed with the tax district by the provisions of KRS 67.750 to 67.790, or by the rules of the tax district or by written request for information to the business entity by the tax district. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">No present or former employee of any tax district shall intentionally and without authorization inspect or divulge any information acquired by him or her of the affairs of any person, or information regarding the tax schedules, returns, or reports required to be filed with the tax district or other proper officer, or any information produced by a hearing or investigation, insofar as the information may have to do with the affairs of the person's business. This prohibition does not extend to information required in prosecutions for making false reports or returns for taxation, or any other infraction of the tax laws, or in any way made a matter of public record, nor does it preclude furnishing any taxpayer or the taxpayer's properly authorized agent with information respecting his or her own return. Further, this prohibition does not preclude any employee of the tax district from testifying in any court, or from introducing as evidence returns or reports filed with the tax district, in an action for violation of a tax district tax laws or in any action challenging a tax district tax laws. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates the provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection by intentionally inspecting confidential taxpayer information without authorization shall be fined not more than five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisoned for not longer than six (6) months, or both. </section><section prefix="c">Any person who violates the provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection by divulging confidential taxpayer information shall be fined not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or imprisoned for not more than one (1) year, or both. </section></section><section prefix="9">If a tax district that imposes a net profits or gross receipts occupational license tax fails to comply with the requirements of KRS 67.766(1) or (2), the Secretary of State shall inform the tax district in writing of its noncompliance. If the tax district is not in compliance within thirty (30) days following the notice from the Secretary, the Secretary shall notify all state agencies which deliver services or payments of money from the Commonwealth to the tax district of the tax district's noncompliance. Those agencies shall suspend delivery of all services or payments to a tax district which fails to comply with the requirements of KRS 67.766(1) or (2). The Secretary of State shall immediately notify those same agencies when the tax district is in compliance with the requirements of KRS 67.766(1) or (2), and those agencies shall reinstate the delivery of services or payments to the tax district. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40273</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>