<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.430</section_number><catch_line>Plaque commemorating prisoners and missing soldiers in Vietnam War -- Duties of Department of Veterans' Affairs and Department for Facilities and Support Services. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To honor those Kentuckians who proudly served their country during the Vietnam War but remain unaccounted for, the Department of Veterans' Affairs shall update the plaque at the base of the Freedom Tree near the Floral Clock on the grounds of the New Capitol Annex to contain the names of Kentucky Vietnam War POW/MIAs from the most recent official accounting available from the United States Department of Defense. The plaque shall also contain a depiction of the POW/MIA flag of the National League of Families of American Prisoners of War and Missing in Southeast Asia. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall be responsible for the design of the new plaque required by subsection (1) of this section, and the plaque shall be paid for by the Department of Veterans' Affairs. The Department of Veterans' Affairs may receive appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and any other funds, both public and private, to defray the cost of updating the plaque. </section><section prefix="3">The Department for Facilities and Support Services shall be responsible for preparing the base for the updated plaque, and for installing the plaque. The Department for Facilities and Support Services shall be reimbursed the cost of the installation by the Department of Veterans' Affairs. The Department for Facilities and Support Services shall also be responsible for the routine maintenance of the Freedom Tree, the memorial plaque, and the grounds surrounding the tree and plaque. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 18, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><former-codification> KRS 42.0271. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22031</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>