<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.540Requirements</section_number><catch_line>for barber schools.   </catch_line><order_by>540Requirements</order_by><text>No license shall be renewed or issued by the barber board to any barber school, unless the school provides: <section prefix="1">The name of the proposed school; </section><section prefix="2">A statement that the proposed school is authorized to operate educational programs beyond secondary education; </section><section prefix="3">As a prerequisite of graduation, a prescribed course of instruction of not less than fifteen hundred (1,500) hours shall be given within a reasonable period with not more than eight (8) hours nor less than four (4) hours of instruction a day, exclusive of Sundays; </section><section prefix="4">Courses of instruction in histology of the hair, skin, muscles, and nerves of the face and neck; elementary chemistry with emphasis on sterilization and antiseptics; disease of the skin, hair, and glands; massaging and manipulating of the muscles of the upper body; cutting, shaving, arranging, dressing, coloring, bleaching, and tinting the hair and such other courses as may be prescribed by regulation of the board; and </section><section prefix="5">Such facilities, equipment, materials, and qualified teachers as may be required by rules and regulations of the board adopted pursuant to this chapter, but in no event shall any school have fewer than one (1) licensed teacher per twenty (20) students enrolled, or more than two (2) students per chair. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 19. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>