<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.164</section_number><catch_line>Political activity prohibited -- Discrimination prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>164</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No employee of the local school district shall take part in the management or activities of any political campaign for school board. </section><section prefix="2">No candidate for school board shall solicit or accept any political assessment, subscription, contribution, or service of any employee of the school district. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall use or promise to use, directly or indirectly, any official authority or influence, whether possessed or anticipated, to secure or attempt to secure for any person an appointment or advantage in appointment to a position as teacher or employee of any district board of education, or an increase in pay or other advantage in employment in any such position, for the purpose of influencing the vote or political action of any person. </section><section prefix="4">No teacher or employee of any district board of education shall be appointed or promoted to, or demoted or dismissed from, any position or in any way favored or discriminated against with respect to employment because of his political or religious opinions or affiliations or ethnic origin or race or color or sex or age or disabling condition. </section><section prefix="5">The local superintendent shall inform all school employees of the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 79, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. IV, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3882</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>