<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-320</section_number><catch_line>Notice of hearing. </catch_line><order_by>2-320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notice of hearings shall be given in accordance with the provision of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13B. If the persons to be given notice are not specified in the provision pursuant to which the hearing is held, the commissioner shall give notice to all persons whose pecuniary interest, to the commissioner's knowledge or belief, are to be directly and immediately affected by the hearing. </section><section prefix="2">If any hearing is to be held for consideration of matters which, under subsection (1) of this section, would otherwise require separate notice to more than thirty (30) persons, in lieu of other notice the commissioner may give notice of the hearing by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424; but the commissioner shall mail this notice to all persons who had requested the same in writing in advance and have paid to the commissioner the reasonable amount fixed by him or her to cover the cost thereof. The costs associated with the publication of a notice of hearing shall be borne by the person seeking the hearing. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 949, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 25, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 228, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 32, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 25, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16683</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>