<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-204</section_number><catch_line>Signing of records. </catch_line><order_by>2-204</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each record delivered to the Secretary of State for filing pursuant to this subchapter shall be signed in the following manner: <section prefix="a">An initial certificate of limited partnership shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate. </section><section prefix="b">An amendment adding or deleting a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate. </section><section prefix="c">An amendment designating as general partner a person admitted under KRS 362.2-803(3)(b) following the dissociation of a limited partnership's last general partner shall be signed by that person. </section><section prefix="d">An amendment required by KRS 362.2-803(3) following the appointment of a person to wind up the dissolved limited partnership's activities shall be signed by that person. </section><section prefix="e">Any other amendment shall be signed by: <section prefix="1">At least one (1) general partner listed in the certificate; </section><section prefix="2">Each other person designated in the amendment as a new general partner; and </section><section prefix="3">Each person that the amendment indicates has dissociated as a general partner, unless: <section prefix="a">The person is deceased, or a guardian or general conservator has been appointed for the person and the amendment so states; or </section><section prefix="b">The person has previously delivered to the Secretary of State for filing a statement of dissociation. </section></section></section><section prefix="f">A restated certificate of limited partnership shall be signed by at least one (1) general partner listed in the certificate, and, to the extent the restated certificate effects a change under any other paragraph of this subsection, the certificate shall be signed in a manner that satisfies that paragraph. </section><section prefix="g">A statement of cancellation shall be signed by all general partners listed in the certificate or, if the certificate of a dissolved limited partnership lists no general partners, then by the person appointed pursuant to KRS 362.2-803(3) or (4) to wind up the dissolved limited partnership's activities. </section><section prefix="h">Articles of conversion shall be signed by each general partner listed in the certificate of limited partnership. </section><section prefix="i">Articles of merger shall be signed as provided in KRS 362.2-958(1). </section><section prefix="j">Any other record delivered on behalf of a limited partnership to the Secretary of State for filing shall be signed by at least one (1) general partner listed in the certificate. </section><section prefix="k">A statement by a person pursuant to KRS 362.2-605(4) stating that the person has dissociated as a general partner shall be signed by that person. </section><section prefix="l">A statement of withdrawal by a person pursuant to KRS 362.2-306 shall be signed by that person. </section><section prefix="m">A record delivered on behalf of a foreign limited partnership to the Secretary of State for filing shall be signed by at least one (1) general partner of the foreign limited partnership. </section><section prefix="n">Any other record delivered on behalf of any person to the Secretary of State for filing shall be signed by that person. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person may sign by an attorney in fact any record to be filed pursuant to this subchapter. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 108, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>