<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.050</section_number><catch_line>Leasing and subleasing of lands by cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may lease or rent portions of lands acquired by it to responsible persons, for cultivation and grazing, but in no event shall it lease or rent lands the use of which would be detrimental to the growth of timber or destructive of game or wild animal life. Proceeds resulting from the leasing of such lands shall be deposited into the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet may, with the consent of the owner of lands leased to it, sublease or rent any of the leased lands in a manner that will not interfere with the growth of timber or the propagation of game and wild animal life. If the lands are subleased or rented under these conditions, the cabinet and the owner shall divide the proceeds arising from the use of the lands, on a fifty-fifty basis, the cabinet's one-half (1/2) shall be deposited into the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="3">In exercising the functions of this section the cabinet shall be exempted from any provision of KRS 45.301 or 45A.045. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 42, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 450, sec. 69, effective July 1, 1983. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(3). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 112. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2007i-21, 2007i-22. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note>.  Pursuant to 1982 Acts Chapter 450, รยง 69, effective July 1, 1983, the reference to KRS 42.030 in subsection (3) of this section is deleted and KRS 45.301 inserted in lieu thereof. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1835</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>