<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.420</section_number><catch_line>Records declared confidential -- Application. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby declares that confidentiality is essential for the proper administration and operation of sexually transmitted disease control activities in this state and that the principle of confidentiality must remain inviolate. </section><section prefix="2">All information, records, and reports in the possession of local health departments or the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and which concern persons infected with or suspected of being infected with or tested for or identified in an epidemiologic investigation for sexually transmitted disease are hereby declared to be strictly confidential and only personnel of local health departments and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services who are assigned to sexually transmitted disease control activities shall have access to such information, records, and reports. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing: <section prefix="a">The release of medical information to the physician retained by the person infected with or suspected of being infected with a sexually transmitted disease; </section><section prefix="b">The release of medical or epidemiological data or information for statistical purposes in a manner so that no individual person can be identified; </section><section prefix="c">The release of medical information with the written consent of all persons identified in the information to be released; </section><section prefix="d">The release of medical or epidemiological information necessary to enforce the provision of the rules and regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, issued pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, relating to the control and treatment of sexually transmitted disease; and </section><section prefix="e">The release of medical information made to medical personnel in a medical emergency to the extent necessary to protect the health or life of the named party. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 458, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 405, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8820</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>