<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.088</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocity for licensure, certification, and registration.   </catch_line><order_by>088</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may permit an out-of-state licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor, certified alcohol and drug counselor, or alcohol and drug peer support specialist to obtain a license, certificate, or registration by reciprocity if: <section prefix="a">The out-of-state licensee, certificate holder, or registrant possesses a valid license, certificate, or registration from another jurisdiction that grants the same privileges to persons licensed, certified, or registered by this state as Kentucky grants to persons licensed, certified, or registered by the other jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="b">The requirements for licensure, certification, or registration are substantially similar to the requirements in KRS 309.080 to 309.089; and </section><section prefix="c">The out-of-state licensee, certificate holder, or registrant seeking licensure, certification, or registration states that he or she has studied, is familiar with, and shall abide by KRS 309.080 to 309.089 and the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the requirements for licensure, certification, or registration under KRS 309.080 to 309.089 are more restrictive than the standards of the other jurisdiction, then the out-of-state licensee, certificate holder, or registrant shall comply with the additional requirements in KRS 309.080 to 309.089 to obtain a reciprocal license, certificate, or registration. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44299</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>