<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.010Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for chapter.  (Effective January 1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>010Definitions</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise:(1)"Real estate brokerage" means a single, multiple, or continuing act of dealingin time shares or options, selling or offering for sale, buying or offering to buy,negotiating the purchase, sale, or exchange of real estate, engaging inproperty management, leasing or offering to lease, renting or offering for rent,or referring or offering to refer for the purpose of securing prospects, any realestate or the improvements thereon for others for a fee, compensation, or othervaluable consideration;(2)"Commission" means the Kentucky Real Estate Commission;(3)"Net listing" means a listing agreement that provides for a stipulated net priceto the owner and the excess over the stipulated net price to be received by thelicensee as the fee compensation or other valuable consideration;(4)"Principal broker" means a person licensed as a broker under KRS 324.046who, in addition to performing acts of real estate brokerage or transactionscomprehended by that definition, is the single broker responsible for theoperation of the company with which he or she is associated;(5)"Real estate" means real estate in its ordinary meaning and includestimeshares, options, leaseholds, and other interests less than leaseholds;(6)"Sales associate" means any person licensed in accordance with KRS324.046(2) that is affiliated with a Kentucky-licensed principal broker and who,when engaging in real estate brokerage, does so under the supervision of theprincipal broker;(7)"Approved real estate school" means:(a)A school that has been given a certificate of approval by the KentuckyCommission on Proprietary Education or other regulatory bodies thatexercise jurisdiction over accreditation and approval and the KentuckyReal Estate Commission. The school shall also be currently in goodstanding with both the Kentucky Commission on Proprietary Education orother regulatory bodies that exercise jurisdiction over accreditation andapproval and the commission; or(b)A National Association of Realtors recognized program which has beenreviewed by the Kentucky Real Estate Commission and deemed anapproved real estate school;(8)"Accredited institution" means a college or university accredited byappropriately recognized educational associations or chartered and licensed inKentucky that grants credits toward a program for either an associate,baccalaureate, graduate, or professional degree;(9)"Property management" means the overall management of real property forothers for a fee, compensation, or other valuable consideration, and mayinclude the marketing of property, the leasing of property, collecting rentalpayments on the property, payment of notes, mortgages, and other debts onthe property, coordinating maintenance for the property, remitting funds andaccounting statements to the owner, and other activities that the commissionmay determine by administrative regulation;(10)"Broker" means any person who is licensed under KRS 324.046(1) andperforms acts of real estate brokerage;(11)"Designated manager" means a licensed sales associate or broker whomanages a main or branch office for the principal broker, at the principalbroker's direction, and has managing authority over the activities of the salesassociates at that office;(12)"Regular employee" means an employee who works for an employer, whosetotal compensation is subject to withholding of federal and state taxes andFICA payments, and who receives from the employer a fixed salary governedby federal wage guidelines that is not affected by specific real estatetransactions;(13)"Referral fee" means consideration of any kind paid or demanded for thereferral of a potential or actual buyer, seller, lessor, or lessee of real estate;(14)"Designated agency" means a form of agency relationship that exists when aprincipal broker, in accordance with KRS 324.121, identifies different licenseesin the same real estate brokerage firm to separately represent more than one<section prefix="1">party in the same real estate transaction;</section>(15)"Affiliation" means the relationship agreed upon between a licensee and aprincipal broker and reported to the commission, where the licensee places hisor her license with the principal broker for supervision of the licensee's realestate brokerage activity;(16)"Canceled" means the status of a license when a licensee fails to renew alicense, writes the commission a check for fees that is not honored, fails tore-affiliate with a principal broker, or fails to complete requirements forcontinuing or post-license education;(17)"Suspended" means the status of a license when disciplinary action has beenordered against a licensee that prohibits the brokerage of real estate for aspecific period of time;(18)"Revoked" means the status of a license when disciplinary action has beenordered that removes the licensee's legal authority to broker real estate for aminimum of five (5) years; and(19)"Post-license education" means the forty-eight (48) hours ofcommission-approved education required within two (2) years of receiving oractivating an initial sales associate license.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 25, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended2009 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky.Acts ch. 488, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 313,sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 2,effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 1, effective July15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. --Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended1978 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky.Acts ch. 100, sec. 7. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1. -- Repealed inpart 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, secs.  9 and12A. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, fromKy. Stat. sec. 3990e-2.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>