<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.450</section_number><catch_line>County buildings commission -- Membership, terms, bond, vacancies, officers. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the fiscal court adopting an order reciting the necessity of financing the acquisition, construction, remodeling or improvement of a county building or buildings of any type which a county has the legal right to acquire, construct, remodel or improve and requesting the county judge/executive to appoint a county buildings commission, the county judge/executive of such county shall thereupon appoint a county buildings commission composed of three (3) members. One (1) of such members shall have his term of office designated as three (3) years, one (1) of such members shall have his term of office designated as two (2) years and the remaining member shall have his term of office designated as one (1) year. Upon the expiration of the term of office of each of these commissioners, the county judge/executive shall appoint a commissioner to succeed him to serve for a term of three (3) years. Each commissioner shall execute a bond to be approved by the county judge/executive and shall be sworn to faithfully perform the duties of his position. Vacancies shall be filled by the county judge/executive.  </section><section prefix="2">The commissioners shall elect a chairman, secretary and treasurer.  </section></text><history>Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23739</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>