<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.8996Reports</section_number><catch_line>on child-care program activity.     </catch_line><order_by>8996Reports</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall prepare the following reports to the General Assembly on child-care programs, and shall make them available to the public: <section prefix="a">A quarterly report detailing the number of children and amounts of child-care subsidies provided in each area development district; </section><section prefix="b">A quarterly report on administrative expenses incurred in the operation of child-care subsidy programs; </section><section prefix="c">A quarterly report on disbursements of federal child-care block grant funds for training, resource and referral, and similar activities; and </section><section prefix="d">Beginning July 15, 1993, an annual report summarizing the average child-care subsidy activities per month in all Kentucky counties. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall file an annual report on its evaluation of the adequacy of the child-care subsidy to enable low-income families in need of child-care services to obtain child care with the Early Childhood Advisory Council and the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall file an annual report on the number of dedicated child-care licensing surveyor positions and the ratio of surveyors to child-care facilities with the Early Childhood Advisory Council and the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="4">By November 1, 2017, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Early Childhood Advisory Council shall report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare on recommendations and plans for sustaining the quality-based graduated early care and education program after the depletion of federal Race to the Top-Early Learning Challenge grant funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 199, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 163, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>