<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="72" order_by="72">CORONERS, INQUESTS, AND MEDICAL EXAMINATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>72.420</section_number><catch_line>Coroner's inquest -- Subpoenas -- Stenographic services -- Verdict. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A coroner may, in his sound discretion, order an inquest in any coroner's case. The inquest shall be conducted by a coroner's jury consisting of six (6) reputable citizens of the county selected and sworn by the coroner. The coroner may issue subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum. No subpoenaed witness shall fail to appear as ordered. Application may be made by the coroner to the Circuit Court for punishment by contempt for failure to obey a coroner's subpoena. </section><section prefix="2">The coroner may employ stenographic services to record the proceeding. Payment for stenographic services shall be made by the fiscal court or urban-county government, whichever is appropriate, upon certification by the coroner that the services were rendered. </section><section prefix="3">In the event the jury returns a verdict of murder, manslaughter, or other criminal act, the coroner shall arrest the named individual or notify the appropriate law enforcement authority to arrest such individual to be dealt with according to law. A copy of the verdict shall be filed with the appropriate Circuit Court clerk. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24317</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>