<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.425</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Nature Preserves Commission. </catch_line><order_by>425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission is hereby created and shall consist of five (5) members qualified and appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">The Governor shall seek advice on the making of appointments to the commission from, though not limited to, the following, if they have an active organization chartered in Kentucky: <section prefix="1">Kentucky Audubon Council </section><section prefix="2">Sierra Club </section><section prefix="3">The Izaak Walton League of America </section><section prefix="4">The Nature Conservancy </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky Ornithological Society </section><section prefix="6">Kentucky Academy of Science </section></section><section prefix="b">Of the five (5) commission members, one (1) shall be a representative from the Farm Bureau Association, one (1) shall be a representative from the National Farmers Organization, and one (1) shall be a representative from the State Association of Soil Conservation Districts. Each member shall be a resident of Kentucky, and not an employee or officer of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="c">Any vacancies on the commission shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. </section></section><section prefix="2">On or before July 1, 1988, the Governor shall make appointments to the commission to take effect on July 1, 1988, as follows: of the five (5) members of the commission, one (1) shall be for a term of one (1) year; two (2) for a term of two (2) years; and two (2) for a term of three (3) years. Thereafter, all successors shall be appointed for a three (3) year term, expiring on June 30 of the third year following appointment. If an appointment is made to fill a vacancy, the appointment shall be for the balance of the unexpired term. Each member of the commission shall hold office until his successor is appointed and qualifies. The commission shall organize by selecting from its membership a chairman and a secretary and shall provide rules for transacting its business and keeping records thereof. The commission shall meet quarterly or more frequently upon the call of the chairman or four (4) members. Three (3) members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The members of the commission shall receive no compensation but may be reimbursed for necessary expenses in connection with the performance of their duties. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 2, effective June 1, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 28, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>June 1, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1514</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>