<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="163" order_by="163">VOCATIONAL EDUCATION AND REHABILITATION </unit></structure><section_number>163.489</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Accessible Electronic Information Service Program -- Access provided -- Use of funding. </catch_line><order_by>489</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Accessible Electronic Information Service Program is created and shall be provided by the Office for the Blind. The program shall include: <section prefix="a">Intrastate access for eligible persons to read audio editions of newspapers, magazines, newsletters, schedules, announcements, and other information using a touch-tone telephone, radio, or other technologies that produce audio editions by use of computer; and </section><section prefix="b">A means of program administration and reader registration on the Internet, or by mail, telephone, or any other method providing consumer access. </section></section><section prefix="2">The program shall: <section prefix="a">Provide accessible electronic information services for all eligible blind and disabled persons as defined by KRS 163.487(2); and </section><section prefix="b">Make maximum use of available state, federal, and other funds by obtaining grants or in-kind support from appropriate programs and securing access to low-cost interstate rates for telecommunications by reimbursement or otherwise. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Office for the Blind shall review new technologies and current service programs in Kentucky for the blind and visually impaired that are available to expand audio communication if the office determines that these new technologies will expand access to consumers in a cost-efficient manner. The office may implement recommendations from the Office for the Blind State Rehabilitation Council for improving the program. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 97, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>