<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.30-110</section_number><catch_line>Agency cooperation and compliance with control requirements -- Review of standards or regulations -- Report to secretary. </catch_line><order_by>30-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">State agencies shall, to the fullest extent consistent with their authorities under state laws administered by them, carry out the programs within their control in such a manner as to further the policy stated in KRS 224.30-100. </section><section prefix="2">State agencies shall cooperate with the secretary in a state program of noise regulation developed and maintained under KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190. </section><section prefix="3">Each cabinet, agency, or instrumentality of the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of the government of this state having jurisdiction over any property or facility, or engaged in any activity resulting, or which may result, in the emission of noise, shall comply with federal, state, interstate, and local requirements respecting control and abatement of environmental noise to the same extent that any person is subject to such requirements. </section><section prefix="4">Each state agency shall consult with the secretary in prescribing standards or regulations respecting noise. If at any time the secretary has reason to believe that a standard or regulation, or any proposed standard or regulation, of any agency respecting noise does not protect the public health and welfare to the extent he believes to be required and feasible, he may request such agency to review and report to him on the advisability of revising such standard or regulation to provide such protection. Such agency shall complete the requested review and report to the secretary within such time as the secretary specifies, but such time specified may not be less than sixty (60) days from the date the request was made. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, secs. 1 and 13, effective June 21, 1974; and ch. 99, sec. 4, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><former-codification> KRS 224.720. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>