<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.080</section_number><catch_line>Registration fees. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The annual registration fee for motorboats shall be set by the department by administrative regulation. Every application for registration or renewal of registration shall be accompanied by the registration fee in addition to a one dollar ($1) fee which shall be deposited in a trust and agency account for use by the Transportation Cabinet in defraying the cost of implementing and operating the boat titling and registration program. </section><section prefix="2">The annual registration fee for motorboats for hire from a livery shall be the registration fees set forth in subsection (1) of this section. Owners of a livery shall apply for licenses or certificates in the manner provided in this chapter, but the Transportation Cabinet may promulgate special administrative regulations relating to their certification and registration. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 446, sec. 11, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 75, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 7. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 8, effective March 17, 1960. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 8, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11051</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>