<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.131</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and goals on national board certification. </catch_line><order_by>131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds that: <section prefix="a">Student achievement is directly related to the competency levels of the teachers and the teachers' ability to nurture student learning; </section><section prefix="b">All students are entitled to have teachers who know the subjects they teach and who demonstrate skill for managing and monitoring student learning; </section><section prefix="c">Teachers who meet entry-level standards need support and opportunities to develop higher-level skills throughout their teaching careers; </section><section prefix="d">Certification through the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards is based on high and rigorous standards and provides a process of development and assessment of teachers' knowledge, skills and abilities embedded in classroom practices in the certificate field; and </section><section prefix="e">Teachers who successfully meet the certification requirements through the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards can help strengthen the teaching profession within their schools and school districts by advising, assisting, and mentoring new teachers; by serving as role models and master teachers to student teachers; and by assisting other experienced teachers who seek national board certification. </section></section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly establishes, on behalf of the public school teachers and students in the Commonwealth, a goal that by the year 2020 there will be at least one (1) national board certified teacher in every public school in Kentucky. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>