<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.9-020</section_number><catch_line>Consequences of transacting business without authority.   </catch_line><order_by>9-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A foreign entity transacting business in this Commonwealth without a certificate of authority may not maintain a proceeding in any court in this Commonwealth until it obtains a certificate of authority. </section><section prefix="2">Neither the successor to a foreign entity that transacted business in this Commonwealth without a certificate of authority nor the assignee of a cause of action arising out of that business shall maintain a proceeding based on that cause of action in any court in this Commonwealth until the foreign entity or the assignee of the cause of action obtains a certificate of authority. </section><section prefix="3">A court may stay a proceeding commenced by a foreign entity, its successor, or assignee until it determines whether the foreign entity, its successor, or assignee requires a certificate of authority. If it so determines, the court may further stay the proceeding until the foreign entity, its successor, or assignee obtains the certificate. </section><section prefix="4">A foreign entity is liable for a civil penalty of two dollars ($2) for each day it transacts business in this Commonwealth without a certificate of authority. The Secretary of State may collect all penalties due under this subsection. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2) of this section, the failure of a foreign entity to obtain a certificate of authority shall not impair the validity of the acts of the foreign entity or prevent it from defending any proceeding in this Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 41, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36569</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>