<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.590</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for disciplinary action -- Payment of fines in lieu of license suspension -- Retesting in certain cases. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue or renew a license, revoke or suspend or place in probation a license, and impose fines in an amount not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500) for each violation upon proper showing of the applicant's or licensee's: <section prefix="a">Gross malpractice or incompetence; </section><section prefix="b">Mental or physical health that would endanger public health or safety; </section><section prefix="c">Failure to comply with regulations or rules of the board; </section><section prefix="d">False or deceptive advertising; </section><section prefix="e">Practicing in an unlicensed shop or in a shop knowing that the shop is not complying with this chapter or regulations of the board promulgated pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">Unprofessional conduct; </section><section prefix="g">Teaching in an unlicensed school or in a school knowing that the school is not complying with this chapter or administrative regulations of the board promulgated pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="h">Practicing as an independent contract owner in any manner that violates any provision of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated under this chapter; or </section><section prefix="i">Violation of a provision of this chapter or an administrative regulation promulgated by the board pursuant to this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board may require retesting of any licensee upon proper showing of gross malpractice or incompetence on the part of each licensee. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 23. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 19, effective June 30, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31148</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>