<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="518" order_by="518">MISCELLANEOUS CRIMES AFFECTING BUSINESSES, OCCUPATIONS, AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>518.090</section_number><catch_line>Assault of sports official. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of assault of a sports official when he intentionally causes physical injury to a sports official: <section prefix="a">Who was performing sports official duties at the time the physical injury was perpetrated; or </section><section prefix="b">If the physical injury occurs while the sports official is arriving at or departing from the athletic facility at which the athletic event occurred. </section></section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of this section, "sports official" means an individual who serves as a referee, umpire, linesman, or in a similar capacity that may be known by another title, and who is duly registered as or is a member of a national, state, regional, or local organization engaged, in part, in providing education and training to sports officials. </section><section prefix="3">A person who is guilty of assault of a sports official shall, for a first offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, unless the defendant assembles with five (5) or more persons for the purpose of assaulting a sports official, in which case it is a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="4">A person who is guilty of assault of a sport official shall, for a second or subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19857</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>