<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="625" order_by="625">TERMINATION OF PARENTAL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>625.050</section_number><catch_line>Petition. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petition for involuntary termination of parental rights shall be entitled "In the interest of ..., a child." </section><section prefix="2">The petition shall be filed in the Circuit Court for any of the following counties: <section prefix="a">The county in which either parent resides or may be found; </section><section prefix="b">The county in which juvenile court actions, if any, concerning the child have commenced; or </section><section prefix="c">The county in which the child involved resides or is present. </section></section><section prefix="3">Proceedings for involuntary termination of parental rights may be initiated upon petition by the cabinet, any child-placing agency licensed by the cabinet, any county or Commonwealth's attorney or parent. </section><section prefix="4">The petition for involuntary termination of parental rights shall be verified and contain the following: <section prefix="a">Name and mailing address of each petitioner; </section><section prefix="b">Name, sex, date of birth and place of residence of the child; </section><section prefix="c">Name and address of the living parents of the child; </section><section prefix="d">Name, date of death and cause of death, if known, of any deceased parent; </section><section prefix="e">Name and address of the putative father, if known by the petitioner, of the child if not the same person as the legal father; </section><section prefix="f">Name and address of the person, cabinet or agency having custody of the child; </section><section prefix="g">Name and identity of the person, cabinet or authorized agency to whom custody is sought to be transferred; </section><section prefix="h">Statement that the person, cabinet or agency to whom custody is to be given has facilities available and is willing to receive the custody of the child; </section><section prefix="i">All pertinent information concerning termination or disclaimers of parenthood or voluntary consent to termination; </section><section prefix="j">Information as to the legal status of the child and the court so adjudicating; and </section><section prefix="k">A concise statement of the factual basis for the termination of parental rights. </section></section><section prefix="5">No petition may be filed under this section prior to five (5) days after the birth of the child. </section><section prefix="6">No petition may be filed to terminate the parental rights of a woman solely because of her use of a nonprescribed controlled substance during pregnancy if she enrolls in and maintains substantial compliance with both a substance abuse treatment or recovery program and a regimen of prenatal care as recommended by her health care practitioner throughout the remaining term of her pregnancy. Upon certified completion of the treatment or recovery program, or six (6) months after giving birth during which time substantial compliance with a substance abuse treatment or recovery program has occurred, whichever is earlier, any records maintained by a court or by the cabinet relating to a positive test for a nonprescribed controlled substance shall be sealed by the court and may not be used in any future criminal prosecution or future petition to terminate the woman's parental rights. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 20, effective March 25, 2015; and ch. 82, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 70, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 101, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>March 25, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/25/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 66 and 82, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>