<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.233</section_number><catch_line>Influencing decision on award of economic incentive package -- Disclosure statement by beneficiary. </catch_line><order_by>233</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246, the term "executive agency lobbyist" does not include a person acting to promote, oppose, or otherwise influence the outcome of a decision of the Cabinet for Economic Development or any board or authority within or attached to that cabinet relating to the issuance or award of a bond, grant, lease, loan, assessment, incentive, inducement, or tax credit pursuant to KRS 42.4588, 103.210, Chapter 154, or Chapter 224A, or otherwise relating to any other component of an economic incentive package. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding subsection (1), before any board or authority within or attached to the Cabinet for Economic Development takes final action on any contract or agreement by which any bond, grant, lease, loan, assessment, incentive, inducement, or tax credit is awarded, the beneficiary of an economic incentive package shall file with the approving board or authority a disclosure statement which shall contain: <section prefix="a">The identity of the beneficiary of an economic incentive package and any person employed to act on its behalf in its dealings with the Cabinet for Economic Development or any board or authority within or attached to that cabinet regarding the matters to which the contract or agreement refers; and </section><section prefix="b">The details of any financial transaction as defined in KRS 11A.201(5)(a) between the beneficiary or any other person listed as an employee or agent of the beneficiary as required by paragraph (a) of this subsection and any agent or public servant of the Cabinet for Economic Development, any member of any board or authority within or attached to that cabinet, or any other public servant involved in the negotiation of the economic incentive package. </section></section><section prefix="3">After final action by the board or authority, the Cabinet for Economic Development shall file the disclosure statement described in subsection (2) of this section with the Executive Branch Ethics Commission, but the cabinet may delete information identifying the beneficiary of the economic-incentive package if the cabinet believes that identification would damage economic development. </section><section prefix="4">No beneficiary of an economic incentive package as referred to in this section shall engage any person to influence decisions of the Cabinet for Economic Development or the approving board or authority for compensation that is contingent in any way on the outcome of the decisions of the cabinet or the approving board or authority regarding contracts or agreements specified in subsection (2) of this section, and no person shall accept any engagement to influence these decisions or conduct lobbying activities related to these decisions for compensation that is contingent in any way on the outcome of the decisions of the cabinet or the approving board or authority regarding these contracts or agreements. </section><section prefix="5">Subsection (4) of this section does not prohibit, and shall not be construed to prohibit, any person from compensating that person's sales employees pursuant to any incentive compensation plan, such as commission sales, if the incentive compensation plan is the same plan used to compensate similarly-situated sales employees who are not engaged by the beneficiary of an economic incentive package in activities and functions referred to in this section. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=613</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>