<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.504</section_number><catch_line>Spinal cord and head injury research trust fund. </catch_line><order_by>504</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The revenues received from the disbursements provided under KRS 42.320(2)(c) shall be credited to the spinal cord and head injury research trust fund which is hereby created. </section><section prefix="2">Federal funds or other funds which may be made available to supplement or match state funds for spinal cord and head injury research programs provided for by KRS 211.500 to 211.504 shall be credited to the trust fund created in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Funds deposited to the credit of the spinal cord and head injury research trust fund shall be used to finance the spinal cord and head injury research programs authorized under the provisions of KRS 211.500 to 211.504 and for the operation of the Kentucky Spinal Cord and Head Injury Research Board. Funds for research shall only be used for spinal cord and head injury research undertaken by the University of Kentucky or University of Louisville. </section><section prefix="4">Funds unexpended at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year or biennium, but any surplus shall be included in the budget considered and approved by the board for the ensuing period. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 22, effective August 1, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>