<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.388</section_number><catch_line>Nonrefundable tax credit for new home purchases. </catch_line><order_by>388</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Approved time" means a period of time beginning on July 26, 2009, and ending on December 31, 2010; </section><section prefix="b">"New home tax credit cap" means a maximum of fifteen million dollars ($15,000,000) allocated to qualified buyers on a first-come, first-served basis; </section><section prefix="c">"Purchase" means a point within the approved time when escrow closes between the qualified buyer and the seller of the qualified principal residence; </section><section prefix="d">"Qualified buyer" means a resident who purchases a qualified principal residence; and </section><section prefix="e">"Qualified principal residence" means a single-family dwelling which is: <section prefix="1">Either detached or attached; </section><section prefix="2">Certified by the seller as having never been occupied; and </section><section prefix="3">Purchased to be the principal residence of the qualified buyer for a minimum of two (2) years. </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">There is hereby created a one (1) time, nonrefundable new home tax credit against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020, with the ordering of credits as provided in KRS 141.0205. </section><section prefix="b">The credit shall apply to the tax liability of a qualified buyer who purchases a qualified principal residence within the approved time. </section><section prefix="c">Within seven (7) calendar days after the purchase of a qualified principal residence, the qualified buyer shall submit via fax a completed application for the new home tax credit on forms provided by the department, except that any qualified buyer who purchased a qualified principal residence after November 6, 2009, but before June 4, 2010, shall have thirty (30) calendar days from June 4, 2010, to submit via fax a completed application. </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">The new home tax credit allowable to the qualified buyer shall be equal to five thousand dollars ($5,000), unless the new home tax credit cap has been reached. </section><section prefix="2">If the new home tax credit cap has been reached, the qualified buyer shall not receive a credit. </section></section><section prefix="e">The new home tax credit is not refundable and any unused amount in the taxable year of the purchase cannot be carried forward or back to another taxable year. </section><section prefix="f">Any credit that reduced the tax imposed by KRS 141.020 shall be repaid in total if the qualified buyer does not occupy the new home for at least two (2) years immediately following the purchase. </section></section><section prefix="3">To administer the new home tax credit and new home tax credit cap, the department shall: <section prefix="a">Create the application required to be filed by a qualified buyer; </section><section prefix="b">Promulgate administrative regulations to administer the new home tax credit, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">The process of recapture of the credit if the qualified buyer does not maintain the new home as his or her principal residence for two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="2">How to allocate the new home tax credit between unmarried co-purchasers or between married individuals who file separate returns; </section></section><section prefix="c">Create a Web site containing the amount of the total credit allocated to date, the date the last processed application was received, and the remaining credit available to qualified buyers; </section><section prefix="d">Establish a dedicated telephone line to receive faxed applications; </section><section prefix="e">Allow the date and time stamp from the faxed application as the order within which the application was received; and </section><section prefix="f">Notify the qualified buyer of the allowable credit available to the qualified buyer by a credit allocation letter, which shall be submitted by the qualified buyer with his or her return. </section></section><section prefix="4">The application for the new home tax credit shall be void if: <section prefix="a">The home has been previously occupied; </section><section prefix="b">The application is not received within seven (7) calendar days from the purchase; </section><section prefix="c">The application is not received within thirty (30) calendar days from June 4, 2010, for purchases of a qualified principal residence after November 6, 2009, but before June 4, 2010; or </section><section prefix="d">The application is received after the new home tax credit cap has been reached. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 6, effective June 4, 2010. -- Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 104, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 4, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (6/4/2010).  2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 29, provides: "The amendments to KRS 141.388(1)(a) and (b) contained in Section 6 of this Act apply to all purchases of qualified residences within the approved time, as those terms are defined within that subsection. The amendments to KRS 141.388(1)(d), (2), and (4) contained in Section 6 of this Act apply to purchases of qualified residences after November 6, 2009." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29128</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>