<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.420</section_number><catch_line>Department of Corrections to administer program -- Treatment in inpatient and outpatient environments -- Transfer -- Staff -- Data collection. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall have the sole authority and responsibility for establishing by regulation the design of the specialized program created in KRS 197.400 to 197.440. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall include diagnostic and treatment services in both inpatient and outpatient environments: <section prefix="a">"Diagnostic services" shall include social and family histories, medical history, educational development, interpersonal development, criminal history, psychological screening, and pre-release evaluation; </section><section prefix="b">"Treatment services" shall include individualized treatment plans to include individual, group, marital, and family counseling; psychoeducational courses to include sex education and victim personalization; and social skills development to include assertiveness training, stress management, and aggression management; and </section><section prefix="c">The department shall have the authority and responsibility for establishing other educational and work programs necessary to complement treatment program objectives. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department may transfer sexual offenders sentenced to its custody to the program and shall adopt administrative regulations concerning the transfer of sexual offenders. </section><section prefix="4">All sexual offenders participating in the program may be housed separately from all other incarcerated inmates but shall be housed in accordance with the department's standard classification system. </section><section prefix="5">The treatment staff of the program shall minimumly consist of the following staff: <section prefix="a">A program director who has at least a master's degree in a recognized mental health field and six (6) years' clinical experience or a doctoral degree in a recognized mental health field and four (4) years' clinical experience. The director shall decide program policies and supervise all staff; </section><section prefix="b">A clinical psychologist or a master's degree level psychologist for each two hundred (200) participants. At least one (1) clinical psychologist shall be a member of the staff at all times; and </section><section prefix="c">A counselor for each fifty (50) participants. </section></section><section prefix="6">The department shall establish a system of data collection and program evaluation so as to allow study of participating sexual offenders and their offenses and to measure the impact of the program on recidivism. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 65, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 478, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6899</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>