<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9103</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Kentucky Radon Program Advisory Committee -- Qualifications of members -- Terms -- Vacancies -- Quorum -- Officers. </catch_line><order_by>9103</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Radon Program Advisory Committee is hereby created and shall be attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. Each member of the committee shall be a citizen and resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The committee shall consist of nine (9) members as follows: <section prefix="a">Four (4) members shall be either a radon measurement contractor, a radon mitigation contractor, or a person associated with a radon laboratory conducting laboratory analysis and shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of six (6) names submitted to the Governor by the Kentucky Association of Radon Professionals; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a representative of the home building industry and shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) names submitted to the Governor by the Home Builders Association of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a real estate salesperson or broker licensed under KRS Chapter 324 and shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) names submitted to the Governor by the Kentucky Association of Realtors; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be a representative of a public health organization and shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) names submitted to the Governor by the Kentucky Cancer Consortium; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or his or her designee; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large appointed by the Governor who shall represent the public and shall not be associated with or financially interested in the practice of radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">To be eligible for initial appointment as a member of the committee under subsection (1)(a) of this section, a person shall have been actively engaged in the practice of radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis for not less than three (3) years immediately preceding the date of appointment to the committee. </section><section prefix="b">Upon expiration of the initial appointments, to be eligible for appointment as a member of the committee under subsection (1)(a) of this section, a person shall have been actively engaged in the practice of radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis for not less than three (3) years immediately preceding the date of the appointment to the committee and hold a valid certification as a radon measurement contractor or radon mitigation contractor, or be associated with a radon laboratory with a valid certification. </section></section><section prefix="3">Except for the commissioner, who shall serve as long as he or she holds his or her appointment as commissioner, the Governor shall initially appoint two (2) members for a term of four (4) years, two (2) members for a term of three (3) years, two (2) members for a term of two (2) years, and two (2) members for a term of one (1) year. All appointments shall expire on June 30 of the last year of the terms. Thereafter, members shall be appointed for terms of four (4) years. No person shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. Members shall serve until their successors are appointed. </section><section prefix="4">Upon recommendation of the committee, the Governor may remove any member of the committee appointed by the Governor for poor attendance, neglect of duty, misfeasance, or malfeasance in office. </section><section prefix="5">Vacancies in the membership of the committee for any cause shall be filled by appointment by the Governor for the balance of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="6">A majority of the committee shall constitute a quorum to do business. The committee shall meet at least once each calendar quarter in a location designated by the chairperson. The committee may meet upon special call by the chairperson or a majority of the committee. </section><section prefix="7">The committee shall elect a chairperson and a vice chairperson. The chairperson shall preside at all meetings at which the chairperson is present. The vice chairperson shall preside at all meetings in the absence of the chairperson. </section><section prefix="8">If the chairperson and vice chairperson are absent from a meeting of the committee when a quorum exists, the members who are present may elect a presiding officer who shall serve as acting chairperson until the conclusion of the meeting or until the arrival of the chairperson or vice chairperson. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39797</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>