<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.5605</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 205.5605 to 205.5607. </catch_line><order_by>5605</order_by><text>As used in KRS 205.5605 to 205.5607, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Budget allowance" means the amount of money made available each month to a consumer to purchase covered services and supports. The amount of money shall not exceed the amount that would have been allocated in the traditional Medicaid program for nonresidential and nonmedical services for the consumer; </section><section prefix="2">"Consumer" means a person who has chosen to participate in the program, has met the enrollment requirements, has a person-centered plan, and has received an approved budget allowance; </section><section prefix="3">"Covered services and supports" means those services and supports that are eligible for reimbursement under the program and that are approved for the consumer following a functional needs assessment and pursuant to a person-centered plan; </section><section prefix="4">"Fiscal intermediary" means an entity that is approved by the cabinet to provide service that helps the consumer manage his or her budget allowance, retains the funds, processes any employment and tax information, reviews records to ensure correctness, writes paychecks to providers, and delivers paychecks or electronically transfers funds to the consumer for distribution to providers or caregivers; </section><section prefix="5">"Provider" means: <section prefix="a">A person or agency licensed or otherwise permitted to render services eligible for reimbursement under this program for whom the consumer is not the employer of record; or </section><section prefix="b">A consumer-employed caregiver that renders services eligible for reimbursement under this program for whom the consumer is the employer of record; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Representative" means an uncompensated individual designated by the consumer to assist in managing the consumer's budget allowance and needed services; and </section><section prefix="7">"Service advisor" means the person who provides technical assistance to a consumer in meeting responsibilities under KRS 205.5605 to 205.5607. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/04). 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 4, provides that 2004 Ky. Acts ch.60, secs. 1 to 3, codified at KRS 205.5605 to 205.5607, shall be known as the Kentucky Independence Plus Through Consumer-Directed Services Program Act of 2004. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7709</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>