<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.12-230</section_number><catch_line>KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220 prevail over other provisions of KRS Chapter 271B -- Severability of provisions. </catch_line><order_by>12-230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220 are in addition to and do not repeal any other provisions of KRS Chapter 271B that govern any corporate actions described in KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220; provided, that in the event of a direct conflict between any provision of KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220 and any other provision of KRS Chapter 271B, the provision of KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220 shall prevail. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be considered that, for the purposes of KRS 446.090, it is the intent of the general assembly in enacting KRS 271B.12-200 to 271B.12-220 that any clause, sentence, subparagraph, paragraph, subsection, section, or other part of the above-stated sections or the application thereof to any person or circumstances held to be invalid shall not affect, impair or invalidate the remainder of the stated sections or the application of that part held invalid to any other person or circumstances, but shall be confined in its operation to the clause, sentence, subparagraph, paragraph, subsection, section, or other part thereof directly involved in that holding or to the person or circumstances therein involved. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1988 </effective><former-codification> KRS 271A.399. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>