<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.530</section_number><catch_line>License to be surrendered upon revocation -- Police chief or sheriff to return license. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text>Within three (3) days after any order of revocation of a license issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 becomes final, notice of revocation shall be given to the licensee and to the owner of the licensed premises. A notice mailed to the licensee and to the owner of the licensed premises at the address shown in the last application for a license or in the last statement supplemental to the application shall be deemed sufficient compliance with this section. The licensee shall at once surrender his license to the board. If the license revoked is for premises located in any city that has a police force of its own, the board, immediately upon mailing notice of the revocation of the license to the licensee, shall mail to the chief of the police department of that city a written notice stating the fact of the revocation, the name of the licensee whose license was revoked, the address of the premises that had been licensed under the revoked license and the date of the revocation. If the license revoked is for premises that are not located in any city with a police force of its own, the board shall in like manner and at like time mail a similar notice to the sheriff of the county in which the premises are located. If the revoked license is not forthwith surrendered by the licensee, the chief of the police department or sheriff shall, at the request of the board, immediately cause one of his officers to take physical possession of the license and return it to the board. </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-143. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11377</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>