<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-415</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Alternative Fuel and Renewable Energy Fund Program -- Purpose.   </catch_line><order_by>20-415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created in the cabinet a Kentucky Alternative Fuel and Renewable Energy Fund Program to provide funding to Kentucky-based companies to undertake research and development and commercialization work in the area of alternative fuels and renewable energy. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the program is to: <section prefix="a">Accelerate knowledge transfer and technological innovation, improve economic competitiveness, and spur economic growth of Kentucky-based companies involved in the areas of alternative fuels or renewable energy; </section><section prefix="b">Support research and development activities that have clear potential to lead to commercially successful products, processes, or services in the areas of alternative fuels or renewable energy within a reasonable period of time; </section><section prefix="c">Stimulate growth-oriented alternative fuels and renewable energy enterprises within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">Encourage partnerships and collaborative projects between private enterprises, Kentucky's public and private colleges and universities, and research organizations in alternative fuels and renewable energy; and </section><section prefix="e">Promote research and development and commercialization activities in alternative fuels and renewable energy that are market-oriented. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 48, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42408</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>