<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="345" order_by="345">COLLECTIVE BARGAINING FOR FIREFIGHTERS </unit></structure><section_number>345.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>When used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Public employer" means a city of the first class or a consolidated local government, or any city that petitions the secretary of the Labor Cabinet to be included by this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">"Firefighter" means an employee of the public employer engaged in serving the public by providing fire protection, including those covered by KRS Chapter 95; </section><section prefix="3">"Labor organization" means any chartered labor organization of any kind in which firefighters participate and which exists for the primary purpose of dealing with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rate of pay, hours of employment, or conditions of employment; </section><section prefix="4">"Exclusive representative" means the labor organization which has been designated by the State Labor Relations Board as the representative of the majority of firefighters in appropriate units or has been so recognized by the public employer; </section><section prefix="5">"Board" means the State Labor Relations Board; </section><section prefix="6">"Person" includes one (1) or more individuals, labor organizations, associations, corporations, legal representatives, trustees, trustees in bankruptcy, or receivers; </section><section prefix="7">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Labor Cabinet of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1868, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 227, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 42, effective July 13, 1994. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32678</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>