<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.18-020</section_number><catch_line>"Group health insurance" defined -- Eligible groups and benefits. </catch_line><order_by>18-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Group health insurance" is hereby declared to be that form of health insurance covering groups of persons as defined in this section, with or without one (1) or more members of their families or one (1) or more of their dependents, or covering one (1) or more members of the families or one (1) or more dependents of such groups of persons, and issued upon the following basis: <section prefix="a">Under a policy issued to an employer or trustees of a fund established by an employer, who shall be deemed the policyholder, insuring employees of such employer for the benefit of persons other than the employer (except as to policies insuring only against aviation or transportation hazards). The term "employees" as used in this paragraph shall be deemed to include the officers, directors, managers and employees of the employer, the individual proprietor or partner if the employer is an individual proprietor or partnership, the officers, directors, managers and employees of subsidiary or affiliated corporations, the individual proprietors, partners and employees of individuals and firms, if the business of the employer and such individual or firm is under common control through stock ownership, contract or otherwise. The term "employees" as used in this paragraph may include retired employees. A policy issued to insure employees of a public body may provide that the term "employees" shall include elected or appointed officers. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include the trustees or their employees, or both, if their duties are principally connected with such trusteeship; </section><section prefix="b">Under a policy issued to an association, including a labor union, which shall have a constitution and bylaws and which has been organized and is maintained in good faith for purposes other than that of obtaining insurance, insuring members, employees, or employees of members of the association for the benefit of persons other than the association or its officers or trustees. The term "employees" as used in this paragraph may include directors of corporate members and retired employees; </section><section prefix="c">Under a policy issued to the trustees of a fund established by two (2) or more employers in the same or related industry or by one (1) or more labor unions or by one (1) or more employers and one (1) or more labor unions or by an association as defined in paragraph (b), which trustees shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure employees of the employers or members of the unions or of such association, or employees of members of such association, for the benefit of persons other than the employers or the unions or such association. The term "employees" as used in this paragraph may include the officers, directors, managers, and employees of the employer, and the individual proprietor or partners if the employer is an individual proprietor or partnership. The term "employees" as used in this paragraph may include retired employees. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include the trustees or their employees, or both, if their duties are principally connected with such trusteeship; </section><section prefix="d">Under a policy issued to a creditor insuring a group of debtors, as defined in KRS 304.16-040, and under the same conditions and limitations as specified in such section, but the amount in indemnity payable with respect to any person insured thereunder shall not at any time exceed the aggregate of the periodic scheduled unpaid installments; </section><section prefix="e">Under a policy issued to any other person or organization to which a policy of group life insurance may be issued or delivered in this state to insure any class or classes of individuals that could be insured under such group life policy; and </section><section prefix="f">Under a policy issued to cover any other substantially similar group which, in the discretion of the commissioner, may be subject to the issuance of a group health policy or contract. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any group health policy which contains provisions for the payment by the insurer of benefits for expenses incurred on account of hospital, nursing, medical, or surgical services for members of the family or dependents of a person in the insured group may provide for the continuation of such benefit provisions, or any part or parts thereof, after the death of the person in the insured group. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1292, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 58, effective April 10, 1998. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 18, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29416</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>