<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.180</section_number><catch_line>Construction services contracts. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Construction services contract" means: <section prefix="1">A contract or agreement relating to the construction, alteration, repair, addition to, subtraction from, improvement to, or maintenance of any building, highway, road, railroad, excavation, or other structure, project, development, or improvement attached to real estate, including moving and demolition connected therewith; or </section><section prefix="2">A contract or agreement relating to the planning, design, administration, study, evaluation, consulting, or other professional and technical support services provided in connection with any of the work or activities described in subparagraph 1. of this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Contractor" means the person offering a contract for services provided. </section><section prefix="c">"Contractee" means the person providing services under a contract. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any provision contained in any construction services contract purporting to indemnify or hold harmless a contractor from that contractor's own negligence or from the negligence of his or her agents, or employees is void and wholly unenforceable. </section><section prefix="3">This section does not apply to construction bonds or affect the validity of insurance contracts. </section><section prefix="4">This section does not affect contracts or agreements entered into before June 20, 2005. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35238</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>