<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.879</section_number><catch_line>Consideration of written report of public hearing -- Ordinance of determination. </catch_line><order_by>879</order_by><text>At a subsequent regular meeting of the urban-county council of the government, the written report of the public hearing shall be publicly received and considered by the urban-county council.  At the meeting, or any subsequent, properly convened, regular, adjourned or special meeting of the urban-county council, prior to enactment of the ordinance of determination, owners of benefited properties may again be heard in person or by representatives.  At any subsequent regular meeting, the urban-county council, following receipt of facts and data determined by it to be sufficient in the premises regarding the wastewater collection project, including the report of public hearing, data submitted by local health authorities, if any, engineering information and data, statements by owners of benefited properties, and any other data deemed relevant, may adopt an ordinance, designated as the ordinance of determination, with respect to the project which may provide for either:  (1) the undertaking of the project with provision for the financing thereof as previously set forth in the ordinance of initiation; (2) the abandonment of the project; or (3) the alteration of the nature and scope of the project, in which event the procedure for ordinance of initiation and public hearing shall be repeated pursuant to the provisions of KRS 67A.871 to 67A.894.  The ordinance of determination shall be published as provided by KRS Chapter 424. </text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 9, effective March 30, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>March 30, 1976 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23962</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>