<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.35-040</section_number><catch_line>Governing committee. </catch_line><order_by>35-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Reinsurance Association shall be governed by a committee consisting of seven (7) persons to be appointed by the commissioner of insurance. The commissioner shall appoint two (2) persons representing insurers chartered under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, one (1) person representing an insurer that is neither chartered under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky nor affiliated with one (1) of the national insurance trade associations, one (1) person representing an insurer from each of the following three (3) associations: American Insurance Association, National Association of Mutual Insurance Companies, the Property Casualty Insurers Association of America, and one (1) licensed insurance agent. </section><section prefix="2">The "FAIR" plan shall maintain a formulated plan and articles consistent with this subtitle. The governing committee of the association may, on its own initiative or shall at the request of the commissioner, amend the plan and articles, subject to approval by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">The governing committee of the association shall, on or before April 1 of each year, file with the commissioner, on such forms as the commissioner requires, an accounting of the plan's operations during the preceding calendar year together with its financial condition, and its underwriting experience as to each separate account maintained therein, as of the end of such year. The commissioner may require interim accountings on a quarterly basis or examine the affairs of the association when, in his or her opinion, such action is necessary to determine the continued solvency of the Reinsurance Association. </section><section prefix="4">If at any time the commissioner determines that the Reinsurance Association is or may become unable to meet its financial obligations during the current year, the commissioner shall order the governing committee to levy appropriate assessments within the limitations of KRS 304.35-030(1) against all members. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1461, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1972. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29903</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>