<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.370</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of plumbing installation permits for on-site sewage disposal systems -- Local board of health as agent for cabinet -- Regulations. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>The commissioner of the Department for Public Health shall, upon written request from a local board of health, authorize the local board of health to serve as its agent to issue permits for on-site sewage disposal systems as described in KRS 211.350 within that area of local board jurisdiction. As agent, the authorized local board of health shall act for the cabinet in issuing permits and granting variances for on-site sewage disposal systems. Actions by the local board of health shall comply with the regulations established by the cabinet relating to on-site sewage disposal systems. The local board of health shall include in the written request a procedure for administering this section. The local board of health may adopt regulations relating to the proper operation and maintenance of on-site sewage disposal systems. In counties containing a city of the first class or a consolidated local government and in urban-counties, the local board of health may adopt regulations relating to the proper construction, installation, and alteration of on-site sewage disposal systems which are more stringent than the regulations adopted by the cabinet. </text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 202, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 300, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 211.370, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 154, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 244, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 30. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification> KRS 318.310 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8390</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>