<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7885</section_number><catch_line>Annual submission by high schools of list of eligible students -- Data in list -- Verification of eligibility -- Reduction of award -- Students ineligible for awards -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>7885</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Not later than August 1, 1999, and each June 30 thereafter, each Kentucky high school shall submit to the authority, a compiled list of all high school students during the academic year. A high school shall report the grade point average of an eligible high school student pursuant to KRS 164.7874 by January 15 following the end of the fall academic term in which the student completed the high school graduation requirements. The list shall identify the high school and shall contain each high school student's name, Social Security number, address, grade point average for the academic year, expected or actual graduation date, highest ACT score, family eligibility status for free or reduced-price lunch, and each AP, Cambridge Advanced International, or IB examination score. The Gatton Academy of Mathematics and Science in Kentucky and the Craft Academy for Excellence in Science and Mathematics shall report the data on its students to the authority. The list need not contain the ACT, AP, Cambridge Advanced International, or IB if the authority receives the scores directly from the testing services. The authority shall notify each eligible high school student of his or her Kentucky educational excellence scholarship award earned each academic year. The authority shall determine the final Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and supplemental award based upon the actual final grade point average, highest ACT score, and qualifying AP, Cambridge Advanced International, or IB scores and shall notify each eligible twelfth-grade high school student of the final determination. The authority shall make available a list of eligible high school and postsecondary students to participating institutions. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall provide data access only to the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System and to those participating institutions that have either received an admission application from an eligible high school or postsecondary student or have been listed by the eligible high school or postsecondary student on the Free Application For Federal Student Aid. </section><section prefix="3">For each eligible postsecondary student enrolling in a participating institution after July 1, 1999, the participating institution shall verify to the authority: <section prefix="a">The student's initial eligibility for a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and supplemental award, or supplemental award only pursuant to KRS 164.7879(3)(d) through the comprehensive list compiled by the authority or an alternative source satisfactory to the authority; </section><section prefix="b">The student's highest ACT score attained by the date of graduation from high school, provided that the participating institution need not report the ACT score if the authority receives the ACT score directly from the testing services; </section><section prefix="c">The eligible postsecondary student's full-time or part-time enrollment status at the beginning of each academic term; and </section><section prefix="d">The eligible postsecondary student's cumulative grade point average after the completion of each award period. </section></section><section prefix="4">Each participating institution shall submit to the authority a report, in a form satisfactory to the authority, of all eligible postsecondary students enrolled for that academic term. Kentucky educational excellence scholarships and supplemental awards shall be disbursed by the authority to each eligible postsecondary student attending a participating institution during the academic term within thirty (30) days after receiving a satisfactory report. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and the supplemental award shall not be reduced, except as provided in KRS 164.7881(4). </section><section prefix="6">Kentucky educational excellence scholarships and supplemental awards shall not be awarded or disbursed to any eligible postsecondary students who are: <section prefix="a">In default on any loan under Title IV of the federal act; or </section><section prefix="b">Liable for any amounts that exceed annual or aggregate limits on any loan under Title IV of the federal act; or </section><section prefix="c">Liable for overpayment of any grant or loan under Title IV of the federal act; or </section><section prefix="d">In default on any obligation to the authority under any programs administered by the authority until financial obligations to the authority are satisfied, except that ineligibility may be waived by the authority for cause. </section></section><section prefix="7">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 164.753, the authority may promulgate administrative regulations for the administration of Kentucky educational excellence scholarships and supplemental awards under the provisions of KRS 164.7871 to 164.7885 and KRS 164.7889. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015; and 112, sec. 5, effective April 2, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 90, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 25, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 198, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 575, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 15 and 112, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. (6/25/2013). This statute was created with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 18 and 90, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together.  (7/14/2000).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 13 and 198. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 198, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44068</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>