<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.285</section_number><catch_line>Permission to connect automated system required -- Exceptions -- Notification of county attorney if vehicle is not properly insured. </catch_line><order_by>285</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall, without prior specific written approval of the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation and the executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology, connect with the automated vehicle registration and titling system, directly or indirectly, by wire, electronic, electromagnetic induction, systemic, or any other means, any device, system or apparatus capable of putting information or electronic signals into, or receiving information or electronic signals from, or blocking, diverting, or altering transmission of data or signals within, the automated vehicle registration and titling system, its components, and its communications network. </section><section prefix="2">This section does not apply to or prohibit connection of devices or systems to the automated vehicle registration and titling system by persons who are acting in accordance with a contract or agreement with the Commonwealth of Kentucky, which in addition to any other required approval, has been approved in writing by the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation and the executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 613, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6193</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>