<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.520</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of district board. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text>The persons elected on the district board shall qualify and organize in the same manner as the county board, and shall thereupon be a body corporate with like powers, duties and responsibilities, within their respective districts, as is conferred upon the county board, and with full jurisdiction and control over the work provided for and established under the proceeding in which their election was provided for, or connected therewith. The district board shall continue in existence only so long as necessary to complete the work in the proceeding in which it was elected, and to pay off all bonds that have been issued. When the work is completed and paid for, and the bonds issued by the district have been fully paid off and satisfied, the improvement of the district, established and constructed by the district board, shall be turned over to the county board, and the district board shall then cease to exist, the district to continue by the same name or number under the jurisdiction and control of the county board. Until all bonds issued by the district board are paid off and the work turned over to the county board, the district board shall have the same authority as the county board to levy maintenance assessments to keep the improvements in repair, and to do anything in connection with the district that the county board could do. </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380-21. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>