<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.2255</section_number><catch_line>Health benefit plans and other information to be submitted to Advisory Committee of State Health Insurers -- Approval or recommendations for changes -- Committee to advise on options, bids, administration, and drug formulary -- Written report or testimony. </catch_line><order_by>2255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall submit to the Advisory Committee of State Health Insurance Subscribers established in KRS 18A.225, at least thirty (30) days prior to issuing requests for proposals, the health benefit plans that will be submitted to carriers. The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall also provide to employee organizations who are represented on the Advisory Committee of State Health Insurance Subscribers information necessary so that the member representing the organization can fulfill his or her responsibilities under this section. The advisory committee shall submit in writing to the secretary the committee's approval of the plans or its recommendations on changes to the plans no later than seven (7) days prior to the issuance of requests for proposals. The advisory committee shall advise the secretary on: <section prefix="a">Health insurance benefit options that should be included in the program; </section><section prefix="b">Procedures for soliciting bids or requesting proposals for contracts from carriers for the program; </section><section prefix="c">The implementation, maintenance, and administration of the health insurance benefits under the program; and </section><section prefix="d">The development of a uniform prescription drug formulary that contains fair and reasonable standards and procedures for patient access to medically necessary alternatives to the formulary and patient choice of higher-cost alternatives to the formulary, and that ensures that discounts negotiated with drug manufacturers are passed to the program. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall, at the discretion of the co-chairs of the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, either submit a written report to or testify before the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue on the state employee health insurance program for the next plan year prior to the issuance of the requests for proposals. </section></text><history> Created 2004 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 5, effective October 19, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> October 19, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1403</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>