<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.783</section_number><catch_line>Wagers considered made in Kentucky -- Prohibited wagers -- Revocation of hub license -- Applicability of KRS 137.170, 138.480, 138.510, and Chapter 230. </catch_line><order_by>783</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any wager that is made for an account maintained with the hub operator shall be considered to have been made in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">Account holders may communicate instructions concerning account wagers to the hub only by telephonic or other electronic means. </section><section prefix="3">None of the following wagers shall be processed through a hub: <section prefix="a">A wager on live racing accepted by a track; </section><section prefix="b">A telephone account wager accepted by a track; </section><section prefix="c">An intertrack wager accepted by a receiving track or simulcast facility; or </section><section prefix="d">An interstate wager accepted by a receiving track or simulcast facility. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any hub that processes any of the wagers delineated in subsection (3) of this section from a track, receiving track, or simulcast facility shall be subject to revocation of its hub license. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in KRS 230.752, nothing in KRS 230.775 to 230.785 shall exempt racetracks or simulcast facilities from any taxes imposed under KRS 137.170, 138.480, 138.510, or Chapter 230. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10932</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>