<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.145</section_number><catch_line>Form of license -- Inquiry into identity of licensee -- Current names and addresses of all facilities to be provided. </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any license issued by the board shall be numbered. The license shall be open to public inspection, and in all actions or proceedings in any court, a transcript, or any part thereof, certified under the seal of the board to be a true copy, shall be entitled to admission in evidence. </section><section prefix="2">The board may at any time inquire into the identity of any person claiming to hold a license to practice chiropractic in the state, and after due service of a notice in writing, require him to prove to the satisfaction of the board that he is the person authorized to practice under the license by virtue of which he claims the privilege to practice in this state. When the board finds that a person claiming to be the holder of a license to practice in this state is not in fact the person to whom the license was issued, it shall reduce its findings to writing and file them in its office, and such findings shall be prima facie evidence that the claimant does not hold a license to practice in this state. </section><section prefix="3">Ownership or operation of a chiropractic facility within this state constitutes the practice of chiropractic requiring licensure. A chiropractic facility using an assumed name shall include the name of the owner or operator, and either the word "chiropractic" or "chiropractors." </section><section prefix="4">By application and renewal, every chiropractor must annually provide the board with the name and address of each facility where the chiropractor practices. The chiropractor shall notify the board within ten (10) days of any change of address or change in practice location. All correspondence from the board shall be sent to the most recent address of record. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 14, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 14(1) and (2), effective June 14, 1962. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>