<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.060</section_number><catch_line>Nature and scope of comprehensive program -- Director under direction of adjutant general. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The General Assembly recognizes that the nature and scope of the activities necessary to develop and to administer a statewide comprehensive emergency management program, together with an integrated emergency management system requires the full support, cooperation, and active participation of all cabinets, departments, divisions, offices, or agencies of state government, local elected officials, local public agencies or entities, special districts, political subdivisions of the Commonwealth, volunteer organizations, individual citizens, and the private sector in this Commonwealth. To provide effective executive leadership for a program area of such broad scope and to ensure the professional administration of the comprehensive emergency management program and integrated emergency management system of the Commonwealth, the General Assembly declares: <section prefix="1">The Division of Emergency Management shall be headed by a director recommended by the Adjutant General and appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="2">The director shall have the powers, rights, responsibilities, and authorities, as provided in KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, or other laws, and shall carry out all duties under the general direction of the Adjutant General of the Department of Military Affairs. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21700</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>