<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.240</section_number><catch_line>Board for certification of librarians. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the Department for Libraries and Archives there shall be a state board for the certification of librarians, composed of the state librarian and five (5) members appointed by the Governor from a list submitted by the board of directors of the Kentucky Library Association. Two (2) members shall be full-time professional librarians in active public library work, two (2) shall be public library trustees and one (1) shall be a professional librarian from a department or school of library science in a state university. </section><section prefix="2">The term of office of each appointive member shall be four (4) years. The first appointive member of the board shall be appointed for terms beginning July 1, 1938; one (1) for a term of one (1) year; one (1) for a term of two (2) years; one (1) for a term of three (3) years; and two (2) for terms of four (4) years. Vacancies shall be filled by appointment for the unexpired terms in the same manner as original appointments are made. The members shall receive reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in attending meetings. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall hold at least one (1) meeting each year at a time fixed by the board, and such special meetings as may be determined by the board. A chairman and secretary shall be elected at each annual meeting to serve during the ensuing year. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VIII, B, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 3. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618-130b. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4777</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>