<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.750</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 67.750 to 67.790.   </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>As used in KRS 67.750 to 67.790, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Business entity" means each separate corporation, limited liability company, business development corporation, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, association, joint stock company, receivership, trust, professional service organization, or other legal entity through which business is conducted; </section><section prefix="2">"Compensation" means wages, salaries, commissions, or any other form of remuneration paid or payable by an employer for services performed by an employee, which are required to be reported for federal income tax purposes and adjusted as follows: <section prefix="a">Include any amounts contributed by an employee to any retirement, profit sharing, or deferred compensation plan, which are deferred for federal income tax purposes under a salary reduction agreement or similar arrangement, including but not limited to salary reduction arrangements under Section 401(a), 401(k), 402(e), 403(a), 403(b), 408, 414(h), or 457 of the Internal Revenue Code; and </section><section prefix="b">Include any amounts contributed by an employee to any welfare benefit, fringe benefit, or other benefit plan made by salary reduction or other payment method which permits employees to elect to reduce federal taxable compensation under the Internal Revenue Code, including but not limited to Sections 125 and 132 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Fiscal year" means "fiscal year" as defined in Section 7701(a)(24) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="4">"Employee" means any person who renders services to another person or business entity for compensation, including an officer of a corporation and any officer, employee, or elected official of the United States, a state, or any political subdivision of a state, or any agency or instrumentality of any one (1) or more of the above. A person classified as an independent contractor under the Internal Revenue Code shall not be considered an employee; </section><section prefix="5">"Employer" means "employer" as defined in Section 3401(d) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="6">"Gross receipts" means all revenues or proceeds derived from the sale, lease, or rental of goods, services, or property by a business entity reduced by the following: <section prefix="a">Sales and excise taxes paid; and </section><section prefix="b">Returns and allowances; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Internal Revenue Code" means the Internal Revenue Code in effect on December 31, 2008, as amended; </section><section prefix="8">"Net profit" means gross income as defined in Section 61 of the Internal Revenue Code minus all the deductions from gross income allowed by Chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code, and adjusted as follows: <section prefix="a">Include any amount claimed as a deduction for state tax or local tax which is computed, in whole or in part, by reference to gross or net income and which is paid or accrued to any state of the United States, local taxing authority in a state, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, or any foreign country or political subdivision thereof; </section><section prefix="b">Include any amount claimed as a deduction that directly or indirectly is allocable to income which is either exempt from taxation or otherwise not taxed; </section><section prefix="c">Include any amount claimed as a net operating loss carryback or carryforward allowed under Section 172 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="d">Include any amount of income and expenses passed through separately as required by the Internal Revenue Code to an owner of a business entity that is a pass-through entity for federal tax purposes; and </section><section prefix="e">Exclude any amount of income that is exempt from state taxation by the Kentucky Constitution or the Constitution and statutory laws of the United States; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Sales revenue" means receipts from the sale, lease, or rental of goods, services, or property; </section><section prefix="10">"Tax district" means a city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, school district, special taxing district, or any other statutorily created entity with the authority to levy net profits, gross receipts, or occupational license taxes; </section><section prefix="11">"Taxable gross receipts," in case of a business entity having payroll or sales revenues both within and without a tax district, means gross receipts as defined in subsection (6) of this section, as apportioned under KRS 67.753; </section><section prefix="12">"Taxable gross receipts," in case of a business entity having payroll or sales revenue only in one (1) tax district, means gross receipts as defined in subsection (6) of this section; </section><section prefix="13">"Taxable net profit," in case of a business entity having payroll or sales revenue only in one (1) tax district, means net profit as defined in subsection (8) of this section; </section><section prefix="14">"Taxable net profit," in case of a business entity having payroll or sales revenue both within and without a tax district, means net profit as defined in subsection (8) of this section, as apportioned under KRS 67.753; </section><section prefix="15">"Taxable year" means the calendar year or fiscal year ending during the calendar year, upon the basis of which net income or gross receipts is computed; and </section><section prefix="16">"City" means a city with a population equal to or greater than one thousand (1,000) based on the most recent federal decennial census and any city with a population of less than one thousand (1,000) based on the most recent federal decennial census that, prior to January 1, 2014, imposed a license fee at a percentage rate on salaries, wages, commission, or other compensation for work done or services performed within the city or on the net profits or gross receipts of businesses, professions, or occupations from activities conducted within the city. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 36, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 197, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 168, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007). 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 3, provides that the amendments to KRS 67.750 in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, "shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2007." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43621</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>