<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.650</section_number><catch_line>Duties of officers -- Oath. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chairman of the extension board shall preside at all meetings of the board, have authority to call special meetings of said board upon such notice as shall be fixed and determined by the extension board, and shall call special meetings of the extension board upon the written request of the majority of the members of said board, and in addition to the duties imposed upon him by KRS 164.605 to 164.675, perform and exercise the usual duties performed and exercised by a chairman or president of a board of directors of a corporation. </section><section prefix="2">The vice chairman, in the absence or disability of the chairman or his refusal to act, shall perform the duties imposed upon the chairman and act in his stead. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall perform the duties usually incident to this office. He shall keep the minutes of all meetings of the extension board. He shall sign such instruments and papers as provided for in KRS 164.605 to 164.675 and as may be required from time to time by the extension board. </section><section prefix="4">The treasurer, within ten (10) days after his election as treasurer and before entering upon the duties of his office as treasurer, shall execute to the extension board a corporate surety bond of one hundred twenty-five percent (125%) of the amount, as near as can be ascertained, that shall be in his hands as treasurer at any one (1) time. The cost of said corporate surety bond for the treasurer shall be paid out of the district cooperative extension education funds. After said treasurer executes said corporate surety bond, he shall receive, deposit and have charge of all of the funds of the extension board and shall pay and disburse said funds as provided for by KRS 164.605 to 164.675 and as may be required from time to time by the extension board. </section><section prefix="5">All members of the extension board shall take and sign the usual oath of public officers. </section><section prefix="6">Each of the officers of the extension board shall perform and carry out the duties as provided for in this section and shall perform and carry out such other duties as shall be required of them from time to time by the extension board. </section></text><history>Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 10. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4372</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>