<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.670</section_number><catch_line>Appeal to circuit court. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The order or determination of the board upon the rehearing shall be conclusive and binding, but any interested party may, within twenty (20) days after the rendition of the order of the board, by petition appeal to the Circuit Court of the county in which the urban-county government is located for a review of the order of the board. </section><section prefix="2">The petition shall state fully the grounds upon which a review is sought, assign all errors relied on and be verified by the petitioner who shall furnish a copy to the board at the time of the filing of the same. Summons shall be issued directing the board to answer within twenty (20) days and directing the board to send the original record to the circuit clerk certifying that such record is the entire original record of the rehearing which shall be filed by the clerk of the Circuit Court and such record shall then become and be considered by the Circuit Court on the review. The appeal provided for herein shall not be considered effective unless the person making the appeal has paid to the board one-half (1/2) of the cost of the transcript of the record of the rehearing within the period provided for making the appeal. </section><section prefix="3">No new nor additional evidence may be introduced in the Circuit Court except as to fraud or misconduct of some person engaged in the administration of KRS 67A.360 to 67A.690, and affecting the order, decision or determination appealed from, but the court shall otherwise hear the cause upon the record as certified by the board and shall dispose of the cause in summary manner, its review being limited to determining whether or not: <section prefix="a">The board acted without or in excess of its powers; </section><section prefix="b">The order, decision or determination was procured by fraud; </section><section prefix="c">The order, decision or determination of the board is not in conformity with the provisions of KRS 67A.360 to 67A.690; </section><section prefix="d">If findings of fact are in issue the party seeking to set aside any order, decision or determination of the board shall have the burden of proof to show by clear and satisfactory evidence that the order, decision or determination is unreasonable or unlawful. If upon appeal as herein provided, the order, decision or determination of the board is reversed the party perfecting the appeal shall be refunded by the board his portion of the costs paid for the transcript of the record made on the rehearing. </section></section><section prefix="4">The board and each interested party may appear before the Circuit Court. The court shall enter judgment affirming, modifying or setting aside the order, decision or determination appealed from, or in its discretion remand the cause to the board for further proceedings in conformity with the direction of the court. The court may, before judgment and upon a sufficient showing of fact, remand the cause to the board. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 32, effective July 1, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1974 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>