<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.250</section_number><catch_line>State aid for promotion of purebred cattle industry -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Department" means the Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="b">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="c">"Registered cattle" means cattle with approved registration papers from an appropriate association, organization, or authority; </section><section prefix="d">"Pen sale cattle" means uniform groups of commercial or registered beef cattle; </section><section prefix="e">"Market animals" means beef prospect steers and market heifers; and </section><section prefix="f">"AOB" means all other breeds. AOB is any combination of two (2) or more registered breeds. Both beef and dairy cattle may have an AOB category. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall support the development and the improvement of the cattle industry in Kentucky by promoting annual shows and sales of cattle with the purpose of establishing Kentucky as one of the greatest centers in the United States for the breeding, producing, raising, exhibiting, showing, and selling of cattle. The General Assembly shall make appropriations from the general expenditure fund for each fiscal year to effectuate that purpose. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, from the appropriations made in accordance with subsection (2) of this section, at least six thousand dollars ($6,000) shall be appropriated in each fiscal year for premiums and advertising expenditures for each of the following registered cattle breeds and other categories: <section prefix="a">Angus; </section><section prefix="b">Beefalo; </section><section prefix="c">Charolais; </section><section prefix="d">Chi; </section><section prefix="e">Hereford; </section><section prefix="f">Limousin; </section><section prefix="g">Market animals; </section><section prefix="h">Maine; </section><section prefix="i">Pen sale cattle; </section><section prefix="j">Red Angus; </section><section prefix="k">Red Poll; </section><section prefix="l">Salers; </section><section prefix="m">Santa Gertrudis; </section><section prefix="n">Shorthorn; </section><section prefix="o">Simmental; </section><section prefix="p">Ayrshire; </section><section prefix="q">Brown Swiss; </section><section prefix="r">Guernsey; </section><section prefix="s">Holstein; </section><section prefix="t">Milking Shorthorn; and </section><section prefix="u">Jersey. </section></section><section prefix="4">If a registered breed from subsection (3) of this section does not have enough entries to meet the minimum number required for a show, then it may combine with one (1) or more other registered breeds to form an AOB category. The AOB shall be funded in an amount equal to six thousand dollars ($6,000) from the allocations provided to the registered breeds that created the AOB. The funding shall be proportionately based on the number of entries per breed. </section><section prefix="5">The remainder of the appropriations made in accordance with subsection (2) of this section for each fiscal year shall be used and applied by the department as follows: At least five thousand dollars ($5,000) shall be divided between the Kentucky National Dairy Shows and Sales Board and the Kentucky Beef Expo Board to help cover facility and event costs; and the remaining balance shall be used and applied by the department in advertising and in promoting the cattle industry in Kentucky as the Commissioner may determine. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Only exhibitors participating in the Kentucky National Dairy Shows and Sales or the Kentucky Beef Expo are eligible for the funds appropriated in subsection (3) or (4) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Only eligible cattle from the United States and Canada may participate in the Kentucky National Dairy Shows and Sales or the Kentucky Beef Expo; </section><section prefix="c">When animals of equal quality are consigned, first consideration shall be given to Kentucky-owned or Kentucky-bred cattle; and </section><section prefix="d">In order to receive funding under subsection (3) or (4) of this section, each breed or category shall be required to match its appropriation on a dollar-for-dollar basis. </section></section><section prefix="7">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 247, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 109, secs. 1 to 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11539</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>