<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.715</section_number><catch_line>Pool administrator. </catch_line><order_by>715</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the cabinet shall appoint a cabinet employee to serve as bond pool administrator. </section><section prefix="2">The bond pool administrator shall: <section prefix="a">Collect and deposit into the bond pool fund all membership fees and tonnage fees submitted by bond pool members; </section><section prefix="b">Assess penalties against members for late payment of tonnage fees; </section><section prefix="c">Compile information about applicants and members for use by the commission in assigning or revising ratings; </section><section prefix="d">Monitor members' reporting and payment of tonnage fees and compliance with laws and administrative regulations of the cabinet and, where appropriate, recommend to the commission that it downgrade a member's rating or revoke a person's membership; </section><section prefix="e">Pay moneys out of the bond pool fund as authorized by the bond pool commission; </section><section prefix="f">At each meeting, report to the commission concerning the status of the bond pool and activities of the bond pool administrator; </section><section prefix="g">Perform such other administrative functions as are necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 350.700 to 350.755; and </section><section prefix="h">Account for the amount of coverage provided for properties in the Abandoned Mine Land Enhancement Program under KRS 350.595. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>