<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="68" order_by="68">COUNTY FINANCE AND COUNTY TREASURER </unit></structure><section_number>68.200</section_number><catch_line>License fee on retailers who rent out motor vehicles in counties containing a designated city, consolidated local government, or urban-county government -- Use of proceeds.   </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="a">Motor vehicle means "vehicle" as defined in KRS 186.010(8)(a); </section><section prefix="b">Retailer means "retailer" as defined in KRS 139.010; and </section><section prefix="c">Gross rental charge means "gross rental charge" as defined in KRS 138.462(4). </section></section><section prefix="2">A county containing a designated city, consolidated local government, or urban-county government may levy a license fee on the rental of motor vehicles which shall not exceed three percent (3%) of the gross rental charges from rental agreements for periods of thirty (30) days or less. The license fee shall apply to retailers who receive more than seventy-five percent (75%) of their gross revenues generated in the county from gross rental charges. Any license fee levied pursuant to this subsection shall be collected by the retailer from the renters of the motor vehicles. </section><section prefix="3">Revenues from rental of motor vehicles shall not be included in the gross rental charges on which the license fee is based if: <section prefix="a">The declared gross weight of the motor vehicle exceeds eleven thousand (11,000) pounds; or </section><section prefix="b">The rental is part of the services provided by a funeral director for a funeral; or </section><section prefix="c">The rental is exempted from the state sales and use tax pursuant to KRS 139.470. </section></section><section prefix="4">A fiscal court or the legislative body of an urban-county government shall provide for collection of the license fee in the ordinance by which the license fee is levied. The revenues shall be deposited in an account to be known as the motor vehicle license fee account. The revenues may be shared among local governments pursuant to KRS 65.245. </section><section prefix="5">The county shall use the proceeds of the license fee for economic development activities. It shall distribute semiannually, by June 30 and December 31, all revenues not shared pursuant to KRS 65.245, to one (1) or more of the following entities if it has established, or contracted with, the entity for the purposes of economic development and is satisfied that the entity is promoting satisfactorily the county's economic development activities: <section prefix="a">A riverport authority established by the county pursuant to KRS 65.520; or </section><section prefix="b">An industrial development authority established by the county pursuant to KRS 154.50-316; or </section><section prefix="c">A nonprofit corporation as defined in KRS 273.161(4) which has been organized for the purpose of promoting economic development. </section></section> The entity shall make a written request for funds from the motor vehicle license fee account by May 31 and November 30, respectively. <section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">As used in this section, "designated city" means a city on the registry maintained by the Department for Local Government under this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">On or before January 1, 2015, the Department for Local Government shall create and maintain a registry of cities that, as of August 1, 2014, were classified as cities of the first, second, and third class. The Department for Local Government shall make the information included on the registry available to the public by publishing it on its Web site. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 40, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 17, effective August 1, 2008. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>