<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.780</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations -- Department of Revenue inspections -- Examinations by Attorney General and state fire marshal. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state fire marshal may promulgate administrative regulations if necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 227.770 to 227.784 in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Revenue, in the regular course of conducting inspections of wholesale dealers and retailers as authorized under the provisions of KRS 138.130 to 138.205, may inspect cigarettes to determine if the cigarettes are marked as required by KRS 227.776. If the cigarettes are not marked as required, the Department of Revenue shall notify the state fire marshal. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">To enforce provisions of KRS 227.770 to 227.784, the Attorney General and the state fire marshal are authorized to examine the books, papers, invoices, and other records of any person in possession, control, or occupancy of any premises where cigarettes are placed, stored, sold, or offered for sale, as well as the stock of cigarettes on the premises. </section><section prefix="b">Every person in the possession, control, or occupancy of any premises where cigarettes are placed, sold, or offered for sale is directed and required to give the Attorney General and the state fire marshal the means, facilities, and opportunity for the examinations authorized by this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 6, effective April 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> April 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>