<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.444</section_number><catch_line>Medical review board -- Purpose -- Members -- Informal hearing --  Authority of cabinet to promulgate administrative regulations -- Prohibition against age-based licensing limitations -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>444</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish a medical review board. The purpose of the medical review board shall be to receive cases relating to the ability of an applicant or holder of a motor vehicle operator's license to drive due to physical or mental disability which may affect or limit a person's ability to safely operate a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall appoint any number of physicians licensed in the Commonwealth to the medical review board. Not less than three (3) members shall be present in order to conduct an informal hearing. Each member shall receive two hundred dollars ($200) per day for attending meetings of the board and shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses incurred in attending meetings. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations regarding the procedures of the medical review board in conducting informal hearings. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall not promulgate administrative regulations for the purpose of creating tests or other criteria that might limit a person's ability to obtain or retain an operator's license because he may be considered too old to drive. </section><section prefix="5">Any person aggrieved by a decision made as a result of an informal hearing conducted under authority of KRS 186.411 and this section may appeal, and upon appeal an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 71, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6058</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>