<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.020</section_number><catch_line>Registered environmental health specialist or sanitarian examining committee. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall appoint a registered environmental health specialist or a sanitarian examining committee consisting of five (5) members. The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall be an ex officio member. The other four (4) members shall be environmental health specialists or sanitarians who are registered under this chapter. The appointed members shall serve for terms of two (2) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify, except that when initial appointments are made under the provisions of this chapter, two (2) members' terms shall be for only one (1) year. Thereafter all appointments shall be for a period of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="2">The examining committee shall conduct, or cause to be conducted, examinations of applicants pursuant to minimum standards and qualifications established by the secretary. The examining committee shall act in an advisory capacity to the secretary in establishing such minimum standards and qualifications. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 562, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 506, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 309, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, secs. 89 and 107(1). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>