<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.3571</section_number><catch_line>Authority of center toward local government -- Reimbursement. </catch_line><order_by>3571</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governmental Services Center may, upon request of the Department for Local Government, and as financial and staff resources permit, develop, coordinate, implement, assist, and conduct employee and management training programs, seminars, and conferences, for agencies, departments, divisions, boards, and commissions of county and city government, and any other political subdivisions of the state. </section><section prefix="2">The Governmental Services Center may enter into contractual agreements with county and city governments and other political subdivisions as necessary to allow the Governmental Services Center to properly perform its duties and responsibilities as established by KRS 164.3571 to 164.3573. </section><section prefix="3">Any agency of a county, city, or other political subdivision whose employees receive the benefit of the Governmental Services Center's services, shall reimburse the Governmental Services Center for those costs and expenses which it incurs as a result of providing these services. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 75, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 79, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 64, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4273</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>