<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="332" order_by="332">DRIVER TRAINING SCHOOLS AND INSTRUCTORS </unit></structure><section_number>332.208</section_number><catch_line>Duration of license -- Renewal -- Fees deposited in trust and agency fund. </catch_line><order_by>208</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every license issued for the operation of a driver training school shall expire on June 30 following the date of the issuance unless revoked or canceled. </section><section prefix="2">Before June 1 of each year, every driver training school shall apply for renewal of its license. The application shall be on forms prepared and furnished by the department. </section><section prefix="3">Every license issued to a driver training instructor shall expire on June 30 following the date of the issuance unless revoked or canceled. </section><section prefix="4">Before June 1 of each year, every driver training instructor shall apply for renewal of his or her license. The application shall be on forms prepared and furnished by the department. </section><section prefix="5">All fees collected under this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter shall be paid into the State Treasury and credited to a trust and agency fund to be used in defraying the costs and expenses of the administration of this chapter. No part of this fund shall revert to the general funds of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 5, effective March 31, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31832</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>