<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.030</section_number><catch_line>Organization of department. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The department shall consist of: <section prefix="1">The Office of the Commissioner, which shall include the Division of Public Relations. </section><section prefix="2">The Office of the Chief Executive Officer. </section><section prefix="3">The Office for Agricultural Marketing and Product Promotion, which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The Division of Agriculture Marketing and Agribusiness Recruitment; </section><section prefix="b">The Division of Show and Fair Promotion; </section><section prefix="c">The Division of Value-Added Animal and Aquaculture Production; </section><section prefix="d">The Division of Value-Added Plant Production; </section><section prefix="e">The Division of Agricultural Education, Farm Safety, and Farmland Preservation; and </section><section prefix="f">The Division of Agritourism. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Office for Consumer and Environmental Protection, which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The Division of Regulation and Inspection; </section><section prefix="b">The Division of Food Distribution; and </section><section prefix="c">The Division of Environmental Services. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Office of State Veterinarian, which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The Division of Animal Health; and </section><section prefix="b">The Division of Producer Services. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Office for Strategic Planning and Administration, which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The Division of Personnel and Budget; and </section><section prefix="b">The Division of Information Technology. </section></section><section prefix="7">The State Board of Agriculture. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 120, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 121, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 33, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 15, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 84, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 127, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 15. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42a-3, 4618-17, 4618-18, 4618-79, 4618i-1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11509</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>