<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.372</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 367.372 to 367.378. </catch_line><order_by>372</order_by><text>As used in KRS 367.372 to 367.378, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Building materials" means lumber, construction tools, windows, and anything else used in the building or rebuilding of property; </section><section prefix="2">"Consumer food item" means any article used or intended for use for food, drink, confection, or condiment by a person or animal; </section><section prefix="3">"Emergency supplies" includes but is not limited to water, flashlights, radios, batteries, candles, blankets, soap, diapers, temporary shelters, tape, toiletries, plywood, nails, and hammers; </section><section prefix="4">"Gasoline" means any fuel used to power any motor vehicle or power tool; </section><section prefix="5">"Goods" has the same meaning as in KRS 355.2-105; </section><section prefix="6">"Housing" means any rental housing and includes any housing provided by a hotel or motel; </section><section prefix="7">"Medical supplies" includes but is not limited to prescription and nonprescription medications, bandages, gauze, isopropyl alcohol, and antibacterial products; </section><section prefix="8">"Person" has the same meaning as in KRS 446.010; </section><section prefix="9">"Repair or reconstruction services" means services performed by any person for repairs to residential or commercial property of any type that is damaged as a result of a natural or man-made disaster or emergency resulting from an event referred to in subsection (11) of this section; </section><section prefix="10">"Services" means work, labor, or services, including services furnished in connection with the sale or repair of goods or real property or improvements thereto; </section><section prefix="11">"State of emergency" means a natural or man-made disaster resulting from a tornado, earthquake, flood, fire, riot, storm, act of war, threat of war, military action, the time of instability following a terrorist attack, or any other event for which a state of emergency has been proclaimed by the President of the United States or declared by the Governor. It shall also include the duration of a Condition Red as declared by the United States Department of Homeland Security under the Homeland Security Advisory System; and </section><section prefix="12">"Transportation, freight, and storage services" means any service that is performed by a person that contracts to move, store, or transport personal or business property or rents equipment for those purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34939</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>