<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="510" order_by="510">SEXUAL OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>510.020</section_number><catch_line>Lack of consent.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whether or not specifically stated, it is an element of every offense defined in this chapter that the sexual act was committed without consent of the victim. </section><section prefix="2">Lack of consent results from: <section prefix="a">Forcible compulsion; </section><section prefix="b">Incapacity to consent; or </section><section prefix="c">If the offense charged is sexual abuse, any circumstances in addition to forcible compulsion or incapacity to consent in which the victim does not expressly or impliedly acquiesce in the actor's conduct. </section></section><section prefix="3">A person is deemed incapable of consent when he or she is: <section prefix="a">Less than sixteen (16) years old; </section><section prefix="b">An individual with an intellectual disability or an individual that suffers from a mental illness; </section><section prefix="c">Mentally incapacitated; </section><section prefix="d">Physically helpless; or </section><section prefix="e">Under the care or custody of a state or local agency pursuant to court order and the actor is employed by or working on behalf of the state or local agency. </section></section><section prefix="4">The provisions of subsection (3)(e) of this section shall not apply to persons who are lawfully married to each other and no court order is in effect prohibiting contact between the parties. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 124, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 30, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 82, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40849</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>