<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74">WATER DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>74.025</section_number><catch_line>Removal of district water commissioner -- Causes. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">From and after the creation and establishment of a water district and the appointment of water commissioners to manage the affairs of the district, and following the acquisition or construction by any duly created and established water district of a public water system, and the consequent establishment of regulatory jurisdiction over such water district by the Public Service Commission of Kentucky, the Public Service Commission may remove any water commissioner from his office for good cause, including, inter alia, incompetency, neglect of duty, gross immorality, or nonfeasance, misfeasance, or malfeasance in office, including without limiting the generality of the foregoing, failure to comply with rules, regulations, and orders issued by the Public Service Commission. </section><section prefix="2">No such order of removal with respect to any water commissioner shall be entered by the Public Service Commission until a public hearing on the merits with reference to such matter has been held by the commission, at which hearing the water commissioner proposed to be removed from office shall be afforded the opportunity to appear, either pro se, or by counsel and file briefs, memoranda and motions, cross-examine witnesses, examine exhibits, and present evidence, both orally and in writing. All such orders of removal entered by the Public Service Commission shall be final and shall not be subject to appeal. Any water commissioner may waive such public hearing, in which case an order on removal may be forthwith entered by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Using procedures of this section the Public Service Commission may also request the removal of directors, trustees or other governing persons of water associations in like manner. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 3. </history><metadata><former-codification>KRS 74.455. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>