<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.255</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Community Crisis Response Board -- Members -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Community Crisis Response Board is hereby created as a separate administrative body of state government within the meaning of KRS Chapter 12 and attached for administrative purposes to the Department of Military Affairs. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the board shall consist of the following: <section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department for Public Health, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Department of Education, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="e">The Kentucky state fire marshal, or the fire marshal's designee; </section><section prefix="f">The executive director of the Division of Emergency Management, or the executive director's designee; </section><section prefix="g">The Attorney General, or the Attorney General's designee; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) representative of local community crisis response teams appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="i">Four (4) members appointed by the Governor to represent mental health disciplines; </section><section prefix="j">Two (2) members appointed by the Governor to represent emergency services disciplines; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) member who is a mental health professional licensed for independent clinical practice, to be appointed by the Governor. The licensed mental health professional member shall serve as clinical director for the board; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) member, appointed by the Governor, from a statewide chaplain's association involved in emergency services, who is trained in grief counseling and has experience in crisis response; </section><section prefix="m">One (1) member from the Kentucky Chapter of the American Red Cross; and </section><section prefix="n">The commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services or the commissioner's designee. </section></section><section prefix="3">All board members appointed pursuant to subsection (2)(h) to (l) of this section shall be approved members of the existing community crisis response team. </section><section prefix="4">All board members appointed pursuant to subsection (2)(h) to (l) of this section shall have demonstrated a commitment to the provision of community crisis response services. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the board appointed by the Governor shall serve for two (2) years and may be reappointed for one (1) additional consecutive two (2) year term. All vacancies in appointed members' terms shall be filled by appointment of the Governor for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall elect annually from its membership a chairperson and shall establish other officers and committees as needed to execute the duties of the board. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall meet at least quarterly, and a majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the board's business. </section><section prefix="8">Except for hired and appointed staff, no board member or team member shall receive compensation. However, board members and crisis response team members may receive reimbursement for expenses incurred in the course of providing crisis response services or executing the duties of the board, consistent with state policy governing the reimbursement of state employees for food, travel, and lodging. Except as provided for in KRS 36.260, nothing in the provisions of KRS 36.250 to 36.270 shall be construed to create liability of a private party for expenses incurred or reimbursed under this subsection. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 119, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 102, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and amended ch. 426, sec. 83, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 42.665. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40744</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>