<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="108" order_by="108">URBAN SERVICES DISTRICTS -- AMBULANCE SERVICE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>108.175</section_number><catch_line>Joinder of an unincorporated area to an existing ambulance service district. </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the people in an unincorporated area desire to become part of an existing ambulance service district, a certified petition of a simple majority, or one hundred (100) or more qualified voters, whichever is less, within the unincorporated area, as set out in metes and bounds, within the county shall be filed with the fiscal court.  The petition shall set out the metes and bounds of the unincorporated area desiring to become part of the existing ambulance district. The fiscal court shall adopt a resolution, submitting to the qualified voters within the unincorporated area, as set out in metes and bounds, the question as to whether they wish to become part of the existing emergency ambulance service district and impose a special ad valorem tax for the maintenance and operation of the district, not to exceed ten cents ($0.10) on each one hundred dollars ($100) of the assessed valuation of all property in the district. A certified copy of the resolution of the fiscal court shall be filed with the county court clerk at least sixty (60) days prior to the next regular election and, thereupon, the clerk shall cause the question to be placed on the ballot. </section><section prefix="2">The question shall be, substantially, the following form: "Are you in favor of becoming a part of the (insert name of the existing emergency ambulance service district) which shall have the authority to impose a special ad valorem tax of (insert exact amount) on each one hundred dollars ($100) worth of property assessed for local taxation in the district for the maintenance and operation of the (insert name) emergency ambulance service district?" </section><section prefix="3">If a majority of those voting on the question in the unincorporated area, as set out in metes and bounds, favor becoming part of the existing ambulance service district, then it shall be so established, and shall be part of the taxing district within the meaning of Section 157 of the Constitution of Kentucky. The cost of the election shall be paid by the fiscal court. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 59, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 231, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 108.073, renumbered effective July 13, 1984. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27229</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>