<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.710</section_number><catch_line>Road fund -- Surplus fund account. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text>There is hereby created in the road fund of the State Treasury a surplus fund account subject to the following terms and conditions: <section prefix="1">It shall contain all surplus tax receipts accruing to the road fund as provided by KRS 48.140(3); </section><section prefix="2">It shall contain all funds lapsed from moneys originating from road fund receipts; </section><section prefix="3">It shall contain all receipts from the sale of surplus property purchased with road fund receipts; </section><section prefix="4">It shall contain all road fund receipts in excess of estimates; </section><section prefix="5">It shall contain all moneys saved as a result of a reorganization of state government operations funded by the road fund; </section><section prefix="6">Funds in the account shall be invested at interest and the interest shall also accrue to this account; </section><section prefix="7">It shall contain any other funds which are required by law or regulation to accrue to the surplus account of the road fund; and </section><section prefix="8">No expenditures shall be made from this account unless appropriated by the General Assembly or unless required by budget reduction provisions of a branch budget bill, or as provided by KRS 48.130. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 18, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 29, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. IX at 750. See Transportation Cabinet Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 127, Pt. I, A, 4, (7) at 789. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22576</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>