<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.165</section_number><catch_line>Emergency medical technicians -- Permitted activities -- Reasonable control by employers -- Utilization of emergency medical technicians in medical care facilities. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An emergency medical technician may, subject to the provisions of this section, perform any procedure: <section prefix="a">Specified in the most recent curriculum of the United States Department of Transportation training course for emergency medical technicians; and </section><section prefix="b">Any additional procedure authorized by the board by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">When there is a change in the United States Department of Transportation curriculum for emergency medical technicians or the board approves an additional skill or procedure by administrative regulation, no person who was not trained under that curriculum or administrative regulation shall perform any activity or procedure in the new curriculum or administrative regulation unless the person has been trained according to the new curriculum or administrative regulation and demonstrates competency in the new knowledge or skill. Competency in a new skill shall be demonstrated through a return demonstration to a competent evaluator. If the board adopts the new procedure or skill, the board shall promulgate an administrative regulation specifying the new procedure, training requirements, examination requirements, and a time period during which the emergency medical technician shall successfully complete the new material or lose his or her certification as an emergency medical technician. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, nothing in this section shall prevent an employer from exercising reasonable fiscal control over the costs of providing emergency medical services to its citizens nor prevent the employer from exercising any reasonable control over emergency medical technicians providing emergency medical care upon behalf of the licensed entity or other provider. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit utilization of a certified emergency medical technician for the purpose of such individual working with primary responsibility and duties limited to hospitals, physician's offices, clinics, or other definitive care facilities, except as an emergency medical technician trainee or a full-time instructor of emergency medical technicians. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>