<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="384" order_by="384">CONTROL OF PROPERTY AND EXERCISE OF RIGHTS OF PERSONS IN ARMED FORCES -- CONTRACTS OF INFANT WAR VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>384.080</section_number><catch_line>Performance of notarial acts by commissioned officers of armed forces. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the acknowledgment of instruments and the performance of official acts in respect to instruments in the manner and form and as otherwise authorized by law, instruments may be acknowledged, documents attested, oaths and affirmations administered, depositions and affidavits executed, and other such official acts performed, before or by any commissioned officer in active service of the Armed Forces of the United States for any person who either  <section prefix="a">Is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, or  </section><section prefix="b">Is serving as a merchant seaman outside the limits of the United States, or  </section><section prefix="c">Is outside said limits by permission, assignment or direction of any department or official of the United States government.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Such acknowledgment of instruments, attestation of documents, administration of oaths and affirmations, execution of depositions and affidavits, and performance of other notarial acts, heretofore or hereafter made or taken, are hereby declared legal, valid and binding, and instruments and documents so acknowledged, authenticated, or sworn to shall be admissible in evidence and eligible to record in this state under the same circumstances, and with the same force and effect as if such acknowledgment, attestation, oath, affirmation, deposition, affidavit, or other official act, had been made or taken within this state before or by a duly qualified officer or official and under his appropriate certificate and seal of office as otherwise provided by law.  </section><section prefix="3">In the taking of acknowledgments and the performing of other notarial acts requiring certification, a certificate endorsed upon or attached to the instrument or document, which shows the date of the notarial act and which states, in substance, that the person appearing before the officer acknowledges the instrument as his act or made or signed the instrument or document under oath, shall be sufficient for all intents and purposes.  </section><section prefix="4">When the official signature of any such commissioned officer appears upon such instrument, document or certificate, it shall be prima facie evidence that the person making such oath or acknowledgment is within the purview of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>