<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.051</section_number><catch_line>Permits for labeling -- Fees -- Registration. </catch_line><order_by>051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following shall apply with regard to permits for labeling: <section prefix="a">Each person who labels agricultural seed in accordance with KRS 250.041 shall obtain a labeling permit from the director and pay a quarterly inspection fee unless labels attached to the seed containers were issued by the Kentucky Seed Improvement Association, or purchased from the director. </section><section prefix="b">Each person who labels vegetable seed, flower seed, or combination mulch, seed, and fertilizer product shall obtain a labeling permit from the director. </section><section prefix="c">Permit holders shall be assessed a yearly fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) based on a calendar year or fraction thereof. The procedure for obtaining a permit, the responsibilities of the permit holders, method to be used in determining inspection fees, and the procedure for payment of inspection fees by permit holders distributing agricultural seed shall be established by administrative regulations promulgated by the director. Permits may be revoked if the director determines that the permit holder is not complying with the provisions of KRS 250.021 to 250.111. </section><section prefix="d">Labels for agricultural seed may be purchased from the director at a price established by administrative regulation promulgated by the director. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each person who distributes agricultural seed in containers of forty (40) pounds or more at retail in Kentucky and each person, other than a certified seed conditioner, who conditions agricultural seed for distribution in Kentucky shall register with the director. </section><section prefix="3">Certified seed growers and certified seed conditioners shall be registered with the director by the Kentucky Seed Improvement Association at no additional fee as a part of the certification process. </section><section prefix="4">The yearly registration fee for retail agricultural seed dealers and for noncertified custom seed conditioners shall be twenty-five dollars ($25). If a person is required to both register and obtain a permit, the permit fee shall apply, and if a person is required to register both as a retail agricultural seed dealer and noncertified custom seed conditioner, only one (1) registration fee shall be paid. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 4, effective April 8, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> April 8, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (4/8/94).  Although the section of 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370 creating this statute directed its placement in KRS Chapter 350, it is clear from the subject matter of this statute and the structure of ch. 370 that placement in KRS Chapter 250 was intended, and this has been done in codification pursuant to KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12083</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>