<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.500</section_number><catch_line>Malt beverage premium prohibition -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person holding a license to sell malt beverages shall offer or give anything tangible of value as a premium for the return of caps, stoppers, corks, stamps, wrappers, coupons, or labels taken from any bottle, case, barrel, or package containing malt beverages or to offer or give anything of value as a premium, gift, or prize for any purpose in connection with the sale of malt beverages. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to the return of moneys specifically deposited for the return of the original containers to the owners; nor shall subsection (1) of this section prohibit brewers, wholesalers, or distributors from giving anything of value as a premium, gift, or prize to wholesalers, distributors, or their employees in connection with sales incentive programs. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to brewer-sponsored national sweepstakes in which major prizes, not including rebates, price discount coupons, or brand-related novelty items are given to consumers based on certificates found in malt beverage packages or on point of sale materials. Malt beverage distributors, retail licensees, and their employees shall not be eligible to redeem the certificates or participate in the national sweepstakes. </section><section prefix="4">Subsection (1) of this section shall not prohibit brewers, out-of-state brewers, wholesalers, distributors, or retail licensees from selling malt beverages packaged in or securely bundled with brand-related novelty items if the price charged for the packaged or bundled malt beverages specifically includes the cost of the brand-related novelty item. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-206. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>