<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.165</section_number><catch_line>Waiver of driving skills test for military personnel. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may waive the driving skills test for an applicant on active military service, or within ninety (90) days of separation of service, who: <section prefix="a">Is currently licensed; </section><section prefix="b">Has experience driving a vehicle in the military that would require a commercial driver's license to operate as a civilian; </section><section prefix="c">Has a good driving record; and </section><section prefix="d">Certifies and provides verification that, during the two (2) year period immediately prior to applying for a commercial driver's license, the applicant: <section prefix="1">Drove a motor vehicle in the military that was representative of the commercial driver's license class and endorsement for which he or she is applying; </section><section prefix="2">Has not had his or her operator's license or commercial driver's license suspended, revoked, or canceled, or been disqualified from operating a commercial motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="3">Has not been convicted of any of the disqualifying offenses in 49 C.F.R. sec. 383.51(b) while operating a commercial motor vehicle, or of any offense in a noncommercial vehicle that would be disqualifying under 49 C.F.R. sec. 383.51(b) if committed in a commercial motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="4">Has not been convicted of more than one (1) serious traffic violation, as defined in 49 C.F.R. sec. 383.5, while operating any type of motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="5">Has not been convicted of any violation of state or local law relating to motor vehicle traffic control, other than a parking violation, arising in connection with a traffic accident; </section><section prefix="6">Has not been convicted of any motor vehicle traffic violation that resulted in an accident; and </section><section prefix="7">Is or was regularly employed in a position in the Armed Forces of the United States requiring operation of a commercial motor vehicle of the group the applicant seeks to drive, and provides evidence of that employment in accordance with subsection (5) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The skills test waiver process described in subsection (1) of this section shall be completed, and the commercial driver's license issued, within ninety (90) days of separation of service. </section><section prefix="3">Military personnel who obtain the skills test waiver under this section shall be required to take the knowledge test pursuant to KRS 281A.130. </section><section prefix="4">Military personnel who obtain the skills test waiver under this section shall be required to pay the application fee as prescribed by KRS 281A.150, but shall not be charged the skills-testing fee as prescribed by KRS 281A.160. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A that establish an application form for waiver of the skills test by military personnel. As part of the application process, the applicant shall be required to provide: <section prefix="a">A copy of the applicant's DD-214 form showing the applicant's military occupational specialty; or </section><section prefix="b">A signed statement by the applicant's commanding officer or transportation officer, on a form provided by the cabinet, attesting to the fact that the applicant meets the requirements of this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39637</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>