<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.029</section_number><catch_line>Duties of cabinet relating to children who are victims of human trafficking.   </catch_line><order_by>029</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide the most effective treatment for children who are victims of human trafficking, as defined in KRS 529.010, the cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Investigate a report alleging a child is a victim of human trafficking pursuant to KRS 620.030(3); </section><section prefix="b">Provide or ensure the provision of appropriate treatment, housing, and services consistent with the status of the child as a victim of human trafficking; and </section><section prefix="c">Proceed in the case in accordance with applicable statutes governing cases involving dependency, neglect, or abuse regardless of whether the person believed to have caused the human trafficking of the child is a parent, guardian, or person exercising custodial control or supervision. </section></section><section prefix="2">In order to effectuate the requirements of this section, the cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Consult with agencies serving victims of human trafficking to promulgate administrative regulations for the treatment of children who are reported to be victims of human trafficking as dependent, neglected, or abused children, including providing for appropriate screening, assessment, treatment, services, temporary and long-term placement of these children, training of staff, the designation of specific staff, and collaboration with service providers and law enforcement; and </section><section prefix="b">By November 1 of each year, beginning in 2013, submit to the Legislative Research Commission a comprehensive report detailing the number of reports the cabinet has received regarding child victims of human trafficking, the number of reports in which the cabinet has investigated and determined that a child is the victim of human trafficking, and the number of cases in which services were provided. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013).This statute was created in Section 1 of 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25. Section 28 of that Act states that "Sections 1 to 28 of this Act may be cited as the 'Human Trafficking Victims Rights Act.'" </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41832</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>