<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.305</section_number><catch_line>Personnel, information, and technical services -- Schedule of fees. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any public purchasing unit is authorized, within its discretion, upon written request from another public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity, to provide personnel to the requesting public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity.  Payment to the public purchasing unit providing the personnel, by the public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity making the request, of direct and indirect costs of furnishing the personnel, and the terms relating thereto shall be agreed upon by the parties involved. </section><section prefix="2">The informational, technical, and other services of any public purchasing unit may be made available to any other public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity provided that the requirements of the public purchasing unit tendering the services shall have precedence over the requesting public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity.  Additionally, and subject to agreement between the parties, the requesting public purchasing unit or foreign purchasing activity shall pay all of the expenses of the services so provided. </section><section prefix="3">This Commonwealth, through the Finance and Administration Cabinet, upon request may make available to all public purchasing units the following services, among others: <section prefix="a">Standard forms; </section><section prefix="b">Printed manuals; </section><section prefix="c">Product specifications and standards; </section><section prefix="d">Quality assurance testing services and methods; </section><section prefix="e">Qualified products lists; </section><section prefix="f">Source information; </section><section prefix="g">Common use commodities listings; </section><section prefix="h">Supplier prequalification information; </section><section prefix="i">Supplier performance ratings; </section><section prefix="j">Debarred and suspended bidders list; </section><section prefix="k">Forms for invitations for bids, requests for proposals, instructions to bidders, general contract provisions, and other contract forms; and </section><section prefix="l">Contracts or published summaries thereof, including price and time of delivery information. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Commonwealth, through the Finance and Administration Cabinet, may provide the following technical services, among others: <section prefix="a">Development of products specifications; </section><section prefix="b">Development of quality assurance test methods, including receiving, inspection, and acceptance procedures; </section><section prefix="c">Use of state product testing and inspection facilities; and </section><section prefix="d">Use of state personnel training programs. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may publish a schedule of fees for the services provided under subsections (3) and (4) of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 61, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22391</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>