<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="411" order_by="411">RIGHTS OF ACTION AND SURVIVAL OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>411.148</section_number><catch_line>Nonliability of licensees and certified technicians for emergency care. </catch_line><order_by>148</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311, registered or practical nurse licensed under KRS Chapter 314, person certified as an emergency medical technician by the Kentucky Cabinet for Health and Family Services, person certified by the American Heart Association or the American Red Cross to perform cardiopulmonary resuscitation, or employee of any board of education established pursuant to the provision of KRS 160.160, who has completed a course in first aid and who maintains current certification therein in accordance with the standards set forth by the American Red Cross shall be liable in civil damages for administering emergency care or treatment at the scene of an emergency outside of a hospital, doctor's office, or other place having proper medical equipment excluding house calls, for acts performed at the scene of such emergency, unless such acts constitute willful or wanton misconduct. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section applies to the administering of such care or treatment where the same is rendered for remuneration or with the expectation of remuneration. </section><section prefix="3">The administering of emergency care or treatment at the scene of an emergency by employees of a board of education shall not be considered to be rendered for remuneration or with the expectation of remuneration because such personnel perform such care as part of their regular professional or work responsibilities for which they receive their regular salaries from the school board which is their employer. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 647, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 599, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, VI, sec. 107(11). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17775</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>