<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.090</section_number><catch_line>City administrative officer. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each city may create the position of city administrative officer which shall be directly responsible to the executive authority of the city.  Prior to appointment of a city administrative officer, the city legislative body shall in accordance with KRS 83A.080 set qualifications, which shall include but not be limited to professional training and experience in administration sufficient to insure competence, and list duties and responsibilities of the position which shall include, but not be limited to the following:  <section prefix="a">Advise the executive authority of the city in policy formulation on overall problems of the city;  </section><section prefix="b">Have major responsibility for preparation and administration of operating and capital improvement budgets under direction of the executive authority;  </section><section prefix="c">Advise the executive authority of the city in the appointment of subordinate administrative personnel if not delegated appointment authority by appropriate order; and  </section><section prefix="d">Have continuing direct relationships with operating department heads on implementation and administration of programs.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The city administrative officer shall carry out all additional duties lawfully delegated by appropriate order of the executive authority and shall have the same powers as the executive authority in carrying out such duties.  </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25178</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>