<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.80-140</section_number><catch_line>Environmental covenant to run with the land -- When covenants to be deemed valid and enforceable -- Validity of instruments recorded before June 20, 2005. </catch_line><order_by>80-140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An environmental covenant in compliance with the provisions of KRS 224.80-100 to 224.80-210 shall run with the land. </section><section prefix="2">An environmental covenant that is otherwise effective shall be deemed valid and shall be enforceable even if: <section prefix="a">The environmental covenant is not appurtenant to an interest in real property; </section><section prefix="b">The environmental covenant can be or has been assigned to a person other than the original holder; </section><section prefix="c">The environmental covenant is not of a character that has been recognized traditionally in common law; </section><section prefix="d">The environmental covenant imposes a negative burden; </section><section prefix="e">The environmental covenant imposes an affirmative obligation on a person having an interest in the real property or on the holder; </section><section prefix="f">The benefit or burden does not touch or concern real property; </section><section prefix="g">There is no privity of estate or contract; </section><section prefix="h">The holder dies, ceases to exist, resigns, or is replaced; or </section><section prefix="i">The owner of an interest subject to the environmental covenant and the holder are the same person. </section></section><section prefix="3">An instrument that creates restrictions or obligations with respect to real property that would qualify as activity and use limitations except for the fact that the instrument was recorded before June 20, 2005, shall not be invalidated or deemed unenforceable due to: <section prefix="a">Any of the limitations on enforcement of interests described in paragraphs (a) to (i) of subsection (2) of this section; or </section><section prefix="b">The identification of the instrument as an easement, servitude, deed restriction, or other interest. </section></section><section prefix="4">KRS 224.80-100 to 224.80-210 shall not invalidate or render unenforceable any interest, whether designated as an environmental covenant or other interest, that is otherwise enforceable under the law. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10539</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>