<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.385</section_number><catch_line>Education program by department -- Certification program for administrators and others. </catch_line><order_by>385</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall develop and administer a program for the purpose of providing education and training in the technical, legal, and administrative aspects of property tax administration for property valuation administrators, deputy property valuation administrators, and department employees. Courses may be created and taught by department personnel or the department may adopt specific courses offered by appropriate professional organizations. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall develop and administer, in cooperation with the property valuation administrators, a certification program for property valuation administrators, deputy property valuation administrators, and department employees. A professional designation, "certified Kentucky assessor" (CKA), shall be awarded to those individuals successfully meeting the standards established by this program. Minimum requirements shall include one hundred twenty (120) hours of classroom instruction, passage of subject matter examinations, and three (3) years of experience in Kentucky property tax administration. An advanced designation, "senior Kentucky assessor" (SKA), shall be awarded to those individuals successfully completing an additional ninety (90) hours of classroom instruction, passage of subject matter examinations, and an additional two (2) years of experience in Kentucky property tax administration. Correspondence course credit administered by the department may be substituted for no more than thirty (30) hours of the one hundred twenty (120) hours required for the "certified Kentucky assessor" (CKA) designation, and for no more than fifteen (15) hours of the additional ninety (90) hours required for the "senior Kentucky assessor" (SKA) designation. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 196, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 479, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 495, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 423, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>