<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.166</section_number><catch_line>Perpetual production of certain special license plates -- Design of Purple Heart license plates.     </catch_line><order_by>166</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall, unless directed otherwise by the General Assembly, perpetually produce the following special license plates: military license plates, U.S. Congressional license plates, firefighter license plates, emergency management license plates, Fraternal Order of Police license plates, Law Enforcement Memorial license plates, street rod license plates, nature license plates, amateur radio license plates, Kentucky General Assembly license plates, Kentucky Court of Justice license plates, Masonic Order license plates, collegiate license plates, independent college and university license plates, child victims' trust fund license plates, Kentucky Horse Council license plates, Ducks Unlimited license plates, Gold Star Mothers license plates, Silver Star Medal license plates, Bronze Star Medal license plates, spay neuter license plates, service academy license plates, and I Support Veterans license plates. </section><section prefix="2">The design of the plates identified for perpetual production under this section may be revised upon request of a group or organization requesting a design revision under the provisions of KRS 186.164(15). </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The design of a Purple Heart license plate shall not include any representation of the word "Kentucky" that is a registered trademark or slogan which appears on a general issue license plate. </section><section prefix="b">The design of a Purple Heart license plate shall include a representation of the Purple Heart medal and the words "Combat Wounded." </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 3, effective upon contingency. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 190, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2, provides that the design specifications indicated in subsection (3)(b) of this statute "shall be included in the first regularly scheduled replating of the Purple Heart license plate after [June 25, 2013]."  (7/12/2012). The amendment to this statute in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 3, takes effect on July 12, 2012. The effective date of that amendment was subject to a contingency, but the contingency was removed in 2012. Section 5 of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 139, which is effective July 12, 2012, repeals 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 4, which established the contingency. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>