<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.132</section_number><catch_line>Removal or suspension of public school officers -- Procedure, grounds, conditions. </catch_line><order_by>132</order_by><text>As used in this section, except subsection (1), "public school officer" means a person who previously served as a superintendent of schools or board member during which time charges were brought against him under this section. <section prefix="1">The chief state school officer shall recommend, by written charges to the proper school authorities having immediate jurisdiction, the removal of any superintendent of schools, principal, teacher, member of a school council, or other public school officer as to whom he has reason to believe is guilty of immorality, misconduct in office, incompetency, willful neglect of duty, or nonfeasance. In the case of a member of a school council, the written charges shall be provided to the local board of education. </section><section prefix="2">The chief state school officer shall recommend by written charges the suspension by the Kentucky Board of Education of any district board member, superintendent of schools, or other public school officer whom he has reason to believe is guilty of immorality, misconduct in office, incompetency, willful neglect of duty, or nonfeasance. If the charges brought under this subsection represent an immediate threat to the public health, safety, or welfare, the Kentucky Board of Education shall summarily suspend the person against whom the charges are made. The action by the Kentucky Board of Education may be taken upon a recommendation of the chief state school officer, or the action may be taken by a majority vote of the Kentucky Board of Education without recommendation from the chief state school officer. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education may suspend a district superintendent of schools or other public school officer under subsection (2) of this section or remove him pursuant to subsection (5) of this section only if, after thirty (30) days of receipt of the written charges specified in subsection (1) of this section, the proper school authorities having immediate jurisdiction, either the superintendent or the district board of education, have refused to act, have acted in bad faith, arbitrarily, or capriciously, or if a recommendation to the district board would have been futile. </section><section prefix="4">Any officer suspended by the Kentucky Board of Education under subsection (2) of this section shall be furnished with an emergency order specifying in detail the reasons for suspension and notifying the officer of his right to appeal the action and have an emergency hearing pursuant to KRS 13B.125. </section><section prefix="5">As an alternative to first seeking suspension, the chief state school officer may recommend by written charges the removal by the Kentucky Board of Education of any district board member, superintendent of schools, or other public school officer whom he has reason to believe is guilty of immorality, misconduct in office, incompetency, willful neglect of duty, or nonfeasance. The officer against whom the written charges are issued by the chief state school officer shall be furnished with the written charges and notice of procedural rights conferred under KRS Chapter 13B. Within twenty (20) days after receipt of the charges, the officer may notify the Kentucky Board of Education of his intention to appear and answer the charges. Upon appeal, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. If the officer fails to notify the board of his intention to appear and answer the charges, the Kentucky Board of Education may remove the officer by a majority vote, and the dismissal shall be final. </section><section prefix="6">The hearing shall be public or private at the discretion of the accused former or current superintendent and shall be public when testimony is taken for board members. </section><section prefix="7">The Kentucky Board of Education may meet in closed session to consider the evidence and may by a majority vote remove the officer. If the board votes to remove the officer, the board shall prepare final order specifying which charge or charges it found to be the basis for removal. If within ninety (90) days from the date of suspension if applicable, the state board has not removed the officer, or has dismissed the charges, the suspended officer shall be reinstated and shall be paid his full salary for the period of suspension. </section><section prefix="8">The officer shall have a right to appeal on the record to the Circuit Court located in the county of the school district in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. If the decision of the court is against removal, the officer shall be paid his full salary from the date of suspension. The payment shall be made from funds appropriated to the State Department of Education. </section><section prefix="9">If a superintendent of schools is removed from office or resigns while charges are pending pursuant to this section after July 15, 1994, any continuing contract pursuant to KRS 161.720 to 161.810 shall be terminated. If the removal is reversed upon appeal, the continuing contract shall be restored and he shall be paid his full salary for the period of suspension. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 15, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 46, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 472, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 50, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. I, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> April 14, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3130</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>