<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.020</section_number><catch_line>Chief Justice -- Delegation of functions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The Chief Justice in his sole discretion may delegate the following functions to the administrative director of the courts or to his administrative assistants: <section prefix="1">Perform administrative services for the Court of Justice and supervise its clerical and administrative personnel, and its accommodations; </section><section prefix="2">Act as fiscal officer of the Court of Justice and in so doing shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain fiscal controls and accounts of funds appropriated for the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="b">Review and audit expense vouchers of justices, judges, and employees of the Court of Justice. Upon approval, the Chief Justice shall submit the vouchers to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, which shall certify the same to the State Treasurer for payment; </section><section prefix="c">Prepare all requisitions for the payment of state moneys appropriated for the maintenance and operation of the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="d">Prepare budget estimates of state appropriations necessary for the maintenance and operation of the Court of Justice and make recommendations in respect thereto; </section><section prefix="e">Collect statistical and other data and make report to the Supreme Court relating to the expenditure of public moneys for the maintenance and operation of the Court of Justice and the offices connected therewith; </section></section><section prefix="3">Ascertain the necessity for assignment of justices and judges as contemplated by Section 110(5)(b) of the Constitution, make reports concerning their performance of duties and certify the compensation payable to them; </section><section prefix="4">Carry on a continuous survey and study of the organization, operation, condition of business, practice and procedure of the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="5">Collect and compile statistical and other data concerning the operations of the courts, and to this end may require all necessary reports from the courts and clerks thereof of this Commonwealth relating to rules, dockets, and business dispatched or pending in such courts; </section><section prefix="6">Formulate and submit to the Supreme Court recommendations of policies for the improvement of the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="7">Provide for educational programs for the members of the Court of Justice; </section><section prefix="8">Report to the General Assembly concerning the work of the Court of Justice and make such recommendations for the improvement of administration of justice as deemed necessary and proper; </section><section prefix="9">Supervise, operate, and administer all pretrial release programs and personnel which come within the purview of the Court of Justice, or which are related thereto; </section><section prefix="10">Perform such other functions as may be assigned by the Chief Justice. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20935</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>