<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.624</section_number><catch_line>Assignment to cabinet by recipient of rights to third-party payments -- Right of recovery by cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>624</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant or recipient shall be deemed to have made to the cabinet an assignment of his rights to third-party payments to the extent of medical assistance paid on behalf of the recipient under Title XIX of the Social Security Act. The applicant or recipient shall be informed in writing by the cabinet of such assignment. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall have the right of recovery which a recipient may have for the cost of hospitalization, pharmaceutical services, physician services, nursing services, and other medical services not to exceed the amount of funds expended by the cabinet for such care and treatment of the recipient under the provisions of Title XIX of the Social Security Act. <section prefix="a">If a payment for medical assistance is made, the cabinet, to enforce its right, may: <section prefix="1">Intervene or join in an action or proceeding brought by the injured, diseased, or disabled person, the person's guardian, personal representative, estate, dependents, or survivors against a third party who may be liable for the injury, disease, or disability, or against contractors, public or private, who may be liable to pay or provide medical care and services rendered to an injured, diseased, or disabled recipient, in state or federal court; or </section><section prefix="2">Institute and prosecute legal proceedings against a third party who may be liable for the injury, disease, or disability, or against contractors, public or private, who may be liable to pay or provide medical care and services rendered to an injured, diseased, or disabled recipient, in state or federal court, either alone or in conjunction with the injured, diseased, or disabled person, the person's guardian, personal representative, estate, dependents, or survivors; or </section><section prefix="3">Institute the proceedings in its own name or in the name of the injured, diseased, or disabled person, the person's guardian, personal representative, estate, dependents, or survivors. </section></section><section prefix="b">The injured, diseased, or disabled person may proceed in his own name, collecting costs without the necessity of joining the cabinet or the Commonwealth as a named party, provided the injured, diseased, or disabled person shall notify the cabinet of the action or proceeding entered into upon commencement of the action or proceeding. The injured, diseased, or disabled person must notify the cabinet of any settlement or judgment of his or her claim. </section><section prefix="c">In the case of an applicant for or recipient of medical assistance whose eligibility is based on deprivation of parental care or support due to absence of a parent from the home, the cabinet may: <section prefix="1">Initiate a civil action or other legal proceedings to secure repayment of medical assistance expenditures for which the absent parent is liable; and </section><section prefix="2">Provide for the payment of reasonable administrative costs incurred by such other state or county agency requested by the cabinet to assist in the enforcement of securing repayment from the absent parent. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Each insurer issuing policies or contracts under Subtitle 17, 18, 32, or 38 of KRS Chapter 304 shall cooperate fully with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or an authorized designee of the cabinet in order for the cabinet to comply with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 247, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 205, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 316, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>