<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.122</section_number><catch_line>Program for certification of firearms instructors for concealed deadly weapon program -- Qualification and certification requirements -- In-service training -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>122</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Criminal Justice Training shall operate and maintain a program for certification of firearms instructors for the concealed deadly weapon training program. Only the General Assembly may eliminate the certified firearms instructor program. </section><section prefix="2">Training courses for certification of firearms instructors shall be conducted by firearms instructor trainers and the department. </section><section prefix="3">An applicant to be a firearms instructor shall hold a concealed deadly weapon license issued pursuant to KRS 237.110, and successfully complete a firearms instructor training course of not more than sixteen (16) hours provided by a certified firearms instructor trainer. </section><section prefix="4">Certification as a firearms instructor shall be valid for a period of three (3) years during which an instructor shall: <section prefix="a">Conduct or assist in at least one (1) applicant training course; </section><section prefix="b">Attend an instructor trainer/instructor in-service training course of not more than four (4) hours conducted by the department; and </section><section prefix="c">Not have become ineligible to be a firearms instructor. </section></section><section prefix="5">The department shall conduct in-service training for firearms instructor trainers and certified firearms instructors as specified in KRS 237.120. </section><section prefix="6">At the end of the certification period, the department shall issue a new firearms instructor certification to any person who has completed the provisions of this section, unless the firearms instructor notifies the department in writing that he or she desires not to be recertified or is otherwise ineligible to be recertified. There shall be no charge for recertification. A firearms instructor who has permitted his or her certification to expire may take the in-service course and be recertified for a period of one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of expiration of the certification without having to repeat the requirements of subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">An instructor trainer shall charge a fee not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150) for a training course for a certified firearms instructor. The instructor shall remit fifty dollars ($50) to the department to defray the cost of materials which the department shall provide to the instructor. </section><section prefix="8">No firearms instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor shall charge a fee in excess of seventy-five dollars ($75) for the conduct of an applicant training course. An instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor may charge a student the actual cost of range use, targets and associated range materials, and classroom rental not to exceed ten dollars ($10) for all of the items specified in this subsection. The instructor trainer or certified firearms instructor shall remit twenty-five dollars ($25) to the department to cover the provision of training materials distributed and providing evidence of successful completion of the course. </section><section prefix="9">No portion of a fee collected pursuant to this section shall be refunded to a student who fails or does not complete the required course of instruction. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>