<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.030</section_number><catch_line>Cosmetology board -- Membership -- Compensation.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created an independent agency of the state government to be known as the Kentucky Board of Hairdressers and Cosmetologists, which shall have complete supervision over the administration of the provisions of this chapter relating to cosmetology, cosmetologists, schools of cosmetology, students enrolled in cosmetology, apprentice cosmetologists, nail technicians, teachers of cosmetology, cosmetology salons, and nail salons. </section><section prefix="2">The cosmetologist board shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">Four (4) of the members shall have been cosmetologists five (5) years prior to their appointment and shall reside in Kentucky: <section prefix="1">Two (2) of whom shall be cosmetology salon owners; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) of whom shall be a cosmetology teacher in public education and shall not own any interest in a cosmetology salon; and </section><section prefix="3">One (1) of whom shall be an owner of or one who shall have a financial interest in a licensed cosmetology school and shall be a member of a nationally recognized association of hairdressers and cosmetologists; </section></section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practices or businesses regulated; and </section><section prefix="c">None of whom nor the administrator shall be financially interested in, or have any financial connection with, wholesale cosmetic supply or equipment businesses. </section></section> At all times in the filling of vacancies of membership on the board, this balance of representation shall be maintained. <section prefix="3">Appointments shall be for a term of two (2) years, ending on February 1. </section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall not remove any member of the board except for cause. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall elect from its members a chair, a vice chair, and a secretary. </section><section prefix="6">Three (3) members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any board business. </section><section prefix="7">Each member of the board shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day of attendance at board meetings, and shall be reimbursed for necessary traveling expenses and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of duties pertaining to official business of the board. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall hold meetings at the place in the state and at the times deemed necessary by the board to discharge its duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 136, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 12. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40880</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>