<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.270</section_number><catch_line>Presentation of judgment for payment -- Appropriations. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each agency which has had an award or judgment against it upon a claim filed pursuant to KRS 45A.240 to 45A.270 shall furnish a certified copy of the award of judgment to the Finance and Administration Cabinet. The first five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) of any award or judgment against the Department of Highways, Transportation Cabinet, shall be paid out of the state road fund, upon warrants drawn by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet upon the State Treasurer. The first five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) of any award or judgment against other departments or agencies of the state, which are not maintained by appropriations out of the general fund, shall be paid out of the funds created or collected for the maintenance and operation of such department or agency, upon warrants drawn by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet upon the State Treasurer. The first five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) of any award or judgment against all other departments and agencies of the state shall be paid out of the general fund, upon warrants drawn by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet upon the State Treasurer. </section><section prefix="2">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall request an appropriation from the next even-numbered-year regular session of the General Assembly for the purpose of satisfying all such awards and judgments granted during the preceding two (2) fiscal years which are not satisfied under subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 11, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended and reenacted as KRS 45A.270, 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 54, effective January 1, 1979. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1) and ch. 181, sec. 6. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification> KRS 44.330. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22384</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>