<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.245</section_number><catch_line>Required equipment on cars for transportation of railroad employees. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text>It shall be unlawful for any owner or operator of a railroad running through or within the boundaries of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and engaged in the business of common carrier to operate for or transport its employees in a motor car which is not equipped with a reasonably substantial top for the protection of said employees from rain, snow, sleet and hail and equipped with a transparent windshield sufficient in width and height to reasonably protect said employees, which windshield shall be of safety glass and such car shall also be equipped with a permanent electric headlamp of sufficient candle power as to render visible at a distance of three hundred (300) feet in advance of such car under ordinary atmospheric conditions, any obstruction, land mark, warning sign or grade crossing on such railroad and said car shall also be equipped with two (2) electric lights on the rear end thereof with sufficient candle power as to be visible at a distance of three hundred (300) feet under ordinary atmospheric conditions, and such car shall also be equipped with an electric windshield wiper that will remove rain, snow and sleet from the windshield on such car while such car is moving, and said windshield wiper shall be so devised that the driver of said car can start or stop said windshield wiper while he is driving the car. </text><history>Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1952 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>