<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.180</section_number><catch_line>Convalescent leave for involuntary patient -- Rehospitalization. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon notice to the court, an authorized staff physician may release an involuntary patient on convalescent leave not to exceed ninety (90) days. The physician may authorize convalescent leave only if he concludes that the patient would not present a danger or a threat of danger to himself or others during such a leave. Release on convalescent leave shall terminate the involuntary hospitalization order and shall include provisions for a jointly developed treatment plan by the hospital and by the provider of outpatient care who will provide follow-up care and the continual monitoring of the patient's condition by the provider. </section><section prefix="2">If there is reason to believe that the patient meets the criteria for involuntary hospitalization, the cabinet, an authorized staff physician of the hospital or other interested person may file a petition for certification or may proceed with an emergency hospitalization under KRS 645.120. </section><section prefix="3">At the conclusion of a convalescent leave, the child may be readmitted to the hospital voluntarily, the child may be discharged or, if appropriate, the cabinet, an authorized staff physician, or other interested person may file a petition for certification or may proceed with an emergency hospitalization under KRS 645.120. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 122, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 163, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>