<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280">PRIVATE TOLL BRIDGES AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>280.030</section_number><catch_line>Application for certificate -- When granted. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person applying for a certificate of convenience and necessity under KRS 280.020 shall, at the time of application, make and file with the Department of Highways a statement in a form as the department prescribes. </section><section prefix="2">The statement shall, in addition to any other information required by the department, contain: <section prefix="a">The name of the applicant; </section><section prefix="b">The nature of the applicant, whether an individual, association, or corporation, and under the laws of what state organized; </section><section prefix="c">The location of its principal office; </section><section prefix="d">The names and post office addresses of its president, secretary, auditor, treasurer, and superintendent or manager; </section><section prefix="e">The name and post office address of its chief officer or managing agent in this state; </section><section prefix="f">The location of the termini between which it transacts its ferry or bridge business; </section><section prefix="g">The number and capacity of boats or other vehicles owned and used for the ferry or the width of driveway of the bridge; </section><section prefix="h">The schedule of hours of service and trips made; and </section><section prefix="i">The schedule showing the rates to be charged and the classification of patrons by rates. </section></section><section prefix="3">The statement shall be made under the oath of the applicant or, if the applicant is an association or corporation, under the oath of its president, secretary, treasurer, superintendent or manager. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall, after the filing of the application, fix a date for a public hearing on the application, which shall be within thirty (30) days after the filing. The applicant shall give notice of the filing of the application by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="5">If it is made to appear to the department that public convenience and necessity requires the operation of the bridge or ferry, the department shall grant the certificate. Any person aggrieved by the decision of the department may appeal, and upon appeal an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 190, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 198. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356za-3, 4356za-7, 4356za-8, 4356za-9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>