<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.814</section_number><catch_line>Comprehensive plan on secondary career and technical education programs -- Consultation with Career and Technical Education Advisory Committee.   </catch_line><order_by>814</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to ensure that high-quality, relevant secondary career and technical programs are available to students in all school districts that enable them to gain the academic and technical skills to meet high school graduation requirements and for successful transition to postsecondary education, work, or the military and to support present-day and future needs of Kentucky employers, the Department of Education shall: <section prefix="a">Review and revise as needed the equipment and facilities standards for each career and technical education program identified and described in the career and technical education supplement to the Kentucky program of studies and published by the Department of Education; and </section><section prefix="b">Determine the statewide unmet needs for career and technical education capital projects, including renovations and expansions of existing facilities and the construction of new technology centers, through a needs assessment process. This process shall be tied to specific criteria in determining if the current programs or career pathways offered in locally and state-operated facilities are appropriate for the students in the school districts served as well as for determining if new programs are needed. The statewide assessment of capital needs for career and technical education shall be incorporated into the local school district facility plan as required by KRS 157.420. The Kentucky Board of Education shall incorporate criteria within the administrative regulations relating to school facility plan requirements to prioritize need for career and technical education programming, regardless of whether the programs are locally or state-operated. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Career and Technical Education Advisory Committee established in KRS 156.806 shall be consulted in carrying out the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 42, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 6, effective April 19, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 82, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>