<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="333" order_by="333">MEDICAL LABORATORIES </unit></structure><section_number>333.090</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications of laboratory director -- Limit on tests. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the director of a medical laboratory shall be a physician licensed to practice medicine in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The director of a medical laboratory may be the holder of an earned doctoral degree, with a chemical, physical or biological science as his major subject, from an institution accredited by an appropriate agency of the state or by any other equivalent accrediting agency acceptable to the cabinet or from an institution which, in the opinion of the cabinet, maintains standards equivalent to those of an institution accredited as aforesaid, who subsequent to graduation has had at least two (2) years of experience in the medical laboratory specialty for which he was trained. </section><section prefix="3">In the event an individual has been serving as a director of a medical laboratory in Kentucky for a period of not less than a year prior to January 1, 1969, he may continue to direct such medical laboratory notwithstanding the requirement of subsections (1) and (2) of this section, provided, however, that the cabinet may require (in the interest of the health, safety, and welfare of the people of this state) as a condition precedent to the issuance of an original or renewal license hereunder, that such individuals demonstrate their ability satisfactorily to perform medical laboratory examinations and to direct a medical laboratory. </section><section prefix="4">Tests performed in a laboratory directed by a nonphysician shall be limited to the specialties or subspecialties of medical laboratory procedures for which the director is personally qualified through education and experience and no medical interpretation of test results, diagnosis, prognosis, or suggested treatment shall be made. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 16. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31848</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>