<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.191</section_number><catch_line>Rights of hospitalized patients. </catch_line><order_by>191</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each and every patient hospitalized under this chapter shall have the following rights: <section prefix="a">The right to be adequately informed as to their individual treatment program; </section><section prefix="b">The right to assist in the planning of their treatment program; </section><section prefix="c">The right to refuse treatment subject to the provisions of KRS 202A.196; </section><section prefix="d">The right to maintain, keep, and use personal possessions and money; </section><section prefix="e">The right to receive visitors; </section><section prefix="f">The right to receive payment for work performed on behalf of the hospital; </section><section prefix="g">The right to refuse intrusive treatment subject to the provisions of KRS 202A.196; </section><section prefix="h">The right to be free from unreasonable use of seclusion and restraint; </section><section prefix="i">The right to seek relief from participating in their treatment plan. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall adopt rules and regulations for the proper administration and enforcement of this chapter. Such regulations shall be filed with the Legislative Research Commission as provided in KRS Chapter 13A. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 27, effective July 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><lrc-note>(10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts..  This section was enacted in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7484</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>