<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.336</section_number><catch_line>Information and education program. </catch_line><order_by>336</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the division an information and education program for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">To develop public awareness of the importance of the forests of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">To promote forest stewardship and sound forest utilization practices of private woodland owners and the forest industry; and </section><section prefix="c">To coordinate with other agencies and organizations to assure effective, long-term forest conservation programs. </section></section><section prefix="2">The division shall implement an educational program that emphasizes sustainable forests and the full range of economic, ecological, and social opportunities provided by privately owned forests by: <section prefix="a">Sponsoring field days that enable individual woodland owners to recognize and resolve problems that they encounter in dealing with their woodland resources; </section><section prefix="b">Developing demonstration programs involving forests and management of forest ecosystems including urban forests; </section><section prefix="c">Developing and implementing programs that give special attention to educational needs of small, private, nonindustrial forest landowners; and </section><section prefix="d">Supporting the Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service in promoting and conducting technology transfer education programs specifically for woodland owners. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 555, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1881</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>