<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.065</section_number><catch_line>Recording of data elements for centralized criminal history record information system -- Definition of front-line staff. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section, "front-line staff" means an employee of the Division of Service Regions of the Department for Community Based Services or the immediate supervisor of an employee whose professional duties include ongoing adult or child protective services, protective services investigations or assessments, or regularly conducting interviews, visits, contacts, or providing transportation services or other services in the homes of family members involved in adult or child protective services. </section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Department of Corrections, the Administrative Office of the Courts, and the Department of Kentucky State Police shall be responsible for the recording of those data elements that are needed for the development of the centralized criminal history record information system. </section><section prefix="3">The database shall at a minimum contain the information required in KRS 27A.310 to 27A.440. </section><section prefix="4">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide access to the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Department of Corrections, the Department of Juvenile Justice, and the Administrative Office of the Courts to its database. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet secretary and the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall establish communications, policies, and procedures to enable designated cabinet staff of the Department for Community Based Services who are working on a protective services investigation or an ongoing protective services case to request a state criminal background check, and within a reasonable time frame, but no later than one (1) hour after receipt of a request, to have the state criminal background check sent to designated cabinet staff. Designated cabinet staff may request a state criminal background check at any time for a protective services investigation and may use the state criminal background check to assess staff safety concerns. </section><section prefix="6">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall prioritize the safety needs of the front-line staff of the Department for Community Based Services and provide improvements in accordance with this section and KRS 194A.562, 194A.564, and 605.170. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 217, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 140, sec. 2, effective April 5, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 153, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 140, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (6/26/2007).  The numbering of subsections in this section has been altered from the numbering of 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 2, by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136. (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6641</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>