<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.035</section_number><catch_line>Delegation of secretary's powers -- Assistance in testing -- Membership on Kentucky Employees Retirement System board. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary may from time to time designate in writing an employee of the cabinet to act for him in case of his absence or inability from any cause to discharge the powers and duties of his position. In this case, the powers and duties of the secretary shall devolve upon his designee. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary may request appropriate persons, including officers and employees in the state service, to assist in the preparation and rating of tests. Department heads shall cooperate to the fullest extent possible in making the services of their employees available for such work. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The secretary may enter into written agreements with an appointing authority which would provide for the delegation of his authority and power to the appointing authority. The secretary is prohibited from delegating any powers or authority pertaining to disciplinary actions, lay-offs, or registers. </section><section prefix="b">All written agreements delegating the secretary's power and authority as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be specific in nature and renewed annually. </section><section prefix="c">A copy of the written agreements shall be forwarded to the Personnel Board. </section></section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall serve ex officio as a member of the board of trustees of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed and reenacted as KRS 18A.035, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, secs. 8 and 17. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.200. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1344</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>