<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.16-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>16-010</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Constituent entity" means an entity that is a party to a merger; </section><section prefix="2">"Constituent limited cooperative association" means a limited cooperative association that is a party to a merger; </section><section prefix="3">"Converted entity" means the limited cooperative association into which a converting entity converts; </section><section prefix="4">"Converting entity" means a foreign entity that converts into a limited cooperative association pursuant to KRS 272A.16-020; </section><section prefix="5">"Converting limited cooperative association" means a converting entity that is a limited cooperative association; </section><section prefix="6">"Foreign entity" has the meaning set forth in KRS 14A.1-070; </section><section prefix="7">"Organizational documents" means articles of incorporation, bylaws, articles of association, operating agreements, partnership agreements, or other documents serving a similar function in the creation and governance of an entity; </section><section prefix="8">"Personal liability" means personal liability for a debt, liability, or other obligation of an entity imposed, by operation of law or otherwise, on a person that co-owns or has an interest in the entity: <section prefix="a">By the entity’s organic law solely because of the person co-owning or having an interest in the entity; or </section><section prefix="b">By the entity’s organizational documents under a provision of the entity’s organic law authorizing those documents to make one (1) or more specified persons liable for all or specified parts of the entity’s debts, liabilities, and other obligations solely because the person co-owns or has an interest in the entity; and </section></section><section prefix="9">"Surviving entity" means an entity into which one (1) or more other entities are merged, whether the entity existed before the merger or is created by the merger. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 110, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41086</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>