<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44">CLAIMS UPON THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>44.055</section_number><catch_line>Insuring state vehicles -- Blanket liability policy -- Effect on sovereign immunity -- Eligibility of insurers. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any state agency, as defined in KRS Chapter 12, may in its discretion, for the protection of the public and its employees, expend state funds to purchase policies of insurance of all kinds deemed advisable covering vehicles, including boats, owned by the state and operated by state employees when in the conduct of official business. The executive director of insurance, upon recommendation of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, shall initiate and be responsible for the purchase of a blanket liability insurance policy to cover the officers and employees of the several state agencies and shall determine, by administrative regulation, the policy limits that shall be applicable to the persons covered in each such affected agency not to exceed the limit prescribed in KRS 44.070. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to be a waiver of sovereign immunity and claims against the Commonwealth, its agencies, officers, employees, or insurers may be asserted only in the manner set forth in KRS 44.070 to 44.160. </section><section prefix="3">Policies authorized by this section shall be purchased only from insurers authorized to do business in this state and shall be countersigned by a licensed resident agent. </section></text><history>Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 372, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>