<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.210</section_number><catch_line>Special tax for construction of roads -- Submission to vote -- Short-term bonds. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of any county may submit to the voters at a special election to be held for that purpose, the question of voting a tax of any sum not exceeding twenty cents ($0.20) on the hundred dollars ($100) on all property subject by law to local taxation, for the construction of the public roads and bridges of the county, as the fiscal court directs. The order of the fiscal court calling the election shall specify the amount of the tax to be levied each year and the number of years for which the tax may be imposed, not exceeding ten (10) years, and shall also provide that no money in excess of the amount that can be raised by the levy in any one (1) year shall be expended in that year. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court may borrow money and issue bonds therefor in advance of the collection of the tax for any year, but the amount borrowed shall not exceed eighty percent (80%) of the estimated tax for the year. The amount of the tax shall be estimated according to the assessment and collection of the preceding year. Any money so borrowed shall be paid out of the money raised from the tax in the year in which the money is borrowed. </section><section prefix="3">For the 1966 tax year and for all subsequent years the rate levied by the levying authority under the provisions of this section for levies which were approved prior to December 16, 1965, shall be the compensating tax rate as defined in KRS 132.010, except as provided in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the limitations contained in subsection (3) of this section no tax rate shall be set lower than that necessary to provide such funds as are required to meet principal and interest payments on outstanding bonded indebtedness. </section></text><history>Amended 1965 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4307b-1, 4307b-2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5442</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>