<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.325</section_number><catch_line>Powers of commission. </catch_line><order_by>325</order_by><text>The powers of the commission shall be:  <section prefix="1">To construct, operate and maintain a sewerage and/or drainage system and sewers and drains within the boundaries of the sewer construction district, or to contract with a metropolitan sewer district for such construction, operation and/or maintenance;  </section><section prefix="2">To provide for disposition of the sewage and/or drainage, and for treatment of sewage, either through its own facilities or by contract with the metropolitan sewer district;  </section><section prefix="3">To clean out, straighten, alter, deepen, fill up or otherwise improve any stream, watercourse receiving sewage, liquid wastes or drainage, located in or out of the district;  </section><section prefix="4">To construct, operate and maintain trunk sewers, intercepting sewers, laterals, siphons, pumping stations, sewage treatment and disposal works necessary for the purposes of the district, through its own facilities or by contract with the metropolitan sewer district;  </section><section prefix="5">To hold, control, acquire by purchase, donation or condemnation any real or personal property necessary for location, construction, operation or maintenance of its works and improvements and easements for rights of way;  </section><section prefix="6">Upon completion of construction of any integral part of the sewer or drainage system, to contract for the operation and maintenance of its works and improvements or easements for rights of way;  </section><section prefix="7">Upon completion of construction of any integral part of the sewer or drainage system, to contract for the operation and maintenance of, and extensions to, such part of the system, with the metropolitan sewer district on a service basis for the users, or, with the approval of the court, to have the territory in such part of the sewer construction district incorporated into the metropolitan sewer district for service as provided to other property within said metropolitan sewer district. </section></text><history>Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 8, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1952</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24554</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>