<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">A ANNEXATION </unit></structure><section_number>81A.420</section_number><catch_line>Ordinance declaring intent to annex -- Election on proposed annexation -- When city may enact ordinance. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a city desires to annex unincorporated territory, the legislative body of the city proposing to annex shall enact an ordinance stating the intention of the city to annex. The ordinance shall accurately define the boundary of the unincorporated territory proposed to be annexed, and declare it desirable to annex the unincorporated territory. </section><section prefix="2">If following the publication of the annexation ordinance pursuant to subsection (1) of this section and within sixty (60) days thereof, or if in any annexation proceeding where the annexing city has not adopted a final annexation ordinance, within sixty (60) days of February 12, 1988, fifty percent (50%) of the resident voters or owners of real property within the limits of the territory proposed to be annexed petition the mayor in opposition to the proposal, an election shall be held at the next regular election if the petition is presented to the county clerk and certified by the county clerk as sufficient not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the regular election: <section prefix="a">The mayor of the city shall deliver a certified copy of the ordinance to the county clerk of the county in which the territory proposed to be annexed is located, who shall have prepared to be placed before the voters in each precinct embraced in whole or in part within the territory proposed to be annexed the question: "Are you in favor of being annexed to the City of _________?" If only a part of any precinct is embraced within the territory proposed to be annexed only persons who reside within the territory proposed to be annexed shall be permitted to vote. The clerk shall cause the sheriff or sheriffs to deliver to the election officers in each precinct in the appropriate counties copies of the ordinance proposing to annex; </section><section prefix="b">If less than fifty-five percent (55%) of those persons voting oppose annexation, the unincorporated territory shall become a part of the city; and </section><section prefix="c">If fifty-five percent (55%) or more of those persons voting oppose annexation, the ordinance proposing annexation shall become ineffectual for any purpose. </section></section><section prefix="3">In not less than sixty (60) days after the enactment of the ordinance, if no petition has been received by the mayor as set out herein, or within sixty (60) days of the certification of election results in which less than fifty-five percent (55%) of those persons voting opposed annexation, the legislative body may enact an ordinance annexing to the city the territory described in the ordinance. If the city has elected to establish the zoning for the new territory prior to the completion of the annexation pursuant to KRS 100.209, the ordinance shall include a map showing the zoning. Upon the enactment of this ordinance, the territory shall become part of the city for all purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 43, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 2, effective February 12, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 43, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>