<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.031</section_number><catch_line>Report as to tickets sold and receipts -- Tax on gross receipts. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person conducting a boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling show or exhibition, other than those holding a permit under subsection (1) of KRS 229.061, shall, within twenty-four (24) hours after the termination of every show or exhibition, furnish to the authority a written report, verified by the person, if an individual, or by some officer, if a corporation or association, showing the number of tickets sold for the show or exhibition, the amount of the gross receipts from such sale and such other matters as the authority prescribes. He or she shall also, within the same period, pay to the authority a tax of twenty-five dollars ($25) or five percent (5%) of the gross receipts from the sale of all tickets to the show or exhibition, whichever is greater. </section><section prefix="2">He or she shall also, prior to any such show or exhibition, file with the authority a copy of each contract involving compensation of the contestants and a copy of each contract under which he or she will receive, directly or indirectly, compensation from any source whatsoever. Any person making payments under any such contract shall promptly report to the authority the amount of any such payments. </section><section prefix="3">All taxes required to be paid by this section shall be computed on the gross receipts without any deduction whatsoever for commissions, brokerage, distribution fees, advertising or other expenses, charges or recoupments in respect thereto, exclusive of any federal excise taxes. </section><section prefix="4">Any person supplying radio, television, or cable facilities for the broadcast or televising of any show shall, prior to the contest, notify the authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 17, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 155, effective March 18, 2005. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 15. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10770</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>