<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLI" order_by="41">LAWS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="446" order_by="446">CONSTRUCTION OF STATUTES </unit></structure><section_number>446.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for statutes generally.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in the statute laws of this state, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Action" includes all proceedings in any court of this state; </section><section prefix="2">"Animal" includes every warm-blooded living creature except a human being; </section><section prefix="3">"Attorney" means attorney-at-law; </section><section prefix="4">"Bequeath" and "devise" mean the same thing; </section><section prefix="5">"Bequest" and "legacy" mean the same thing, and embrace either real or personal estate, or both; </section><section prefix="6">"Business trust" includes, except when utilized in KRS Chapter 386, a "statutory trust" as organized under KRS Chapter 386A; </section><section prefix="7">"Case plan" means an individualized accountability and behavior change strategy for supervised individuals that: <section prefix="a">Targets and prioritizes the specific criminal risk factors of the individual based upon his or her assessment results; </section><section prefix="b">Matches the type and intensity of supervision and treatment conditions to the individual's level of risk, criminal risk factors, and individual characteristics, such as gender, culture, motivational stage, developmental stage, and learning style; </section><section prefix="c">Establishes a timetable for achieving specific behavioral goals, including a schedule for payment of victim restitution, child support, and other financial obligations; and </section><section prefix="d">Specifies positive and negative actions that will be taken in response to the supervised individual's behaviors; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Cattle" includes horse, mule, ass, cow, ox, sheep, hog, or goat of any age or sex; </section><section prefix="9">"Certified mail" means any method of governmental, commercial, or electronic delivery that allows a document or package to have proof of: <section prefix="a">Sending the document or package; </section><section prefix="b">The date the document or package was delivered or delivery was attempted; and </section><section prefix="c">The signature of the receipt of the document or package; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Company" may extend and be applied to any corporation, company, person, partnership, joint stock company, or association; </section><section prefix="11">"Corporation" may extend and be applied to any corporation, company, partnership, joint stock company, or association; </section><section prefix="12">"Criminal risk factors" are characteristics and behaviors that, when addressed or changed, affect a person's risk for committing crimes. The characteristics may include but are not limited to the following risk and criminogenic need factors: antisocial behavior; antisocial personality; criminal thinking; criminal associates; dysfunctional family; low levels of employment or education; poor use of leisure and recreation; and substance abuse; </section><section prefix="13">"Cruelty" as applied to animals includes every act or omission whereby unjustifiable physical pain, suffering, or death is caused or permitted; </section><section prefix="14">"Directors," when applied to corporations, includes managers or trustees; </section><section prefix="15">"Domestic," when applied to a corporation, partnership, business trust, or limited liability company, means all those incorporated or formed by authority of this state; </section><section prefix="16">"Domestic animal" means any animal converted to domestic habitat; </section><section prefix="17">"Evidence-based practices" means policies, procedures, programs, and practices proven by scientific research to reliably produce reductions in recidivism when implemented competently; </section><section prefix="18">"Federal" refers to the United States; </section><section prefix="19">"Foreign," when applied to a corporation, partnership, limited partnership, business trust, statutory trust, or limited liability company, includes all those incorporated or formed by authority of any other state; </section><section prefix="20">"Generally accepted accounting principles" are those uniform minimum standards of and guidelines to financial accounting and reporting as adopted by the National Council on Governmental Accounting, under the auspices of the Municipal Finance Officers Association and by the Financial Accounting Standards Board, under the auspices of the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants; </section><section prefix="21">"Graduated sanction" means any of a wide range of accountability measures and programs for supervised individuals, including but not limited to electronic monitoring; drug and alcohol testing or monitoring; day or evening reporting centers; restitution centers; disallowance of future earned compliance credits; rehabilitative interventions such as substance abuse or mental health treatment; reporting requirements to probation and parole officers; community service or work crews; secure or unsecure residential treatment facilities or halfway houses; and short-term or intermittent incarceration; </section><section prefix="22">"Humane society," "society," or "Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals," means any nonprofit corporation, organized under the laws of this state and having as its primary purpose the prevention of cruelty to animals; </section><section prefix="23">"Issue," as applied to the descent of real estate, includes all the lawful lineal descendants of the ancestors; </section><section prefix="24">"Land" or "real estate" includes lands, tenements, and hereditaments and all rights thereto and interest therein, other than a chattel interest; </section><section prefix="25">"Legatee" and "devisee" convey the same idea; </section><section prefix="26">"May" is permissive; </section><section prefix="27">"Month" means calendar month; </section><section prefix="28">"Oath" includes "affirmation" in all cases in which an affirmation may be substituted for an oath; </section><section prefix="29">"Owner" when applied to any animal, means any person having a property interest in such animal; </section><section prefix="30">"Partnership" includes both general and limited partnerships; </section><section prefix="31">"Peace officer" includes sheriffs, constables, coroners, jailers, metropolitan and urban-county government correctional officers, marshals, policemen, and other persons with similar authority to make arrests; </section><section prefix="32">"Penitentiary" includes all of the state penal institutions except the houses of reform; </section><section prefix="33">"Person" may extend and be applied to bodies-politic and corporate, societies, communities, the public generally, individuals, partnerships, joint stock companies, and limited liability companies; </section><section prefix="34">"Personal estate" includes chattels, real and other estate that passes to the personal representative upon the owner dying intestate; </section><section prefix="35">"Pretrial risk assessment" means an objective, research-based, validated assessment tool that measures a defendant's risk of flight and risk of anticipated criminal conduct while on pretrial release pending adjudication; </section><section prefix="36">"Registered mail" means any governmental, commercial, or electronic method of delivery that allows a document or package to have: <section prefix="a">Its chain of custody recorded in a register to enable its location to be tracked; </section><section prefix="b">Insurance available to cover its loss; and </section><section prefix="c">The signature of the recipient of the document or package available to the sender; </section></section><section prefix="37">"Regular election" means the election in even-numbered years at which members of Congress are elected and the election in odd-numbered years at which state officers are elected; </section><section prefix="38">"Risk and needs assessment" or "validated risk and needs assessment" means an actuarial tool scientifically proven to determine a person's risk to reoffend and criminal risk factors, that when properly addressed, can reduce that person's likelihood of committing future criminal behavior; </section><section prefix="39">"Shall" is mandatory; </section><section prefix="40">"State" when applied to a part of the United States, includes territories, outlying possessions, and the District of Columbia; "any other state" includes any state, territory, outlying possession, the District of Columbia, and any foreign government or country; </section><section prefix="41">"State funds" or "public funds" means sums actually received in cash or negotiable instruments from all sources unless otherwise described by any state agency, state-owned corporation, university, department, cabinet, fiduciary for the benefit of any form of state organization, authority, board, bureau, interstate compact, commission, committee, conference, council, office, or any other form of organization whether or not the money has ever been paid into the Treasury and whether or not the money is still in the Treasury if the money is controlled by any form of state organization, except for those funds the management of which is to be reported to the Legislative Research Commission pursuant to KRS 42.600, 42.605, and 42.615; </section><section prefix="42">"Supervised individual" means an individual placed on probation by a court or serving a period of parole or post-release supervision from prison or jail; </section><section prefix="43">"Sworn" includes "affirmed" in all cases in which an affirmation may be substituted for an oath; </section><section prefix="44">"Treatment" when used in a criminal justice context, means targeted interventions that focus on criminal risk factors in order to reduce the likelihood of criminal behavior. Treatment options may include but shall not be limited to community-based programs that are consistent with evidence-based practices; cognitive-behavioral programs; faith-based programs; inpatient and outpatient substance abuse or mental health programs; and other available prevention and intervention programs that have been scientifically proven to produce reductions in recidivism when implemented competently. "Treatment" does not include medical services; </section><section prefix="45">"United States" includes territories, outlying possessions, and the District of Columbia; </section><section prefix="46">"Vacancy in office," or any equivalent phrase, means such as exists when there is an unexpired part of a term of office without a lawful incumbent therein, or when the person elected or appointed to an office fails to qualify according to law, or when there has been no election to fill the office at the time appointed by law; it applies whether the vacancy is occasioned by death, resignation, removal from the state, county or district, or otherwise; </section><section prefix="47">"Violate" includes failure to comply with; </section><section prefix="48">"Will" includes codicils; "last will" means last will and testament; </section><section prefix="49">"Year" means calendar year; </section><section prefix="50">"City" includes town; </section><section prefix="51">Appropriation-related terms are defined as follows: <section prefix="a">"Appropriation" means an authorization by the General Assembly to expend, from public funds, a sum of money not in excess of the sum specified, for the purposes specified in the authorization and under the procedure prescribed in KRS Chapter 48; </section><section prefix="b">"Appropriation provision" means a section of any enactment by the General Assembly which is not provided for by KRS Chapter 48 and which authorizes the expenditure of public funds other than by a general appropriation bill; </section><section prefix="c">"General appropriation bill" means an enactment by the General Assembly that authorizes the expenditure of public funds in a branch budget bill as provided for in KRS Chapter 48; </section></section><section prefix="52">"Mediation" means a nonadversarial process in which a neutral third party encourages and helps disputing parties reach a mutually acceptable agreement. Recommendations by mediators are not binding on the parties unless the parties enter into a settlement agreement incorporating the recommendations; </section><section prefix="53">"Biennium" means the two (2) year period commencing on July 1 in each even-numbered year and ending on June 30 in the ensuing even-numbered year; </section><section prefix="54">"Branch budget bill" or "branch budget" means an enactment by the General Assembly which provides appropriations and establishes fiscal policies and conditions for the biennial financial plan for the judicial branch, the legislative branch, and the executive branch, which shall include a separate budget bill for the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="55">"AVIS" means the automated vehicle information system established and maintained by the Transportation Cabinet to collect titling and registration information on vehicles and boats and information on holders of motor vehicle operator's licenses and personal identification cards; and </section><section prefix="56">"Cooperative," except in KRS Chapter 272, includes a limited cooperative association. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 126, effective July 12, 2012; ch.139, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 160, sec. 139, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 151, sec. 120, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 42, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 237, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 389, sec. 110, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 3, effective January 3, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective January 26, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2; and ch. 188, sec. 181, effective July 1, 1980. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 462, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 331. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 277. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 446, 451, 452, 456, 457, 458, 463, 467, 469, 575, 751, 1521. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 81, 139, and 160, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (3/30/90).  The definition of "animal" contained in subsection (2) of this section does not reflect the amendatory language contained in Senate Bill 263 of the 1980 Regular Session of the Kentucky General Assembly because the 1980 Senate Journal indicates that Senate Bill 263 was vetoed by Governor John Y. Brown, Jr., on April 9, 1980, and recommitted by action of the Senate to its Committee on Appropriations and Revenue on April 14, 1980. Senate Bill 263 proposed to change subsection (2) to read as follows: " 'Animal' includes every warmblooded living creature except birds and human beings;". By a letter dated March 16, 1990, the Attorney General has informally opined that Governor Brown's veto of Senate Bill 263 was not timely; that letter has exhibits showing that the bill was received by the Governor on March 28, 1980, and that his veto was received by the Senate Clerk on April 10, 1980. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>