<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6326</section_number><catch_line>Review of Medicaid reimbursement systems -- Implementation of a standardized patient assessment tool and consistent quality-of-care mandates. </catch_line><order_by>6326</order_by><text>The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall review all medical assistance reimbursement systems for appropriateness and cost-effectiveness. The review shall include: <section prefix="1">Review of cost-based reimbursement policies for hospitals and nursing homes to determine the effectiveness and appropriateness of alternate systems. Consideration shall be given to the use of modified diagnostic-related groups and resource utilization groups systems, using capitated payment methods; and </section><section prefix="2">Review of reimbursement rates for physicians to determine whether savings or cost containment would be better achieved through using a relative-based resource value scale system, a capitated payment method, or other alternative methods of reimbursement; and </section><section prefix="3">For all Medicaid-covered long-term-care services, implementation of a standardized patient assessment tool and consistent quality-of-care mandates. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 255, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 213, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 80, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>