<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.140</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors -- Management of district -- Qualifications -- Appointment -- Terms -- Vacancies. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text>Within twenty (20) days after the commissioner certifies to the county clerk of each county in which the district is located that the district is incorporated, there shall be appointed a board of directors for the district, consisting of three (3) members, which shall control and manage the affairs of the district. If the district lies wholly within a single county, the county judge/executive of that county shall appoint all of the directors. If the district lies within two (2) counties, the county judge/executive of the county in which the greater portion of the population of the district resides may appoint two (2) directors and the county judge/executive of the other county shall appoint the third. If the district lies within more than two (2) counties, the county judges/executive of all the counties shall jointly select the directors, but each one so appointed must reside in a different county. Not less than two (2) of the directors shall be freeholders, and not more than two (2) of them shall belong to or be affiliated with the same political party. If the district is coextensive with the boundaries of two (2) or more counties, four (4) directors shall be appointed by the county judge/executive of the most populous county and two (2) shall be appointed by the county judge/executive of each remaining county. All appointments by county judges/executive shall be subject to the approval of the respective fiscal courts. In a district which is coextensive with the boundaries of two (2) or more counties, not less than two-thirds (2/3) of the directors shall be freeholders. No director shall be in any way associated or connected with the ownership, operation or control of any privately owned public utility operating within the district. The terms of office of the first board of directors shall be two (2), three (3), and four (4) years, respectively, from the date of their appointment, the length of the term of office of each member to be determined by lot at their first meeting, but the individual holding such office shall do so at the pleasure of the county judge/executive by whom he is appointed, and he may be removed without cause, with the approval of the respective fiscal court, by the county judge/executive by whom he was appointed and his unexpired term filled by another appointee of such county judge/executive. After the expiration of the respective terms of office of the first board, each director shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years, subject to the will of the county judge/executive making the appointment. Vacancies resulting from any cause other than expiration of term shall be filled only for the unexpired term. The county judge/executive of the county whose director has completed his term of office or whose office has otherwise been vacated shall fill the vacant office, except that when the district lies within more than three (3) counties, if each county is not represented, vacancies resulting from expiration of term shall be filled in rotation by the county judges/executive of those counties not represented by a director at the time a vacancy occurs. The directors shall at all times be residents of the district, and the office of any director who moves his residence outside the district shall automatically be vacated. </text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-13. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9783</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>