<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6313</section_number><catch_line>Medicaid reimbursement for primary care practitioners at community mental health centers. </catch_line><order_by>6313</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Advanced practice registered nurse" has the same meaning as in KRS 314.011; </section><section prefix="b">"Physician" has the same meaning as in KRS 311.550; and </section><section prefix="c">"Physician assistant" has the same meaning as in KRS 311.840. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services and any regional managed care partnership or other entity under contract with the cabinet for the administration or provision of the Medicaid program shall provide Medicaid reimbursement for primary care services provided by a licensed physician, advanced practice registered nurse, or physician assistant employed by a community mental health center established pursuant to KRS 210.370 to 210.480, if the community mental health center is in compliance with the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services regulations on enhanced primary care reimbursements. </section><section prefix="3">Primary care services provided by a physician, advanced practice registered nurse, or physician assistant in a community mental health center shall be subject to the same reimbursement rates as established by the Department for Medicaid Services for primary care providers operating in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement this section. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43456</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>