<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">TURNPIKE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175.750</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky determines as a legislative finding of fact that the economy of the Commonwealth and the consequent economic development potential of the citizens of the Commonwealth are vitally dependent upon the existence and availability of a statewide system of safe, adequate and well-maintained highways, roads and thoroughfares; that there is a serious need for construction, reconstruction, and in some cases relocation of many such highways, roads and thoroughfares to preserve and enhance the economic well-being and development of the Commonwealth and the health and safety of the public; and that in many cases, highways, roads and thoroughfares which are vital economic links between various sections of the Commonwealth have become, by reason of age and continued usage obsolete and are no longer capable of affording the services required in a modern industrial society.  The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky further determines as a legislative finding of fact that the construction, reconstruction, and relocation of a system of such economic development roads through the Turnpike Authority of Kentucky will preserve and enhance the economic viability of the Commonwealth, will enable the Commonwealth to prosper and make available its economic potentials to the fullest possible degree, will protect and enhance the safety, health, convenience and welfare of the traveling public and will therefore constitute the performance of essential governmental and public purposes. </text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5103</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>