<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.615</section_number><catch_line>Authority pilot projects permitted. </catch_line><order_by>615</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authorities established under KRS 151.610 to 151.615 may conduct one (1) or more of the following restoration and mitigation activities as pilot projects, identified within its watershed plan: <section prefix="a">Restoration and mitigation of impairments or permanent loss of water resources due to mining operations; </section><section prefix="b">Restoration and mitigation of impairment or permanent loss of water resources due to highway or road construction; </section><section prefix="c">Restoration and mitigation of impairment or permanent loss of water resources due to agricultural or sivicultural operations; or </section><section prefix="d">Restoration and mitigation of impairment or permanent loss of water resources due to residential or commercial building construction. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority undertakes a project that does not otherwise require development and submittal to a state or federal agency of a plan with standards and criteria for evaluating project success, the authority shall develop standards and criteria for evaluating the project's success. The authority shall include an account of the pilot projects findings in the report required under KRS 151.614(3). </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2142</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>