<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.215</section_number><catch_line>Conveyance of prisoner to institution of confinement. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the judgment imposes a sentence of death or confinement in the penitentiary, county jail or other institution, two (2) certified copies thereof shall be furnished forthwith to the sheriff who shall execute the same by delivering the defendant and a certified copy of the judgment to the person in charge of the penitentiary, jail or institution of confinement and making a written return thereof in the office of the circuit clerk within ten (10) days after the execution. </section><section prefix="2">When the judgment imposes a sentence of death or confinement in the penitentiary, the county in which the prisoner is incarcerated shall receive from the State Treasury a fee per day beginning on the day on which judgment was rendered and ending the day that the defendant is delivered to the penitentiary. The fee shall be paid to the county treasurer for use for the incarceration of prisoners as provided in KRS 441.025. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 441, effective January 2, 1978. -- Reenacted 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 44. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1137-2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014</effective><former-codification> KRS 431.230.</former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43377</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>