<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.625</section_number><catch_line>Injunction -- Cease and desist order. </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever, in the judgment of the commissioner, any person has engaged, or is about to engage, in any acts or practices that constitute, or will constitute a violation of the provisions of KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565, the commissioner may inform the Attorney General, who may make application to the Circuit Court of the county where the violation occurred for an order enjoining such acts or practices. </section><section prefix="2">If a person is practicing without the requisite license or certificate required under KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565, the commissioner shall inform the Attorney General of the unlawful practice within seven (7) days of receiving notice of its occurrence. The Attorney General may apply to the Circuit Court of the county where the violation occurred for an order enjoining the acts or practices. </section><section prefix="3">Additionally, the commissioner may issue a cease and desist order, the violation of which shall be cause for the imposition of an administrative fine, suspension, or revocation as provided for in KRS 198B.620. Upon showing via the commissioner that such person has engaged, or is about to engage, in any such acts or practices, an injunction or restraining order, or such other order as may be appropriate, shall be granted by the Circuit Court. Any order of the Circuit Court of the county where the violation occurred shall be enforceable and shall be valid anywhere in this Commonwealth and the order of that court shall be reviewable as provided for in the Rules of Civil Procedure, in the case of other injunctions and restraining orders. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 285, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7039</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>