<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.520</section_number><catch_line>Title and purpose of KRS 205.510 to 205.630 -- Recovery from third parties for services rendered. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 205.510 to 205.630 shall be known as the "Medical Assistance Act." </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky recognizes and declares that it is an essential function, duty, and responsibility of the state government to provide medical care to its indigent citizenry; and it is the purpose of KRS 205.510 to 205.630 to provide such care. </section><section prefix="3">Further, it is the policy of the Commonwealth to take advantage of all federal funds that may be available for medical assistance. To qualify for federal funds the secretary for health and family services may by regulation comply with any requirement that may be imposed or opportunity that may be presented by federal law. Nothing in KRS 205.510 to 205.630 is intended to limit the secretary's power in this respect. </section><section prefix="4">It is the intention of the General Assembly to comply with the provisions of Title XIX of the Social Security Act which require that the Kentucky Medical Assistance Program recover from third parties which have a legal liability to pay for care and services paid by the Kentucky Medical Assistance Program. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Medical Assistance Program shall be the payor of last resort and its right to recover under KRS 205.622 to 205.630 shall be superior to any right of reimbursement, subrogation, or indemnity of any liable third party. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 228, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 195, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 124, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 252, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 8, effective February 10, 1979. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (15), (16) and (19). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VII, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7700</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>