<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.0012</section_number><catch_line>Workers' Compensation Advisory Council. </catch_line><order_by>0012</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Workers' Compensation Advisory Council which shall consist of sixteen (16) members appointed by the Governor. Each member shall serve for a term of four (4) years and until his or her successor has been appointed and has qualified. </section><section prefix="2">Vacancies shall be filled by appointment of the Governor for the unexpired term of the member whose office is vacant and shall be made within sixty (60) days of the occurrence of the vacancy. </section><section prefix="3">Annually, the members of the council shall elect co-chairmen. One co-chairman shall be elected by the members of the council representing labor and the other co-chairman shall be elected by the members representing management. A majority of the members of the council shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall meet at least quarterly and on other occasions as may be necessary, on the call of the co-chairmen or a majority of the members. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall be attached to the Department of Workers' Claims in the Labor Cabinet for administrative purposes, and the commissioner of the Department of Workers' Claims shall supply necessary staff and supplies to the council. </section><section prefix="6">The principal office of the council shall be located in Frankfort, Kentucky, but meetings of the council may be held at any location in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="7">In making appointments to the council, the Governor shall appoint eight (8) members representing labor and eight (8) members representing management. </section><section prefix="8">The council shall not infringe upon or assume the duties of the Labor Cabinet, Cabinet for Economic Development or the Department of Insurance. The council shall serve in an advisory capacity and shall make recommendations to the Governor and the legislature on all matters relating to workers' compensation including, but not limited to: efficient administration; coverage of employers and employees; adequacy and delivery of the benefit structure; insurance and self-insurance; medical cost containment and medical services; rehabilitation; liability and financing of the special fund; attorney fees; and lump-sum compensation and settlement procedures. In addition, the council may recommend legislation and administrative regulations as it deems necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1778, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 61(1) to (8), effective October 26, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32357</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>