<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.030</section_number><catch_line>Number of persons permitted to work in same air current or split-ventilation -- Repair. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As many as sixty (60) persons may work in the same air current or split, and with the approval of the mine inspector and the commissioner, as many as eighty (80) persons may work in the same air current. Each active section in a mine shall be ventilated by a separate split of intake air. Every mine, and all portions thereof, shall be ventilated by one (1) or more currents of air, which shall contain not less than nineteen and one-half percent (19.5%) of oxygen, nor any dangerous quantities of flammable gas, nor any harmful amount of poisonous gases or dust, when the current of air enters into each split. The ventilation shall be sufficient to prevent methane accumulations, so far as practicable, and to keep the methane percentage in the return of any split to not more than two percent (2%). </section><section prefix="2">The ventilating current shall be circulated through the haulageways, travelways, and airways to reach all portions of the mine, except sealed sections; and it shall be circulated through the entries and rooms around the ends of line brattice and along pillar lines. It shall be conducted to the last breakthrough, or to the working faces if required, by means of stoppings, check doors, curtains, and brattice that may be necessary or required, in order to dilute, render harmless, and carry away the noxious and dangerous gases, smoke, and dust liberated therein, and to supply a sufficient quantity of ventilation for all emergencies. The ventilating current in the area of a mine's belt entries shall be directed to an air return before the ventilating current reaches the face area, unless the department, under certain conditions issues a permit for belt air to be used at the coal face. The department shall render a final written decision within sixty (60) calendar days of receipt of the permit application. </section><section prefix="3">When mine ventilation, formerly satisfactory and adequate, becomes deficient in quality or quantity, the department shall have authority to order improvement of the ventilation. </section><section prefix="4">No licensee, superintendent, or mine foreman shall permit any person to work at a place where sufficient ventilation cannot be maintained, except persons employed to make the places of employment safe in compliance with the requirements of this chapter, and while repair work necessary to comply with the requirements is in progress no person shall be permitted to enter that part of the mine affected except those actually employed in doing the repair work. The repair work shall be done under the constant supervision of a certified official designated by the mine foreman. </section><section prefix="5">Each licensee shall adopt a plan which shall provide that when any mine fan stops, immediate action shall be taken by the licensee or his agent: <section prefix="a">To withdraw all persons from the working sections; </section><section prefix="b">To cut off the power in the mine in a timely manner; </section><section prefix="c">To provide for restoration of power and resumption of work if ventilation is restored within a reasonable period, of not more than fifteen (15) minutes, as set forth in the plan after the working places and other active workings where methane is likely to accumulate are reexamined by a certified person to determine if methane in amounts of one percent (1%) or more exists therein; and </section><section prefix="d">To provide for withdrawal of all persons from the mine if ventilation cannot be restored within a reasonable time, of not more than fifteen (15) minutes. </section></section> The plan and revisions thereof approved by the commissioner or his authorized representative shall be set out in printed form and a copy shall be furnished to the commissioner or his authorized representative. </text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 23, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 6. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 3. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 16, effective March 5, 1952. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-19. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>