<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.625</section_number><catch_line>Highway construction lakes. </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Highways is authorized to construct fills, made necessary by road construction, so that such will impound water. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources and the Department of Highways shall decide whether the creation of a lake in any one (1) particular spot is deemed reasonable and beneficial. The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources shall do everything necessary to insure good fishing and may regulate boating and other recreational interest so that there may be the least amount of interference. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources may, if the site is suitable, assist the local party or parties in obtaining deeds or easements where necessary. Interested local parties may obtain title to excess land required and deed it to the Commonwealth for creation of a public fishing lake. A parking lot at or near the fill may be created on land deeded free of charge to the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">Surrounding landowners may by permission irrigate from said lake providing that there is no adverse affect on the lake itself. </section><section prefix="5">Parking shall be regulated to prevent obstruction of the highway. </section></text><history>Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1958 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2050</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>