<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.080</section_number><catch_line>State coordinator for search and rescue -- Appointment and duties. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>The director of the Division of Emergency Management shall appoint a state coordinator of search and rescue, who shall: <section prefix="1">Identify, inventory, and coordinate resources available for searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="2">Investigate and apply for grants and other financial assistance for searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="3">Maintain statistics regarding searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="4">Coordinate assistance during searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="5">Act as liaison with other states' operations involving searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="6">Provide assistance, upon request, during searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="7">Prepare a plan for searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="8">Prepare and distribute publications relating to searches and rescues; </section><section prefix="9">Establish, by administrative regulation, recommendations for organizations specializing in search and rescue, and certify organizations which meet those recommendations at the appropriate level; </section><section prefix="10">Maintain a list of all certified organizations and resources; </section><section prefix="11">Coordinate training in techniques of search and rescue; and </section><section prefix="12">Coordinate requests for federal assistance with the Air Force Rescue Coordination Center. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 90, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21801</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>