<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.470</section_number><catch_line>Right of entry on land of others by land surveyor -- Notification of landowner -- Liability of landowner. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text>As used in this section, "professional land surveyor" shall include the agents, the employees, and any personnel under the supervision of a professional land surveyor. <section prefix="1">A professional land surveyor may go on, over, and upon the lands of others if necessary to perform surveys for the location of property corners, boundary lines, rights-of-way, and easements, and may carry with them their customary equipment and vehicles. <section prefix="a">Entry under the right hereby granted shall not constitute trespass; and </section><section prefix="b">A professional land surveyor shall not be liable to arrest or a civil action by reason of this entry. </section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall be construed as giving authority to a professional land surveyor to destroy, injure, damage, or move anything on the lands of another without the written permission of the landowner; and nothing in this section shall be construed as removing civil liability for these damages. </section><section prefix="3">A professional land surveyor shall make reasonable effort to notify adjoining landowners upon whose land it is necessary to enter. </section><section prefix="4">No owner or occupant of the land shall be liable for any injury or damage sustained by any person entering upon his or her land under the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 38, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>