<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.140</section_number><catch_line>Criminal gang recruitment -- Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of criminal gang recruitment when he solicits or entices another person to join a criminal gang, or intimidates or threatens another person because the other person: <section prefix="a">Refuses to join a criminal gang; </section><section prefix="b">Has withdrawn or is attempting to withdraw from a criminal gang; or </section><section prefix="c">Refuses to submit to a demand made by a criminal gang. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in this chapter: <section prefix="a">"Criminal gang" means any alliance, network, or conspiracy, in law or in fact, of five (5) or more persons with an established hierarchy that, through its membership or through the action of any member, engages in a continuing pattern of criminal activity. "Criminal gang" shall not include fraternal organizations, unions, corporations, associations, or similar entities, unless organized for the primary purpose of engaging in criminal activity. </section><section prefix="b">"Continuing pattern of criminal activity" means a conviction by any member or members of a criminal gang for the commission, attempt, or solicitation of two (2) or more felony offenses, the commission of two (2) or more violent misdemeanor offenses, or a combination of at least one (1) of these felony offenses and one (1) of these violent misdemeanor offenses, on separate occasions within a two (2) year period for the purpose of furthering gang activity. </section><section prefix="c">"Violent misdemeanor offense" means KRS 508.030, 508.050, 508.070, 508.080, 508.120, 508.150, 509.030, and 509.080. </section></section><section prefix="3">Criminal gang recruitment is a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for a second or subsequent offense. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 83, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>