<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.001</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>001</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Administrator" means the chief executive officer of the institution; </section><section prefix="2">"Adult basic education" means instruction in mathematics, science, social studies, reading, language arts, and related areas to enable individuals to better function in society; </section><section prefix="3">"Benchmarks" means objective measures developed where applicable or practical by the Council on Postsecondary Education to judge the performance of the postsecondary education system and progress toward the goals as stated in KRS 164.003(2); </section><section prefix="4">"Board" or "governing board" means the board of trustees for the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville, the board of regents for a comprehensive university, or the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="5">"Board of regents" means the governing board of each comprehensive university and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="6">"Committee" means the Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education created in KRS 164.004; </section><section prefix="7">"Comprehensive university" means the following public institutions: Eastern Kentucky University, Kentucky State University, Morehead State University, Murray State University, Northern Kentucky University, and Western Kentucky University; </section><section prefix="8">"Council" means the Council on Postsecondary Education created in KRS 164.011; </section><section prefix="9">"Customized training" means training in specific academic areas, work processes, or technical skills that are designed to serve a specific industry or industries to upgrade worker skills; </section><section prefix="10">"Goals" means the six (6) goals specified in KRS 164.003(2); </section><section prefix="11">"Independent institution" means a nonpublic postsecondary education institution in Kentucky whose instruction is not solely sectarian in nature, is accredited by a regional accrediting association recognized by the United States Department of Education, and is licensed by the Council on Postsecondary Education; </section><section prefix="12">"Institution" means a university, college, community college, health technology center, vocational-technical school, technical institute, technical college, technology center, or the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="13">"Kentucky Community and Technical College System" means the system composed of public community and technical colleges, including those postsecondary institutions operated by the former Cabinet for Workforce Development and those community colleges in the University of Kentucky Community College System on May 30, 1997. </section> The system also includes institutions created by the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System and approved by the General Assembly; <section prefix="14">"Literacy" means an individual's ability to read, write, and speak in English and compute and solve problems at levels of proficiency necessary to function on the job and in society to achieve one's goals and develop one's knowledge and potential; </section><section prefix="15">"Lower division academic course" means any academic course offered for college or university credit that is designated as a freshman or sophomore level academic course; </section><section prefix="16">"Nonteaching personnel" means any employee who is a full-time staff member, excluding a president, chancellor, vice president, academic dean, academic department chair, or administrator; </section><section prefix="17">"Postsecondary education system" means the following public institutions: University of Kentucky, University of Louisville, Eastern Kentucky University, Kentucky State University, Morehead State University, Murray State University, Northern Kentucky University, Western Kentucky University, and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="18">"P-16 council" or "council of partners" means a local or state council that is composed of educators from public and private preschools, elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education institutions, local board of education members, and may include community and business representatives that have voluntarily organized themselves for the purpose of improving the alignment and quality of the education continuum from preschool through postsecondary education as well as student achievement at all levels; </section><section prefix="19">"Public" means operated with state support; </section><section prefix="20">"Relative" means a person's father, mother, brother, sister, husband, wife, son, daughter, aunt, uncle, son-in-law, or daughter-in-law; </section><section prefix="21">"Remedial education" means any program, course, or activity that is designed specifically for students who have basic deficiencies in reading, written or oral communication, mathematics, study skills, or other skills necessary to do beginning postsecondary work as defined by the institution; </section><section prefix="22">"Standardized degree program" means a program, approved by the Council on Postsecondary Education, that consists of specific competencies, curriculum, and performance requirements regardless of the providing institution; </section><section prefix="23">"Strategic agenda" means the state strategic postsecondary education agenda described in KRS 164.0203; </section><section prefix="24">"Technical institution" means an educational institution that offers certificates, diplomas, or technical degrees in technical or occupational-related programs, including a facility called a vocational-technical school, technical institute, health technology center, technology center, technical college, or similar designation; and </section><section prefix="25">"Learning outcomes" means the knowledge, skills, and abilities that students have attained as a result of their involvement in a particular set of educational experiences. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 100, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 3, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4156</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>