<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.620</section_number><catch_line>Refusal to renew license -- Revocation or suspension of license -- Administrative fine -- Appeal -- Criminal penalty. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the commissioner may refuse to renew or may suspend or revoke the license of a licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor or the certificate of a certificate holder to engage in the business of fire protection sprinkler systems or in lieu thereof establish an administrative fine not to exceed two thousand dollars ($2,000) for any of the following reasons: <section prefix="a">Gross incompetency or gross negligence in the installation, repair, alteration, maintenance, inspection, or addition to fire protection sprinkler systems, as determined by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="b">Conviction of a felony; </section><section prefix="c">Fraudulent or dishonest practices while engaging in the business of fire protection sprinkler systems; </section><section prefix="d">Use of false evidence or misrepresentation in an application for a license or certificate; </section><section prefix="e">Signing or affixing his or her seal to any plans, prints, specifications or reports, which have not been prepared by him or her personally or under his or her immediate supervision, or in violation of KRS 198B.585; </section><section prefix="f">Knowingly violating any provisions of KRS 198B.550 to 198B.630 or the regulations issued thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall revoke, subject to a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the license of a licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor or a certificate holder who engages in the fire protection sprinkler system business while his or her or its license is suspended. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who engages in the drawings, installation, repair, alteration, extension, maintenance, or inspection of fire protection sprinkler systems or uses any title, sign, card, or device indicating or intending to indicate that he or she is a certified fire sprinkler contractor without having first obtained the requisite license or certificate shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. Each violation shall be regarded as a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any license or certificate holder who is aggrieved by a final order of the commissioner suspending or revoking a license may appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court or the Circuit Court of the county of the license or certificate holder's place of business in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 284, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 87, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7038</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>