<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="422" order_by="422">EVIDENCE AND LOST RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>422.295</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of communications between human trafficking victim and caseworker. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Confidential communication" means information transmitted between the victim and the caseworker in the course of their relationship and in confidence by a means which, so far as the victim is aware, discloses the information to no third persons other than those who are present to further the interests of the victim in the consultation or those to whom disclosures are reasonably necessary for the transmission of the information or an accomplishment of the purposes for which the human trafficking counselor is consulted and includes all information regarding the facts and circumstances involving the trafficking; </section><section prefix="b">"Holder of the privilege" means the victim when he or she has no guardian or conservator, or a guardian or conservator of the victim when the victim has a guardian or conservator; and </section><section prefix="c">"Trafficking victim counselor" includes any of the following: <section prefix="1">A counselor, as that term is defined in Rule 506 of the Kentucky Rules of Evidence; </section><section prefix="2">A psychotherapist as that term is defined in Rule 507 of the Kentucky Rules of Evidence; and </section><section prefix="3">A person employed and supervised by one (1) of the persons specified in this paragraph to render services to human trafficking victims and who has received forty (40) hours of training in the history of human trafficking; civil and criminal law as it relates to human trafficking; societal attitudes towards human trafficking; peer counseling techniques; housing, public assistance, and other financial resources available to meet the financial needs of human trafficking victims; and referral services available to human trafficking victims. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A human trafficking victim has a privilege to refuse to disclose and to prevent any other person from disclosing confidential communications made to a trafficking victim counselor for the purpose of receiving counseling, therapy, services, information, or treatment related to human trafficking. </section><section prefix="3">A human trafficking caseworker shall inform a trafficking victim of any applicable limitations on confidentiality of communications between the victim and the caseworker. This information may be given orally. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>