<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.790</section_number><catch_line>District director of health -- Qualifications and authority -- Compensation -- Removal procedure. </catch_line><order_by>790</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall appoint a district director of health for the department as set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The district director of health may be a physician, qualified by training in public health, preventive medicine and public administration, and licensed or eligible for practice as a medical practitioner in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or may be a nonphysician with a master's degree in public health or related field and at least five (5) years' experience in a management capacity with a health department. The district director of health shall receive an annual salary as prescribed by the board, subject to the provisions of the department's merit system, and shall serve at the pleasure of the board. If the district director of health is removed by the board, he shall be notified in writing, and within fourteen (14) days may make a written request for a hearing. If no request is made, the removal shall become effective upon the expiration of fourteen (14) days. If a request for hearing is made, the hearing shall be held at the office of the department within fourteen (14) calendar days after the request is received by the board. The district director of health shall not be removed until after a hearing has been held, and a decision rendered by the board. The board decision shall be final. </section><section prefix="3">The district director of health shall serve as secretary to the board of health, the chief administrative officer of the department, and may employ and fix compensation of, by contract or otherwise, all employees necessary for the maintenance and operation of the department in accordance with the merit system as established by the board. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8682</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>