<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.619</section_number><catch_line>Medicaid plan amendment to permit establishing of Kentucky Long-Term Care Partnership Insurance Program. </catch_line><order_by>619</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By October 30, 2008, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall submit to the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Services an amendment to the State Medicaid Plan to permit the establishment of a Kentucky Long-Term Care Partnership Insurance Program that provides for the disregard of any assets or resources in an amount equal to the insurance benefit payments made to or on behalf of an individual who is a beneficiary of the partnership insurance program that meets the requirements of KRS 304.14-640 and 304.14-642. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the cabinet shall notify in writing the commissioner of the Department of Insurance and the co-chairs of the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare and the Interim Joint Committee on Banking and Insurance within two (2) business days of the submission of the plan amendment and of the receipt of the response by the federal agency. </section><section prefix="3">Upon approval by the federal government of the state plan amendment, the Department for Medicaid Services, in conjunction with the Department of Insurance, shall establish the Kentucky Long-Term Care Partnership Insurance Program in accordance with KRS 304.14-640 and 304.14-642. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall: <section prefix="a">Provide consultation, information, and materials to the Department of Insurance to assist in the development and issuance of uniform training materials in accordance with KRS 304.14-642(4); and </section><section prefix="b">Collaborate in the preparation of the report required in KRS 304.14-642(6). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 303, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  Pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938, the Reviser of Statutes has changed a reference to the "executive director" of insurance in subsection (2) of this section to the "commissioner" of insurance to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>