<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.050</section_number><catch_line>Privilege from arrest or civil suit -- Censure -- Fine or expulsion. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A member of the General Assembly, while going to, attending or returning from any session of the house to which he belongs shall not be arrested, menaced or disturbed at any place in the Commonwealth of Kentucky except on legal process for treason, felony, or breach or surety of the peace. </section><section prefix="2">It is declared to be the legislative intent of the General Assembly to prohibit the arrest of any member of the General Assembly at any place within the Commonwealth while going to, attending or returning from any session of the house to which he belongs, except for treason, felony, or breach or surety of the peace. </section><section prefix="3">A member of the General Assembly shall not be required to stand trial in any civil action except between terms of the legislature, and then only in the county of his residence; but either party to such an action may obtain a change of venue as in other cases. </section><section prefix="4">A member of either house, by a vote of two-thirds (2/3) of the members present, may be censured, fined, or expelled for breach of privilege. </section></text><history>Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92,sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1981. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=252</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>