<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.543</section_number><catch_line>Determination of service credit -- Picked-up employee contributions. </catch_line><order_by>543</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Employee contributions shall be deducted from the creditable compensation of each member of the retirement system in the active employment of the Department of Kentucky State Police of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet as an officer as defined in KRS 16.520. After August 1, 1982, employee contributions shall be picked up by the employer pursuant to KRS 16.545(4). Service credit shall be allowed for each month such member receives creditable compensation for an average of one hundred (100) hours or more of work per month. If the average number of hours of work is less than one hundred (100) per month, the member shall be allowed credit only for those months he or she receives creditable compensation for one hundred (100) hours of work. </section><section prefix="2">Contributions shall not be made and no service will be earned while on authorized leave except: <section prefix="a">A member shall be entitled to service credit in accordance with KRS 61.555; and </section><section prefix="b">A member on educational leave, approved by the Personnel Cabinet, who is receiving seventy-five percent (75%) or more of full salary, shall receive service credit and shall pay member contributions or such contributions shall be picked up in accordance with KRS 16.545 and his or her employer shall pay employer contributions in accordance with KRS 61.565. If a tuition agreement is broken by the member, the member and employer contributions paid or picked up during the period of educational leave shall be refunded. </section></section><section prefix="3">The retirement office, upon detection, shall refund any erroneous employer and employee contributions made to the retirement system and any interest credited in accordance with KRS 16.560. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 74, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 166, secs. 9 and 26, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 4. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(1). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>