<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.495</section_number><catch_line>Hours of work and annual leave for members of police department in urban-county governments and cities on DLG's registry of cities that belonged to the second and third classes on January 1, 2014.   </catch_line><order_by>495</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In cities listed on the registry pursuant to subsection (3) of this section or urban-county governments, except those in which, by ordinance, the patrolmen are employed or paid by the day, the members of the police department shall not be required to work more than eight (8) hours per day, for five (5) days each week or ten (10) hours per day, for four (4) days each week, except in the event of an emergency. Each member of the police department shall have an annual leave of fifteen (15) working days with full pay. Nothing in this section shall prohibit a member of the police department from voluntarily agreeing to work a different work schedule provided that the officer is paid overtime for any work performed in excess of forty (40) hours per week. </section><section prefix="2">The salary of the members of the police department shall not be reduced by reason of the enactment of this section. </section><section prefix="3">On or before January 1, 2015, the Department for Local Government shall create a registry of cities that shall comply with the provisions of this section. The Department for Local Government shall include each of those cities on the registry that were classified as cities of the second or third class on August 1, 2014. The Department for Local Government shall make the information included on the registry available to the public by publishing it on its Web site. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 117, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 117, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008.. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 12. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1-- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 1, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43702</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>