<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.101</section_number><catch_line>Declaration of legislative finding of fact. </catch_line><order_by>101</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds and declares the following: <section prefix="1">The highest priority and concern of the Commonwealth must be the health and safety of the coal industry's most valuable resource, the miner. </section><section prefix="2">The continued prosperity of the coal industry is of primary importance to the state. </section><section prefix="3">A high priority must be given to increasing the productivity and competitiveness of the mines in this state. </section><section prefix="4">An inordinate number of miners are killed or injured during the first few months of their experience in a mine and upon acquiring new work assignments in a mine. </section><section prefix="5">These injuries result in the loss of life and serious injury to miners and are an impediment to the future growth of the state's coal industry. </section><section prefix="6">Mining is a technical occupation with various specialties requiring individualized training and education. </section><section prefix="7">Injuries can be reduced through proper miner training, education, and certification. </section><section prefix="8">Mine safety can be improved by the imposition and enforcement of sanctions against licensed premises and certified and noncertified personnel whose willful and repeated violations of mine safety laws place miners in imminent danger of serious injury or death. </section><section prefix="9">Abuse of illicit substances and alcohol in the mining industry represents a serious threat to the health and safety of all miners. Substance and alcohol abuse adversely affect the health and safety of miners. Mine safety can be significantly improved by establishing as a condition of certification that miners remain drug and alcohol free. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 1, effective March 20, 2001. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32901</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>