<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.135</section_number><catch_line>Members or managers as agents. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, every member shall be an agent of the limited liability company for the purpose of its business or affairs, and the act of any member, including but not limited to the execution in the name of the limited liability company of any instrument, for apparently carrying on in the usual way the business or affairs of the limited liability company of which he is a member, shall bind the limited liability company, unless the member so acting has, in fact, no authority to act for the limited liability company in the particular matter, and the person with whom the member is dealing has knowledge or has received notification of the fact that the member has no such authority. </section><section prefix="2">If the articles of organization provide that management of the limited liability company is vested in a manager or managers: <section prefix="a">No member, solely by reason of being a member, shall be an agent of the limited liability company; and </section><section prefix="b">Every manager shall be an agent of the limited liability company for the purpose of its business or affairs, and the act of any manager, including, but not limited to, the execution in the name of the limited liability company of any instrument, for apparently carrying on in the usual way the business or affairs of the limited liability company of which he is the manager shall bind the limited liability company, unless the manager so acting has, in fact, no authority to act for the limited liability company in the particular matter, and the person with whom the manager is dealing has knowledge or has received notification of the fact that the manager has no such authority. </section></section><section prefix="3">An act of a manager or a member which is apparently not for the carrying on in the usual way of the business or affairs of the limited liability company shall not bind the limited liability company unless, at the time of the transaction or at any other time, the act is authorized in accordance with the operating agreement. </section><section prefix="4">An act of a manager or member in contravention of a restriction on authority shall not bind the limited liability company to persons having knowledge of the restriction. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 107, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 107, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13855</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>