<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.960</section_number><catch_line>Preparation of fiscal note for bill introduced in General Assembly or executive order. </catch_line><order_by>960</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director of the Legislative Research Commission shall have the fiscal note prepared by the Legislative Research Commission or by other departments or agencies of state government for any bill introduced before the General Assembly which relates to any aspect of local government or any service provided thereby. Departments or agencies of state government so requested by the director shall comply with the request within seven (7) working days of receipt. The fiscal note shall be filed with the clerk in the chamber of the General Assembly in which the bill was introduced and attached to each copy of the bill. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of finance shall have the fiscal note prepared by the Finance and Administration Cabinet or by other departments or agencies of state government for any order promulgated by an executive department or agency which relates to any aspect of local government or any service provided thereby. The director of the Legislative Research Commission shall determine the form of such notes. The secretary may request the advice or assistance of the Legislative Research Commission in the preparation of the fiscal note. The fiscal note shall be attached to each copy of the order. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>