<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="26" order_by="26">A COURT OF JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>26A.115</section_number><catch_line>Operating costs allowance and use allowance payments. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each unit of government providing space in a court facility to the Court of Justice under the provisions of KRS 26A.100 shall be paid an operating costs allowance plus a use allowance to be administered by the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section><section prefix="2">The precise amount paid for operating costs allowance and use allowance shall be computed by allocating to the Court of Justice its proportionate share of each category according to the relative portion of the floor space in the facility which is occupied by the Court of Justice. Compensation shall be calculated on an annualized basis, may be in the form of rental per square footage, and shall be paid quarterly. Should the availability of space provided to the Court of Justice be limited by the governmental unit to a part-time basis, the compensation shall be apportioned according to the number of days or partial days per week in which it is made available, one (1) day or partial day per week being considered as one-fifth (0.2) of the time. </section><section prefix="3">If requested by a unit of government, operating costs allowance and use allowance payments due in accordance with subsection (2) of this section shall be due and payable to the unit of government not less than ten (10) days prior to the interest due date for the bonds, notes, or other debt obligations issued to finance the capital costs for court facility space provided to the Court of Justice by the requesting unit of government. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449, sec. 4, effective June 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 336, effective July 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>