<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.13-011</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>13-011</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">A "market" is the interaction between buyers and sellers consisting of a product market component and a geographic market component. A product market component consists of identical or readily substitutable products including but not limited to consideration of coverage, policy terms, rate classifications, and underwriting. A geographic market component is a geographical area in which buyers have a reasonable degree of access to insurance sales outlets. Determination of a geographic market component shall consider existing market patterns; </section><section prefix="2">"Supplementary rating information" includes any manual or plan of rates, classification, rating schedule, minimum premium, policy fees, rating rules, or any other similar information needed to determine the applicable rate or premium. This shall include underwriting rules, but only to the extent necessary to determine the rate or premium that will be applicable to a risk should the insurer decide to provide coverage. This does not include guidelines that relate to the selection of those risks that are acceptable to an insurer; </section><section prefix="3">"Supporting information" is the experience and judgment of the filer and the experience or data of other insurers or organizations relied on by the filer, the interpretation of any other data relied on by the filer, descriptions of methods used in making the rates, and any other information required to be filed by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="4">"Personal risks" means homeowners, tenants, private passenger nonfleet automobiles, mobile homes, and other property and casualty insurance for personal, family, or household needs; </section><section prefix="5">"Commercial risks" are any kinds of risks that are not personal risks; </section><section prefix="6">"Joint underwriting" is a voluntary arrangement established to provide insurance coverage for a risk pursuant to which two (2) or more insurers jointly contract with the insured at a price and under policy terms agreed on between the insurers; </section><section prefix="7">A "pool" is a voluntary arrangement, other than by a contract of reinsurance, established on a general and continuing basis pursuant to which two (2) or more insurers participate in the sharing of risks on a predetermined basis. A pool may operate through an association, syndicate or other pooling agreement; </section><section prefix="8">A "residual market mechanism" is an agreement, either voluntary or mandated by law, involving participation by insurers in the equitable apportionment among them of insurance that may be afforded applicants who are unable to obtain insurance through ordinary methods; </section><section prefix="9">An "advisory organization" is any entity, including its affiliates or subsidiaries, which either has two (2) or more member insurers or is controlled either directly or indirectly by two (2) or more insurers and which assists insurers in ratemaking related activities. Two (2) or more insurers having a common ownership or operating in this state under common management or control constitute a single insurer for purposes of this definition; </section><section prefix="10">A "competitive market" is a market that has not been found to be noncompetitive pursuant to KRS 304.13-041 and for which no such order is in effect; </section><section prefix="11">A "noncompetitive market" is a market for which there is an order in effect pursuant to KRS 304.13-041 that a reasonable degree of competition does not exist; </section><section prefix="12">"Trending" is any procedure for projecting developed losses to the average date of loss, or premiums or exposures to the average date of writing, for the period during which the policies are to be effective; </section><section prefix="13">"Expenses" are those portions of any rate attributable to acquisition, field supervision, and collection expenses, general expenses, and premium taxes, licenses, and fees; </section><section prefix="14">"Profit" is the portion of any rate attributable to funds needed for growth, contingencies, and return to stockholders; </section><section prefix="15">"Pure premium" means the loss cost per unit of exposure excluding all loss adjustment expenses; </section><section prefix="16">"Classification system" or "classification" means the process of grouping risks with similar risk characteristics so that differences in cost may be recognized; </section><section prefix="17">"Developed losses" means losses (including loss adjustment expenses) adjusted, using standard actuarial techniques, to their ultimate anticipated value; </section><section prefix="18">"Experience rating" means a rating procedure utilizing past insurance experience of the individual policyholder to forecast future losses by measuring the policyholder’s loss experience against the loss experience of policyholders in the same classification to produce a prospective premium credit, debit, or unity modification; </section><section prefix="19">"Form provider" means a person who prepares, files, and distributes policy contract forms and endorsements and consults with members, subscribers, customers, or others relative to their use and application, but is not an advisory organization as defined in this subtitle; </section><section prefix="20">"Loss adjustment expenses" means the expenses incurred by the insurer in the course of settling claims; </section><section prefix="21">"Prospective loss costs" means that portion of a rate that does not include provisions for expenses (other than loss adjustment expenses) or profit, and are based on historical aggregate losses or output from simulation models and loss adjustment expenses adjusted through development to their ultimate value and projected through trending to a future point in time. Loss costs, derived in part or entirely upon output form simulation models, must be approved by the commissioner before they become effective; </section><section prefix="22">"Rate" means the expected value of the future cost of insurance per exposure unit which accounts for the treatment of losses, expenses, and profit prior to any application of individual risk variations based on loss or expense considerations, but does not include minimum premium; </section><section prefix="23">"Special assessments" means guaranty fund assessments, residual market mechanism assessments, and other similar assessments which are included in ratemaking. Special assessments shall not be considered as either expenses or losses. Additional charges collected by the insurer and returned to a governmental agency on behalf of an insured are not special assessments. Examples of these additional charges include, but are not limited to, the special fund charge for workers’ compensation imposed by KRS Chapter 342, local government premium tax imposed by KRS 91A.080, and the Department of Revenue surcharge imposed by KRS Chapter 136; and </section><section prefix="24">"Statistical agent" means an entity that has been licensed by the commissioner to collect statistics from insurers and provide reports developed from these statistics to the commissioner for the purpose of fulfilling the statistical reporting obligations of those insurers under this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1114, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 679, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>