<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.070</section_number><catch_line>Dependency, neglect, or abuse action -- Contents of summons. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dependency, neglect, or abuse action may be commenced by the filing of a petition by any interested person in the juvenile session of the District Court. </section><section prefix="2">After a petition has been filed, the clerk of the court shall issue, and the sheriff or other authorized agent shall serve, a copy of the petition and a summons to the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision, unless their identity or location is unknown, in which case the petition and summons shall be served on the nearest known adult relative. </section><section prefix="3">The summons shall include an explanation of the importance of the petition and an explanation of the rights of the parent or other person exercising custodial control in any subsequent proceedings. The summons shall emphasize the importance of immediately contacting the court about legal representation and to be advised of the date, time, and place when the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision is to appear before the court. The summons shall include written notification that the case may be reviewed by a local citizen foster care review board and the report of the board review shall become part of the court record. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 412, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 47, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 68, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20193</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>