<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.400</section_number><catch_line>School subjects' adoption groups -- Textbook contracts and purchases. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief state school officer shall arrange the elementary, middle, and high school subjects included in the state courses of study as prescribed by the Kentucky Board of Education into six (6) adoption groups. </section><section prefix="2">Contracts for each of the six (6) adoption groups shall be for a period of six (6) years and shall be executed on a staggered basis, with one (1) group being up for adoption each year. The six (6) adoption groups shall be arranged by similarity of content to the extent possible, while being arranged as nearly equal in number and purchase cost as possible. Subjects with rapidly changing or highly technical content may be considered more frequently than once during a six (6) year cycle. </section><section prefix="3">The chief state school officer may delay the purchase of books due to insufficient funds, but any purchases of books shall be in accordance with this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 145, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3176</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>