<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.612</section_number><catch_line>Assistance in establishing Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority. </catch_line><order_by>612</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any 2020 water management planning council located in a given HUC 10 watershed or portion of a given HUC 10 watershed may contact the water service coordinator in the area development district that serves the council and request assistance with the establishment of a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority. </section><section prefix="2">If there is a request by a 2020 water management planning council to develop a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority for a HUC 10 watershed, and if that watershed extends through more than one (1) area development district, the water service coordinator shall contact the water service coordinators of the affected area development districts and inform them of the request to form a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority. </section><section prefix="3">The water service coordinators shall request the 2020 water management planning councils submit their list of nominees for the Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority, and the water service coordinator shall forward those lists to the Governor for appointment in accordance with KRS 151.613. </section><section prefix="4">Any 2020 water management council located in the watershed may elect at any time not to participate in a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority by indicating the election in a resolution. However, that election shall not limit the right of any other 2020 water management council to establish a Stream Restoration and Mitigation Authority for that watershed. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2139</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>