<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.080</section_number><catch_line>Persons prohibited from operating ambulance service or first response program -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person as defined in KRS 446.010 who is not licensed to do so, or whose license to do so has been suspended, revoked, or denied, shall operate an ambulance service or advanced life support emergency medical first response program. </section><section prefix="2">Any person as defined in KRS 446.010 who violates subsection (1) of this section is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall not preclude the board from revoking or increasing the suspension period of a person operating an ambulance service or advanced life support first response program which has illegally operated while its license is under suspension or has been revoked. </section><section prefix="4">The filing of criminal charges or a criminal conviction for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the board from instituting or imposing board disciplinary action authorized by this chapter against any person or organization violating this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="5">The institution or imposition of disciplinary action by the board against any person or organization violating the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the filing of criminal charges against or a criminal conviction of any person or organization for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30732</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>