<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.352</section_number><catch_line>Motorcycle rider training courses -- Exemption from motorcycle driver's license skill test. </catch_line><order_by>352</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The motorcycle safety education program shall offer motorcycle rider training courses designed to develop and instill the knowledge, attitudes, habits, and skills necessary for the proper operation of a motorcycle. The courses shall be taught by instructors approved under KRS 15A.354 and shall include no fewer than eight (8) hours of hands-on instruction for a novice course. </section><section prefix="2">Rider training courses shall be open to any resident of the state who is eligible for a motor vehicle instruction permit. </section><section prefix="3">Rider training courses shall be provided free of charge to applicants under eighteen (18) years of age. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall issue certificates of completion in a manner and form prescribed by administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to persons who satisfactorily complete the requirements of a motorcycle rider training course offered or authorized by the state program. </section><section prefix="5">The Transportation Cabinet may exempt applicants for a motorcycle driver's license or endorsement from the licensing skill test if they present satisfactory evidence of successful completion of an approved rider training course that includes a similar test of skill. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>