<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Administrator" means the person or the designee of the person, in charge of the operation of an alcohol and other drug abuse prevention, intervention, or treatment program; </section><section prefix="2">"Agency" means a legal entity operating hospital-based or nonhospital-based alcohol and other drug abuse prevention, intervention, or treatment programs; </section><section prefix="3">"Alcohol and other drug abuse" means a dysfunctional use of alcohol or other drugs or both, characterized by one (1) or more of the following patterns of use: <section prefix="a">The continued use despite knowledge of having a persistent or recurrent social, legal, occupational, psychological, or physical problem that is caused or exacerbated by use of alcohol or other drugs or both; </section><section prefix="b">Use in situations which are potentially physically hazardous; </section><section prefix="c">Loss of control over the use of alcohol or other drugs or both; and </section><section prefix="d">Use of alcohol or other drugs or both is accompanied by symptoms of physiological dependence, including pronounced withdrawal syndrome and tolerance of body tissues to alcohol or other drugs or both; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="5">"Director" means the director of the Division of Behavioral Health of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="6">"Hospital" means an establishment with organized medical staff and permanent facilities with inpatient beds which provide medical services, including physician services and continuous nursing services for the diagnosis and treatment of patients who have a variety of medical conditions, both surgical and nonsurgical; </section><section prefix="7">"Intoxication" means being under the influence of alcohol or other drugs, or both, which significantly impairs a person's ability to function; </section><section prefix="8">"Juvenile" means any person who is under the age of eighteen (18); </section><section prefix="9">"Narcotic treatment program" means a substance abuse program using approved controlled substances and offering a range of treatment procedures and services for the rehabilitation of persons dependent on opium, morphine, heroin, or any derivative or synthetic drug of that group; </section><section prefix="10">"Other drugs" means controlled substances as defined in KRS Chapter 218A and volatile substances as defined in KRS 217.900; </section><section prefix="11">"Patient" means any person admitted to a hospital or a licensed alcohol and other drug abuse treatment program; </section><section prefix="12">"Program" means a set of services rendered directly to the public that is organized around a common goal of either preventing, intervening, or treating alcohol and other drug abuse problems; </section><section prefix="13">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="14">"Treatment" means services and programs for the care and rehabilitation of intoxicated persons and persons suffering from alcohol and other drug abuse. "Treatment" includes those services provided by the cabinet in KRS 222.211 and, in KRS 222.430 to 222.437, it specifically includes the services described in KRS 222.211(1)(c) and (d); and </section><section prefix="15">"Qualified health professional" has the same meaning as qualified mental health professional in KRS 202A.011, except that it also includes an alcohol and drug counselor licensed or certified under KRS Chapter 309. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 19, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 109, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 67, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 558, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 11, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 498, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44307</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>