<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-430</section_number><catch_line>Payment of expenses of department from general fund -- Reimbursement. </catch_line><order_by>2-430</order_by><text>Nothing in KRS 304.2-400 to 304.2-420 shall prevent continuing the practice of paying any of the direct or indirect expenses incurred by the department, including, but not limited to, those involving salaries, retirement, and Social Security of officers, employees, or representatives of the department, or any other expenses by appropriations from the general fund. However, the general fund shall be reimbursed for any such payments made on or after July 15, 1986, as well as any money transferred to the insurance regulatory trust fund in connection with the initial funding of the insurance regulatory trust fund, and shall be repaid by transfer from the insurance regulatory trust fund to the general fund no later than the end of the next biennium. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 956, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 492, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note>(7/14/2000).  2000 Ky. Acts ch. 492, sec. 1 states that it is amending this statute. The entire change to the statute proposed in the introduced version of House Bill 709 was eliminated, however, by House Committee Amendment 1, which passed the House of Representatives, but the section amending the statute was mistakenly not deleted from the bill. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16694</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>