<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.235</section_number><catch_line>License or permit required -- To be carried on person -- Nonresidents -- Effect of revocation or suspension of license or permit. </catch_line><order_by>235</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall perform any act authorized to be performed by any of the various licenses or permits provided for in this chapter without first procuring the type of license which authorizes the performance of the act and unless at the time of the performance of the act he has the license on his person, except that in the case of a fur processor it shall be sufficient if the license is posted in a conspicuous place upon the licensed premises. </section><section prefix="2">Wherever in this chapter reference is made to the "holder" of a license, or permit, it means the person in whose name the license or permit was issued. No person to whom a license or permit has been issued under this chapter may authorize or permit any other person to carry his license or permit. No person shall present the license of another person for inspection. </section><section prefix="3">No nonresident shall perform any act under this chapter without first procuring the proper nonresident license or permit. </section><section prefix="4">No person who has had his privilege to perform an act authorized under this chapter revoked or suspended shall possess the kind of license or permit that would otherwise permit the act for the period of the suspension. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 11. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 33. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 6. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1983</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>