<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.2970</section_number><catch_line>Auditory screening of infants at hospitals and birthing centers -- Forwarding of reports. </catch_line><order_by>2970</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As a condition of licensure or relicensure, all hospitals offering obstetric services and alternative birthing centers with at least forty (40) births per year shall provide an auditory screening for all infants using one (1) of the methods approved by the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">An auditory screening report that indicates a finding of potential hearing loss shall be forwarded by the hospital or alternative birthing center within twenty-four (24) hours of receipt to the: <section prefix="a">Attending physician or health care provider; </section><section prefix="b">Parents; </section><section prefix="c">Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs for evaluation or referral for further evaluation in accordance with KRS 211.647; and </section><section prefix="d">Audiological assessment and diagnostic center approved by the commission if a follow-up assessment has been scheduled prior to the infant's discharge from the hospital. </section></section><section prefix="3">An auditory screening report that does not indicate a potential hearing loss shall be forwarded within one (1) week to the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs with no information that personally identifies the child. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9002</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>