<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.570</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Heritage Land Conservation fund.   </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established in the State Treasury a fund entitled "Kentucky Heritage Land Conservation fund." The fund shall primarily receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and tax receipts. The fund shall be disbursed by the State Treasurer upon the warrant of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. Moneys in the fund not expended at the end of a fiscal year shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year, and the fund shall not lapse. Moneys in the fund shall be invested in accordance with administrative regulations developed by the State Investment Commission in accordance with KRS 42.525. Interest earnings shall accrue to the fund. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall be attached for administrative, budgeting, and capital planning and reporting purposes to the Energy and Environment Cabinet. Land acquisitions shall be authorized by the General Assembly and reported to the Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee in accordance with KRS 45.750 to 45.800. Allocation of moneys as approved by the board for management of the lands shall be appropriated to each separate agency as part of its operating budget. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the fund shall be used exclusively for the purposes of acquisition and management of lands as defined in KRS 146.560. Each recipient of moneys shall develop and implement a resource management plan for each tract acquired, except a resource management plan for properties adjacent to a state park shall be developed and managed by the Department of Parks, and shall allocate at least ten percent (10%) of moneys received for management of lands acquired. Lands acquired shall be maintained in perpetuity for the purposes set out in KRS 146.560. </section><section prefix="4">Moneys in the fund shall be allocated as follows: <section prefix="a">The Department of Parks shall receive ten percent (10%); </section><section prefix="b">The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources shall receive ten percent (10%); </section><section prefix="c">The Energy and Environment Cabinet, Division of Forestry, shall receive ten percent (10%); </section><section prefix="d">Ten percent (10%) shall be allocated for wild rivers corridors established by the Kentucky Wild Rivers Act, KRS 146.200 to 146.360, and any administrative regulations promulgated pursuant thereto; </section><section prefix="e">The Nature Preserves Commission shall receive ten percent (10%); and </section><section prefix="f">The board shall receive the remaining fifty percent (50%), for allocation to private, nonprofit land trust organizations, state agencies, local governments, and state colleges and universities. Any funds expended under this paragraph to private, nonprofit land trust organizations shall be matched dollar-for-dollar as required in KRS 146.560(2). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 135, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 446, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42231</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>