<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.440</section_number><catch_line>Records of certificate holders. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person certified under KRS 223.425, shall keep a record of each well constructed, altered or sealed after July 13, 1984, and shall furnish a signed copy of such record to the cabinet within thirty (30) days after the completion of the construction or alteration. A copy of the record shall be furnished to the property owner by the driller within thirty (30) days of completion of the well. Each record required under this section shall be in a form prescribed by the cabinet and shall show: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the owner of the well and the persons constructing or altering the well; </section><section prefix="b">A sketch showing the distance from any road, intersection, septic tank drain fields and permanent structures; </section><section prefix="c">The dates of commencement and completion of the construction or alteration of the well; </section><section prefix="d">The depth, diameter, and type of casing; </section><section prefix="e">The kind of joint couplings; </section><section prefix="f">Information on screens and type of completion; </section><section prefix="g">The discharge in gallons per minute and the shut-in pressure in pounds per square inch of a flowing well; </section><section prefix="h">The static water level with reference to the land surface and estimation of well yield, and the drawdown with respect to the amount of water yielded per minute; </section><section prefix="i">The kind, nature, approximate thickness and water-bearing capacity of the material in each stratum penetrated that shows the presence of water, with at least one (1) entry for each change in rock types; and </section><section prefix="j">The type and amount of disinfectant used and the date of disinfection. </section></section><section prefix="2">Where the well is for potable use the well driller shall be responsible for having the well tested for fecal coliform and the initial disinfection of the well. The driller shall provide the well owner and the cabinet with the written results of any and all testing and a written assurance that the well has been properly disinfected, within thirty (30) days of well completion. </section><section prefix="3">A copy of the record shall be furnished by the cabinet to the Kentucky Geological Survey. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9981</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>