<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.111</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Administrative official" means any department, employee, or advisory, elected, or appointed body which is authorized to administer any provision of the zoning regulation, subdivision regulations, and, if delegated, any provision of any housing or building regulation or any other land use control regulation; </section><section prefix="2">"Agricultural use" means the use of: <section prefix="a">A tract of at least five (5) contiguous acres for the production of agricultural or horticultural crops, including but not limited to livestock, livestock products, poultry, poultry products, grain, hay, pastures, soybeans, tobacco, timber, orchard fruits, vegetables, flowers, or ornamental plants, including provision for dwellings for persons and their families who are engaged in the agricultural use on the tract, but not including residential building development for sale or lease to the public; </section><section prefix="b">Regardless of the size of the tract of land used, small farm wineries licensed under KRS 243.155; </section><section prefix="c">A tract of at least five (5) contiguous acres used for the following activities involving horses: <section prefix="1">Riding lessons; </section><section prefix="2">Rides; </section><section prefix="3">Training; </section><section prefix="4">Projects for educational purposes; </section><section prefix="5">Boarding and related care; or </section><section prefix="6">Shows, competitions, sporting events, and similar activities that are associated with youth and amateur programs, none of which are regulated by KRS Chapter 230, involving seventy (70) or less participants. Shows, competitions, sporting events, and similar activities that are associated with youth and amateur programs, none of which are regulated by KRS Chapter 230, involving more than seventy (70) participants shall be subject to local applicable zoning regulations; or </section></section><section prefix="d">A tract of land used for the following activities involving horses: <section prefix="1">Riding lessons; </section><section prefix="2">Rides; </section><section prefix="3">Training; </section><section prefix="4">Projects for educational purposes; </section><section prefix="5">Boarding and related care; or </section><section prefix="6">Shows, competitions, sporting events, and similar activities that are associated with youth and amateur programs, none of which are regulated by KRS Chapter 230, involving seventy (70) or less participants. Shows, competitions, sporting events, and similar activities that are associated with youth and amateur programs, none of which are regulated by KRS Chapter 230, involving more than seventy (70) participants shall be subject to local applicable zoning regulations. </section></section> This paragraph shall only apply to acreage that was being used for these activities before July 13, 2004; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the board of adjustment unless the context indicates otherwise; </section><section prefix="4">"Citizen member" means any member of the planning commission or board of adjustment who is not an elected or appointed official or employee of the city, county, or consolidated local government; </section><section prefix="5">"Commission" means planning commission; </section><section prefix="6">"Conditional use" means a use which is essential to or would promote the public health, safety, or welfare in one (1) or more zones, but which would impair the integrity and character of the zone in which it is located, or in adjoining zones, unless restrictions on location, size, extent, and character of performance are imposed in addition to those imposed in the zoning regulation; </section><section prefix="7">"Conditional use permit" means legal authorization to undertake a conditional use, issued by the administrative official pursuant to authorization by the board of adjustment, consisting of two (2) parts: <section prefix="a">A statement of the factual determination by the board of adjustment which justifies the issuance of the permit; and </section><section prefix="b">A statement of the specific conditions which must be met in order for the use to be permitted; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Development plan" means written and graphic material for the provision of a development, including any or all of the following: location and bulk of buildings and other structures, intensity of use, density of development, streets, ways, parking facilities, signs, drainage of surface water, access points, a plan for screening or buffering, utilities, existing manmade and natural conditions, and all other conditions agreed to by the applicant; </section><section prefix="9">"Fiscal court" means the chief body of the county with legislative power, whether it is the fiscal court, county commissioners, or otherwise; </section><section prefix="10">"Housing or building regulation" means the Kentucky Building Code, the Kentucky Plumbing Code, and any other building or structural code promulgated by the Commonwealth or by its political subdivisions; </section><section prefix="11">"Legislative body" means the chief body of the city, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, or unified local government with legislative power, whether it is the board of aldermen, the general council, the common council, the city council, the board of commissioners, or otherwise; at times it also implies the county's fiscal court; </section><section prefix="12">"Mayor" means the chief elected official of the city, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, or unified local government, whether the official designation of his office is mayor or otherwise; </section><section prefix="13">"Nonconforming use or structure" means an activity or a building, sign, structure, or a portion thereof which lawfully existed before the adoption or amendment of the zoning regulation, but which does not conform to all of the regulations contained in the zoning regulation which pertain to the zone in which it is located; </section><section prefix="14">"Planning operations" means the formulating of plans for the physical development and social and economic well-being of a planning unit, and the formulating of proposals for means of implementing the plans; </section><section prefix="15">"Planning unit" means any city, county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, or unified local government, or any combination of cities, counties, or parts of counties, or parts of consolidated local governments engaged in planning operations; </section><section prefix="16">"Plat" means the map of a subdivision; </section><section prefix="17">"Political subdivision" means any city, county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, or unified local government; </section><section prefix="18">"Several" means two (2) or more; </section><section prefix="19">"Public facility" means any use of land whether publicly or privately owned for transportation, utilities, or communications, or for the benefit of the general public, including but not limited to libraries, streets, schools, fire or police stations, county buildings, municipal buildings, recreational centers including parks, and cemeteries; </section><section prefix="20">"Street" means any vehicular way; </section><section prefix="21">"Structure" means anything constructed or made, the use of which requires permanent location in or on the ground or attachment to something having a permanent location in or on the ground, including buildings and signs; </section><section prefix="22">"Subdivision" means the division of a parcel of land into three (3) or more lots or parcels except in a county containing a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census or in an urban-county government or consolidated local government where a subdivision means the division of a parcel of land into two (2) or more lots or parcels; for the purpose, whether immediate or future, of sale, lease, or building development, or if a new street is involved, any division of a parcel of land; provided that a division of land for agricultural use and not involving a new street shall not be deemed a subdivision. The term includes resubdivision and when appropriate to the context, shall relate to the process of subdivision or to the land subdivided; any division or redivision of land into parcels of less than one (1) acre occurring within twelve (12) months following a division of the same land shall be deemed a subdivision within the meaning of this section; </section><section prefix="23">"Unit" means planning unit; and </section><section prefix="24">"Variance" means a departure from dimensional terms of the zoning regulation pertaining to the height, width, length, or location of structures, and the size of yards and open spaces where such departure meets the requirements of KRS 100.241 to 100.247. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 190, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 133, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 358, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 141, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43775</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>