<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.115</section_number><catch_line>Prequalification of suppliers. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text>The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet may provide for prequalification of suppliers as responsible prospective contractors for particular types of supplies, services, and construction. The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall not prequalify a supplier as a responsible prospective contractor until the supplier provides the secretary with his sworn statement made under penalty of perjury that he has not knowingly violated any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth and that the award of a contract to the supplier will not violate any provision of the campaign finance laws of the Commonwealth. "Knowingly" means, with respect to conduct or to a circumstance described by a statute defining an offense, that a person is aware or should have been aware that his conduct is of that nature or that the circumstance exists. Solicitation lists of potential contractors of such supplies, services, and construction shall include but shall not be limited to such prequalified suppliers. Prequalification shall not foreclose a written determination: <section prefix="1">Between the time of the bid opening or receipt of offers and the making of an award, that a prequalified supplier is not responsible; or </section><section prefix="2">That a supplier who is not prequalified at the time of bid opening or receipt of offers is responsible. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 18, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 24, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22349</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>