<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.215</section_number><catch_line>Department to purchase textbooks for use by nonpublic school pupils in grades one through twelve. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Libraries and Archives shall purchase textbooks from publishers whose books have been adopted by the state textbook commission for distribution without cost to pupils attending grade one (1) through grade twelve (12) of the state's nonpublic schools which have been accredited by the State Department of Education. </section><section prefix="2">The chief school administrator of each eligible school may file a requisition with the state librarian for the books needed for the next ensuing school term. Textbooks eligible for distribution by grade level or subject shall conform to the schedule in use by the Kentucky Board of Education for distribution to the public schools. </section><section prefix="3">The state librarian shall develop rules and regulations governing the purchase, requisition, distribution, assignment to students, care, use and return of textbooks, and a plan for permanently labeling the textbooks as the property of the Department for Libraries and Archives. The rules and regulations shall provide for the allocation of textbooks in a manner reflecting, and not to exceed the expressly limited appropriation to fund the allocation. The rules and regulations shall be developed in consultation with the Department of Education and shall conform, within statutory limits, to the rules and regulations already established by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section><section prefix="4">All textbooks purchased under the provisions of this section are the property of the state. Each school administrator obtaining books through the Department for Libraries and Archives is custodian of the books in his school. He shall issue the books to the students according to the rules and regulations formulated by the state librarian. </section><section prefix="5">Funds appropriated by the General Assembly to the Department for Libraries and Archives for this purpose shall not be expended for any textbooks which present a particular religious philosophy and shall not be considered as or commingled with common school funds and shall be allocated each year to the nonpublic school students as provided by rule and regulation of the Department for Libraries and Archives to the extent allowed by the appropriation provided in Acts 1978, ch. 139, sec. 2. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>