<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.060</section_number><catch_line>Horticultural research. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The experiment station through the Princeton and Quicksand substations shall: <section prefix="1">Discover and demonstrate the best known methods for the culture, packing and marketing of fruits; </section><section prefix="2">Discover and demonstrate the most effective methods for the prevention and control of diseases and insects affecting fruit crops; </section><section prefix="3">Make or cause to be made studies of the various types of pruning and cultural practices, and a thorough testing of the most promising new and approved varieties of fruits and plants; </section><section prefix="4">Obtain and disseminate scientific and practical findings relating to the subjects mentioned in subsections (1), (2) and (3); </section><section prefix="5">Arrange and promote meetings by which growers of fruits may exchange ideas and receive information relating to improved methods of growing, packing and marketing of fruits, and obtain and provide for outstanding specialists to attend and address such meetings; </section><section prefix="6">Provide for the publication and distribution of bulletins giving the results of scientific and practical studies, of market information, and of such other facts and experiences as may be helpful to producers; </section><section prefix="7">Provide for displaying fruit exhibits for the purpose of advertising the fruit production of the state, when such displays will promote the best interests of development of fruit production in the state; and </section><section prefix="8">Carry on such other investigations and studies as will assist the horticultural interests of the state. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4636m-2. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>