<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.550</section_number><catch_line>Required monthly return. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before the twentieth day of the month following each calendar month, a return for the preceding month shall be filed with the department in a form the department may prescribe. </section><section prefix="2">For purposes of the sales tax, a return shall be filed by every retailer or seller. For purposes of the use tax, a return shall be filed by every retailer engaged in business in the state and by every person purchasing tangible personal property or digital property, the storage, use or other consumption of which is subject to the use tax, who has not paid the use tax due to a retailer required to collect the tax. If a retailer's responsibilities have been assumed by a certified service provider as defined by KRS 139.795, the certified service provider shall file the return. </section><section prefix="3">Returns shall be signed by the person required to file the return or by a duly authorized agent but need not be verified by oath. </section><section prefix="4">Persons not regularly engaged in selling at retail and not having a permanent place of business, but who are temporarily engaged in selling from trucks, portable roadside stands, concessionaires at fairs, circuses, carnivals, and the like, shall report and remit the tax on a nonpermit basis, under rules as the department shall provide for the efficient collection of the sales tax on sales. </section><section prefix="5">The return shall show the amount of the taxes for the period covered by the return and other information the department deems necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 20, effective July 1, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 430, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 26, effective July 1, 2004. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 51, effective February 5, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>