<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.170</section_number><catch_line>Office and meetings of the board -- Records -- Reports -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall furnish its secretary with the necessary office room, furniture, fixtures, stationery, maps, plats, typewriter, and postage. The board shall meet as often as necessary for the proper discharge of duties at whatever places these duties require within the county in which any part of the district lies. The board shall keep complete records of its proceedings, which shall be at all times open to the inspection of the public. </section><section prefix="2">The treasurer of the board shall, by May 1 of each year, make a complete and itemized report of its accounts and doings during the previous year, showing the amount of money received and from what source and the amount paid out and for what purposes. This report shall be spread upon the records and open for public inspection, and shall be submitted to the Department for Local Government as required by KRS 65A.020. </section><section prefix="3">All expenses incurred by the board shall be taken out of drainage funds and not from any general funds of the county. The commissioners shall be paid not more than three dollars ($3) per day while actually engaged in the performance of their duties as well as all traveling expenses incurred in attending any meeting of the board or in the performance of their duties, to be paid out of the funds of the district. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 78, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 191. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 189, secs. 1, 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380b-12. </history><metadata><effective>March 21, 2013</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41758</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>