<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.7531</section_number><catch_line>Clearing of foreign protective orders from Law Information Networkof Kentucky.  </catch_line><order_by>7531</order_by><text>(1)A foreign protective order which has been entered into the Law InformationNetwork of Kentucky shall be immediately cleared as an active record from thecomputer system when:(a)The order expires according to its terms;(b)A Kentucky court notifies the Law Information Network of Kentucky that aforeign protective order has been dismissed, either by court order or entryof notification by a circuit clerk; or(c)A circuit clerk notifies the Law Information Network of Kentucky that aforeign protective order tendered to the clerk has not been authenticatedin the time period specified in KRS 403.7527.(2)For validation purposes, the Law Information Network of Kentucky shallprovide the circuit court clerk with a printout of foreign protective orders. Theclerk shall validate each order annually by contacting the original issuing courtor jurisdiction. If the clerk has not received information from the foreignjurisdiction within thirty-one (31) days, the clerk shall cause those orders to becleared from the Law Information Network of Kentucky.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 14, effective January1, 2016. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2016). In codification, the Reviser ofStatutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in subsection(1)(c) of this statute by changing a reference to the time period for authenticationof foreign protective orders to read "time period specified in KRS 403.7527," thesection which contains the deadlines for authentication of foreign protectiveorders. The error was corrected under the authority of KRS 7.136(1).</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44762</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>