<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-320</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of filing for employer-organized association -- Effect -- Revocation. </catch_line><order_by>17A-320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No employer-organized association shall in this state self-insure in order to provide health benefit plans for its members unless it holds a certificate of filing from the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">To qualify for a certificate of filing and to maintain a certificate of filing, the employer-organized association shall comply with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-800 to 304.17A-844 to the extent not in conflict with the expressed provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Each association that holds a certificate of filing from the commissioner shall be subject to the following: <section prefix="a">All assessments placed on insurers under KRS 304.17B-021; </section><section prefix="b">All rating restrictions placed on employer-organized associations under KRS 304.17A-0954; </section><section prefix="c">All rate review requirements placed on insurers under this subtitle; </section><section prefix="d">All data collection requirements placed on insurers under this subtitle; and </section><section prefix="e">Provisions of Subtitle 12 of this chapter that apply to health insurers. </section></section><section prefix="4">Each association that holds a certificate of filing from the commissioner shall notify its members that health benefit plans issued to its members through the association are not protected through the Kentucky Life and Health Insurance Guaranty Association. </section><section prefix="5">Under the provisions of KRS 304.17A-840, the commissioner may revoke the certificate of filing of any association. A violation of any provision of this section shall be deemed a violation of KRS 304.17A-800 to 304.17A-844 for purposes of KRS 304.17A-840. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1224, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 24, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 23, effective January 1, 2001. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 40, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17413</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>