<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.720</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for teachers' tenure law. </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The term "teacher" for the purpose of KRS 161.730 to 161.810 shall mean any person for whom certification is required as a basis of employment in the public schools of the state, with the exception of the superintendent. </section><section prefix="2">The term "year" as applied to terms of service means actual service of not less than seven (7) school months within a school year; provided, however, that any board of education may grant a leave of absence for professional advancement or military leave for active duty service with full credit for service. </section><section prefix="3">The term "limited contract" shall mean a contract for the employment of a teacher for a term of one (1) year only or for that portion of the school year that remains at the time of employment. </section><section prefix="4">The term "continuing service contract" shall mean a contract for the employment of a teacher which shall remain in full force and effect until the teacher resigns or retires, or until it is terminated or suspended as provided in KRS 161.790 and 161.800. </section><section prefix="5">The term "continuing status" means employment of a teacher under a continuing contract. </section><section prefix="6">The term "standard" or "college" certificate for the purpose of KRS 161.730 to 161.810 shall mean any certificate issued upon the basis of graduation from a standard four (4) year college or completion of a local district alternative certification training program. </section><section prefix="7">The term "superintendent" for the purpose of KRS 161.765 shall mean the school officer appointed by a board of education under the authority of KRS 160.350 or any person authorized by law to perform the duties of that officer. </section><section prefix="8">The term "administrator" for the purpose of KRS 161.765 shall mean a certified employee, below the rank of superintendent, who devotes the majority of his employed time to service as a principal, assistant principal, supervisor, coordinator, director, assistant director, administrative assistant, finance officer, pupil personnel worker, guidance counselor, school psychologist, or school business administrator. The term "administrator" shall also include those assistant, associate, or deputy superintendents who do not fall within the definition of "superintendent" as set forth in subsection (7) of this section. </section><section prefix="9">The terms "demote" or "demotion" for the purpose of KRS 161.765 shall mean a reduction in rank from one position on the school district salary schedule to a different position on that schedule for which a lower salary is paid. The terms shall not include lateral transfers to positions of similar rank and pay or minor alterations in pay increments required by the salary schedule. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 518, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 80, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3991</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>