<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.490</section_number><catch_line>Duties of the circuit clerk. </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text>The circuit clerk of each county shall: <section prefix="1">Comply with all rules and regulations issued by the cabinet under KRS 186.400 relating to his duties; </section><section prefix="2">Act for the cabinet for the purpose of issuing temporary operator's licenses and instruction permits; </section><section prefix="3">Administer the oath required by KRS 186.412 to the applicant without fee; </section><section prefix="4">Report and remit monthly to the state all moneys collected during the preceding month and remit a copy of all applications taken by him during the same period to the Transportation Cabinet. Upon failure of any clerk to report and remit therefor more than seven (7) days after the due date, he shall pay, in addition to the amount due, a penalty of ten percent (10%) of the amount due. Penalties collected under this section shall be paid into the State Treasury as a part of the revenue collected under KRS 186.531; </section><section prefix="5">Keep adequate records of all moneys collected and remitted to the state; and </section><section prefix="6">Keep in his office at all times available to the cabinet a record of all temporary licenses issued in his county, all denials, cancellations, suspensions, revocations or withdrawals of operator's licenses or motorcycle operator's licenses within his county and, to the extent that he is advised, of all other withdrawals of the privilege to operate a motor vehicle on the highways. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 309, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 6. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 4, effective June 13, 1968. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 5. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. X, sec. 12, effective September 1, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-42, 2739m-44, 2739m-70. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6067</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>