<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.460</section_number><catch_line>Licensed treatment services to participate in cabinet's evaluation or client- outcome effectiveness study. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As a requirement to receive state or federal funds, including Medicaid, a treatment center or program licensed as a chemical dependency treatment service pursuant to KRS 216B.105 or this chapter shall participate in an evaluation or client-outcome effectiveness study conducted by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">Information for the evaluation shall include, but is not limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">The total number of alcohol and drug abuse clients admitted to treatment; </section><section prefix="b">The total number of referrals from the District and Circuit Courts and the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="c">The client's change in alcohol and other drug use patterns from admission to discharge from treatment; </section><section prefix="d">The client's change in employment status from admission to discharge from treatment; and </section><section prefix="e">The client's change in involvement with the criminal justice system from admission to discharge from treatment. </section></section><section prefix="3">All information collected pursuant to this chapter shall be held confidential with respect to the identity of individual clients. Access to information that identifies individual clients may be provided to qualified persons or organizations with a valid scientific interest, as determined by the secretary, who are engaged in research related to patterns of drug and alcohol use, the effectiveness of treatment, or similar studies and who agree in writing to maintain confidentiality. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 15, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 503, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 82, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9952</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>