<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.420</section_number><catch_line>Limits on state general fund grants -- Purpose for which made -- Distribution formula.   </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as hereinafter provided, grants from state general funds for any program shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of the total expenditures for: <section prefix="a">Salaries; </section><section prefix="b">Contract facilities and services; </section><section prefix="c">Operation, maintenance, and service costs; </section><section prefix="d">Per diem and travel expenses for members of the community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability; and </section><section prefix="e">Other expenditures specifically approved by the secretary for health and family services. </section></section> No grants from state general funds shall be made for capital expenditures. Grants from state general funds may be made for expenditures for services for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability, whether provided by operation of a local facility or through contract with other public or private agencies. <section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall distribute to community boards for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability those general funds appropriated to the cabinet for the operation of regional community programs for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability. This distribution shall be by a formula which includes provisions for: <section prefix="a">Per capita allocations; </section><section prefix="b">Incentive allocations which require local matching funds based on the per capita wealth of the area served; and </section><section prefix="c">Discretionary allocations to be available to the secretary to maintain essential services pursuant to KRS 210.410. </section></section> The formula for allocation of community program general funds for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability shall be prescribed by administrative regulations. </text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 81, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 331, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 275, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (8). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 64(3). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 203.460. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40809</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>