<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="180" order_by="180">STATE BRIDGES, TUNNELS, AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>180.060</section_number><catch_line>Advertising -- Opening of bids -- Letting of contracts. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall formulate a general plan for advertising, which plan shall be filed in the office of the department and be available to any person inquiring therefor. </section><section prefix="2">All competitive bids received under the terms of this chapter shall be opened and read publicly by representatives of the department at a designated place, day, and hour, all of which shall be announced in the advertising relative thereto. At the time the bids are opened, the department shall announce the department's engineer's estimate and make it a part of the department's records pertaining to the letting of any contract for which bids were received. Each bid, together with the name of the bidder and the department's engineer's estimate, shall be recorded and be open to public inspection. </section><section prefix="3">All bridges and approaches or substantial portions thereof when built by contract shall be let to the lowest and best bidder after advertisement, and after the preparation of detailed plans and specifications, which shall be submitted to all prospective bidders in ample time before a contract is awarded. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may reject any and all bids made either for material, for construction or for the bonds or any one (1) or more of them. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4356s-9, 4356s-11. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5537</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>