<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-016</section_number><catch_line>Fees for permit to construct or operate hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility. </catch_line><order_by>46-016</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for a permit to construct or operate a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject to a filing fee by the cabinet in the amount of twenty percent (20%) of the permit review fee. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant for a permit to construct or operate a treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject by the cabinet to a review fee equal to the sum of the unit fees charged for each type of hazardous waste management unit at the facility. The incinerator unit fee shall apply once for each different type of incinerator unit at the facility. The types of incinerator units shall include liquid injection, rotary kiln, fluidized bed, and multiple hearth. The tank unit fee shall apply once for each different tank design. Tank design criteria shall include: differences in materials of construction, pressure vessels, nonpressure vessels, shape, and ancillary equipment. The container unit fee shall apply once for each different container type. Container types shall include: drums, tote bins, bottles, and roll-off boxes. The unit fees shall be: <section prefix="a">Incinerator: nineteen thousand four hundred dollars ($19,400); </section><section prefix="b">Waste pile: twelve thousand two hundred dollars ($12,200); </section><section prefix="c">Surface impoundment: fourteen thousand dollars ($14,000); </section><section prefix="d">A tank with a total capacity of seven thousand five hundred (7,500) or more gallons: seven thousand four hundred dollars ($7,400); </section><section prefix="e">A tank with a total capacity less than seven thousand five hundred (7,500) gallons: three thousand seven hundred dollars ($3,700); </section><section prefix="f">Additional tanks of similar design with a combined capacity greater than seven thousand five hundred (7,500) gallons: four thousand four hundred dollars ($4,400); </section><section prefix="g">Additional tanks of similar design with a combined capacity less than seven thousand five hundred (7,500) gallons: one thousand eight hundred fifty dollars ($1,850); </section><section prefix="h">A container with a total capacity of five thousand (5,000) or more gallons: six thousand dollars ($6,000); </section><section prefix="i">A container with a total capacity less than five thousand (5,000) gallons: three thousand dollars ($3,000); </section><section prefix="j">Additional container of similar design with a combined capacity greater than five thousand (5,000) gallons: three thousand dollars ($3,000); </section><section prefix="k">Additional container of similar design with a combined capacity less than five thousand (5,000) gallons: one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500); </section><section prefix="l">Land treatment: fifteen thousand eight hundred dollars ($15,800); and </section><section prefix="m">Landfill: fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000). </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may subject an applicant seeking a permit to construct or operate a treatment, storage, or disposal facility to a facility assessment fee as follows: <section prefix="a">One hundred (100) or more solid waste management units: eleven thousand five hundred dollars ($11,500); </section><section prefix="b">Sixty (60) to ninety-nine (99) solid waste management units: nine thousand dollars ($9,000); </section><section prefix="c">Twenty (20) to fifty-nine (59) solid waste management units: six thousand five hundred dollars ($6,500); or </section><section prefix="d">Fewer than twenty (20) solid waste management units: four thousand dollars ($4,000). </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may require an applicant seeking a permit to construct or operate a treatment, storage, or disposal facility to submit an investigation fee or corrective action fee, or both, if the facility includes a facility investigation or corrective action study or plan. The facility investigation fee shall be equal to the cost of the review, but shall not exceed fourteen thousand five hundred dollars ($14,500). The corrective action fee shall be equal to the cost of the review, but shall not exceed twenty-nine thousand dollars ($29,000). </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.1161. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>