<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-030</section_number><catch_line>Available insurance agent licenses. </catch_line><order_by>9-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless denied a license according to KRS 304.9-440, applicants who have met the requirements for the license in accordance with this subtitle, shall be issued the applicable license. </section><section prefix="2">An insurance agent may receive qualification for a license in one (1) or more of the following applicable lines of authority: <section prefix="a">Life -- insurance coverage on human lives including benefits of endowment and annuities, and may include benefits in the event of death or dismemberment by accident and benefits for disability income; </section><section prefix="b">Health -- insurance coverage for sickness, bodily injury, or accidental death and may include benefits for disability income; </section><section prefix="c">Property -- insurance coverage for the direct or consequential loss or damage to property of every kind; </section><section prefix="d">Casualty -- insurance coverage against legal liability, including that for death, injury, or disability, or damage to real or personal property; </section><section prefix="e">Variable life and variable annuity products -- insurance coverage provided under variable life insurance contracts and variable annuities; </section><section prefix="f">Limited line insurance as identified in KRS 304.9-230; </section><section prefix="g">Personal lines -- property and casualty insurance coverage sold to individuals and families for primarily noncommercial purposes; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other line of insurance authorized by Kentucky law and deemed by the commissioner appropriate to be issued as a separate line of authority. </section></section><section prefix="3">A resident applicant for a variable life and variable annuities line of authority shall hold an active life line of authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1042, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16886</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>