<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.722</section_number><catch_line>Expiration of license -- Renewal -- Continuing education -- Inactive license. </catch_line><order_by>722</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The initial license for a home inspector issued in accordance with KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738, shall expire on the last day of the licensee's birth month in the following year. The board may reduce the license fee on a pro rata basis for initial licenses issued for less than twelve (12) months. </section><section prefix="2">Renewed licenses shall expire on the last day of the licensee's birth month of each even numbered year after the date of issuance of the renewed license. </section><section prefix="3">An individual who applies to renew a license as a licensed home inspector shall: <section prefix="a">Furnish evidence showing successful completion of the continuing education requirements of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Pay the renewal fee and late fee, if applicable, established by the board; </section><section prefix="c">Show proof of general liability insurance in the amount required by KRS 198B.712(3)(d); and </section><section prefix="d">Submit a recent background check performed by the Kentucky State Police. </section></section><section prefix="4">Renewal notices shall be sent to each licensee at least sixty (60) days prior to the expiration of the license. The notice shall inform the licensee of the need to renew and the requirement of payment of the renewal fee. </section><section prefix="5">Renewal and applicable late fees shall be paid with a credit card, a draft, a money order, a cashier's check, a certified or other personal check, or, if payment is made in person, the payment may be made in cash. If the board receives an uncertified personal check for the renewal fee and if the check does not clear the bank, the board may refuse to renew the license. </section><section prefix="6">Each licensee shall complete the continuing education required by the board prior to applying for license renewal. This requirement shall not exceed thirty (30) hours per two (2) year license cycle. </section><section prefix="7">The board may, through the promulgation of administrative regulations: <section prefix="a">Establish an inactive license for licensees who are not actively engaging in the home inspection business but wish to maintain their license; </section><section prefix="b">Reduce license and renewal fees for inactive licenses; and </section><section prefix="c">Waive the insurance requirements established in KRS 198B.712 for inactive licenses. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 10, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39906</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>