<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.570</section_number><catch_line>Persons accepted for supervision under compact subject to arrest and detention -- Notice to sending state -- Applicability of supervision fee and of drug testing and substance abuse treatment fee. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All persons accepted for supervision under the terms of the interstate compact as set forth in KRS 439.560 shall be subject to arrest or detention by a probation or parole officer under the same circumstances as Kentucky probationers or parolees. The probation or parole officer shall immediately notify the sending state through the interstate compact of the arrest or detention of the person in question, setting forth the reasons for the arrest or detention. </section><section prefix="2">All persons accepted for supervision under the terms of the interstate compact as set forth in KRS 439.560 shall be subject to the payment of a supervision fee as established in KRS 439.315 and the payment of a drug testing and substance abuse treatment fee as conditions of supervision imposed by the Division of Probation and Parole. Failure to pay the required supervision fee or drug testing and substance abuse treatment fee is grounds for the termination of supervision or shall subject the person to the initiation of revocation proceedings under the same circumstances as set forth in KRS 439.315. For purposes of implementing KRS 439.315, the Division of Probation and Parole shall be the releasing authority. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19211</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>