<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.546</section_number><catch_line>Sick leave for employees who began participating before January 1, 2014.   </catch_line><order_by>546</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any member of the Kentucky Employees Retirement System or the State Police Retirement System whose retirement date is July 14, 1984, or thereafter, shall receive credit for unused sick leave accrued while contributing to the retirement system from which the retirement benefit is to be paid in accordance with this section. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the member's notification of retirement as prescribed in KRS 16.576 or 61.590, the employer shall certify the retiring member's unused, accumulated sick leave balance to the system. The member's sick leave balance, expressed in days, shall be divided by the average number of working days per month in the state service and rounded to the nearest number of whole months. The member's sick leave balance, expressed in months, shall be added to his service credit for the purpose of determining his annual retirement allowance under KRS 16.505 to 16.652 or 61.510 to 61.705 and for the purpose of determining whether the member is eligible to receive a retirement allowance under KRS 16.505 to 16.652 or 61.510 to 61.705, except as provided by subsection (3) of this section. Accumulated sick leave in excess of six (6) months shall be added to the member's service credit, and the last participating Kentucky Employees Retirement Systems employer shall pay to the retirement system the value of the additional service credit based on the formula adopted by the board, except as provided by subsection (3) of this section. All of a state policeman's sick leave balance, expressed in months, except as provided by subsection (3) of this section, shall be added to his service credit for the purposes of determining his annual retirement allowance and whether the member is eligible to receive a retirement allowance under KRS 16.505 to 16.652. </section><section prefix="3">For a member who begins participating in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System or the State Police Retirement System on or after September 1, 2008: <section prefix="a">The member shall receive no more than twelve (12) months of service credit upon retirement for accumulated unused sick leave accrued while contributing to the retirement system or systems from which the retirement benefit is to be paid; </section><section prefix="b">The service credited for accumulated unused sick leave and added to the member's service credit shall be used for purposes of determining the member's annual retirement allowance under KRS 16.505 to 16.652 and 61.510 to 61.705; </section><section prefix="c">The service credited for accumulated unused sick leave and added to the member's service credit shall not be used to determine whether a member is eligible to receive a retirement allowance under any of the provisions of KRS 16.505 to 16.652 and 61.510 to 61.705; and </section><section prefix="d">Except as provided by subsection (4) of this section, the value of any accumulated unused sick leave in excess of six (6) months that is added to the member's service credit in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System shall be paid to the retirement system by the last participating Kentucky Employees Retirement System employer based upon the formula adopted by the board. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section to the contrary, the value of any accumulated sick leave that is added to the member's service credit in the Kentucky Employees Retirement System or the State Police Retirement System on or after July 1, 2010, shall be paid to the retirement system by the last participating Kentucky Employees Retirement System or State Police Retirement System employer based upon a formula adopted by the board. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of this section shall not apply to a participating agency whose employees are not employed by the Commonwealth until the agency certifies to the system that a sick leave program has been formally adopted and is universally administered within the agency. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to members who begin participating in the systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems on or after January 1, 2014. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 49, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 11, effective June 27, 2008. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 20. effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 349, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 423, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/27/2008). A manifest clerical or typographical error in 2008 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 11 (this statute), has been corrected in codification by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42677</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>