<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.442</section_number><catch_line>Center for School Safety -- Duties -- Members of board.   </catch_line><order_by>442</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby authorizes the establishment of the Center for School Safety. The center's mission shall be to serve as the central point for data analysis; research; dissemination of information about successful school safety programs, research results, and new programs; and, in collaboration with the Department of Education and others, to provide technical assistance for safe schools. </section><section prefix="2">To fulfill its mission, the Center for School Safety shall: <section prefix="a">Establish a clearinghouse for information and materials concerning school violence prevention; </section><section prefix="b">Provide program development and implementation expertise and technical support to schools, law enforcement agencies, and communities, which may include coordinating training for administrators, teachers, students, parents, and other community representatives; </section><section prefix="c">Analyze the data collected in compliance with KRS 158.444; </section><section prefix="d">Research and evaluate school safety programs so schools and communities are better able to address their specific needs; </section><section prefix="e">Administer a school safety grant program for local districts as directed by the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="f">Promote the formation of interagency efforts to address discipline and safety issues within communities throughout the state in collaboration with other postsecondary education institutions and with local juvenile delinquency prevention councils; </section><section prefix="g">Prepare and disseminate information regarding best practices in creating safe and effective schools; </section><section prefix="h">Advise the Kentucky Board of Education on administrative policies and administrative regulations; and </section><section prefix="i">Provide an annual report by July 1 of each year to the Governor, the Kentucky Board of Education, and the Interim Joint Committee on Education regarding the status of school safety in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Center for School Safety shall be governed by a board of directors appointed by the Governor. Members shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The commissioner or a designee of the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner or a designee of the Department of Juvenile Justice; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner or a designee of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner or a designee of the Department for Community Based Services; </section><section prefix="e">The secretary or a designee of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet; </section><section prefix="f">A juvenile court judge; </section><section prefix="g">A local school district board of education member; </section><section prefix="h">A local school administrator; </section><section prefix="i">A school council parent representative; </section><section prefix="j">A teacher; </section><section prefix="k">A classified school employee; and </section><section prefix="l">A superintendent of schools who is a member of the Kentucky Association of School Administrators. </section></section> In appointing the board of education member, the school administrator, the school superintendent, the school council parent member, the teacher, and the classified employee, the Governor shall solicit recommendations from the following groups respectively: the Kentucky School Boards Association, the Kentucky Association of School Administrators, the Kentucky Association of School Councils, the Kentucky Education Association, and the Kentucky Education Support Personnel Association. The initial board shall be appointed by July 15, 1998. The board shall hold its first meeting no later than thirty (30) days after the appointment of the members. </text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 48, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 84, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 3, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40752</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>