<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.409</section_number><catch_line>Records to be kept.   </catch_line><order_by>409</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each limited partnership shall keep, at the office referred to in KRS 362.407(2), the following records: <section prefix="a">A current list of the full names and last known business, residence, or mailing addresses of all partners, separately identifying in alphabetical order the general partners and the limited partners; </section><section prefix="b">A copy of the certificate of limited partnership and all certificates of amendment thereto, together with executed copies of any powers of attorney pursuant to which any certificate was executed; </section><section prefix="c">Copies of the limited partnership's federal, state and local income tax returns and reports, if any, for the three (3) most recent years; </section><section prefix="d">Copies of any then effective written partnership agreement and of any financial statements of the limited partnership for the three (3) most recent years; and </section><section prefix="e">Unless contained in a written partnership agreement, a writing setting out: <section prefix="1">The amount of cash and a description and statement of the agreed value of the other property or services contributed by each partner and which each partner has agreed to contribute; </section><section prefix="2">The times at which, or events upon the happening of which, any additional contributions agreed to be made by each partner are to be made; </section><section prefix="3">Any right of a partner to receive distributions, or of a general partner to make distributions to a partner, that includes a return of all or any part of the partner's contribution; and </section><section prefix="4">Any events upon the happening of which the limited partnership is to be dissolved and its affairs wound up. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Records kept under this section may be inspected and copied during ordinary business hours at the reasonable request, and at the expense, of any partner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 122, effective January 1, 2011. -- Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 116, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>