<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.225</section_number><catch_line>Health care insurance coverage -- Requirements of prospectivecarriers -- Analysis of carrier coverage data -- Agency's termination ofparticipation -- Provision of amount of employer contribution -- Lapse ofexcess flexible spending account funds -- Appeal of formulary change --Retiree's participation -- Mail order drug option coverage -- Hearing aidcoverage for minors -- Coverage for diagnosis and treatment of autismspectrum disorders -- Access to certain services in contiguous counties-- Study of bid variation -- Regional rating bid scenario -- Optometriccoverage -- Nondiscrimination against provider in geographic coveragearea -- Standards for provider participation -- Utilization review -- Paymentof claims -- Uniform health insurance claim forms -- Emergency medicalcare -- Administrative regulations.  </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text>(1)(a)The term "employee" for purposes of this section means:1.Any person, including an elected public official, who is regularlyemployed by any department, office, board, agency, or branch ofstate government; or by a public postsecondary educationalinstitution; or by any city, urban-county, charter county, county, orconsolidated local government, whose legislative body has opted toparticipate in the state-sponsored health insurance programpursuant to KRS 79.080; and who is either a contributing member toany one (1) of the retirement systems administered by the state,including but not limited to the Kentucky Retirement Systems,Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System, the Legislators' RetirementPlan, or the Judicial Retirement Plan; or is receiving a contractualcontribution from the state toward a retirement plan; or, in the caseof a public postsecondary education institution, is an individualparticipating in an optional retirement plan authorized by KRS161.567;2.Any certified or classified employee of a local board of education;3.Any elected member of a local board of education;4.Any person who is a present or future recipient of a retirementallowance from the Kentucky Retirement Systems, KentuckyTeachers' Retirement System, the Legislators' Retirement Plan, theJudicial Retirement Plan, or the Kentucky Community and TechnicalCollege System's optional retirement plan authorized by KRS161.567, except that a person who is receiving a retirementallowance and who is age sixty-five (65) or older shall not beincluded, with the exception of persons covered under KRS61.702(4)(c), unless he or she is actively employed pursuant tosubparagraph 1. of this paragraph; and5.Any eligible dependents and beneficiaries of participatingemployees and retirees who are entitled to participate in thestate-sponsored health insurance program;(b)The term "health benefit plan" for the purposes of this section means ahealth benefit plan as defined in KRS 304.17A-005;(c)The term "insurer" for the purposes of this section means an insurer asdefined in KRS 304.17A-005; and(d)The term "managed care plan" for the purposes of this section means amanaged care plan as defined in KRS 304.17A-500.(2)(a)The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, upon therecommendation of the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet, shall procure,in compliance with the provisions of KRS 45A.080, 45A.085, and45A.090, from one (1) or more insurers authorized to do business in thisstate, a group health benefit plan that may include but not be limited tohealth maintenance organization (HMO), preferred provider organization(PPO), point of service (POS), and exclusive provider organization (EPO)benefit plans encompassing all or any class or classes of employees.With the exception of employers governed by the provisions of KRSChapters 16, 18A, and 151B, all employers of any class of employees orformer employees shall enter into a contract with the Personnel Cabinetprior to including that group in the state health insurance group. Thecontracts shall include but not be limited to designating the entityresponsible for filing any federal forms, adoption of policies required forproper plan administration, acceptance of the contractual provisions withhealth insurance carriers or third-party administrators, and adoption of thepayment and reimbursement methods necessary for efficientadministration of the health insurance program. Health insurancecoverage provided to state employees under this section shall, at aminimum, contain the same benefits as provided under Kentucky KareStandard as of January 1, 1994, and shall include a mail-order drugoption as provided in subsection (13) of this section. All employees andother persons for whom the health care coverage is provided or madeavailable shall annually be given an option to elect health care coveragethrough a self-funded plan offered by the Commonwealth or, if aself-funded plan is not available, from a list of coverage optionsdetermined by the competitive bid process under the provisions of KRS45A.080, 45A.085, and 45A.090 and made available during annual openenrollment.(b)The policy or policies shall be approved by the commissioner ofinsurance and may contain the provisions the commissioner of insuranceapproves, whether or not otherwise permitted by the insurance laws.(c)Any carrier bidding to offer health care coverage to employees shallagree to provide coverage to all members of the state group, includingactive employees and retirees and their eligible covered dependents andbeneficiaries, within the county or counties specified in its bid. Except asprovided in subsection (19) of this section, any carrier bidding to offerhealth care coverage to employees shall also agree to rate all employeesas a single entity, except for those retirees whose former employersinsure their active employees outside the state-sponsored healthinsurance program.(d)Any carrier bidding to offer health care coverage to employees shallagree to provide enrollment, claims, and utilization data to theCommonwealth in a format specified by the Personnel Cabinet with theunderstanding that the data shall be owned by the Commonwealth; toprovide data in an electronic form and within a time frame specified by thePersonnel Cabinet; and to be subject to penalties for noncompliance withdata reporting requirements as specified by the Personnel Cabinet. ThePersonnel Cabinet shall take strict precautions to protect theconfidentiality of each individual employee; however, confidentialityassertions shall not relieve a carrier from the requirement of providingstipulated data to the Commonwealth.(e)The Personnel Cabinet shall develop the necessary techniques andcapabilities for timely analysis of data received from carriers and, to theextent possible, provide in the request-for-proposal specifics relating todata requirements, electronic reporting, and penalties for noncompliance.The Commonwealth shall own the enrollment, claims, and utilization dataprovided by each carrier and shall develop methods to protect theconfidentiality of the individual. The Personnel Cabinet shall include in theOctober annual report submitted pursuant to the provisions of KRS18A.226 to the Governor, the General Assembly, and the Chief Justice ofthe Supreme Court, an analysis of the financial stability of the program,which shall include but not be limited to loss ratios, methods of riskadjustment, measurements of carrier quality of service, prescriptioncoverage and cost management, and statutorially required mandates. Ifstate self-insurance was available as a carrier option, the report also shallprovide a detailed financial analysis of the self-insurance fund includingbut not limited to loss ratios, reserves, and reinsurance agreements.(f)If any agency participating in the state-sponsored employee healthinsurance program for its active employees terminates participation andthere is a state appropriation for the employer's contribution for activeemployees' health insurance coverage, then neither the agency nor theemployees shall receive the state-funded contribution after terminationfrom the state-sponsored employee health insurance program.(g)Any funds in flexible spending accounts that remain after allreimbursements have been processed shall be transferred to the credit ofthe state-sponsored health insurance plan's appropriation account.(h)Each entity participating in the state-sponsored health insurance programshall provide an amount at least equal to the state contribution rate for theemployer portion of the health insurance premium. For any participatingentity that used the state payroll system, the employer contributionamount shall be equal to but not greater than the state contribution rate.(3)The premiums may be paid by the policyholder:(a)Wholly from funds contributed by the employee, by payroll deduction orotherwise;(b)Wholly from funds contributed by any department, board, agency, publicpostsecondary education institution, or branch of state, city, urban-county,charter county, county, or consolidated local government; or(c)Partly from each, except that any premium due for health care coverageor dental coverage, if any, in excess of the premium amount contributedby any department, board, agency, postsecondary education institution,or branch of state, city, urban-county, charter county, county, orconsolidated local government for any other health care coverage shall bepaid by the employee.(4)If an employee moves his place of residence or employment out of the servicearea of an insurer offering a managed health care plan, under which he haselected coverage, into either the service area of another managed health careplan or into an area of the Commonwealth not within a managed health careplan service area, the employee shall be given an option, at the time of themove or transfer, to change his or her coverage to another health benefit plan.(5)No payment of premium by any department, board, agency, publicpostsecondary educational institution, or branch of state, city, urban-county,charter county, county, or consolidated local government shall constitutecompensation to an insured employee for the purposes of any statute fixing orlimiting the compensation of such an employee. Any premium or other expenseincurred by any department, board, agency, public postsecondary educationalinstitution, or branch of state, city, urban-county, charter county, county, orconsolidated local government shall be considered a proper cost ofadministration.(6)The policy or policies may contain the provisions with respect to the class orclasses of employees covered, amounts of insurance or coverage fordesignated classes or groups of employees, policy options, terms of eligibility,and continuation of insurance or coverage after retirement.(7)Group rates under this section shall be made available to the disabled child ofan employee regardless of the child's age if the entire premium for the disabledchild's coverage is paid by the state employee. A child shall be considereddisabled if he has been determined to be eligible for federal Social Securitydisability benefits.(8)The health care contract or contracts for employees shall be entered into for aperiod of not less than one (1) year.(9)The secretary shall appoint thirty-two (32) persons to an Advisory Committeeof State Health Insurance Subscribers to advise the secretary or his designeeregarding the state-sponsored health insurance program for employees. Thesecretary shall appoint, from a list of names submitted by appointingauthorities, members representing school districts from each of the seven (7)Supreme Court districts, members representing state government from each ofthe seven (7) Supreme Court districts, two (2) members representing retireesunder age sixty-five (65), one (1) member representing local healthdepartments, two (2) members representing the Kentucky Teachers'Retirement System, and three (3) members at large. The secretary shall alsoappoint two (2) members from a list of five (5) names submitted by theKentucky Education Association, two (2) members from a list of five (5) namessubmitted by the largest state employee organization of nonschool stateemployees, two (2) members from a list of five (5) names submitted by theKentucky Association of Counties, two (2) members from a list of five (5)names submitted by the Kentucky League of Cities, and two (2) members froma list of names consisting of five (5) names submitted by each state employeeorganization that has two thousand (2,000) or more members on state payrolldeduction. The advisory committee shall be appointed in January of each yearand shall meet quarterly.(10)Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the policy or policiesprovided to employees pursuant to this section shall not provide coverage forobtaining or performing an abortion, nor shall any state funds be used for thepurpose of obtaining or performing an abortion on behalf of employees or theirdependents.(11)Interruption of an established treatment regime with maintenance drugs shallbe grounds for an insured to appeal a formulary change through theestablished appeal procedures approved by the Department of Insurance, if thephysician supervising the treatment certifies that the change is not in the bestinterests of the patient.(12)Any employee who is eligible for and elects to participate in the state healthinsurance program as a retiree, or the spouse or beneficiary of a retiree, underany one (1) of the state-sponsored retirement systems shall not be eligible toreceive the state health insurance contribution toward health care coverage asa result of any other employment for which there is a public employercontribution. This does not preclude a retiree and an active employee spousefrom using both contributions to the extent needed for purchase of one (1) statesponsored health insurance policy for that plan year.(13)(a)The policies of health insurance coverage procured under subsection (2)of this section shall include a mail-order drug option for maintenancedrugs for state employees. Maintenance drugs may be dispensed by mailorder in accordance with Kentucky law.(b)A health insurer shall not discriminate against any retail pharmacy locatedwithin the geographic coverage area of the health benefit plan and thatmeets the terms and conditions for participation established by theinsurer, including price, dispensing fee, and copay requirements of amail-order option. The retail pharmacy shall not be required to dispenseby mail.(c)The mail-order option shall not permit the dispensing of a controlledsubstance classified in Schedule II.(14)The policy or policies provided to state employees or their dependentspursuant to this section shall provide coverage for obtaining a hearing aid andacquiring hearing aid-related services for insured individuals under eighteen(18) years of age, subject to a cap of one thousand four hundred dollars($1,400) every thirty-six (36) months pursuant to KRS 304.17A-132.(15)Any policy provided to state employees or their dependents pursuant to thissection shall provide coverage for the diagnosis and treatment of autismspectrum disorders consistent with KRS 304.17A-142.(16)If a state employee's residence and place of employment are in the samecounty, and if the hospital located within that county does not offer surgicalservices, intensive care services, obstetrical services, level II neonatalservices, diagnostic cardiac catheterization services, and magnetic resonanceimaging services, the employee may select a plan available in a contiguouscounty that does provide those services, and the state contribution for the planshall be the amount available in the county where the plan selected is located.(17)If a state employee's residence and place of employment are each located incounties in which the hospitals do not offer surgical services, intensive careservices, obstetrical services, level II neonatal services, diagnostic cardiaccatheterization services, and magnetic resonance imaging services, theemployee may select a plan available in a county contiguous to the county ofresidence that does provide those services, and the state contribution for theplan shall be the amount available in the county where the plan selected islocated.(18)The Personnel Cabinet is encouraged to study whether it is fair and reasonableand in the best interests of the state group to allow any carrier bidding to offerhealth care coverage under this section to submit bids that may vary county bycounty or by larger geographic areas.(19)Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the bid for proposals forhealth insurance coverage for calendar year 2004 shall include a bid scenariothat reflects the statewide rating structure provided in calendar year 2003 and abid scenario that allows for a regional rating structure that allows carriers tosubmit bids that may vary by region for a given product offering as described inthis subsection:(a)The regional rating bid scenario shall not include a request for bid on astatewide option;(b)The Personnel Cabinet shall divide the state into geographical regionswhich shall be the same as the partnership regions designated by theDepartment for Medicaid Services for purposes of the Kentucky HealthCare Partnership Program established pursuant to 907 KAR 1:705;(c)The request for proposal shall require a carrier's bid to include everycounty within the region or regions for which the bid is submitted andinclude but not be restricted to a preferred provider organization (PPO)option;(d)If the Personnel Cabinet accepts a carrier's bid, the cabinet shall awardthe carrier all of the counties included in its bid within the region. If thePersonnel Cabinet deems the bids submitted in accordance with thissubsection to be in the best interests of state employees in a region, thecabinet may award the contract for that region to no more than two (2)carriers; and(e)Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit the Personnel Cabinet fromincluding other requirements or criteria in the request for proposal.(20)Any fully insured health benefit plan or self-insured plan issued or renewed onor after July 12, 2006, to public employees pursuant to this section whichprovides coverage for services rendered by a physician or osteopath dulylicensed under KRS Chapter 311 that are within the scope of practice of anoptometrist duly licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 320 shallprovide the same payment of coverage to optometrists as allowed for thoseservices rendered by physicians or osteopaths.(21)Any fully insured health benefit plan or self-insured plan issued or renewed onor after July 12, 2006, to public employees pursuant to this section shallcomply with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-270 and 304.17A-525.(22)Any full insured health benefit plan or self insured plan issued or renewed on orafter July 12, 2006, to public employees shall comply with KRS 304.17A-600 to304.17A-633 pertaining to utilization review, KRS 205.593 and 304.17A-700 to304.17A-730 pertaining to payment of claims, KRS 304.14-135 pertaining touniform health insurance claim forms, KRS 304.17A-580 and 304.17A-641pertaining to emergency medical care, KRS 304.99-123, and anyadministrative regulations promulgated thereunder.</text><history>Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 28, effective July 15, 2010; and ch.150, sec. 19, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec.3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effectiveJuly 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch.12, sec.1, effective June 24, 2003;and ch. 29, sec. 1, effective March 18, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 67,sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002; ch. 275,sec. 34, effective July 1, 2002; ch. 345, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; ch. 351,sec. 17, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 352, secs. 1 and 4, effective July 15,2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 3, effective March 15, 2001. --Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 2, effective April 21, 2000. -- Amended1998 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 154, sec. 45, effectiveJuly 15, 1998; and ch. 515, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky.Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 371, sec. 60, effective July15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994;and ch. 512, sec. 94, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 92,sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch.235, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 348, sec. 3,effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 489, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended1986 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky.Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Repealed and reenacted as KRS18A.225, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended1980 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 (1stExtra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 2.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2011</effective><former-codification> KRS 18.470.</former-codification><lrc-note> (1/1/2011). This section was amended by2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 150, which do not appear to be in conflict and havebeen codified together. (10/19/2004). 2004 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky.Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, provides, "Notwithstanding KRS 18A.225, 45A.022, 45A.080,45A.085, 45A.090, 45A.225 to 45A.290, or any other provision of KRS Chapter45A to the contrary, retroactive to August 12, 2004, the Finance andAdministration Cabinet shall implement the provisions of this Act by amendingthe previously negotiated contracts for public employee health insurance. Thesecretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall provide an actuarialcertification that the self-insured contract amounts are actuarially sound. Anycontracts entered into or modified pursuant to this section shall be forwarded tothe Legislative Research Commission." (7/15/2002). This section was amendedby 2002 Ky. Acts chs. 67, 106, 275, 345, 351, and 352. Where these Acts arenot in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists betweenActs ch. 275, sec. 34, and ch. 352, sec. 1, Acts ch. 352, which was last enactedby the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36560</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>