<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.590</section_number><catch_line>Falsification of statement, forgery of documents, dishonesty, fraud, deceit, collusion, or conspiracy concerning licensure prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall make any statement or submit any document, paper, or thing to the board, or to its executive director, or to any county clerk, relating in any manner to issuance, registration, suspension, or revocation of any license or permit, knowing same to be false, forged, or fraudulent. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall engage in dishonesty, fraud, deceit, collusion, or conspiracy in connection with any examination, hearings, or disciplinary proceedings conducted by the board. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall make or issue any false or counterfeit certificate that purports to have been issued by the board, or by its executive director, or forge the signature of any person thereon, or alter any such certificate that has been issued by the board or by its executive director. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 476, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30531</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>