<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.138</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service to administer home-based microprocessor program -- Certification by cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>138</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service shall develop, implement, and administer a program to train home-based microprocessors or personnel in compliance with 21 C.F.R. sec. 114.10. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall evaluate and certify home-based microprocessors or personnel who have completed the pilot microprocessing program or the microprocessing program. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall by June 30, 2003: <section prefix="a">Establish certification terms, conditions, and length of time the certification is valid; </section><section prefix="b">Establish terms, conditions, and standards for recertification; </section><section prefix="c">Establish fees for certification and recertification; and </section><section prefix="d">Develop a certification document. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet and the Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service shall by June 30, 2003: <section prefix="a">Develop an examination document; </section><section prefix="b">Establish examination subject matter; </section><section prefix="c">Establish criteria for program completion; and </section><section prefix="d">Establish fees for the pilot microprocessing program and the microprocessing program. </section></section><section prefix="5">The certification document shall be made in triplicate, with one (1) copy given to the home-based microprocessor or personnel, one (1) copy given to the Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service, and one (1) copy given to the cabinet. </section><section prefix="6">Upon completion of the program, home-based microprocessors and personnel shall be deemed to be certified and to have met the training requirements pursuant to 21 C.F.R. sec. 114.10. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9297</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>