<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.6601Advance</section_number><catch_line>notice to surface owner located within 1,000 feet of high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment of a horizontal well.   </catch_line><order_by>6601Advance</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An operator employing a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment shall provide notice required under subsection (3) of this section to each surface property owner within one thousand (1,000) feet of the surface location of the proposed well, at least twenty (20) days prior to commencement of a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment of a horizontal well. For purposes of this subsection, a surface property owner is the person who is assessed for the purpose of taxes imposed according to the records of the property valuation administrator of the county where the property is located. </section><section prefix="2">The operator shall, for the purpose of giving notice, secure from the property valuation administrator's office the names of persons entitled to notice under this section. Notice to the persons indicated as surface property owners in the office of the property valuation administrator shall be conclusive evidence that the operator has met the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The notice to surface property owners shall include: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the operator; </section><section prefix="b">The surface location of the proposed well; and </section><section prefix="c">The name and location of the cabinet office where the permit and related documents are available for public inspection and, if the documents are available electronically, the Web site where the permit and related documents may be inspected. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44244</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>