<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.530</section_number><catch_line>Calculation of receipts factor. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The receipts factor is a fraction, the numerator of which is the receipts of the financial institution in this Commonwealth during the taxable year as determined by subsection (2) of this section and the denominator of which is the receipts of the financial institution within and without this Commonwealth during the taxable year. Receipts shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Receipts from the lease or rental of real property owned by the financial institution; </section><section prefix="b">Receipts from the lease or rental of tangible personal property owned by the financial institution; </section><section prefix="c">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property; </section><section prefix="d">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property; </section><section prefix="e">Net gains from the sale of loans. Net gains from the sale of loans includes income recorded under the coupon stripping rules of Section 1286 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="f">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, such as annual fees; </section><section prefix="g">Net gains, but not less than zero (0), from the sale of credit card receivables; </section><section prefix="h">All credit card issuer's reimbursement fees; </section><section prefix="i">Receipts from merchant discount. Receipts from merchant discount shall be computed net of any cardholder charge backs, but shall not be reduced by any interchange transaction fees or by any issuer's reimbursement fees paid to another for charges made by its card holders; </section><section prefix="j">Loan servicing fees derived from loans secured by real property; </section><section prefix="k">Loan servicing fees derived from loans not secured by real property; </section><section prefix="l">Interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero (0), and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities. Investment assets and activities and trading assets and activities include but are not limited to investment securities, trading account assets, federal funds, securities purchased and sold under agreements to resell or repurchase, options, futures contracts, forward contracts, notional principal contracts such as swaps, equities, and foreign currency transactions. The receipts factor shall include the following amounts: <section prefix="1">The amount by which interest from federal funds sold and securities purchased under resale agreements exceeds interest expense on federal funds purchased and securities sold under repurchase agreements; and </section><section prefix="2">The amount by which interest, dividends, gains, and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book, and foreign currency transactions, exceed amounts paid in lieu of interest, amounts paid in lieu of dividends, and losses from these assets and activities; </section></section><section prefix="m">All receipts derived from sales that would be included in the factor established by KRS 141.120(8)(c); and </section><section prefix="n">Receipts from services not otherwise specifically listed. </section></section><section prefix="2">A determination of whether receipts should be included in the numerator of the fraction shall be made as follows: <section prefix="a">Receipts from the lease or rental of real property owned by the financial institution shall be included in the numerator if the property is located within this Commonwealth or receipts from the sublease of real property if the property is located within this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Except as described in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, receipts from the lease or rental of tangible personal property owned by the financial institution shall be included in the numerator if the property is located within this Commonwealth when it is first placed in service by the lessee. </section><section prefix="2">Receipts from the lease or rental of transportation property owned by the financial institution are included in the numerator of the receipts factor to the extent that the property is used in this Commonwealth. The extent an aircraft will be deemed to be used in this Commonwealth and the amount of receipts that is to be included in the numerator of this Commonwealth's receipts factor is determined by multiplying all the receipts from the lease or rental of the aircraft by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of landings of the aircraft in this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the total number of landings of the aircraft. If the extent of the use of any transportation property within this Commonwealth cannot be determined, then the property shall be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which the property has its principal base of operations. A motor vehicle shall be deemed to be used wholly in the state in which it is registered. </section></section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property shall be included in the numerator if the property is located within this Commonwealth. If the property is located both within this Commonwealth and one (1) or more other states, receipts shall be included if more than fifty percent (50%) of the fair market value of the real property is located within this Commonwealth. If more than fifty percent (50%) of the fair market value of the real property is not located within any one (1) state, then the receipts described in this subparagraph shall be included in the numerator if the borrower is located in this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">The determination of whether the real property securing a loan is located within this Commonwealth shall be made as of the time the original agreement was made, and any subsequent substitutions of collateral shall be disregarded. </section></section><section prefix="d">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property shall be included in the numerator if the borrower is located in this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="e">Net gains from the sale of loans shall be included in the numerator as provided in subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph. Net gains from the sale of loans includes income recorded under the coupon stripping rules of Section 1286 of the Internal Revenue Code. <section prefix="1">The amount of net gains, but not less than zero (0), from the sale of loans secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (c) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property. </section><section prefix="2">The amount of net gains, but not less than zero (0), from the sale of loans not secured by real property included in the numerator is determined by multiplying net gains by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (d) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property. </section></section><section prefix="f">Interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and receipts from fees charged to card holders, such as annual fees, shall be included in the numerator if the billing address of the card holder is in this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="g">Net gains, but not less than zero (0), from the sale of credit card receivables to be included in the numerator shall be determined by multiplying the amount established in paragraph (g) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (f) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the financial institution's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders. </section><section prefix="h">Credit card issuer's reimbursement fees to be included in the numerator shall be determined by multiplying the amount established in paragraph (h) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (f) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the financial institution's total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from credit card receivables and fees charged to card holders. </section><section prefix="i">Receipts from merchant discount shall be included in the numerator if the commercial domicile of the merchant is in this Commonwealth. Receipts from merchant discount shall be computed net of any cardholder charge backs but shall not be reduced by any interchange transaction fees or by any issuer's reimbursement fees paid to another for charges made by its card holders. </section><section prefix="j"><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Loan servicing fees derived from loans secured by real property to be included in the numerator shall be determined by multiplying the amount determined under paragraph (j) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (c) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans secured by real property. </section><section prefix="b">Loan servicing fees derived from loans not secured by real property to be included in the numerator shall be determined by multiplying the amount determined under paragraph (k) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the amount included in the numerator of the receipts factor pursuant to paragraph (d) of this subsection and the denominator of which is the total amount of interest and fees or penalties in the nature of interest from loans not secured by real property. </section></section><section prefix="2">In circumstances in which the financial institution receives loan servicing fees for servicing either the secured or the unsecured loans of another, the numerator of the receipts factor shall include the fees if the borrower is located in this Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="k">Receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section shall be included in the numerator if the service is performed in this Commonwealth. If the service is performed both within and without this Commonwealth, the numerator of the receipts factor includes receipts from services not otherwise apportioned under this section, if a greater proportion of the income-producing activity is performed in this Commonwealth based on cost of performance. </section><section prefix="l"><section prefix="1">The numerator of the receipts factor includes interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero (0), and other income from investment assets and activities and from trading assets and activities described in paragraph (l) of subsection (1) of this section that are attributable to this Commonwealth. <section prefix="a">The amount of interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero (0), and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all income from the assets and activities by a fraction the numerator of which is the average value of the assets that are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the average value of all the assets. </section><section prefix="b">The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph 1. of paragraph (l) of subsection (1) of this section from funds and securities by a fraction the numerator of which is the average value of federal funds sold and securities purchased under agreements to resell which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the average value of all funds and securities. </section><section prefix="c">The amount of interest, dividends, gains, and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book, and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subdivisions a. and b. of this subparagraph, attributable to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph 2. of paragraph (l) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the average value of trading assets which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the average value of all assets. </section><section prefix="d">For purposes of this subparagraph, average value shall be determined using the rules for determining the average value of tangible personal property set forth in KRS 136.535(3) and (4). </section></section><section prefix="2">In lieu of using the method set forth in subparagraph 1. of this paragraph, the financial institution may elect, or the department may require in order to fairly represent the business activity of the financial institution in this Commonwealth, the use of the method set forth in this subparagraph. <section prefix="a">The amount of interest, dividends, net gains, but not less than zero (0), and other income from investment assets and activities in the investment account to be attributed to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying all income from assets and activities by a fraction the numerator of which is the gross income from assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the gross income from all assets and activities. </section><section prefix="b">The amount of interest from federal funds sold and purchased and from securities purchased under resale agreements and securities sold under repurchase agreements attributable to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph 1. of paragraph (l) of subsection (1) of this section from funds and securities by a fraction the numerator of which is the gross income from funds and securities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the gross income from all funds and securities. </section><section prefix="c">The amount of interest, dividends, gains, and other income from trading assets and activities, including but not limited to assets and activities in the matched book, in the arbitrage book and foreign currency transactions, but excluding amounts described in subdivisions a. and b. of this subparagraph, attributable to this Commonwealth and included in the numerator is determined by multiplying the amount described in subparagraph 2. of paragraph (l) of subsection (1) of this section by a fraction the numerator of which is the gross income from trading assets and activities which are properly assigned to a regular place of business of the financial institution within this Commonwealth and the denominator of which is the gross income from all assets and activities. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the financial institution elects or is required by the department to use the method set forth in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, it shall use this method on all subsequent returns unless the financial institution receives prior permission from the department to use, or the department requires, a different method. </section><section prefix="4">The financial institution shall have the burden of proving that an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity was properly assigned to a regular place of business outside this Commonwealth by demonstrating that the day-to-day decisions regarding the asset or activity occurred at a regular place of business outside this Commonwealth. Where the day-to-day decisions regarding an investment asset or activity or trading asset or activity occur at more than one (1) regular place of business and one (1) regular place of business is in this Commonwealth and one (1) regular place of business is outside this Commonwealth, the asset or activity shall be considered to be located at the regular place of business of the financial institution where the investment or trading policies or guidelines with respect to the asset or activity are established. Unless the financial institution demonstrates to the contrary, the policies and guidelines shall be presumed to be established at the commercial domicile of the financial institution. </section></section><section prefix="m">The numerator of the receipts factor includes all other receipts derived from sales as determined pursuant to the provisions set forth in KRS 141.120(8)(c). </section><section prefix="n"><section prefix="1">All receipts that would be assigned under this section to a state in which the financial institution is not taxable shall be included in the numerator of the receipts factor, if the financial institution's commercial domicile is in this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">For purposes of subparagraph 1. of this paragraph, "taxable" means either: <section prefix="a">That a financial institution is subject in another state to a net income tax, a franchise tax measured by net income, a franchise tax for the privilege of doing business, a corporate stock tax including a bank shares tax, a single business tax, an earned surplus tax, or any tax which is imposed upon or measured by net income; or </section><section prefix="b">That another state has statutory authority to subject the financial institution to any of the taxes in subdivision a. of this subparagraph, whether in fact the state does or does not impose the tax. </section></section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 332, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 33, effective March 18, 2005. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (3/18/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 168, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/15/96).  In codifying subsections (1)(m) and (2)(m) of this statute, references to Section 28 of 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 254 (KRS 134.380) have been shown instead as references to Section 31 of that Act (KRS 136.070). Without changing these references or the text of the material referred to, House Floor Amendment 1 to House Bill 416 (which became Acts ch. 254) added three new sections to the bill and changed the numbering of the original Section 28 (KRS 136.070) to Section 31 but did not make the necessary corresponding adjustment to these internal references. This action has been taken under KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28571</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>