<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">C RESTRUCTURE OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT IN COUNTY CONTAINING CITY OF FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>67C.103</section_number><catch_line>Consolidated local government council -- Council districts -- Redistricting following decennial census -- Terms, qualifications, and election of members and president -- Regular and special meetings -- Notice requirements -- Ordinances -- Vacancies -- Legislative powers -- Name of council.   </catch_line><order_by>103</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The legislative authority of a consolidated local government, except as otherwise specified in KRS 67C.101 to 67C.137, shall be vested in a consolidated local government council. The members of the council shall be nominated and elected by district. There shall be only one (1) council member elected from each council district. </section><section prefix="2">There shall be twenty-six (26) council districts. The initial boundaries, population, and numerical designation of the council districts shall be as specified by KRS 67C.135. The population of the council districts shall be as nearly equal as is reasonably possible. For any newly consolidated local governments whose officials take office in 2003, upon taking office, the legislative council may take action to adjust the boundaries and population of the districts in order to equalize the population of the districts which may have changed as a result of recent census information. Any changes made to alter the boundaries of council districts shall be based on the population of the county as determined by the most recent United States Census or official census estimates as provided by the United States Bureau of the Census. </section><section prefix="3">Following the official publication of each decennial census by the United States Bureau of the Census for the area embraced by a consolidated local government, the council shall adopt an ordinance, if necessary, to redistrict the council districts. A redistricting ordinance shall provide for the distribution of population among the council districts as nearly equal as is reasonably possible. Every council district shall be compact and contiguous and shall respect existing neighborhood, community, and city boundaries whenever possible. </section><section prefix="4">The consolidated local government council members shall serve for a term of four (4) years beginning on the first Monday in January following their election except that the initial election of council members shall be in a manner as to provide for staggered terms for council members. At the initial election of the members of a consolidated local government council, those representing even-numbered districts shall be elected for a two (2) year term. Those representing odd-numbered districts shall be elected for a four (4) year term. Thereafter, all council members shall be elected for four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="5">The members of a consolidated local government council shall be nominated and elected from the district in which they reside in partisan elections. After the initial terms of office of the first elected council members, council members shall be elected in the same election years as other local government officials as regulated by the regular election laws of the Commonwealth and as provided in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall be eligible to serve as a member of a consolidated local government council unless he or she is at least eighteen (18) years old, a qualified voter, and a resident within the territory of the consolidated local government and the district that he or she seeks to represent for at least one (1) year immediately prior to the person's election. A council member shall continue to reside within the district from which he or she was elected throughout the term of office. </section><section prefix="7">The presiding officer of a consolidated local government council shall be a president who shall be chosen annually by a majority vote of the entire council from among its members at the first meeting of the council in January. The council president has the right to introduce any resolution or recommend any ordinance and shall be entitled to vote on all matters. </section><section prefix="8">The consolidated local government council shall upon notice meet within seven (7) days after its members have taken office, and shall thereafter hold at least two (2) regular meetings per month. No newspaper notice shall be required for regular or special meetings of the consolidated local government council. However, notice of all meetings of the council and all meetings of committees of the council shall be held pursuant to KRS 61.805 to 61.850. </section><section prefix="9">A majority of the members of the consolidated local government council shall constitute a quorum, but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day. The consolidated local government council may enforce the attendance of members by rules or ordinances with appropriate fines. The mayor or two-thirds (2/3) of the entire membership of the council may call a special meeting at any time. Meetings shall be held in such places in the county as are provided by ordinance, and the place of meetings shall not be changed except by an ordinance for which two-thirds (2/3) of the members of the consolidated local government council have voted. </section><section prefix="10">The council shall determine its own rules and order of business, and keep and provide a public record of its proceedings. The council shall provide for the publication of all ordinances in a composite code of ordinances. </section><section prefix="11">Council ordinances that prescribe penalties for their violation shall be enforced through the entire area of the consolidated local government unless: <section prefix="a">Otherwise provided by statute; or </section><section prefix="b">The legislative body of any city within the consolidated local government area has adopted an ordinance pertaining to the same subject matter that is the same as or more stringent than the standards set forth in the consolidated local government's ordinance. </section></section><section prefix="12">In the case of a vacancy on the consolidated local government council by reason of death, resignation, or removal, the council by majority vote of the membership of the council shall elect a qualified resident of the council district not later than thirty (30) days after the date the vacancy occurs. Should the council fail to elect, by majority vote of the membership of the council, a qualified person to fill the vacancy within thirty (30) days, the mayor of the consolidated local government shall fill the vacancy by appointment of a qualified person for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="13">All legislative powers of a consolidated local government are vested in the consolidated local government council. The term "legislative power" is to be construed broadly and shall include the power to: <section prefix="a">Enact ordinances, orders, and resolutions, and override a veto of the mayor by a two-thirds (2/3) majority of the membership of the legislative council; </section><section prefix="b">Review the budgets of and appropriate money to the consolidated local government; </section><section prefix="c">Adopt a budget ordinance; </section><section prefix="d">Levy taxes, subject to the limitations of the Constitution and the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="e">Establish standing and temporary committees; and </section><section prefix="f">Make independent audits and investigations concerning the affairs of the consolidated local government. </section></section><section prefix="14">The consolidated local government council shall be known as the legislative council of ...................../................... County Metro Government, which shall be a combination of the names of the largest city in existence in the county on the date of the adoption of the consolidated local government and the county. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 54, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40192</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>