<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.195</section_number><catch_line>Title to contraband seized in dry territory to be vested in appropriate court -- Destruction of contraband upon conviction of defendant. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Title to contraband included in KRS 244.180(1), (2), (3), (4), and (5) seized shall be vested in the appropriate court within whose jurisdiction the seizure occurred, irrespective of whether such contraband was seized by peace officers of the city or county or state administrators or field representatives of the department, notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 242.380. </section><section prefix="2">The court shall order the sheriff for the county in which such contraband as included in subsection (1) of this section was seized to destroy such contraband, except firearms or ammunition, upon conviction of the defendant. </section><section prefix="3">Contraband firearms and ammunition shall be transferred to the Department of Kentucky State Police for disposition as provided in KRS 500.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 592, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 274, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11455</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>