<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.083</section_number><catch_line>Taxpayer ombudsman -- Duties -- Annual reports.   </catch_line><order_by>083</order_by><text>The department shall provide the services of a taxpayer ombudsman to carry out the spirit and specific purposes of KRS 131.041 to 131.081. The taxpayer ombudsman shall: <section prefix="1">Coordinate the resolution of taxpayer complaints and problems, if so requested by a taxpayer or the taxpayer's representative; </section><section prefix="2">Provide recommendations to the department for new or revised informational publications and recommend taxpayer and department employee education programs needed to reduce or eliminate errors or improve voluntary taxpayer compliance; </section><section prefix="3">Provide recommendations to the department for simplification or other improvements needed in tax laws, regulations, forms, systems, and procedures to promote better understanding and voluntary compliance by taxpayers; and </section><section prefix="4">At least annually, on or before October 1, prepare and submit a report to the commissioner of the Department of Revenue summarizing the activities of the taxpayer ombudsman during the immediately preceding fiscal year, describing any recommendations made pursuant to subsections (2) and (3) of this section, including the progress in implementing such recommendations, and providing such other information as the taxpayer ombudsman deems appropriate relating to the rights of Kentucky taxpayers. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>