<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.430</section_number><catch_line>Notice of buyer's right to cancel home solicitation sale -- Emergency sales exempted. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a home solicitation sale, unless the buyer requests the seller to provide goods or services in an emergency, the seller must present to the buyer and obtain his signature to a written agreement or offer to purchase which designates as the date of the transaction the date on which the buyer actually signs and contains a statement of the buyer's rights which complies with subsection (2).  </section><section prefix="2">The statement must:  <section prefix="a">Appear under the conspicuous caption: "BUYER'S RIGHT TO CANCEL," and  </section><section prefix="b">Read as follows: "If this agreement was solicited to your residence and you do not want the goods or services, you may cancel this agreement by mailing a notice to the seller. The notice must say that you do not want the goods or services and must be mailed before midnight of the third business day after you sign this agreement. The notice must be mailed to:  </section>                           ......................................................................                            ......................................................................" </section><section prefix="3">Until the seller has complied with this section the buyer may cancel the home solicitation by notifying the seller in any manner and by any means of his intention to cancel.  </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 3. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34960</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>