<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.778</section_number><catch_line>Tangible personal property purchased out of state -- Collection of tax at titling or first registration -- Exemptions -- remittance to department. </catch_line><order_by>778</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county clerk shall collect any applicable sales and use tax for the following tangible personal property purchased out of state at the time the property is offered for titling or first registration: <section prefix="a">Recreational vehicles as defined in KRS 186.650; </section><section prefix="b">Manufactured homes as defined in KRS 186.650; </section><section prefix="c">Motorboats as defined in KRS 235.010; </section><section prefix="d">Vessels as defined in KRS 235.010; and </section><section prefix="e">Any other tangible personal property offered for titling or first registration in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">The tax shall be collected unless the owner: <section prefix="a">Presents a tax receipt from the seller verifying that the tax has been previously paid; </section><section prefix="b">Demonstrates that the transfer of the property is exempt under KRS 139.470(4); or </section><section prefix="c">Provides a properly executed resale certificate or certificate of exemption in accordance with KRS 139.270. </section></section><section prefix="3">The tax collected by the county clerk shall be reported and remitted to the department on forms provided by the department. </section><section prefix="4">For services provided in collecting the tax, the county clerk shall deduct a fee of three percent (3%) of the tax collected and remit the balance to the department as provided in KRS 138.464. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XIV, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>