<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.918</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for establishment of classification -- First ordinance. </catch_line><order_by>918</order_by><text>The governing body of any city desiring to establish special classes of sewer users shall initiate proceedings by adopting an ordinance to be known as the "First Ordinance," which shall state: <section prefix="1">The special classes of sewer users proposed to be created, the reasons and justifications for each classification, and the general geographical boundaries of each class, if susceptible of geographic identification; </section><section prefix="2">Whether a basic sewer service charge is proposed; </section><section prefix="3">The charges proposed initially for each special class; or, if such charges are dependent upon factors later to be determined, the formula, method, or basis upon which such charges will be established; </section><section prefix="4">Whether differences in charges, or schedules thereof shall be of indefinite duration, or of limited duration; </section><section prefix="5">Whether immediate construction and installation of sewer facilities, including reconstructing, replacing, repairing, extending, improving, enlarging, adding to, or completing any existing facilities, is proposed, and if so, a brief summary of preliminary findings and recommendations of an engineer, licensed by the Commonwealth, showing the occasion for such necessity and the general nature, scope, and estimated cost thereof; and </section><section prefix="6">The aggregate of revenues to be produced, and the amount of annual revenue estimated to be produced from users of each proposed special class. </section></text><history>Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 8, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1958 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26305</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>