<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-425</section_number><catch_line>Payment or acceptance of commission, brokerage, or other valuable consideration -- Exception.   </catch_line><order_by>9-425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No insurer, financial institution, agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, life settlement broker or provider, or consultant shall pay, directly or indirectly, any commission, brokerage, or other valuable consideration to any individual or business entity for services as an agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, life settlement broker or provider, or consultant within this state, unless the individual or business entity held at the time the services were performed a valid license for that line of insurance as required by the laws of this state for the services. </section><section prefix="2">No individual or business entity, other than an individual or business entity duly licensed by this state as an agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, life settlement broker or provider, or consultant at the time the services were performed, shall accept any commission, brokerage, or other valuable consideration for those services, unless the individual or business entity is licensed at the time the services were performed, if a license is required by law. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not prevent payment or receipt of renewal or other deferred commissions to or by any individual or business entity entitled under this section. </section><section prefix="4">Services as an agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, or consultant within this state shall not include a referral by an unlicensed person of a consumer to a licensed agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, or consultant that does not include a discussion of specific insurance policy terms and conditions. </section><section prefix="5">An insurer, financial institution, agent, surplus lines broker, adjuster, administrator, reinsurance intermediary broker or manager, rental vehicle agent or managing employee, or consultant may pay any compensation, fee, or other consideration to an individual not licensed to sell insurance for the referral of a consumer to a licensed individual, only if the consideration is paid regardless of whether the insurance coverage is sold to the consumer. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 31, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 32 intended to change all existing references in the KRS from "viatical settlements" to "life settlements." One reference to "viatical settlement" in this section was overlooked during the bill drafting process. The Reviser of Statutes has made this change upon the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42566</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>