<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.250</section_number><catch_line>Refiners' and importers' reports -- Deduction for evaporation, shrinkage and unaccountable losses -- Measurement of terminal storage tanks. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who produces, refines, manufactures or compounds gasoline or special fuel in this state shall, by the twenty-fifth day of each month, file a report with the Department of Revenue, on forms prescribed by it, covering the next preceding calendar month, showing the number of gallons of gasoline and special fuels at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit produced, refined, manufactured or compounded, the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit withdrawn from storage and received and the number of gallons withdrawn at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit from refinery storage and shipped to points outside of this state, and the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit withdrawn from refinery storage and shipped to points within this state upon which the tax has not been paid. This report shall give in detail such information as the department may require, regarding each separate shipment, the date of shipment, the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit in each shipment, the name of owner and license number of truck if shipped by transport truck, the initial and number of tank car if shipped by rail, the name and owner of barge if shipped by water, the name and address of person to whom shipped, the point of shipment, the point of destination and the name of carrier to whom delivered for transportation to destination. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who imports and stores gasoline or special fuel in any marine or pipeline terminal storage in this state, shall by the twenty-fifth day of the month, file a report with the Department of Revenue, on forms prescribed by it, covering the next preceding calendar month, showing the number of gallons of gasoline and special fuels at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit unexported and stored, the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit withdrawn from storage and received, the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit withdrawn from storage and shipped to points outside of this state, and the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit withdrawn from storage and shipped to points within this state, upon which the tax has not been paid. This report shall give in detail such information as the department may require, regarding each separate shipment, the date of shipment, the number of gallons at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit in each shipment, the name of owner and license number of truck if shipped by transport truck, the initial and number of tank car if shipped by rail, the name and owner of barge if shipped by water, the name and address of person to whom shipped, the point of shipment and point of destination, and the name of carrier to whom delivered for transportation to destination. </section><section prefix="3">There shall be allowed a monthly deduction for evaporation, shrinkage or unaccountable losses while in storage, of that number of gallons equal to the actual loss of gasoline or special fuel so sustained out of the total number of gallons of gasoline or special fuel stored in any marine terminal, refinery or pipeline terminal, except that such deduction may not in any event exceed three-fourths of one percent of the total number of gallons of gasoline or special fuel stored in any marine terminal, refinery or pipeline terminal. The remaining gasoline and special fuel placed in storage must be fully accounted for as in physical inventory, accountable loss, withdrawn for export or withdrawn from storage and received for taxable purposes. </section><section prefix="4">The number of gallons of gasoline or special fuel added to marine, pipeline or refinery storage shall be determined by the department by actual measurement of terminal storage tanks in the manner it deems necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 359, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 6, effective August 1, 1988. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 3. -- Amended 1956 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective March 27, 1956. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4281g-5. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>