<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="369" order_by="369">INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>369.116</section_number><catch_line>Transferable records. </catch_line><order_by>116</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "transferable record" means an electronic record that: <section prefix="a">Would be a note under Article 3 of KRS Chapter 355 or a document under Article 7 of KRS Chapter 355 if the electronic record were in writing; and </section><section prefix="b">The issuer of the electronic record expressly has agreed is a transferable record. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person has control of a transferable record if a system employed for evidencing the transfer of interests in the transferable record reliably establishes that person as the person to which the transferable record was issued or transferred. </section><section prefix="3">A system satisfies subsection (2) of this section, and a person is deemed to have control of a transferable record, if the transferable record is created, stored, and assigned in such a manner that: <section prefix="a">A single authoritative copy of the transferable record exists which is unique, identifiable, and, except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (d), (e), and (f) of this subsection, unalterable; </section><section prefix="b">The authoritative copy identifies the person asserting control as: <section prefix="1">The person to which the transferable record was issued; or </section><section prefix="2">If the authoritative copy indicates that the transferable record has been transferred, the person to which the transferable record was most recently transferred; </section></section><section prefix="c">The authoritative copy is communicated to and maintained by the person asserting control or its designated custodian; </section><section prefix="d">Copies of revisions that add or change an identified assignee of the authoritative copy can be made only with the consent of the person asserting control; </section><section prefix="e">Each copy of the authoritative copy and any copy of a copy is readily identifiable as a copy that is not the authoritative copy; and </section><section prefix="f">Any revision of the authoritative copy is readily identifiable as authorized or unauthorized. </section></section><section prefix="4">Except as otherwise agreed, a person having control of a transferable record is the holder, as defined in KRS 355.1-201(20), of the transferable record and has the same rights and defenses as a holder of an equivalent record or writing under KRS Chapter 355, including, if the applicable statutory requirements under KRS 355.3-302(1), 355.7-501, or 355.9-330 are satisfied, the rights and defenses of a holder in due course, a holder to which a negotiable document of title has been duly negotiated, or a purchaser, respectively. Delivery, possession, and indorsement are not required to obtain or exercise any of the rights under this subsection. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise agreed, an obligor under a transferable record has the same rights and defenses as an equivalent obligor under equivalent records or writing under KRS Chapter 355. </section><section prefix="6">If requested by a person against which enforcement is sought, the person seeking to enforce the transferable record shall provide reasonable proof that the person is in control of the transferable record. Proof may include access to the authoritative copy of the transferable record and related business records sufficient to review the terms of the transferable record and to establish the identity of the person having control of the transferable record. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch.  301, sec. 23, effective July 1 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 16, effective August 1, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>