<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subchapter.   </catch_line><order_by>47-005</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Approved network" means a flexible manufacturing network approved by the cabinet in accordance with KRS 154.47-040; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Economic Development; </section><section prefix="3">"Center" means the Quicksand Wood Utilization Center located in Breathitt County, Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">"Certified tree farmer" means a person whose tree farm is certified by the Kentucky Tree Farm Committee and approved by the American Forest Foundation; </section><section prefix="5">"Council" means the Kentucky Forest Products Council as created in KRS 154.47-110; </section><section prefix="6">"Flexible manufacturing network" or "network" means an affiliation of secondary wood products businesses as provided by KRS 154.47-040; </section><section prefix="7">"Forest steward" means a person whose forest property is certified as a stewardship forest and approved by the Division of Forestry of the Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="8">"Procurement area" means an area specified by the applicant in a radius of miles from the applicant's site of operations from which the applicant acquires raw wood products; </section><section prefix="9">"Secondary wood products industry" means businesses that compose that segment of the forest products industry that manufacture, assemble, process, or produce wood into a finished or semifinished product; however, the "secondary wood products industry" does not include primary wood products operations such as logging, sawmilling, chip milling, veneer milling, or pulp milling. Businesses that include both primary and secondary wood products operations are deemed to be within the secondary wood products industry only in regard to their secondary wood products operations; and </section><section prefix="10">"Wood industry hub" or "hub" means a system in which the technical and workforce training needs of the secondary wood products industry are integrated. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42110</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>