<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.100</section_number><catch_line>Membership. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Judicial Council composed of the following persons: The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court or his designee from among the members of that court; the Chief Judge of the Court of Appeals or his designee from among the members of that court; four (4) Circuit Judges, and four (4) District Judges, all of whom shall be appointed by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court; the president of the Kentucky Association of Circuit Court Clerks; three (3) members of the State Bar of Kentucky who shall be appointed by its board of governors; and the chairmen of the Judiciary Committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate, or the vice chairman of any of these committees if the chairman declines to serve. </section><section prefix="2">The appointed members shall serve for a term of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify. Vacancies in the office of appointed members shall be filled by the original appointing authority. </section><section prefix="3">The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall be the chairman of the council, or if he is not a member or declines to serve as chairman, a member of the council shall be appointed by him to serve as chairman. The administrative director of the courts shall serve as secretary. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>