<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-806</section_number><catch_line>Known claims against dissolved limited partnership. </catch_line><order_by>2-806</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dissolved limited partnership may dispose of the known claims against it by following the procedure described in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A dissolved limited partnership may in a record notify its known claimants of the dissolution. The notice shall: <section prefix="a">Specify the information required to be included in a claim; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a mailing address to which the claim is to be sent; </section><section prefix="c">State the deadline for receipt of the claim, which shall not be less than one hundred twenty (120) days after the date the notice in a record is received by the claimant; </section><section prefix="d">State that the claim will be barred if not received by the deadline; and </section><section prefix="e">Unless the limited partnership has been throughout its existence a limited liability limited partnership, state that the barring of a claim against the limited partnership will also bar any corresponding claim against any present or dissociated general partner which is based on KRS 362.2-404. </section></section><section prefix="3">A claim against a dissolved limited partnership is barred if the requirements of subsection (2) of this section are met and: <section prefix="a">The claim is not received by the specified deadline; or </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a claim that is timely received but rejected by the dissolved limited partnership, the claimant does not commence a proceeding to enforce the claim against the limited partnership within ninety (90) days after the receipt of the notice of the rejection. </section></section><section prefix="4">This section does not apply to a contingent liability or a claim based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 154, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34616</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>