<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.816</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for refusal to consider or to disqualify an applicant for, or to remove a person from, a certified or equivalent position.   </catch_line><order_by>816</order_by><text>Except as provided by the provisions of KRS 156.800 to 156.860, the appointing authority or designee for the Office of Career and Technical Education may refuse to consider an applicant for a certified or equivalent position or, after consideration, may disqualify the applicant or may remove an employee already appointed if: <section prefix="1">It is found that the person did not maintain certification or that certification has been revoked for the position; </section><section prefix="2">The person is unable to perform the duties of the position; </section><section prefix="3">The person made a false statement of material fact in the application; </section><section prefix="4">The application was not submitted correctly or within the prescribed time limits; </section><section prefix="5">The person has been convicted of a felony within the preceding five (5) years and has not had civil rights restored or has not been pardoned by the Governor; </section><section prefix="6">The person has been convicted of a job related misdemeanor, except that convictions for violations of traffic regulations shall not constitute grounds for disqualification; </section><section prefix="7">The person has previously been dismissed from a position in his department for cause or has resigned while charges for dismissal for cause of which the person had knowledge were pending; or </section><section prefix="8">The person has otherwise violated the provisions of KRS 156.800 to 156.860. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 27, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (17) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification>KRS 151B.050. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42167</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>