<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.562Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Abandoned Storage Tank Reclamation Program.   </catch_line><order_by>562Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Abandoned Storage Tank Reclamation Program. The purpose of the program is to reclaim abandoned storage tank facilities in order to return the property to productive use. Reclamation of abandoned storage tank facilities shall include removing necessary tank infrastructure and removing primary and secondary sources of contamination of the land, air, and water. Abandoned storage tank facilities enrolled in the program shall be eligible for reclamation and clean up funds from the Kentucky abandoned storage tank reclamation fund. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky abandoned storage tank reclamation fund is hereby created as an interest-bearing, restricted, agency account. The fund shall be administered by the cabinet. Interest credited to the account shall be retained in the account. Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section and KRS 353.561, 353.563, and 353.564. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the fund shall be for carrying out the purpose provided in subsection (1) of this section including any administrative costs set forth in this section and KRS 353.561, 353.563, and 353.564. The fund may receive moneys from federal and state grants or appropriations, and from any other proceeds for the purposes of this section and KRS 353.561, 353.563, and 353.564. </section><section prefix="4">Funds expended for costs incurred in reclaiming abandoned storage tank facilities shall be in accordance with the provisions of this section and after the cabinet deems that: <section prefix="a">There is no person identified or found with continuing legal responsibility for the abandoned storage tank facility; or </section><section prefix="b">Reclamation measures are necessary to respond to an imminent threat to the public health, safety, and environment. </section></section><section prefix="5">Reclamation measures paid for by the fund shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Removal and disposal of abandoned storage tank facilities; and </section><section prefix="b">Reclamation of lands affected by abandoned storage tank facilities including: <section prefix="1">Removal of aboveground flow lines; </section><section prefix="2">Removal or treatment of contaminated soil to no more than three (3) feet in depth; </section><section prefix="3">Elimination of all berms, dikes, and other structures utilized as spill prevention, control, and countermeasure structures; and </section><section prefix="4">Grading and seeding of the surface where the tank or tank battery was located. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">If during the course of removing and reclaiming an abandoned storage tank facility, the division observes evidence of soil contamination below three (3) feet depth, the division shall consult with the Department for Environmental Protection to determine whether further action is necessary to protect public health and the environment. Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to obligate the fund to provide additional moneys for removal or treatment of contaminated soil other than provided in subsection (5)(b)2. of this section. </section><section prefix="7">Any person performing reclamation measures pursuant to this section shall comply with applicable local, state, and federal laws and regulations. </section><section prefix="8">The cabinet shall have the authority to: <section prefix="a">Contract for services provided by and engage in cooperative projects with other government agencies for the remediation, cleanup, and disposal of abandoned storage tanks; </section><section prefix="b">Enter into agreements with those government agencies to compensate those agencies with funds from the account; and </section><section prefix="c">Accept and deposit into the fund any federal, state, and other funds for the purposes of this section and KRS 353.6603, 353.6605, and 353.6606. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44241</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>