<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.213</section_number><catch_line>Interim expense allowances for members. </catch_line><order_by>213</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the per diem and all allowances provided by law to members of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, each member of the Legislature is hereby granted an expense allowance of nine hundred fifty dollars ($950) per month for secretarial assistance, books and periodicals, other reports or publications, conduct of small-scale studies related to governmental activity, postage, telephone service, or any other expense incident to performance of the legislator's duties. </section><section prefix="2">The expense allowance provided for herein shall not be payable during any session of the General Assembly. For sessions occurring during a part of the month, the expense allowance shall be prorated. </section><section prefix="3">Such expense allowances shall be paid by the State Treasury out of the general fund of the Commonwealth upon warrant of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, issued on the certification of the director of the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449,sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 3, effective March 31, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 10, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 4. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 5. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 31, secs. 1 to 3. </history><metadata><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (1) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=280</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>