<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="405" order_by="405">PARENT AND CHILD </unit></structure><section_number>405.025</section_number><catch_line>Parent or guardian liable for willful damage to property caused by minor. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The parent or guardian of any unemancipated minor, in his care and custody, against whom judgment has been rendered for the willful marking upon, defacing or damaging of any property, shall be liable for the payment of that judgment up to an amount not to exceed twenty-five hundred dollars ($2500), if the parent or guardian has been joined as a party defendant in the original action. The judgment provided herein to be paid shall be paid to the owner of the property damaged but such payment shall not be a bar to any criminal action or any proceeding against the unemancipated minor committing such damage for the balance of the judgment not paid by the parent or guardian.  No parent or guardian shall be liable under the provisions of this subsection in a cumulative amount in excess of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) for the willful marking upon, defacing or damaging of any property by any child.  </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section is intended to or shall limit to twenty-five hundred dollars ($2500) the liability of a person to whom the negligence of a minor is imputed by KRS 186.590, nor shall this section limit the liability set forth in any other statute to the contrary.  </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 44, secs. 1, 2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>