<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.337</section_number><catch_line>Legislative finding -- Certain administrative regulations void -- Prohibition  against promulgating substantially similar regulations -- Judicial review. </catch_line><order_by>337</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that certain administrative regulations, as evidenced by the records of the Legislative Research Commission, including but not limited to the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service and the Administrative Register of Kentucky, were found deficient on or after July 15, 1988, and either expired prior to or upon adjournment of the 2001 General Assembly, or were scheduled to expire upon adjournment of the 2002 Regular Session of the General Assembly, under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A as existing before the issuance of the Opinion and Order of the Franklin Circuit Court in Patton v. Sherman et al., Civil Action No. 01-CI-00660, entered January 11, 2002. </section><section prefix="2">Contrary provisions of any section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, the administrative regulations identified in subsection (1) of this section shall be null, void, and unenforceable, as follows: <section prefix="a">Those administrative regulations identified in subsection (1) of this section which expired prior to or upon adjournment of the 2001 Regular Session of the General Assembly under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A existing before the issuance of the court order referenced in subsection (1) of this section shall be null, void, and unenforceable as of their recorded date of expiration, according to the records of the Legislative Research Commission. Administrative bodies and regulated persons and entities have relied on the assumption that these administrative regulations have previously expired; therefore, this subsection shall have the retroactive effect necessary to implement its provisions; and </section><section prefix="b">Those administrative regulations identified in subsection (1) of this section due to expire upon adjournment of the 2002 Regular Session of the General Assembly, under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A existing before the issuance of the court order referenced in subsection (1) of this section, shall be null, void, and unenforceable on March 27, 2002. </section></section><section prefix="3">Contrary provisions of any section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, an administrative body shall be prohibited from promulgating an administrative regulation that is identical to or substantially the same as any administrative regulation identified in subsection (1) of this section for a period beginning on January 11, 2002, and concluding upon adjournment of the 2003 Regular Session of the General Assembly. This subsection shall have the retroactive effect necessary to implement its provisions. </section><section prefix="4">The Legislative Research Commission may file an action in the Franklin Circuit Court for judicial review to determine if any administrative regulation is lawfully promulgated in accordance with the laws and Constitution of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective March 27, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> March 27, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=777</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>