<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="530" order_by="530">FAMILY OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>530.064</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful transaction with a minor in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>064</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of unlawful transaction with a minor in the first degree when he or she knowingly induces, assists, or causes a minor to engage in: <section prefix="a">Illegal sexual activity; or </section><section prefix="b">Illegal controlled substances activity other than activity involving marijuana, synthetic drugs, or salvia, as defined in KRS 218A.010; </section></section> Except those offenses involving minors in KRS Chapter 531 and in KRS 529.100 where that offense involves commercial sexual activity. <section prefix="2">Unlawful transaction with a minor in the first degree is a: <section prefix="a">Class C felony if the minor so used is less than eighteen (18) years old at the time the minor engages in the prohibited activity; </section><section prefix="b">Class B felony if the minor so used is less than sixteen (16) years old at the time the minor engages in the prohibited activity; and </section><section prefix="c">Class A felony if the minor so used incurs physical injury thereby. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 16, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.45, sec.14, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 16, effective April 13, 2010; and ch. 160, sec. 16, effective April 26, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 13, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 38, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 184, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40039</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>