<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9203</section_number><catch_line>Documentation to be furnished by seller of unit -- Certificate. </catch_line><order_by>9203</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 381.9201(2), a seller of a unit shall furnish to a purchaser or purchaser's agent before execution of any contract for sale of a unit, or otherwise before conveyance, a copy of the declaration, other than the plats and plans, and a copy of the bylaws, the rules or regulations of the association, and a certificate, current to the date of issuance and signed and dated by the association's manager or authorized agent, containing: <section prefix="a">A statement disclosing the effect on the proposed disposition of any right of first refusal or other restraint on the free alienability of the unit; </section><section prefix="b">A statement setting forth the amount of the monthly common expense assessment and any unpaid common expense, emergency assessment, or special assessment currently due and payable from the selling unit owner; </section><section prefix="c">A statement of any other fees payable by unit owners; </section><section prefix="d">A statement of any capital expenditures anticipated by the association for the current and, if known, next two (2) fiscal years; </section><section prefix="e">A statement of the amount of any reserves for capital expenditures, if any, and of any portions of those reserves designated by the association for any specified projects; </section><section prefix="f">The most recent regularly prepared balance sheet and income and expense statement, if any, of the association; </section><section prefix="g">The current operating budget of the association; </section><section prefix="h">The date of the most current financial report prepared for the association pursuant to KRS 381.9197; </section><section prefix="i">A statement of any unsatisfied judgments against the association, the status of any pending suits in which the association is a defendant, or any pending suits in which the association is a named party and the amount in dispute or contest is more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000); </section><section prefix="j">A statement describing any insurance coverage maintained by the association or an attachment of a certificate of insurance issued to the association; and </section><section prefix="k">If any portion of the condominium is situated upon a leasehold estate, a statement of the remaining term of any leasehold estate affecting the condominium and the provisions governing any extension or renewal thereof. </section></section><section prefix="2">The association shall, within ten (10) days after receipt of a written request by a unit owner, furnish a certificate containing the information necessary to enable the unit owner to comply with subsection (1) of this section. A unit owner or unit owner's agent providing a purchaser with the certificate issued pursuant to this subsection shall not be liable to the purchaser for any erroneous information provided by the association and included in the certificate. </section><section prefix="3">A unit owner or unit owner's agent shall not be liable to a purchaser for the failure or delay of the association to provide the certificate in a timely manner, but the sales contract is voidable by the purchaser until the certificate has been provided and for five (5) days thereafter or until conveyance, whichever first occurs. </section><section prefix="4">An association may not deny the validity of any statement in the certificate. </section><section prefix="5">Failure to provide a certificate does not void a deed to a purchaser. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 10, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 52, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40017</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>