<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="238" order_by="238">CHARITABLE GAMING </unit></structure><section_number>238.547</section_number><catch_line>Special limited charitable fundraising event licenses -- Limitation -- Times  -- Locations -- Restrictions on wagering, stakes, and prizes. </catch_line><order_by>547</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A licensed charitable organization shall be limited to two (2) special limited charity fundraising event licenses per year, and a special limited charity fundraising event shall be limited to one (1) session not to exceed six (6) hours. A special limited charity fundraising event shall be conducted only between the hours of 12 noon and 1 a.m. </section><section prefix="2">A special limited charity fundraising event may be held: <section prefix="a">On or in the premises of a licensed charitable organization; </section><section prefix="b">In a licensed charitable gaming facility, subject to restrictions contained in KRS 238.555(7); or </section><section prefix="c">At an unlicensed facility under the following conditions: <section prefix="1">An unlicensed facility shall host no more than one (1) special limited charity fundraising event per year; </section><section prefix="2">The facility shall be closed to the general public during the conduct of a special limited charity fundraising event or the event shall be held in a separate room or area not accessible to the general public; </section><section prefix="3">Equipment used in the conduct of a special limited charity fundraising event shall be removed from the premises within two (2) working days after the event; and </section><section prefix="4">The unlicensed facility shall be subject to requirements stipulated in KRS 238.555(3). </section></section></section><section prefix="3">No cash shall be used in playing special limited charity games at a special limited charity fundraising event. Games shall be played with chips, scrip, or imitation money which shall be purchased only through a central bank or cashier under the authority of the chairperson designated by the licensed charitable organization conducting the special limited charity fundraising event. No chips, scrip, or imitation money shall be sold at a gaming table or by a dealer. </section><section prefix="4">Chips, scrip, or imitation money may be redeemed for cash or prizes. Prizes to be offered and their fair market values shall be displayed or listed in a conspicuous location within the gaming area. Prizes shall be redeemed directly or through an auction process within twenty-four (24) hours after the conclusion of the event. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 10, effective April 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 1, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11203</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>