<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.6-015</section_number><catch_line>Organization procedure. </catch_line><order_by>6-015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any seven (7) or more residents of this state, of legal age, who have a common bond referred to in KRS 286.6-107 may organize a credit union and become charter members thereof by complying with this section. </section><section prefix="2">The subscribers shall execute in duplicate articles of incorporation and agree to the terms thereof, which articles shall state: <section prefix="a">The name, which shall include the words "credit union" and which shall not be the same as that of any other credit union in this state, and the location where the proposed credit union is to have its principal place of business; </section><section prefix="b">That the existence of the credit union shall be perpetual; </section><section prefix="c">The par value of the shares of the credit union; and </section><section prefix="d">The names and addresses of the subscribers to the articles of incorporation, and the number of shares subscribed to by each, which shall be determined by the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">The subscribers shall prepare and adopt bylaws for the general government of the credit union, consistent with this subtitle, and execute the same in duplicate. </section><section prefix="4">The subscribers shall select at least five (5) qualified persons who agree to serve on the board of directors, and at least three (3) other qualified persons who agree to serve on the supervisory committee. A signed agreement to serve in these capacities until the first annual meeting or until the election of their successors, whichever is later, shall be executed by those who so agree. </section><section prefix="5">The subscribers shall forward any required fee, the articles of incorporation, the bylaws and the agreements to serve to the commissioner, who shall act upon the application for a charter within thirty (30) days. The commissioner shall issue a certificate of approval, if the articles and bylaws are in conformity with this subtitle and the commissioner is satisfied that: <section prefix="a">The characteristics of the sponsoring group are favorable to the economic viability of such credit union; </section><section prefix="b">The standing and character of the proposed organizers are such as to give assurance that its affairs will be properly administered; and </section><section prefix="c">The share and deposit insurance requirements of KRS 286.6-405 will be met. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commissioner shall return a copy of the bylaws and the articles to the applicants or their representatives, which shall be preserved in the permanent files of the credit union. </section><section prefix="7">The subscribers for a credit union charter may not transact any business until formal approval of the charter has been received. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 716, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 290.015. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>