<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.723</section_number><catch_line>When physician may perform abortion -- Guidelines. </catch_line><order_by>723</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No abortion shall be performed except by a physician after either:  <section prefix="a">He determines that, in his best clinical judgment, the abortion is necessary; or  </section><section prefix="b">He receives what he reasonably believes to be a written statement signed by another physician, hereinafter called the "referring physician," certifying that in the referring physician's best clinical judgment the abortion is necessary, and, in addition, he receives a copy of the report form required by KRS 213.055.  </section></section><section prefix="2">No abortion shall be performed except in compliance with regulations which the cabinet shall issue to assure that:  <section prefix="a">Before the abortion is performed, the pregnant woman shall have a private medical consultation either with the physician who is to perform the abortion or with the referring physician in a place, at a time and of a duration reasonably sufficient to enable the physician to determine whether, based upon his best clinical judgment, the abortion is necessary;  </section><section prefix="b">The physician who is to perform the abortion or the referring physician will describe the basis for his best clinical judgment that the abortion is necessary on a form prescribed by the cabinet as required by KRS 213.055; and  </section><section prefix="c">Paragraph (a) of this subsection shall not apply when, in the medical judgment of the attending physician based on the particular facts of the case before him, there exists a medical emergency. In such a case, the physician shall describe the basis of his medical judgment that an emergency exists on a form prescribed by the cabinet as required by KRS 213.055.  </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any statute to the contrary, nothing in this chapter shall be construed as prohibiting a physician from prescribing or a woman from using birth control methods or devices, including, but not limited to, intrauterine devices, oral contraceptives, or any other birth control method or device.  </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><lrc-note>(6/19/97).  KRS 213.055, which is cited within this statute, was repealed by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 38, effective July 13, 1990. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>