<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6029</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Rural Innovation Program -- Purposes. </catch_line><order_by>6029</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established in the Council on Postsecondary Education a Kentucky Rural Innovation Program to provide awards to rural Kentucky-based, small companies to undertake research, development, and entrepreneurial innovation work in partnership with Kentucky postsecondary institutions, the Small Business Development Center Network in Kentucky, and other entities engaged in research and development work. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the Kentucky Rural Innovation Program is to: <section prefix="a">Accelerate knowledge transfer and technological innovation that improve economic competitiveness and spur economic growth in rural, Kentucky-based, small companies; </section><section prefix="b">Support entrepreneurial activities that have clear potential to lead to commercially successful products, processes, or services within a reasonable period of time; </section><section prefix="c">Stimulate growth-oriented enterprises within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">Encourage partnerships and collaborative projects between private enterprises, Kentucky's postsecondary institutions, research organizations, and the Small Business Development Center Network in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="e">Promote research, development, and entrepreneurial activities that are driven by private sector requirements. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4355</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>