<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.330</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction of court to liquidate assets and affairs of corporation. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Courts of equity shall have full power to liquidate the assets and affairs of a corporation: <section prefix="a">In an action by a member or director when it is made to appear: <section prefix="1">That the directors are deadlocked in the management of the corporate affairs and that irreparable injury to the corporation is being suffered or is threatened by reason thereof, and either that the members are unable to break the deadlock or there are no members having voting rights; </section><section prefix="2">That the acts of the directors or those in control of the corporation are illegal, oppressive or fraudulent; </section><section prefix="3">That the members entitled to vote in the election of directors are deadlocked in voting power and have failed for at least two (2) years to elect successors to directors whose terms have expired or would have expired upon the election of their successors; </section><section prefix="4">That the corporate assets are being misapplied or wasted; or </section><section prefix="5">That the corporation is unable to carry out its purposes. </section></section><section prefix="b">In an action by a creditor: <section prefix="1">When the claim of the creditor has been reduced to judgment and an execution thereon has been returned unsatisfied and it is established that the corporation is insolvent; or </section><section prefix="2">When the corporation has admitted in writing that the claim of the creditor is due and owing and it is established that the corporation is insolvent. </section></section><section prefix="c">Upon application by a corporation to have its dissolution continued under the supervision of the court. </section><section prefix="d">When an action has been filed by the Attorney General to dissolve a corporation and it is established that liquidation of its affairs should precede the entry of a decree of dissolution. </section></section><section prefix="2">Proceedings under this section shall be brought in the Circuit Court in which the registered office or the principal office of the corporation is situated. </section><section prefix="3">It shall not be necessary to make directors or members parties to any such action or proceedings unless relief is sought against them personally. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 53. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13695</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>