<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.470</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.470 to 211.478.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.470 to 211.478: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Traumatic Brain Injury Trust Fund Board created pursuant to KRS 211.472; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Traumatic brain injury" means a partial or total disability caused by injury to the central nervous system from physical trauma, damage to the central nervous system from anoxia, hypoxic episodes, allergic conditions, toxic substances, or other acute medical clinical incidents resulting in impaired cognitive abilities or impaired physical functioning. "Traumatic brain injury" does not include: <section prefix="a">Strokes that can be treated in nursing facilities providing routine rehabilitation services; </section><section prefix="b">Spinal cord injuries for which there are no known or obvious injuries to the intracranial central nervous system; </section><section prefix="c">Progressive dementias and other mentally impairing conditions; </section><section prefix="d">Depression and psychiatric disorders in which there is no known or obvious central nervous system damage; </section><section prefix="e">An intellectual disability and birth defect related disorders of long standing nature; or </section><section prefix="f">Neurological degenerative, metabolic, and other medical conditions of a chronic, degenerative nature; and </section></section><section prefix="4">"Trust fund" means the traumatic brain injury trust fund created pursuant to KRS 211.476. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 99, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 359, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40827</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>