<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-202</section_number><catch_line>Amendment or restatement of certificate.   </catch_line><order_by>2-202</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to amend its certificate of limited partnership, a limited partnership shall deliver to the Secretary of State for filing an amendment that satisfies KRS 14A.2-010 to 14A.2-150 or, pursuant to KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963, articles of merger, stating: <section prefix="a">The name of the limited partnership; </section><section prefix="b">The date of filing of its initial certificate; and </section><section prefix="c">The changes the amendment makes to the certificate as most recently amended or restated. </section></section><section prefix="2">A limited partnership shall promptly deliver to the Secretary of State for filing an amendment to a certificate of limited partnership to reflect: <section prefix="a">The admission of a new general partner; </section><section prefix="b">The dissociation of a person as a general partner; or </section><section prefix="c">The appointment of a person to wind up the limited partnership's activities under KRS 362.2-803(3) or (4). </section></section><section prefix="3">A general partner who knows that any information in a filed certificate of limited partnership was false when the certificate was filed or has become false due to changed circumstances shall promptly: <section prefix="a">Cause the certificate to be amended; or </section><section prefix="b">If appropriate, deliver to the Secretary of State for filing a statement of change pursuant to KRS 14A.5-010 or a statement of correction pursuant to KRS 14A.2-090. </section></section><section prefix="4">A certificate of limited partnership may be amended at any time for any other proper purpose as determined by the limited partnership. </section><section prefix="5">A restated certificate of limited partnership may be delivered to the Secretary of State for filing in the same manner as an amendment. </section><section prefix="6">An amendment or restated certificate is effective as provided in KRS 14A.2-070. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 106, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 106, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36809</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>