<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.210</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and local health boards. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the local boards of health may examine into all nuisances, sources of filth, and causes of sickness that may, in their opinion, be injurious to the health of the inhabitants in any county in this state, or in any vessel within any harbor or port in any county in this state. Whenever any such nuisance, source of filth, or cause of sickness is found to exist on any private property, or in any vessel within any port or harbor in any county in this state, or upon any watercourse in this state, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the local board of health may order, in writing, the owner or occupant thereof, at his own expense, to remove the same within twenty-four (24) hours, or within such reasonable time thereafter as the board may order. </section><section prefix="2">If drinking water used by school children is found to be dangerous to their health, the local board of health or Cabinet for Health and Family Services may order that a supply of pure water be furnished at the expense of the county or city board of education. </section><section prefix="3">If in the opinion of the local board of health or Cabinet for Health and Family Services a school building is constructed in violation of law and is found to be unsanitary or unsafe for the housing of children, the local board of health or Cabinet for Health and Family Services may institute an action in the Circuit Court of the county where the building is situated, and the court, after due hearing and verifying the facts, may order a safe and sanitary school building to be erected within a reasonable time by the county or city board of education in accordance with the laws of the state governing the erection of schoolhouses and the control of disease, and the rules and regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="4">Any local board of health shall, for the purpose of controlling and eradicating rats and other unsanitary nuisances, require the owner or possessor of any building designed for human habitation and containing two (2) or more apartment units, to provide, where a specific area has been designated for the depositing of refuse on the premises, waste receptacles approved by the board. The board may further require that the design, construction, and maintenance of the area in which the waste receptacles are kept meet reasonable standards set by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 402, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 353, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2054a-14, 2057. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8589</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>