<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.491Certification</section_number><catch_line>of an electrical installation by an inspector -- Invalidation by another inspector prohibited -- Certification and inspection of electrical installation without seal prohibited -- Other duties of inspector -- Sanctions for inspector's failure to comply.   </catch_line><order_by>491Certification</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An electrical inspector who certifies an electrical installation shall furnish and attach an approval sticker, bearing his or her signature and certification number in a conspicuous place on the main service entrance equipment. He or she shall also provide the owner of the electrical installation or his or her authorized agent with a certificate of approval if the same is requested. A complete record of each inspection shall be kept by the inspector and these records shall be made available to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction upon its request. </section><section prefix="2">An electrical inspector shall: <section prefix="a">Not attempt to supplant, overrule, or otherwise invalidate the judgment of another electrical inspector whose services for a particular building, structure, or other project have been solicited by an owner, contractor, municipality, or other person without first obtaining express written consent from the designated inspector's office supervising the original inspector; </section><section prefix="b">Not certify unlicensed or unlawful electrical installations; </section><section prefix="c">Not certify or inspect an electrical installation in a manufactured home or mobile home where the certified installer seal is not present pursuant to KRS 227.570; </section><section prefix="d">Not certify or inspect an electrical installation in a previously owned manufactured home or a previously owned mobile home when a Class B1 seal is not present as required by KRS 227.605; and </section><section prefix="e">Verify required electrical licensure on projects within the inspector's jurisdiction. The electrical inspector shall report all electrical licensure violations to the department within ten (10) days of discovery. </section></section><section prefix="3">Failure of an electrical inspector to comply with any provision of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall subject that inspector to review by the commissioner of housing, buildings and construction with possible suspension of certification for a period not to exceed one (1) year from the date of the commissioner's ruling. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 407, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 222, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 47, effective July 1, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>