<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="107" order_by="107">MUNICIPAL IMPROVEMENTS -- ALTERNATE METHODS </unit></structure><section_number>107.320</section_number><catch_line>Community improvement districts for counties containing a city with population of 3,000 or more -- Corporate powers.   </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text>In counties containing a city with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, a community improvement district may be created as provided in KRS 65.182 for the purpose of erecting buildings and related facilities for any governmental unit, or combination of governmental units, in the county. Any community improvement district so created shall include all of the territory in the county, including the area of incorporated cities, and shall be designated the "County Community Improvement District" (hereinafter called the "district"). The district shall constitute a public body corporate, with perpetual succession and power in its name to contract and be contracted with, sue and be sued, adopt bylaws, have and use a corporate seal, and exercise all of the powers granted to public nonprofit corporations generally by KRS Chapter 273, except such powers as may be inconsistent with specific provisions of KRS 107.310 to 107.500. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 209, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 238, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 1. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>