<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">A RECREATIONAL VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190A.030</section_number><catch_line>Conditions applicable to area of sales responsibility of a new recreational vehicle dealer included in an agreement between a new recreational vehicle manufacturer and a dealer -- Prohibition against sales activity outside of designated area -- Exception.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following conditions shall apply to the area of sales responsibility of a new recreational vehicle dealer included in a dealer agreement between a new recreational vehicle manufacturer and a dealer: <section prefix="a">A manufacturer or distributor shall not sell a recreational vehicle in this state to or through a dealer without first having entered into a written dealer agreement with a dealer which has been signed by both parties; </section><section prefix="b">The new recreational vehicle manufacturer shall designate in the dealer agreement the area of sales responsibility in which the dealer has the exclusive right to display or sell the manufacturer's new recreational vehicles of a line-make included in the dealer agreement; </section><section prefix="c">The manufacturer shall not contract with another dealer for the sale of the same line-make included in the designated area for the duration of the agreement; and </section><section prefix="d">The area of sales responsibility shall not be reviewed or changed without the consent of both parties until one (1) year after the execution of the dealer agreement. </section></section><section prefix="2">A new recreational vehicle dealer shall not conduct sales activity or display for sale recreational vehicles outside of its designated area of sales responsibility except as provided in KRS 190.030(7) and the laws of this state. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43550</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>