<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.350</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of canceled checks -- Microfilm reproductions of checks, printed warrants, and electronic fund transfers. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Canceled checks of the State Treasurer upon state depository banks shall be microfilmed and the original check preserved by the State Treasurer for a period of one (1) year. At the expiration of this period, unless required for the purpose of an action then pending, the checks shall be sold as waste paper or destroyed. Microfilm reproductions of Treasury Department checks shall be preserved for a period of five (5) years. Microfilm reproductions of printed warrants shall be preserved for a period of five (5) years. </section><section prefix="2">Microfilm reproductions of electronic fund transfer entries debiting state accounts transmitted to the State Treasurer by state depositories shall be preserved by the State Treasurer for a period of five (5) years. At the expiration of this period, unless required for the purpose of an action then pending, they may be destroyed. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1983; and ch. 382, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>