<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.0441</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet to license and regulate adult day care health programs. </catch_line><order_by>0441</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "adult day health care program" means a program licensed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services that provides organized health care for its clients during specified daytime hours, that may include continuous supervision to assure that health care needs are being met, supervision of self-administration of medications, and provision of nursing services, personal care services, self-care training, and social and recreational activities for individuals of all ages. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish health, safety, and treatment requirements for licensed adult day health care programs. No person, association, corporation, or other organization shall operate or maintain an adult day health care program without first obtaining a license as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may issue a license upon request to any adult day health care program meeting the standards required under subsection (2) of this section and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. The cabinet may deny, revoke, suspend, or modify an adult day health care program license for failure to comply with standards set by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Services provided in an adult day health care program for its clients may include: <section prefix="a">Medical therapeutic services; and </section><section prefix="b">Physical and speech therapy. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 505, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9194</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>