<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.100</section_number><catch_line>Fees -- Application for renewal or reinstatement of license. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each licensee licensed under the provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall annually, on or before the last day of the licensee's birth month, pay to the department a renewal fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="2">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed after the anniversary date of the license during which time a licensee may continue to practice and may renew his or her license upon payment of the renewal fee plus a late renewal fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the department. </section><section prefix="3">A license not renewed before the end of the sixty (60) day grace period shall terminate based on the failure of the licensee to renew in a timely manner. Upon termination, the licensee is no longer eligible to practice in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">After the sixty (60) day grace period, a former licensee with a terminated license may have the license reinstated upon payment of the renewal fee plus a reinstatement fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the department. An applicant for reinstatement after termination of the license shall not be required to submit to any examination as a condition for reinstatement, if the reinstatement application is made within three (3) years from the date of termination. </section><section prefix="5">A suspended license is subject to expiration and termination and shall be renewed as provided in this section. Renewal shall not entitle the licensee to engage in the practice until the suspension has ended or is otherwise removed by the department and the right to practice is restored by the department. </section><section prefix="6">A revoked license is subject to expiration or termination but may not be renewed. If it is reinstated, the former licensee shall pay the reinstatement fee as promulgated by administrative regulations under subsection (4) of this section and the renewal fee as promulgated by administrative regulations under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">The department shall require an applicant for renewal or reinstatement of a license to show evidence of completing at least six (6) hours of continuing education provided by the National Electrical Contractors Association, the Associated Builders and Contractors, the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, the Associated General Contractors, the International Association of Electrical Inspectors, the Independent Electrical Contractors Association, the Kentucky Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, or other provider of instruction approved by the department. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing the content of the programs and the qualifications of the providers. </section><section prefix="8">The department shall require, where applicable, that an applicant for renewal or reinstatement of a license submit proof that the applicant has complied with workers' compensation and unemployment insurance laws and regulations and has obtained a general liability insurance policy of not less than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). </section><section prefix="9">The department may, through the promulgation of administrative regulations: <section prefix="a">Establish an inactive license for licensees who are not actively engaging in the electrical business but wish to maintain their license; </section><section prefix="b">Reduce license and renewal fees for inactive licensees; and </section><section prefix="c">Waive the requirements established in subsection (8) of this section for inactive licensees. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 436, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3, effective April 6, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>