<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="221" order_by="221">FROZEN FOOD LOCKER PLANTS </unit></structure><section_number>221.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Food" includes any article used by man for food, drink, confectionery, or condiment, or which enters into the composition of the same whether simple, blended, mixed, or compounded; </section><section prefix="4">"Frozen food locker plant" means a location or establishment in which space in individual lockers is rented to persons for storage of frozen food and which is equipped with a chill room, sharp-freezing facilities, and facilities for cutting, preparing, wrapping, and packaging meats and meat products, fruits, and vegetables; </section><section prefix="5">"Branch frozen food locker plant" means a location or establishment in which space in individual lockers is rented to persons for storage of frozen food after preparation for storage at a frozen food locker plant; and </section><section prefix="6">"Sharp-frozen" means the freezing of food in a room in which the temperature is zero (0) degrees Fahrenheit or lower. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 557, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 497, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 85. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9872</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>