<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.005</section_number><catch_line>Elder Abuse Committee -- Membership -- Duties -- Annual report.   </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall create an Elder Abuse Committee to develop a model protocol on elder abuse and neglect in the Commonwealth, that shall be comprised of various agency representatives that include but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">The Department for Community Based Services; </section><section prefix="b">The Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="c">The Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="d">The Department for Aging and Independent Living; </section><section prefix="e">The Office of Inspector General's Division of Health Care; </section><section prefix="f">The Office of the Ombudsman; </section><section prefix="g">Area Agencies on Aging; </section><section prefix="h">Local and state law enforcement official; and </section><section prefix="i">Prosecutors. </section></section><section prefix="2">The committee shall address issues of prevention, intervention, investigation, and agency coordination of services on a state and local level through interaction with local groups or entities that either directly or indirectly provide services to the elder population, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Senior citizen centers; </section><section prefix="b">Local governmental human service groups; </section><section prefix="c">The Sanders-Brown Center on Aging at the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Long-Term Care Ombudsmen; and </section><section prefix="e">Other organizations or associations dedicated to serving elder citizens and their families in the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">The committee shall: <section prefix="a">Recommend a model protocol for the joint multidisciplinary investigation of reports of suspected abuse, neglect, or exploitation of the elderly; </section><section prefix="b">Recommend practices to assure timely reporting of referrals of abuse, neglect, or exploitation required under KRS 209.030(12); </section><section prefix="c">Explore the need for a comprehensive statewide resource directory of services for the elderly; </section><section prefix="d">Enhance existing public awareness campaigns for elder abuse and neglect; and </section><section prefix="e">Provide forums for the exchange of information to educate the elder population and their families on the rights of elders. </section></section><section prefix="4">The committee shall produce an annual report of their activities, products, and recommendations for public policy to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 66, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 34, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 16, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 293, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 132, sec. 29, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 40, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40953</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>