<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.395</section_number><catch_line>Information to be given to individual filing new claim -- Deduction and withholding of income tax. </catch_line><order_by>395</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual filing a new claim for unemployment compensation shall, at the time of filing the claim, be advised that: <section prefix="a">Unemployment compensation is subject to federal and state income tax; </section><section prefix="b">Requirements exist pertaining to estimated tax payments; </section><section prefix="c">The individual may elect to have federal income tax deducted and withheld from the individual's payment of unemployment compensation at the amount specified in the Federal Internal Revenue Code; and </section><section prefix="d">The individual shall be permitted to change a previously elected withholding status one (1) time during the individual's benefit year. </section></section><section prefix="2">Amounts deducted and withheld from unemployment compensation shall remain in the unemployment fund until transferred to the federal taxing authority as a payment of income tax. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall follow all procedures specified by the United States Department of Labor and the Federal Internal Revenue Service pertaining to the deducting and withholding of income tax. </section><section prefix="4">Amounts shall be deducted and withheld in accordance with the priorities established in administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32300</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>