<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.298</section_number><catch_line>Advanced practice doctoral program in nursing -- Degree -- Portrayal of credentials.   </catch_line><order_by>298</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The governing board as defined in KRS 164.001 of each eligible postsecondary education institution and college as defined in KRS 164.945 that offers an advanced practice doctoral degree in nursing shall be accredited by a national nursing accrediting body that includes but is not limited to the Accreditation Commission for Education in Nursing, the National League for Nursing Commission for Nursing Education Accreditation, the Council on Accreditation of Nurse Anesthesia Educational Programs, the Accreditation Commission for Midwifery Education, or the Commission on Collegiate Nursing Education and with minimal education and licensure standards for admission to and graduation from an advanced practice doctoral program in nursing. </section><section prefix="2">Each university offering an advanced nursing practice doctoral program shall refer to the degree as the "doctor of nursing practice," with the degree being abbreviated as "DNP." Any advertisement about the advanced nursing practice doctoral program shall not refer to graduates using the term "doctor." Graduates of the program shall accurately portray their academic credentials as well as their registered nurse and advanced practice registered nurse credentials, if applicable, subject to sanction under KRS 311.375(4). </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44645</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>