<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.398</section_number><catch_line>Statutory provisions not superseded by KRS 15.380 to 15.404. </catch_line><order_by>398</order_by><text>The following Kentucky Revised Statutes and any administrative regulations promulgated thereunder affecting those peace officers required to be certified pursuant to KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall not be superseded by the provisions of KRS 15.380 to 15.404, and in all instances the provisions of all statutes specified below shall prevail: <section prefix="1">KRS Chapter 16, relating to Department of Kentucky State Police Officers; </section><section prefix="2">KRS Chapter 70, relating to sheriffs, and deputy sheriffs; </section><section prefix="3">KRS Chapter 78, relating to county police; </section><section prefix="4">KRS Chapters 15 and 95, except for KRS 95.955, relating to city and urban-county police; </section><section prefix="5">KRS Chapter 183, relating to airport safety and security officers; </section><section prefix="6">KRS Chapter 164, relating to State Universities and Colleges; Regional Education and Archaeology officers; </section><section prefix="7">KRS Chapter 18A, relating to all state peace officers; </section><section prefix="8">KRS 241.090, relating to Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control field representatives and investigators; </section><section prefix="9">KRS 304.47-040, relating to Division of Insurance Fraud Investigators; and </section><section prefix="10">Any other statutes affecting peace officers not specifically cited herein. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 21, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 108, effective December 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2002).  The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered the subsections of this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=949</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>