<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.3971</section_number><catch_line>Court security officers -- Minimum qualifications -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>3971</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person certified as a court security officer after June 26, 2007, under KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall, at the time of becoming certified, meet the following minimum qualifications: <section prefix="a">Be a citizen of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Be at least twenty-one (21) years of age; </section><section prefix="c">Be a high school graduate or have successfully completed a General Educational Development (GED) examination; </section><section prefix="d">Possess a valid license to operate a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="e">Be fingerprinted for a criminal background check; </section><section prefix="f">Not have been convicted of any felony; </section><section prefix="g">Not be prohibited by federal or state law from possessing a firearm; </section><section prefix="h">Have received and read the Kentucky Law Enforcement Officers Code of Ethics, as established by the council; </section><section prefix="i">Have not received a dishonorable discharge, a bad conduct discharge, or general discharge under other than honorable conditions if he or she served in any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="j">Have passed a drug screening test administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation. A person shall be deemed to have passed a drug screening test if the results of the test are negative for the use of an illegal controlled substance or prescription drug abuse. Any agency that administers its own test that meets or exceeds this standard shall certify passing test results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.380 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="k">Have undergone a background investigation established or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine suitability for the position of a court security officer. If the employing agency has established its own background investigation that meets or exceeds the standards of the council, as set forth by administrative regulation, the agency shall conduct the background investigation and shall certify background investigation results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.380 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="l">Have been interviewed by the employing agency; </section><section prefix="m">Have taken a psychological suitability screening administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine the person's suitability to perform court security officer duties; and </section><section prefix="n">Have taken a polygraph examination administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine his or her suitability to perform court security officer duties. Any agency that administers its own polygraph examination as approved by the council shall certify the results that indicate whether a person is suitable for employment as a court security officer to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.380 to 15.404. </section></section><section prefix="2">A court security officer employed on or before June 26, 2007, shall comply with the requirements of subsection (1) of this section within six (6) months of June 26, 2007. </section><section prefix="3">A peace officer who has previously attended law enforcement basic training and met the certification requirements of KRS 15.380 and 15.382 shall not be required to meet the requirements of this section to be appointed a court security officer, but shall meet the requirements of KRS 15.386(3). </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>