<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-420</section_number><catch_line>Fifteen percent discount. </catch_line><order_by>20-420</order_by><text>Motor vehicle insurance companies shall give a fifteen percent (15%) discount on comprehensive coverage on any motor vehicle equipped with any of the following antitheft devices: <section prefix="1">Internally-operated alarm system which automatically cuts off the ignition or disconnects the starter and is activated if any door, the trunk or hood is opened, but which does not meet all the criteria in subsection (1) of KRS 304.20-430; </section><section prefix="2">Nonpassive fuel cutoff device which is activated when a switch is tripped or when the device is engaged by a key; </section><section prefix="3">Nonpassive steering wheel lock consisting of a steel collar and barrel, into which the shackle of a lock fits, which is permanently attached to the steering post and the lock is operated by a tubular key; </section><section prefix="4">Armored cable hood lock and ignition cutoff switch where the cable extends through the firewall and is secured to prevent retraction, but which does not meet all the criteria in paragraph (a) of subsection (6) of KRS 304.20-430; or </section><section prefix="5">Window identification system in which identification letters or numbers are etched into all windows of the motor vehicle other than small vent window. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29511</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>