<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7881</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for educational excellence scholarship and supplemental awards -- Time limits for receiving aid -- Adjustment of amounts and loss of award -- Extension of time limits -- Senator Jeff Green Scholars. </catch_line><order_by>7881</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Eligible high school students who have graduated from high school and eligible postsecondary students who have earned a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and a supplemental award, or a supplemental award only pursuant to KRS 164.7879(3)(e), shall be eligible to receive the Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, the Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and the supplemental award, or a supplemental award only for a maximum of eight (8) academic terms in an undergraduate or other postsecondary program of study at a participating institution, except as provided in subsections (5) and (6) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">To receive the Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and supplemental award, or a supplemental award only, an eligible high school or postsecondary student shall: <section prefix="a">Enroll in and attend a participating institution as a full-time student or a part-time student; and </section><section prefix="b">Maintain eligibility as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">Eligibility for a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship or a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and supplemental award shall terminate upon the earlier of: <section prefix="a">The expiration of five (5) years following the student's graduation from high school, except as provided in subsection (5) or (6) of this section; or </section><section prefix="b">The successful completion of an undergraduate or other postsecondary course of study. However, any student who successfully completes the requirements for a degree or certification involving a postsecondary course of study that normally requires less than eight (8) academic terms to complete may continue to receive the benefits of a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and supplemental award, or a supplemental award only, for a cumulative total of eight (8) academic terms if the student enrolls as at least a part-time student in a four </section></section><section prefix="4">year program. </section>(4) (a) The maximum award amount shall be determined by the authority and shall be adjusted as provided in this subsection. The award amount ultimately determined to be available to an eligible postsecondary student for an award period shall be delivered by the authority to the participating institution for disbursement to the eligible postsecondary student. (b) The authority shall, by promulgation of administrative regulations, provide for the proportionate reduction of the maximum award amount for an eligible postsecondary student for any academic term in which the student is enrolled on a part-time basis. Each academic term for which any scholarship or supplemental award funds are accepted by an eligible postsecondary student shall count as a full academic term, even if the award amount was reduced to reflect the part-time status of the eligible postsecondary student, except if the eligible postsecondary student interrupts enrollment during the award period for any reason specified in subsection (5) of this section, and the participating institution does not certify a cumulative grade point average for that student at the end of that award period. (c) 1. An eligible postsecondary student who is enrolled full-time in an undergraduate program of study, in the pharmacy program at the University of Kentucky, or in a program of study designated as an equivalent undergraduate program of study by the authority in an administrative regulation, shall receive the maximum award amount for the first award period that the student is enrolled in and attending the program of study. 2. To retain the maximum award for the second award period, an eligible postsecondary student shall have at least a 2.5 grade point average at the end of the first award period. If the eligible postsecondary student interrupts enrollment during the award period for any reason specified in subsection (5) of this section, and the participating institution does not certify a cumulative grade point average for that student at the end of that award period, the eligible postsecondary student shall, subject to paragraph (b) of this subsection, retain the maximum award for the award period in which he or she resumes enrollment. 3. To retain the maximum award amount for subsequent award periods, an eligible postsecondary student shall have: a. A cumulative grade point average of 3.0 or greater at the end of the prior award period. If the eligible postsecondary student interrupts enrollment during the award period for any reason specified in subsection (5) of this section, and the participating institution does not certify a cumulative grade point average for that student at the end of that award period, the eligible postsecondary student shall, subject to paragraph (b) of this subsection, retain the same award for the award period in which he or she resumes enrollment as he or she received in the award period in which enrollment was interrupted; or b. A cumulative grade point average of 2.5 or greater but less than 3.0 at the end of the prior award period and be on track to graduate. If the eligible postsecondary student interrupts enrollment during the award period for any reason specified in subsection (5) of this section, and the participating institution does not certify a cumulative grade point average for that student at the end of that award period, the eligible postsecondary student shall, subject to paragraph (b) of this subsection, retain the same award for the award period in which he or she resumes enrollment as he or she received in the award period in which enrollment was interrupted. 4. Any eligible full-time postsecondary student who maintains a cumulative grade point average of less than 3.0 but at least 2.5 but is not on track to graduate at the completion of any award period shall receive a reduction in the maximum award amount equal to fifty percent (50%) of the maximum award amount for the next award period. 5. Any eligible postsecondary student who maintains a cumulative grade point average of less than 2.5 at the completion of any award period shall lose his or her award for the next award period. 6. a. Each participating institution shall certify to the authority at the close of each award period the cumulative grade point average of each Kentucky educational excellence scholarship recipient enrolled as a full-time or part-time student at the participating institution. b. In addition to reporting the grade point average, beginning with the 2010-2011 academic year, each participating institution shall certify to the authority at the close of each award period whether a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship recipient who initially enrolled in college in 2009-2010 or thereafter is on track to graduate. 7. Any student who loses eligibility through failure to maintain the required cumulative grade point average may regain eligibility in a subsequent award period upon reestablishing at least a 2.5 cumulative grade point average or its equivalent during a subsequent award period, as certified by the participating institution. <section prefix="5">The expiration of a student's eight (8) academic terms and five (5) year eligibility shall be extended by the authority upon a determination that the student was unable to enroll for or complete an academic term due to any of the following circumstances: <section prefix="a">A serious and extended illness or injury of the student, certified by an attending physician; </section><section prefix="b">The death or serious and extended illness or injury of an immediate family member of the student, certified by an attending physician, which would render the student unable to attend classes; </section><section prefix="c">Natural disasters that would render a student unable to attend classes; or </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">Active duty status for the student in the United States Armed Forces or as an officer in the Commissioned Corps of the United States Public Health Service, or active service by the student in the Peace Corps Act or the Americorps, for the total number of years during which the student was on active duty status. The number of months served on active duty status shall be rounded up to the next higher year to determine the maximum length of eligibility extension allowed. </section><section prefix="2">A student whose eligibility expired prior to July 15, 2008, due to the three (3) year time limit on eligibility extensions imposed by this paragraph prior to July 15, 2008, shall have his or her eligibility reinstated for the number of years beyond the three (3) years during which he or she was on active duty status. The number of months served on active duty status shall be rounded up to the next higher year to determine the maximum length of eligibility extension allowed. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">An eligible postsecondary student who is enrolled at a participating institution in a five (5) year undergraduate degree program designated in an administrative regulation promulgated by the authority shall be eligible to receive the Kentucky educational excellence scholarship, the Kentucky educational excellence scholarship and the supplemental award, or the supplemental award only for a maximum of ten (10) academic terms. The expiration of an eligible postsecondary student's five (5) year eligibility shall be extended to six (6) years for eligible postsecondary students meeting the requirements of this subsection. </section><section prefix="7">Each participating institution shall notify its students of their terms of eligibility. </section><section prefix="8">Each eligible high school student who attains a 28 or above on the ACT and a 4.0 grade point average for all four (4) years of high school shall be designated as a "Senator Jeff Green Scholar" in honor of the late Senator Jeff Green of Mayfield, Kentucky, First District, and shall be recognized by the high school in a manner consistent with recognition given by the high school to other high levels of academic achievement. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 4, effective April 2, 2015. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 24, effective July 15, 2008; and ch. 137, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 2, effective July 15 2002; and ch. 326, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 198, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 575, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 2, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (4/2/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 6 provides that the amendments made to this statute in Section 4 of that Act shall be applied retroactively beginning with the 2013-2014 academic year. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44029</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>