<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.645</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 311.645 to 311.647.   </catch_line><order_by>645</order_by><text>As used in KRS 311.645 to 311.647: <section prefix="1">"Anaphylaxis" means an allergic reaction resulting from sensitization following prior contact with an antigen which can be a life-threatening emergency, including reactions triggered by, among other agents, foods, drugs, injections, insect stings, and physical activity; </section><section prefix="2">"Administer" means to directly apply an epinephrine auto-injector to the body of an individual; </section><section prefix="3">"Authorized entity" means an entity that may at any time have allergens present that are capable of causing a severe allergic reaction and has an individual who holds a certificate issued under KRS 311.646 on the premises or officially associated with the entity. The term includes but is not limited to restaurants, recreation camps, youth sports leagues, theme parks and resorts, and sports arenas; </section><section prefix="4">"Certified individual" means an individual who successfully completes an approved educational training program and obtain a certificate, as described in KRS 311.646; </section><section prefix="5">"Epinephrine auto-injector" means a single-use device used to administer a premeasured dose of epinephrine; </section><section prefix="6">"Health-care practitioner" means a physician or other health-care provider who has prescriptive authority; and </section><section prefix="7">"Self-administration" means an individual's administration of an epinephrine auto-injector on herself or himself. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 29, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 32 provides that this statute and KRS 311.646 and 311.647 created in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, secs. 29, 30, and 31 may be cited as the "Emergency Allergy Treatment Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44632</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>