<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="2">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="3">"Internal Revenue Code" means the Internal Revenue Code in effect on December 31, 2013, exclusive of any amendments made subsequent to that date, other than amendments that extend provisions in effect on December 31, 2013, that would otherwise terminate, and as modified by KRS 141.0101; </section><section prefix="4">"Dependent" means those persons defined as dependents in the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="5">"Fiduciary" means "fiduciary" as defined in Section 7701(a)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="6">"Fiscal year" means "fiscal year" as defined in Section 7701(a)(24) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="7">"Individual" means a natural person; </section><section prefix="8">"Modified gross income" means the greater of: <section prefix="a">Adjusted gross income as defined in Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including any subsequent amendments in effect on December 31 of the taxable year, and adjusted as follows: <section prefix="1">Include interest income derived from obligations of sister states and political subdivisions thereof; and </section><section prefix="2">Include lump-sum pension distributions taxed under the special transition rules of Pub. L. No. 104-188, sec. 1401(c)(2); or </section></section><section prefix="b">Adjusted gross income as defined in subsection (10) of this section and adjusted to include lump-sum pension distributions taxed under the special transition rules of Pub. L. No. 104-188, sec. 1401(c)(2); </section></section><section prefix="9">"Gross income," in the case of taxpayers other than corporations, means "gross income" as defined in Section 61 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="10">"Adjusted gross income," in the case of taxpayers other than corporations, means gross income as defined in subsection (9) of this section minus the deductions allowed individuals by Section 62 of the Internal Revenue Code and as modified by KRS 141.0101 and adjusted as follows, except that deductions shall be limited to amounts allocable to income subject to taxation under the provisions of this chapter, and except that nothing in this chapter shall be construed to permit the same item to be deducted more than once: <section prefix="a">Exclude income that is exempt from state taxation by the Kentucky Constitution and the Constitution and statutory laws of the United States and Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Exclude income from supplemental annuities provided by the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 as amended and which are subject to federal income tax by Public Law 89-699; </section><section prefix="c">Include interest income derived from obligations of sister states and political subdivisions thereof; </section><section prefix="d">Exclude employee pension contributions picked up as provided for in KRS 6.505, 16.545, 21.360, 61.560, 65.155, 67A.320, 67A.510, 78.610, and 161.540 upon a ruling by the Internal Revenue Service or the federal courts that these contributions shall not be included as gross income until such time as the contributions are distributed or made available to the employee; </section><section prefix="e">Exclude Social Security and railroad retirement benefits subject to federal income tax; </section><section prefix="f">Include, for taxable years ending before January 1, 1991, all overpayments of federal income tax refunded or credited for taxable years; </section><section prefix="g">Deduct, for taxable years ending before January 1, 1991, federal income tax paid for taxable years ending before January 1, 1990; </section><section prefix="h">Exclude any money received because of a settlement or judgment in a lawsuit brought against a manufacturer or distributor of "Agent Orange" for damages resulting from exposure to Agent Orange by a member or veteran of the Armed Forces of the United States or any dependent of such person who served in Vietnam; </section><section prefix="i"><section prefix="1">For taxable years ending prior to December 31, 2005, exclude the applicable amount of total distributions from pension plans, annuity contracts, profit-sharing plans, retirement plans, or employee savings plans. <section prefix="a">Twenty-five percent (25%), but not more than six thousand two </section><section prefix="b">Fifty percent (50%), but not more than twelve thousand five </section><section prefix="c">Seventy-five percent (75%), but not more than eighteen thousand </section><section prefix="d">One hundred percent (100%), but not more than thirty-five </section></section> The "applicable amount" shall be: hundred fifty dollars ($6,250), for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1994, and before January 1, 1996; hundred dollars ($12,500), for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1995, and before January 1, 1997; seven hundred fifty dollars ($18,750), for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1996, and before January 1, 1998; and thousand dollars ($35,000), for taxable years beginning after December 31, 1997. <section prefix="2">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2005, exclude up to forty-one thousand one hundred ten dollars ($41,110) of total distributions from pension plans, annuity contracts, profit-sharing plans, retirement plans, or employee savings plans. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this paragraph: <section prefix="a">"Distributions" includes but is not limited to any lump-sum distribution from pension or profit-sharing plans qualifying for the income tax averaging provisions of Section 402 of the Internal Revenue Code; any distribution from an individual retirement account as defined in Section 408 of the Internal Revenue Code; and any disability pension distribution; </section><section prefix="b">"Annuity contract" has the same meaning as set forth in Section 1035 of the Internal Revenue Code; and </section><section prefix="c">"Pension plans, profit-sharing plans, retirement plans, or employee savings plans" means any trust or other entity created or organized under a written retirement plan and forming part of a stock bonus, pension, or profit-sharing plan of a public or private employer for the exclusive benefit of employees or their beneficiaries and includes plans qualified or unqualified under Section 401 of the Internal Revenue Code and individual retirement accounts as defined in Section 408 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section></section></section><section prefix="j"><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Exclude the portion of the distributive share of a shareholder's net income from an S corporation subject to the franchise tax imposed under KRS 136.505 or the capital stock tax imposed under KRS 136.300; and </section><section prefix="b">Exclude the portion of the distributive share of a shareholder's net income from an S corporation related to a qualified subchapter S subsidiary subject to the franchise tax imposed under KRS 136.505 or the capital stock tax imposed under KRS 136.300. </section></section><section prefix="2">The shareholder's basis of stock held in a S corporation where the S corporation or its qualified subchapter S subsidiary is subject to the franchise tax imposed under KRS 136.505 or the capital stock tax imposed under KRS 136.300 shall be the same as the basis for federal income tax purposes; </section></section><section prefix="k">Exclude, to the extent not already excluded from gross income, any amounts paid for health insurance, or the value of any voucher or similar instrument used to provide health insurance, which constitutes medical care coverage for the taxpayer, the taxpayer's spouse, and dependents, or for any person authorized to be provided excludable coverage by the taxpayer pursuant to the federal Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act of 2010, Pub. L. No. 111-148, or the Health Care and Education Reconciliation Act of 2010 Pub. L. No. 111-152, during the taxable year. Any amounts paid by the taxpayer for health insurance that are excluded pursuant to this paragraph shall not be allowed as a deduction in computing the taxpayer's net income under subsection (11) of this section; </section><section prefix="l">Exclude income received for services performed as a precinct worker for election training or for working at election booths in state, county, and local primary, regular, or special elections; </section><section prefix="m">Exclude any amount paid during the taxable year for insurance for long-term care as defined in KRS 304.14-600; </section><section prefix="n">Exclude any capital gains income attributable to property taken by eminent domain; </section><section prefix="o">Exclude any amount received by a producer of tobacco or a tobacco quota owner from the multistate settlement with the tobacco industry, known as the Master Settlement Agreement, signed on November 22, 1998; </section><section prefix="p">Exclude any amount received from the secondary settlement fund, referred to as "Phase II," established by tobacco companies to compensate tobacco farmers and quota owners for anticipated financial losses caused by the national tobacco settlement; </section><section prefix="q">Exclude any amount received from funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation for the Tobacco Loss Assistance Program as a result of a reduction in the quantity of tobacco quota allotted; </section><section prefix="r">Exclude any amount received as a result of a tobacco quota buydown program that all quota owners and growers are eligible to participate in; </section><section prefix="s">Exclude state Phase II payments received by a producer of tobacco or a tobacco quota owner; </section><section prefix="t">Exclude all income from all sources for active duty and reserve members and officers of the Armed Forces of the United States or National Guard who are killed in the line of duty, for the year during which the death occurred and the year prior to the year during which the death occurred. For the purposes of this paragraph, "all income from all sources" shall include all federal and state death benefits payable to the estate or any beneficiaries; and </section><section prefix="u">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, exclude all military pay received by active duty members of the Armed Forces of the United States, members of reserve components of the Armed Forces of the United States, and members of the National Guard, including compensation for state active duty as described in KRS 38.205; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Net income," in the case of taxpayers other than corporations, means adjusted gross income as defined in subsection (10) of this section, minus: <section prefix="a">The deduction allowed by KRS 141.0202; </section><section prefix="b">Any amount paid for vouchers or similar instruments that provide health insurance coverage to employees or their families; </section><section prefix="c">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, the amount of domestic production activities deduction calculated at six percent (6%) as allowed in Section 199(a)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code for taxable years beginning before 2010; and </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">All the deductions allowed individuals by Chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code as modified by KRS 141.0101 except: <section prefix="a">Any deduction allowed by the Internal Revenue Code for state or foreign taxes measured by gross or net income, including state and local general sales taxes allowed in lieu of state and local income taxes under the provisions of Section 164(b)(5) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="b">Any deduction allowed by the Internal Revenue Code for amounts allowable under KRS 140.090(1)(h) in calculating the value of the distributive shares of the estate of a decedent, unless there is filed with the income return a statement that such deduction has not been claimed under KRS 140.090(1)(h); </section><section prefix="c">The deduction for personal exemptions allowed under Section 151 of the Internal Revenue Code and any other deductions in lieu thereof; </section><section prefix="d">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, the domestic production activities deduction allowed under Section 199 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="e">Any deduction for amounts paid to any club, organization, or establishment which has been determined by the courts or an agency established by the General Assembly and charged with enforcing the civil rights laws of the Commonwealth, not to afford full and equal membership and full and equal enjoyment of its goods, services, facilities, privileges, advantages, or accommodations to any person because of race, color, religion, national origin, or sex, except nothing shall be construed to deny a deduction for amounts paid to any religious or denominational club, group, or establishment or any organization operated solely for charitable or educational purposes which restricts membership to persons of the same religion or denomination in order to promote the religious principles for which it is established and maintained; </section><section prefix="f">Any deduction directly or indirectly allocable to income which is either exempt from taxation or otherwise not taxed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="g">The itemized deduction limitation established in 26 U.S.C. sec. 68 shall be determined using the applicable amount from 26 U.S.C. sec. 68 as it existed on December 31, 2006; and </section><section prefix="h">A taxpayer may elect to claim the standard deduction allowed by KRS 141.081 instead of itemized deductions allowed pursuant to 26 U.S.C. sec. 63 and as modified by this section; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to permit the same item to be deducted more than once; </section></section></section><section prefix="12">"Gross income," in the case of corporations, means "gross income" as defined in Section 61 of the Internal Revenue Code and as modified by KRS 141.0101 and adjusted as follows: <section prefix="a">Exclude income that is exempt from state taxation by the Kentucky Constitution and the Constitution and statutory laws of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Exclude all dividend income received after December 31, 1969; </section><section prefix="c">Include interest income derived from obligations of sister states and political subdivisions thereof; </section><section prefix="d">Exclude fifty percent (50%) of gross income derived from any disposal of coal covered by Section 631(c) of the Internal Revenue Code if the corporation does not claim any deduction for percentage depletion, or for expenditures attributable to the making and administering of the contract under which such disposition occurs or to the preservation of the economic interests retained under such contract; </section><section prefix="e">Include in the gross income of lessors income tax payments made by lessees to lessors, under the provisions of Section 110 of the Internal Revenue Code, and exclude such payments from the gross income of lessees; </section><section prefix="f">Include the amount calculated under KRS 141.205; </section><section prefix="g">Ignore the provisions of Section 281 of the Internal Revenue Code in computing gross income; </section><section prefix="h">Exclude income from "safe harbor leases" (Section 168(f)(8) of the Internal Revenue Code); </section><section prefix="i">Exclude any amount received by a producer of tobacco or a tobacco quota owner from the multistate settlement with the tobacco industry, known as the Master Settlement Agreement, signed on November 22, 1998; </section><section prefix="j">Exclude any amount received from the secondary settlement fund, referred to as "Phase II," established by tobacco companies to compensate tobacco farmers and quota owners for anticipated financial losses caused by the national tobacco settlement; </section><section prefix="k">Exclude any amount received from funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation for the Tobacco Loss Assistance Program as a result of a reduction in the quantity of tobacco quota allotted; </section><section prefix="l">Exclude any amount received as a result of a tobacco quota buydown program that all quota owners and growers are eligible to participate in; </section><section prefix="m">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, exclude the distributive share income or loss received from a corporation defined in subsection (24)(b) of this section whose income has been subject to the tax imposed by KRS 141.040. The exclusion provided in this paragraph shall also apply to a taxable year that begins prior to January 1, 2005, if the tax imposed by KRS 141.040 is paid on the distributive share income by a corporation defined in subparagraphs 2. to 8. of subsection (24)(b) of this section with a return filed for a period of less than twelve (12) months that begins on or after January 1, 2005, and ends on or before December 31, 2005. This paragraph shall not be used to delay payment of the tax imposed by KRS 141.040; and </section><section prefix="n">Exclude state Phase II payments received by a producer of tobacco or a tobacco quota owner; </section></section><section prefix="13">"Net income," in the case of corporations, means "gross income" as defined in subsection (12) of this section minus: <section prefix="a">The deduction allowed by KRS 141.0202; </section><section prefix="b">Any amount paid for vouchers or similar instruments that provide health insurance coverage to employees or their families; </section><section prefix="c">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, the amount of domestic production activities deduction calculated at six percent (6%) as allowed in Section 199(a)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code for taxable years beginning before 2010; and </section><section prefix="d">All the deductions from gross income allowed corporations by Chapter 1 of the Internal Revenue Code and as modified by KRS 141.0101, except: <section prefix="1">Any deduction for a state tax which is computed, in whole or in part, by reference to gross or net income and which is paid or accrued to any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, or to any foreign country or political subdivision thereof; </section><section prefix="2">The deductions contained in Sections 243, 244, 245, and 247 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of Section 281 of the Internal Revenue Code shall be ignored in computing net income; </section><section prefix="4">Any deduction directly or indirectly allocable to income which is either exempt from taxation or otherwise not taxed under the provisions of this chapter, and nothing in this chapter shall be construed to permit the same item to be deducted more than once; </section><section prefix="5">Exclude expenses related to "safe harbor leases" (Section 168(f)(8) of the Internal Revenue Code); </section><section prefix="6">Any deduction for amounts paid to any club, organization, or establishment which has been determined by the courts or an agency established by the General Assembly and charged with enforcing the civil rights laws of the Commonwealth, not to afford full and equal membership and full and equal enjoyment of its goods, services, facilities, privileges, advantages, or accommodations to any person because of race, color, religion, national origin, or sex, except nothing shall be construed to deny a deduction for amounts paid to any religious or denominational club, group, or establishment or any organization operated solely for charitable or educational purposes which restricts membership to persons of the same religion or denomination in order to promote the religious principles for which it is established and maintained; </section><section prefix="7">Any deduction prohibited by KRS 141.205; </section><section prefix="8">Any dividends-paid deduction of any captive real estate investment trust; and </section><section prefix="9">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, the domestic production activities deduction allowed under Section 199 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section></section></section><section prefix="14"><section prefix="a">"Taxable net income," in the case of corporations that are taxable in this state, means "net income" as defined in subsection (13) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">"Taxable net income," in the case of corporations that are taxable in this state and taxable in another state, means "net income" as defined in subsection (13) of this section and as allocated and apportioned under KRS 141.120. A corporation is taxable in another state if, in any state other than Kentucky, the corporation is required to file a return for or pay a net income tax, franchise tax measured by net income, franchise tax for the privilege of doing business, or corporate stock tax; </section><section prefix="c">"Taxable net income," in the case of homeowners' associations as defined in Section 528(c) of the Internal Revenue Code, means "taxable income" as defined in Section 528(d) of the Internal Revenue Code. Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (3) of this section, the Internal Revenue Code sections referred to in this paragraph shall be those code sections in effect for the applicable tax year; and </section><section prefix="d">"Taxable net income," in the case of a corporation that meets the requirements established under Section 856 of the Internal Revenue Code to be a real estate investment trust, means "real estate investment trust taxable income" as defined in Section 857(b)(2) of the Internal Revenue Code, except that a captive real estate investment trust shall not be allowed any deduction for dividends paid; </section></section><section prefix="15">"Person" means "person" as defined in Section 7701(a)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="16">"Taxable year" means the calendar year or fiscal year ending during such calendar year, upon the basis of which net income is computed, and in the case of a return made for a fractional part of a year under the provisions of this chapter or under regulations prescribed by the commissioner, "taxable year" means the period for which the return is made; </section><section prefix="17">"Resident" means an individual domiciled within this state or an individual who is not domiciled in this state, but maintains a place of abode in this state and spends in the aggregate more than one hundred eighty-three (183) days of the taxable year in this state; </section><section prefix="18">"Nonresident" means any individual not a resident of this state; </section><section prefix="19">"Employer" means "employer" as defined in Section 3401(d) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="20">"Employee" means "employee" as defined in Section 3401(c) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="21">"Number of withholding exemptions claimed" means the number of withholding exemptions claimed in a withholding exemption certificate in effect under KRS 141.325, except that if no such certificate is in effect, the number of withholding exemptions claimed shall be considered to be zero; </section><section prefix="22">"Wages" means "wages" as defined in Section 3401(a) of the Internal Revenue Code and includes other income subject to withholding as provided in Section 3401(f) and Section 3402(k), (o), (p), (q), and (s) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="23">"Payroll period" means "payroll period" as defined in Section 3401(b) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="24"><section prefix="a">For taxable years beginning before January 1, 2005, and after December 31, 2006, "corporation" means "corporation" as defined in Section 7701(a)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; and </section><section prefix="b">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, "corporations" means: <section prefix="1">"Corporations" as defined in Section 7701(a)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="2">S corporations as defined in Section 1361(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="3">A foreign limited liability company as defined in KRS 275.015; </section><section prefix="4">A limited liability company as defined in KRS 275.015; </section><section prefix="5">A professional limited liability company as defined in KRS 275.015; </section><section prefix="6">A foreign limited partnership as defined in KRS 362.2-102(9); </section><section prefix="7">A limited partnership as defined in KRS 362.2-102(14); </section><section prefix="8">A limited liability partnership as defined in KRS 362.155(7) or in 362.1-101(7) or (8); </section><section prefix="9">A real estate investment trust as defined in Section 856 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="10">A regulated investment company as defined in Section 851 of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="11">A real estate mortgage investment conduit as defined in Section 860D of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="12">A financial asset securitization investment trust as defined in Section 860L of the Internal Revenue Code; and </section><section prefix="13">Other similar entities created with limited liability for their partners, members, or shareholders. </section></section> For purposes of this paragraph, "corporation" shall not include any publicly traded partnership as defined by Section 7704(b) of the Internal Revenue Code that is treated as a partnership for federal tax purposes under Section 7704(c) of the Internal Revenue Code or its publicly traded partnership affiliates. As used in this paragraph, "publicly traded partnership affiliates" shall include any limited liability company or limited partnership for which at least eighty percent (80%) of the limited liability company member interests or limited partner interests are owned directly or indirectly by the publicly traded partnership; </section><section prefix="25">"Doing business in this state" includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">Being organized under the laws of this state; </section><section prefix="b">Having a commercial domicile in this state; </section><section prefix="c">Owning or leasing property in this state; </section><section prefix="d">Having one (1) or more individuals performing services in this state; </section><section prefix="e">Maintaining an interest in a pass-through entity doing business in this state; </section><section prefix="f">Deriving income from or attributable to sources within this state, including deriving income directly or indirectly from a trust doing business in this state, or deriving income directly or indirectly from a single-member limited liability company that is doing business in this state and is disregarded as an entity separate from its single member for federal income tax purposes; or </section><section prefix="g">Directing activities at Kentucky customers for the purpose of selling them goods or services. </section></section> Nothing in this subsection shall be interpreted in a manner that goes beyond the limitations imposed and protections provided by the United States Constitution or Pub. L. No. 86-272; <section prefix="26">"Pass-through entity" means any partnership, S corporation, limited liability company, limited liability partnership, limited partnership, or similar entity recognized by the laws of this state that is not taxed for federal purposes at the entity level, but instead passes to each partner, member, shareholder, or owner their proportionate share of income, deductions, gains, losses, credits, and any other similar attributes; </section><section prefix="27">"S corporation" means "S corporation" as defined in Section 1361(a) of the Internal Revenue Code; </section><section prefix="28">"Limited liability pass-through entity" means any pass-through entity that affords any of its partners, members, shareholders, or owners, through function of the laws of this state or laws recognized by this state, protection from general liability for actions of the entity; and </section><section prefix="29">"Captive real estate investment trust" means a real estate investment trust as defined in Section 856 of the Internal Revenue Code that meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The shares or other ownership interests of the real estate investment trust are not regularly traded on an established securities market; or </section><section prefix="2">The real estate investment trust does not have enough shareholders or owners to be required to register with the Securities and Exchange Commission; and </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The maximum amount of stock or other ownership interest that is owned or constructively owned by a corporation equals or exceeds: <section prefix="a">Twenty-five percent (25%), if the corporation does not occupy property owned, constructively owned, or controlled by the real estate investment trust; or </section><section prefix="b">Ten percent (10%), if the corporation occupies property owned, constructively owned, or controlled by the real estate investment trust. </section></section> The total ownership interest of a corporation shall be determined by aggregating all interests owned or constructively owned by a corporation; <section prefix="2">For the purposes of this paragraph: <section prefix="a">"Corporation" means a corporation taxable under KRS 141.040, and includes an affiliated group as defined in KRS 141.200, that is required to file a consolidated return pursuant to the provisions of KRS 141.200; and </section><section prefix="b">"Owned or constructively owned" means owning shares or having an ownership interest in the real estate investment trust, or owning an interest in an entity that owns shares or has an ownership interest in the real estate investment trust. Constructive ownership shall be determined by looking across multiple layers of a multilayer pass-through structure; and </section></section></section><section prefix="c">The real estate investment trust is not owned by another real estate investment trust. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective June 4, 2010. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 42, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 105, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 137, sec. 42, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 202, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 251, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 16, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 471, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 168, sec. 3, effective March 18, 2005; and ch. 173, Part XVIII, sec. 1, effective March 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 367, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective March 15, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 533, sec. 1, effective April 26, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective February 6, 1998; ch. 365, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 402, sec. 3, effective April 7, 1998; ch. 496, sec. 63, effective April 10, 1998; ch. 509, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 550, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 586, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1995 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective April 28, 1995. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 242, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 303, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. VII D, sec. 630, effective April 11, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 459, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, Pt. V, sec. 14, effective July 29, 1985. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective March 24, 1982; and ch. 166, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 7. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 2. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 62, Pt. III, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 3. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 40, Part II, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 176, Part I, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. III, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 194, secs. 1 and 2. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4281b-1, 4281b-2, 4281b-5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014).  2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 40 provides that the amendments to this statute made in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2014.  (3/16/2011).  2011 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 2, provides that the amendments to KRS 141.010 in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, "apply for taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2011."  (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 3, provides that the amendments to KRS 141.010 in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, "shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2007."  (6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007."  (6/28/2006).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136, a manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected. In the first sentence of 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch 2, sec. 11, the citation to KRS 141.010(24)(b) to (h) has been changed to KRS 141.010(24)(b)2. to 8. to conform to other amendments citing this statute elsewhere in the Act.  (4/25/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 18 provides that "The amendment in Section 16 of this Part is applicable for tax years beginning after December 31, 2001."  (3/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 173, Part XVIII, sec. 2, provides that changes made to subsection (11)(a) of this section are effective for taxable years beginning after December 1, 2004. (7/13/2004).  The amendments made to subsections (10)(r) and (12)(l) of this statute in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, "shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2003." 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 4.  (7/15/2002).  The change of dates in subsection (3) of this statute from December 31, 1999, to December 31, 2001, applies to "taxable years beginning after December 31, 2001." 2002 Ky. Acts. ch. 367, sec. 4.  (7/15/2002).  The amendments made to subsections (10)(k), (11), and (13) of this statute in 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, "shall apply for taxable years beginning after December 31, 2001." 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 2.  (7/14/2000).  The change of dates in subsection (3) of this statute from December 1, 1997, to December 31, 1999, applies to "taxable years beginning after December 31, 1999." 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 4.  (4/26/2000).  The exclusions set forth in subsection (10)(p) and (q) and subsection (12)(i) to (k) of this statute took effect April 26, 2000, and "retroactively apply to tax years beginning after December 31, 1998. 2000 Ky. Acts. ch. 533, secs. 4 and 5.  (4/28/95).  The exclusion set forth in subsection (10)(i) of this statute applies "to income received after December 31, 1994," pursuant to 1995 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 11. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>