<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.905</section_number><catch_line>Requirements to be licensed as an athletic trainer -- Exception to requirements -- Inactive status -- Automatic licensure.   </catch_line><order_by>905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be licensed by the board as an athletic trainer, an applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Submit a completed application form with the required fee on a form prescribed by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Be of good character and reputation; and </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Be certified and in good standing as an athletic trainer by the National Athletic Trainers Association Board of Certification, Inc., or its successor; or </section><section prefix="2">Be authorized to practice as an athletic trainer in another state and be in good standing in that state, if that state has standards equivalent to those of this Commonwealth. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Any person who is issued initial licensure as an athletic trainer shall be registered for three (3) years, or for the completion of the current three (3) year cycle. The person shall then apply to the board for triennial renewal and shall submit all information requested by the board and pay a renewal fee as prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall hold himself or herself out as an athletic trainer or perform any of the activities of an athletic trainer as prescribed in KRS 311.900 to 311.928, without first obtaining a license under KRS 311.900 to 311.928. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit: <section prefix="a">The activities, services, and use of title on the part of a person in the employ of the federal government, to the extent the person is operating within the specific parameters of that employment; or </section><section prefix="b">The activities or services of a student athletic trainer or someone in a similar educational position, if the service is not for compensation and is carried out under the supervision of a physician and a licensed athletic trainer licensed under KRS 311.900 to 311.928. </section></section><section prefix="5">Upon petition to the board, licensed athletic trainers may be granted inactive status for a period of time not to exceed three (3) years. Licensed athletic trainers shall not practice athletic training while under inactive status. Inactive athletic trainers may apply for an active license after paying a fee as prescribed in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="6">Persons who are certified by the board and are in good standing as athletic trainers on July 12, 2006, shall be automatically licensed under KRS 311.900 to 311.928 without meeting the requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41867</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>