<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.135</section_number><catch_line>Reemployment of career employees. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any career employee who has been laid-off or dismissed, other than for cause, and, in the case of an unclassified management employee, resignation other than resignation in lieu of dismissal for cause, shall automatically be placed on the reemployment list for the class from which he was terminated. If a career employee wishes to be on the reemployment list for other classes of positions for which he is qualified and passes the appropriate selection method, he shall notify the cabinet in writing. </section><section prefix="2">If more than one (1) career employee requests to be placed on the reemployment list for any job classification, the cabinet shall list the names of such career employees in the order of their seniority. </section><section prefix="3">No vacancy may be filled from a competitive register until all career employees on the reemployment list for that class of position have denied employment in that class. An appointing authority may refuse to reemploy a qualified employee on the reemployment list only for cause. The secretary and the employee shall be furnished with a written statement of the specific reasons for the refusal within ten (10) days following the appointing authority's refusal. The employee may appeal the appointing authority's action in accordance with KRS 18A.095 and 18A.100. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.135, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.217. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1373</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>