<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.827</section_number><catch_line>Dispute resolution with respect to statements of expenditures and statements of financial transactions -- Civil liability for false information. </catch_line><order_by>827</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An employer or legislative agent who is required to file a statement describing an expenditure or a financial transaction shall deliver a copy of the statement to the official with whom or for whose benefit the transaction was made at least ten (10) days before the date on which the statement is filed. </section><section prefix="2">If a dispute arises between any member of the General Assembly or a member of the staff of the General Assembly and an employer or legislative agent with respect to an expenditure or financial transaction alleged in a statement to be filed under KRS 6.821 or 6.824, the member, employer, or legislative agent may file a complaint with the commission. The commission shall proceed to investigate the complaint in the same manner as set out in KRS 6.686. The commission shall notify the parties of its final decision by certified mail. If the commission decides the disputed expenditure or financial transaction should be reported, the employer or legislative agent shall include the matter in an amended statement and file the amended statement not later than ten (10) days after the employer or agent receives notice of the decision of the committee by certified mail. </section><section prefix="3">An employer or legislative agent who files a false statement of expenditures or details of a financial transaction is liable in a civil action to any official or employee who sustains damage as a result of the filing or publication of the statement. </section></text><history>Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 31, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=407</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>