<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.1752</section_number><catch_line>Local Health Department Employment Personnel Council. </catch_line><order_by>1752</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Local Health Department Employment Personnel Council is hereby created. The council shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the secretary for health and family services. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the council shall serve for a term of three (3) years or until successors are appointed, except that for members of the initially appointed council, two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) members shall be appointed for two (2) years, and one (1) member shall be appointed for three (3) years. A member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term shall be appointed for the remainder of the term. </section><section prefix="3">The council shall elect a chairperson from its membership. Regular meetings of the council shall be held at least semiannually. Special meetings of the council may be held upon call of the chairperson or the department. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall be attached to the department for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall: <section prefix="a">Advise the cabinet on administration of the local health department personnel program pursuant to KRS Chapter 212; </section><section prefix="b">Hear appeals from: <section prefix="1">Applicants for positions for which examinations are being or have been conducted; </section><section prefix="2">Eligible applicants on examination registers; and </section><section prefix="3">Classified employees who have been dismissed, demoted, or suspended for cause; </section></section><section prefix="c">Hear appeals regarding discrimination in a personnel action involving an agency employee or an applicant for employment; </section><section prefix="d">Make an annual report to the department and agency; and </section><section prefix="e">Consider and act upon matters that may be referred to the council by the department. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 344, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 288, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 103, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8357</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>