<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 177.230 to 177.310 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon arrest and conviction therefor, shall be punished by a fine of not less than five dollars ($5) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who willfully violates any of the provisions of KRS 177.841 to 177.890 shall, in addition to any other penalty herein provided, be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="3">In addition to any other penalty provided by KRS 177.910 to 177.950, any person violating any order or provision of KRS 177.910 to 177.950 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) and not more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). Each day of violation of the provisions of KRS 177.910 to 177.950 shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates the weight provisions of KRS 177.9771 shall, upon conviction, be fined in an amount equal to three cents ($0.03) per pound when the excess is three thousand (3,000) pounds or less, five cents ($0.05) per pound when the excess exceeds three thousand (3,000) pounds but is less than four thousand (4,000) pounds, seven cents ($0.07) per pound when the excess exceeds four thousand (4,000) pounds but is less than five thousand (5,000) pounds, and nine cents ($0.09) per pound when the excess exceeds five thousand (5,000) pounds. In no case shall the fine be less than sixty dollars ($60) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="5">Any person who transports coal in violation of the weight provisions of KRS 189.221 and 189.222 and does not have a current decal or is not transporting coal under a valid cooperative agreement within KRS 177.9771(4)(f), shall, in addition to any applicable penalty prescribed by law, be fined five hundred dollars ($500) and be required to purchase the decal described in KRS 177.9771(4). </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 177.305 shall be fined not less than twenty dollars ($20) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 498, sec. 4, effective April 1, 1987. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 7(9), (10), effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 11. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 8. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>