<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.033</section_number><catch_line>Caterer's license.   </catch_line><order_by>033</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A caterer's license may be issued as a supplementary license to a caterer that holds a quota retail package license, a quota retail drink license, an NQ1 license, an NQ2 license, or a limited restaurant license. </section><section prefix="2">The caterer's license may be issued as a primary license to a caterer in any wet territory or in any moist territory under KRS 242.1244 for the premises that serves as the caterer's commissary and designated banquet hall. No primary caterer's license shall be issued to a premises that operates as a restaurant. The alcoholic beverage stock of the caterer shall be kept under lock and key at the licensed premises during the time that the alcoholic beverages are not being used in conjunction with a catered function. </section><section prefix="3">The caterer's license shall authorize the caterer to: <section prefix="a">Purchase and store alcoholic beverages in the manner prescribed in KRS 243.088, 243.250, and 244.310; </section><section prefix="b">Transport, sell, serve, and deliver malt beverages by the drink at locations away from the licensed premises or at the caterer's designated banquet hall in conjunction with the catering of food and malt beverages for a customer and his or her guests, in: <section prefix="1">Cities and counties established as moist territory under KRS 242.1244 if the receipts from the catering of food at any catered event are at least seventy percent (70%) of the gross receipts from the catering of both food and malt beverages; or </section><section prefix="2">All other wet territory if the receipts from the catering of food at any catered event are at least thirty-five percent (35%) of the gross receipts from the catering of both food and malt beverages; </section></section><section prefix="c">Transport, sell, serve, and deliver distilled spirits and wine by the drink at locations away from the licensed premises or at the caterer's designated banquet hall in conjunction with the catering of food and alcoholic beverages for a customer and his or her guests, in: <section prefix="1">Cities and counties established as moist territory under KRS 242.1244 if the receipts from the catering of food at any catered event are at least seventy percent (70%) of the gross receipts from the catering of both food and alcoholic beverages; </section><section prefix="2">Cities and counties established as wet territory permitting distilled spirits and wine drink sales by ordinance under KRS 243.072 if the receipts from the catering of food at any catered event are at least fifty percent (50%) of the gross receipts from the catering of both food and alcoholic beverages; or </section><section prefix="3">All other wet territory in which the sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink is authorized if the receipts from the catering of food at any catered event are at least thirty-five percent (35%) of the gross receipts from the catering of both food and alcoholic beverages; </section></section><section prefix="d">Receive and fill telephone orders for alcoholic beverages in conjunction with the ordering of food for a catered event; and </section><section prefix="e">Receive payment for alcoholic beverages served at a catered event on a by-the-drink or by-the-event basis. The caterer may bill the host for by-the-function sales of alcoholic beverages in the usual course of the caterer's business. </section></section><section prefix="4">A caterer licensee shall not cater alcoholic beverages at locations for which retail alcoholic beverage licenses or special temporary licenses have been issued. A caterer licensee may cater a fundraising event for which a special temporary distilled spirits and wine auction license has been issued under KRS 243.036. </section><section prefix="5">A caterer licensee shall not cater distilled spirits and wine on Sunday except in territory in which the Sunday sale of distilled spirits and wine is permitted under the provisions of KRS 244.290 and 244.295. A caterer licensee shall not cater malt beverages on Sunday except in territory in which the Sunday sale of malt beverages is permitted under the provisions of KRS 244.480. </section><section prefix="6">The location at which alcoholic beverages are sold, served, and delivered by a caterer, pursuant to this section, shall not constitute a public place for the purpose of KRS Chapter 222. If the location is a multi-unit structure, only the unit or units at which the function being catered is held shall be excluded from the public place provisions of KRS Chapter 222. </section><section prefix="7">The caterer licensee shall post a copy of his or her caterer's license at the location of the function for which alcoholic beverages are catered. </section><section prefix="8">The name and license numbers of the caterer shall be painted or securely attached, in a contrasting color, in a form prescribed by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation, upon all vehicles used by the caterer to transport alcoholic beverages. </section><section prefix="9">All restrictions and prohibitions applying to a distilled spirits and wine quota retail drink licensee not inconsistent with this section shall apply to the caterer licensee. </section><section prefix="10">The caterer licensee shall maintain records as set forth in KRS 244.150 and in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 92, sec. 295, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 47, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 9, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 22 and 92, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43880</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>