<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.116</section_number><catch_line>Collection of data relating to marriages, divorces, and annulments.   </catch_line><order_by>116</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall perform the collection, indexing, tabulation, and registration of data relating to marriages, divorces, and annulments. The secretary shall adopt administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Each county clerk shall on or before the tenth day of each month furnish to the state registrar, from the marriage licenses issued and the marriage certificates returned to the clerk during the previous month, the information required by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services upon forms prescribed and furnished by the cabinet. The county clerk shall collect from the applicants for a marriage license at the time the license is issued one dollar ($1), which shall constitute the clerk's fee for forwarding the required information to the state registrar. </section><section prefix="3">A marriage record not filed within the time prescribed by this section may be registered in accordance with administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">In all actions for dissolution of marriage, the petitioner, or the petitioner's attorney or legal representative, shall file, concurrently with the petition, the information requested on forms prescribed and furnished by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. By January 1, 2013, these forms shall be available on the cabinet's Web site as a downloadable document that can be completed electronically and printed. The provisions of the information shall be prerequisite to the issuance of a final decree in the matter by the court. </section><section prefix="5">Each Circuit Court clerk shall, within forty-five (45) days after entry of a final judgment of divorce, absolute or limited, or annulment of marriage, complete the form prescribed and furnished by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and forward it to the state registrar. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 440, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 389, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 22, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>