<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.700</section_number><catch_line>Early Childhood Advisory Council -- Membership -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Early Childhood Advisory Council is established as a public agency and political subdivision of the Commonwealth with all powers, duties, and responsibilities conferred upon it by statute and essential to perform its functions including but not limited to employing other persons, consultants, attorneys, and agents. The council shall be attached to the Office of the Governor for administrative purposes and shall establish necessary advisory councils. The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or the secretary's designee shall be the appointing authority for the council pursuant to KRS Chapter 18A. The council shall have the ability to make expenditures from the early childhood development fund and shall ensure that expenditures made from the early childhood development fund are in conformance with its duties as established by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the Governor pursuant to KRS 12.040. The executive director shall report to the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or the secretary's designee. </section><section prefix="3">The council shall consist of the following twenty-six (26) members: <section prefix="a">The state director of Head Start Collaboration; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or designee; </section><section prefix="c">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or designee; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) nonvoting ex officio member from the House of Representatives who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) nonvoting ex officio member from the Senate who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="f">Six (6) private sector members knowledgeable about the health, mental health, education, and development of prenatal to school entry children who shall be appointed by the Governor. One (1) private sector member shall be appointed from each congressional district; </section><section prefix="g">Seven (7) citizens at large of the Commonwealth who shall be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) early childhood development advocate who shall be appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) member representing higher education with expertise in early childhood who shall be appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="j">Six (6) members appointed by the Governor, including one (1) member from a Head Start program located in the state, one (1) member from a local education agency, one (1) member from the state agency responsible for education, one (1) member from the state agency responsible for child care, one (1) member from the state agency responsible for Part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA), and one (1) member from the state agency for health and mental health. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The initial terms of the private sector and citizen-at-large members of the council shall be for: <section prefix="1">One (1) year for five (5) of the initial terms; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) years for five (5) of the initial terms; </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) years for six (6) of the initial terms; and </section><section prefix="4">Four (4) years for five (5) of the initial appointments. </section></section><section prefix="b">All succeeding appointments shall be for four (4) years from the expiration date of the preceding appointment. The private and citizen-at-large members shall serve no more than two (2) full successive terms. A term shall expire on June 30 in the appropriate year. </section><section prefix="c">Members shall serve until a successor has been appointed. If a vacancy on the council occurs, the Governor shall appoint a replacement for the remainder of the unexpired term except for the members appointed by the Speaker of the House and President of the Senate. </section><section prefix="d">The members and nonmember appointees of the council shall comply with the gift and conflict of interest statutes in KRS Chapter 11A. Any conflict of interest issue shall be submitted to the Executive Branch Ethics Commission for resolution. </section><section prefix="e">The Governor shall appoint the chair of the council from the private sector or citizen-at-large membership. </section><section prefix="f">The chair may appoint nonmembers of the council to committees or workgroups. </section></section><section prefix="5">Private sector and citizen-at-large members and nonmembers appointed to a committee or workgroup shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses in accordance with state travel expenses and reimbursement administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="6">In making appointments to the council, the Governor shall assure broad geographical, ethnic, and gender diversity representation from the major sectors of Kentucky's early childhood development community. In filling vacancies, the Governor shall attempt to assure the continuing representation on the council of broad constituencies of Kentucky's early childhood development community. </section><section prefix="7">The council shall meet at least quarterly and at other times upon call of the chair or a majority of the council. </section><section prefix="8">Members of the council shall serve on a voluntary basis and be reimbursed for their expenses in accordance with state travel expense and reimbursement administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 61, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 119, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 49, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42143</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>