<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.015</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">A "political party" is an affiliation or organization of electors representing a political policy and having a constituted authority for its government and regulation, and whose candidate received at least twenty percent (20%) of the total vote cast at the last preceding election at which presidential electors were voted for; </section><section prefix="2">The word "election" used in reference to a state, district, county, or city election, includes the decisions of questions submitted to the qualified voters as well as the choice of officers by them; </section><section prefix="3">A "ballot" or "official ballot" means the voting machine ballot label, ballot cards, paper ballots, an absentee ballot, or a supplemental paper ballot which has been authorized for the use of the voters in any primary, general, or special election by the Secretary of State or the county clerk; </section><section prefix="4">"Ballot label" means the cards, papers, booklet, pages, or other material on which appear the names of candidates and the questions to be voted on by means of ballot cards or voting machines; </section><section prefix="5">"Ballot card" means a tabulating card on which votes may be recorded by a voter by use of a voting punch device or by marking with a pen or special marking device; </section><section prefix="6">"Voting machine" or "machine" shall include lever machines and, as far as applicable, any electronic or electromechanical unit and supplies utilized or relied upon by a voter in casting and recording his votes in an election; </section><section prefix="7">The word "resident" used in reference to a candidate in a state, district, county, or city election shall mean actual resident, without regard to the residence of the spouse of the candidate; </section><section prefix="8">"Political organization" means a political group not constituting a political party within the meaning of subsection (1) of this section but whose candidate received two percent (2%) or more of the vote of the state at the last preceding election for presidential electors; and </section><section prefix="9">"Political group" means a political group not constituting a political party or a political organization within the meaning of subsections (1) and (8) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 35, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 360, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 402, sec. 6, effective January  1, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 252, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective March 19, 1977. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 97, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27559</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>