<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.805</section_number><catch_line>Powers of authority. </catch_line><order_by>805</order_by><text>The authority may: <section prefix="1">Acquire, construct, reconstruct, maintain, repair, operate, and regulate, health projects including appropriately designed housing for elderly citizens at such locations within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, as may be determined by the authority; </section><section prefix="2">Acquire any interests in real property pursuant to the condemnation procedures of the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding KRS Chapter 56, the authority may issue revenue bonds payable solely from the charges, revenues, rentals, and other funds pledged for their payment, for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any project or for the acquisition of property; </section><section prefix="4">Sell any building, structure, facility, or any interests in land to the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the federal, city, or county government, or any person or corporation; </section><section prefix="5">Lease any interest in real property, any building, facility, or structure to the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the federal, city, or county government or to any person or corporation; </section><section prefix="6">Fix and revise from time to time the charges and rent payments which will be paid by the different lessees for the use of the land, buildings and parking facilities; </section><section prefix="7">Combine for financing purposes any two (2) or more projects; </section><section prefix="8">Establish and enforce rules, specifications, and regulations for the construction and use of any project, except during any period when such powers are assigned to a lessee pursuant to a lease agreement; </section><section prefix="9">Notwithstanding KRS Chapter 56, to acquire and hold in the name of the authority real and personal property in the exercise of its powers and the performance of its functions and duties under KRS 216.800 to 216.853, and to dispose of these interests in property; </section><section prefix="10">Make and enter into such contracts and agreements with the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any federal, city, or county government or other person or corporation as may be necessary or incidental to the effectiveness of a project; </section><section prefix="11">Employ consulting engineers, attorneys, accountants, construction and financial experts, superintendents, managers, and such other employees and agents as may be necessary in the judgment of the authority, and to fix their compensation; </section><section prefix="12">Receive and accept from the Commonwealth, the cabinet, any federal agency, and the city or county, grants for or in aid of the construction of any project, and receive and accept aid or contributions from any source of either money, property, labor or other things of value, to be held, used and applied for the purposes for which such grants and contributions may be made; and </section><section prefix="13">Do all acts necessary and proper to carry out the powers expressly granted in KRS 216.800 to 216.853. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 92. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 3, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9118</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>