<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.390</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings on military burial honors -- Authority to promulgate administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth of Kentucky recognizes the need to provide for honorable burials for Kentuckians who have served their state and nation in the Armed Forces. Historically these burial services have been conducted by the active military units in Kentucky, the Kentucky National Guard, the military reserves, and the veterans’ service organizations. However, increasing death rates, declining military resources, and an aging membership of veterans’ service organizations present the need for new initiatives in support of military burial honors. </section><section prefix="2">To correct this situation, and recognizing the immediate need, the Department of Military Affairs shall oversee a Military Burial Honor Guard Program, in coordination with the Department of Veterans’ Affairs, on behalf of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Military Affairs, in consultation with and as a supplement to the Department of Defense, active United States military commands in Kentucky, the Department of Veterans' Affairs, the military reserves, and veterans service organizations, shall implement and administer the provisions of KRS 36.390 to 36.396 through the promulgation of administrative regulations. These regulations shall be in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A and shall comply with and supplement the Department of Defense and the Armed Services’ guidance. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>