<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.789</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for entering into agreement. </catch_line><order_by>789</order_by><text>The department shall not enter into the SSUTA agreement unless the SSUTA agreement requires each state to abide by the following requirements: <section prefix="1">The SSUTA agreement shall set restrictions to achieve more uniform state rates through the following: <section prefix="a">Limiting the number of state rates; </section><section prefix="b">Limiting the application of maximums on the amount of state tax that is due on a transaction; and </section><section prefix="c">Limiting the application of thresholds on the application of state tax. </section></section><section prefix="2">The SSUTA agreement shall establish uniform standards for the following: <section prefix="a">The sourcing of transactions to taxing jurisdictions; </section><section prefix="b">The administration of exempt sales; </section><section prefix="c">The allowances a seller can take for bad debts; and </section><section prefix="d">Sales and use tax returns and remittances. </section></section><section prefix="3">The SSUTA agreement shall require states to develop and adopt uniform definitions of sales and use tax terms. The definitions shall enable a state to preserve its ability to make policy choices not inconsistent with the uniform definitions. </section><section prefix="4">The SSUTA agreement shall provide a central, electronic registration system that allows a seller to register to collect and remit sales and use taxes for all signatory states. </section><section prefix="5">The SSUTA agreement shall provide that registration with the central registration system and the collection of sales and use taxes in the signatory state will not be used as a factor in determining whether the seller has nexus with a state for any tax. </section><section prefix="6">The SSUTA agreement shall provide for a reduction of the burdens of complying with local sales and use taxes through the following: <section prefix="a">Restricting variances between the state and local tax bases; </section><section prefix="b">Requiring states to administer any sales and use taxes levied by local jurisdictions within the state so that sellers collecting and remitting these taxes will not have to register or file returns with, remit funds to, or be subject to independent audits from local taxing jurisdictions; </section><section prefix="c">Restricting the frequency of changes in the local sales and use tax rates and setting effective dates for the application of local jurisdictional boundary changes to local sales and use taxes; and </section><section prefix="d">Providing notice of changes in local sales and use tax rates and of changes in the boundaries of local taxing jurisdictions. </section></section><section prefix="7">The SSUTA agreement shall outline any monetary allowances that are to be provided by the states to sellers or certified service providers. </section><section prefix="8">The SSUTA agreement shall require each state to certify compliance with the terms of the agreement prior to joining and to maintain compliance under the laws of the member state, with all provisions of the SSUTA agreement while a member. </section><section prefix="9">The SSUTA agreement shall require each state to adopt a uniform policy for certified service providers that protects the privacy of consumers and maintains the confidentiality of tax information. </section><section prefix="10">The SSUTA agreement shall provide for the appointment of an advisory council of private sector representatives and an advisory council of non-member state representatives to consult with in the administration of the SSUTA agreement. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 24, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 449, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 6, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28965</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>