<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.315</section_number><catch_line>Articles of dissolution. </catch_line><order_by>315</order_by><text>After the dissolution of the limited liability company pursuant to KRS 275.285(2), (3), or (4), the limited liability company shall file articles of dissolution with the Secretary of State which set forth: <section prefix="1">The name of the limited liability company; </section><section prefix="2">A statement of the subsection of KRS 275.285 pursuant to which the limited liability company has dissolved; </section><section prefix="3">The effective date, which shall be a date certain, of the dissolution; and </section><section prefix="4">Any other information the members or managers filing the articles of dissolution shall deem proper. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 17, effective June 8, 2011. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 121, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 121, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 63, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39667</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>