<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="38" order_by="38">NATIONAL GUARD </unit></structure><section_number>38.440</section_number><catch_line>Entities who may drill or parade with arms without Governor's permission. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as permitted in subsections (2), (3), and (4) of this section, no persons other than the Kentucky National Guard or Kentucky active militia shall associate together as an armed company or drill or parade with arms without permission from the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Students in educational institutions chartered under the laws of Kentucky, in which military science is part of the course of instruction, may drill and parade with arms in public under the supervision of their instructors. </section><section prefix="3">Veterans' service organizations may wear swords and may drill or parade with arms in public. </section><section prefix="4">People participating in the reenactment of a historical military event from the French and Indian War, Revolutionary War, War of 1812, United States Civil War, or Spanish-American War may wear swords and may drill or parade with arms in public. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective March 15, 2011. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 22. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2711a-211. </history><metadata><effective> March 15, 2011 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. III, 31 at 742. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>