<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.080</section_number><catch_line>State Plumbers Examining Committee. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to conduct examinations for persons to qualify as licensed master plumbers or journeyman plumbers, the department shall appoint as examiners the following persons to a State Plumbers Examining Committee: An employee of the department and three (3) other persons who shall be licensed either as master or journeyman plumbers. The commissioner shall be an ex officio examiner and permanent commissioner of the committee. With the exception of the issuance of any order involving the revocation, suspension or cancellation of a master or journeyman plumber's license, the commissioner may delegate to a subordinate employee in the department the power to be present and participate, including the right to vote, as his or her representative at any meeting, hearing or other proceeding of the State Plumbers Examining Committee. Plumber examiners shall serve at the pleasure of the department. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall appoint assistant plumber examiners who shall be qualified licensed master or journeyman plumbers who shall serve at the pleasure of the department. Assistant plumber examiners shall perform such duties as are delegated to them by the State Plumbers Examining Committee. </section><section prefix="3">Plumber examiners and assistant plumber examiners shall receive no compensation for their services but shall be reimbursed for their necessary traveling expenses. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1681, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 55, effective July 1, 1978; and ch. 155, sec. 153, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 68. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 92. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 87. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 12, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3909b-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31199</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>