<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.940</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions from traffic regulations. </catch_line><order_by>940</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 189.920, the speed limitations set forth in the Kentucky Revised Statutes do not apply to emergency vehicles: <section prefix="a">When responding to emergency calls; or </section><section prefix="b">To police vehicles when in pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law; or </section><section prefix="c">To ambulances when transporting a patient to medical care facilities; and </section><section prefix="d">The driver thereof is giving the warning required by subsection (5)(a) and (b) of this section. </section></section> No portion of this subsection shall be construed to relieve the driver of the duty to operate the vehicle with due regard for the safety of all persons using the street or highway. <section prefix="2">The driver of an emergency vehicle, when responding to an emergency call, or of a police vehicle in pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law, or of an ambulance transporting a patient to a medical care facility and giving the warning required by subsection (5) of this section, upon approaching any red light or stop signal or any stop sign shall slow down as necessary for safety to traffic, but may proceed past such red or stop light or stop sign with due regard for the safety of persons using the street or highway. </section><section prefix="3">The driver of an emergency vehicle, when responding to an emergency call, or of a police vehicle in pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law, or of an ambulance transporting a patient to a medical care facility and giving warning required by subsection (5) of this section, may drive on the left side of any highway or in the opposite direction of a one-way street provided the normal lanes of traffic are blocked and he does so with due regard for the safety of all persons using the street or highway. </section><section prefix="4">The driver of an emergency or public safety vehicle may stop or park his vehicle upon any street or highway without regard to the provisions of KRS 189.390 and 189.450, provided that, during the time the vehicle is parked at the scene of an emergency, at least one (1) warning light is in operation at all times. </section><section prefix="5">The driver of an emergency vehicle desiring the use of any option granted by subsections (1) through (3) of this section shall give warning in the following manner: <section prefix="a">By illuminating the vehicle's warning lights continuously during the period of the emergency; and </section><section prefix="b">By continuous sounding of the vehicle's siren, bell, or exhaust whistle; unless </section><section prefix="c">The vehicle is an ambulance and the driver is of the opinion that sounding of the siren, bell, or exhaust whistle would be detrimental to the victim's health.  In the event the driver of an ambulance elects not to use the siren, bell, or exhaust whistle he shall not proceed past red lights or drive in the opposite direction on a one-way street or in oncoming lanes of traffic unless no other vehicles are within five hundred (500) feet of the front of the ambulance.  The driver shall not extinguish the warning lights during the period of the emergency. </section></section><section prefix="6">No driver or operator of any emergency or public safety or other vehicle shall use the warning lights or siren, bell, or exhaust whistle of his vehicle for any purposes or under any circumstances other than those permitted by KRS 189.910 to 189.950. </section><section prefix="7">KRS 189.910 to 189.950 does not relieve the driver of any emergency or public safety vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons and property upon the highway. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 36. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39896</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>