<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.310</section_number><catch_line>Mining Council -- Members -- Terms. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The "Mining Council," hereinafter called "the council," is hereby established in the office of the Governor. The council shall be the advisory body referred to in Article V(a) of the Interstate Mining Compact. No member of the council shall receive any compensation on account of his service thereon, but any such member shall be entitled to reimbursement for expenses actually incurred by him in connection with his possible service as the Governor's alternate on the Interstate Mining Commission. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall be composed of eight (8) members: one (1) of whom shall be the Lieutenant Governor; three (3) of whom shall be representatives of mining industries; two (2) of whom shall be representatives of nongovernmental conservation interests; the commissioner for environmental protection and the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The members of the council representing mining industries and nongovernmental conservation interests shall be appointed by the Governor. The term of office of such members shall be for four (4) years concurrent with that of the Governor or until their successor has been qualified. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1886, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(7). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 79. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 30. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32837</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>