<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.19-090</section_number><catch_line>Premiums and refunds. </catch_line><order_by>19-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any insurer may revise its schedules of premium rates from time to time, and shall file such revised schedules with the commissioner. No insurer shall issue any credit life insurance or credit health insurance policy for which the premium rate exceeds that determined by the schedules of such insurer as then on file with the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Each individual policy or group certificate shall provide that in the event of termination of the insurance prior to the scheduled maturity date of the indebtedness, any refund of an amount paid by the debtor for insurance shall be paid or credited promptly to the person entitled thereto. The commissioner shall prescribe a minimum refund and no refund which would be less than such minimum need be made. The formula to be used in computing such refund shall be filed with and approved by the commissioner. Nothing contained in this section shall require the debtor to surrender any policy or group certificate for cancellation or termination solely because the indebtedness has been paid in full prior to the scheduled maturity date nor require the insurer to return any premiums. </section><section prefix="3">When a debtor purchases credit life insurance or credit health insurance and an individual policy or group certificate of insurance is not issued, the creditor shall immediately give written notice to such debtor and shall promptly make an appropriate credit to the account. </section><section prefix="4">The amount charged to a debtor for any credit life insurance or credit health insurance shall not exceed the premiums charged by the insurer, as computed at the time the charge to the debtor is determined. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this subtitle shall be construed to authorize any payments for insurance now prohibited under any statute, or rule thereunder, governing credit transactions. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1304, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 19, sec. 9, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29467</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>