<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="433" order_by="433">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>433.902</section_number><catch_line>Secondary metals recycler to obtain certificate of registration from Office of Occupations and Professions -- Application -- Name-based background check -- Fees -- Annual renewal -- Display of certificate -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>902</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Each secondary metals recycler shall submit to a name-based background check as provided in subsection (2) of this section and obtain a certificate of registration from the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet within sixty (60) days of the effective date of administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="b">The application for certificate of registration shall be in a form and format determined by the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet and shall contain at a minimum the following: <section prefix="1">The name of the secondary metals recycling business; </section><section prefix="2">The name or names of each applicant; </section><section prefix="3">The address of each secondary metals recycling business owned by the applicant; and </section><section prefix="4">Contact information for the purposes of KRS 433.906. </section></section><section prefix="c">Any person listed on an application for a certificate of registration shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age prior to the date that the application is submitted. </section><section prefix="d">Any corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, incorporated association, or any other entity engaged in business as, or organized for the purpose of engaging in business as, a secondary metals recycler submitting an application must be organized and qualified to do business in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="e">The Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall charge each applicant a reasonable fee established by administrative regulation equal to the actual administrative costs of processing an application for a certificate of registration. </section><section prefix="f">If an applicant is the owner of more than one (1) secondary metals recycling location, the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall charge a fee for each location that is no greater than the actual administrative costs of processing the application for certificate of registration. Upon approval of the application, the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall issue a certificate of registration for each location. </section><section prefix="g">Each applicant that receives a certificate of registration from the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet as provided in this section shall be required to pay an annual renewal fee equal to the actual administrative costs of processing the renewal of the certificate for registration. </section><section prefix="h">The list of secondary metals recyclers registered with the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet as provided in this section shall be public information and available upon written request to the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Prior to approval of the application, the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall require a name-based background check on each applicant. </section><section prefix="b">Each applicant shall provide written authorization to the Department of Kentucky State Police to perform a name-based background check and release the results to the Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet. </section><section prefix="c">Any request for a name-based background check shall be on a form or through a process approved by the Department of Kentucky State Police, which may charge a fee to be paid by the applicant in an amount no greater than the actual cost of processing the request. </section><section prefix="d">The Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall not issue a certificate of registration to an applicant if the name-based background check results reveal that the applicant has been convicted of, or entered a plea of guilty, an Alford plea, or a plea of nolo contendere to, a felony involving theft, larceny, dealing in stolen property, receiving stolen property, burglary, embezzlement, or obtaining property by false pretenses, any felony drug offense, or knowingly and intentionally violating the laws of the Commonwealth relating to registration as a secondary metals recycler. </section></section><section prefix="3">A secondary metals recycler's certificate of registration shall be conspicuously displayed at the location of the secondary metals recycler listed on the application for certificate of registration or at each location if the secondary metals recycler owns more than one (1) business location. </section><section prefix="4">The Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The Office of Occupations and Professions of the Public Protection Cabinet shall not be responsible for any disciplinary action against any secondary metals recycler seeking an application for certificate of registration. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>