<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="38" order_by="38">NATIONAL GUARD </unit></structure><section_number>38.090</section_number><catch_line>Enlistment in Kentucky National Guard -- Oath -- Transfer -- Extension of enlistments. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All able-bodied citizens of the United States, of good character, who can read and write the English language, who are between the ages of seventeen (17) and thirty-five (35) years with no prior service; between thirty-six (36) and under thirty-eight (38) with one (1) year of service; thirty-eight (38) and under forty-one (41) with two </section><section prefix="2">years of service and forty-one (41) and under fifty-seven (57) with two (2) years </section>plus the number of years applicant is over age forty (40), and who have passed the required physical examination and who are not ineligible for enlistment or reenlistment in the Armed Forces of the United States, subject to current United States Armed Forces regulations covering enlistments and reenlistments, may be enlisted or reenlisted in the Kentucky National Guard for a term of one (1) or more years. (2) No person dishonorably discharged or discharged without honor from the Armed Forces of the United States shall be eligible for enlistment in the Kentucky National Guard. <section prefix="3">Every person who enlists, extends his enlistment or reenlists shall sign and make oath to an enlistment paper before any officer from any branch of the armed services authorized to administer oaths. </section><section prefix="4">Enlisted persons may be transferred to or from organizations, as provided by regulations. </section><section prefix="5">By order of the Governor in case of emergency, enlistments in the Kentucky National Guard may be extended for one (1) year. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 46, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 15. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 4. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2711a-174, 2711a-175, 2711a-176. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>