<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.680</section_number><catch_line>State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement.  (Expired) </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text>There shall be appointed by the Governor a State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement in accordance with the following: <section prefix="1">The State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement shall be eighteen (18) members broadly representative of citizens, parents, teachers, and administrators. Their principal duties shall be to advise the Governor, the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education, and the department on the implementation of the provisions of KRS 158.650 to 158.710 and KRS 158.6453 and 158.6455. </section><section prefix="2">All members shall be voting members appointed by the Governor and shall serve terms of four (4) years, except that the original appointments will be made as follows: <section prefix="a">Five (5) members for four (4) year terms; </section><section prefix="b">Five (5) members for three (3) year terms; </section><section prefix="c">Four (4) members for two (2) year terms; and </section><section prefix="d">Four (4) members for a one (1) year term. </section></section><section prefix="3">The State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement shall elect a chairman annually from its membership; </section><section prefix="4">The members shall be remunerated for actual and necessary expenses incurred while attending meetings of the State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement or while serving in the capacity as representative of the State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement. </section><section prefix="5">The State Advisory Committee for Educational Improvement shall meet at least three (3) times each year at times and places as it determines by resolution. </section></text><history> Expired 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 11, effective June 30, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><lrc-note>(7/15/98).  This statute expired June 30, 1996, under KRS 158.710(6), although this expiration was suspended for the period of the 1996-98 biennium. See LRC Note of 7/2/97. Because the statute had expired, its amendment in 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 4, was without effect.(7/2/97).Although this statute has expired under the terms of KRS 158.710(6), this expiration has been suspended for the period of the 1996-98 biennium by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 380, part IX, item 12. d., at 1965. 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 4 renamed the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education, referenced in subsection (1) of this statute, as the Kentucky Board of Education. (7/15/96).  Because this statute has expired as of June 30, 1996, under KRS 158.710(6), a reference to the State Board for Elementary and Secondary Education in subsection (1) of this statute has not been changed to the Kentucky Board of Education as required by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>