<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.110</section_number><catch_line>Power to secure information -- Coercing production of evidence -- Cooperation of other agencies -- Cooperation with other states -- Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws -- Subcommittee and citizens' committee reports and recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission, its co-chairmen or director, any other member of the General Assembly authorized by the director, or any employee authorized by the director, shall have access to all public records as provided in KRS 61.870 to 61.884, of every agency, division or department of state government, and of any agency or institution, public or private, which has been the recipient of public funds. The Commission, its co-chairmen or director, any other member of the General Assembly authorized by the director, or any employee authorized by the director, may utilize automated data processing procedures and equipment in the accession of public records, if such records exist in machine readable form.  To effect the purposes of this section, the Commission shall promulgate such rules and regulations relating to the accession of public records as are necessary.  The Commission, its co-chairmen or director, any other member of the General Assembly authorized by the director, or any employee authorized by the director, may require information on oath of any person touching any matter which he is instructed to investigate, study or audit, and shall have the power to subpoena witnesses and records for such purpose, and otherwise compel the giving of evidence of any matter under study. If any person fails or refuses to testify or furnish documentary evidence concerning any matter with respect to which the Commission desires information pertaining to the studies in which it is engaged, the Franklin Circuit Court, on application of the Commission, may compel obedience by proceedings for contempt as in the case of disobedience of a subpoena issued from the Circuit Court or a refusal to testify therein. Every witness so subpoenaed under this section shall receive for his attendance the fee and mileage provided for witnesses in civil cases in Circuit Court, which shall be audited and paid upon the presentation of proper vouchers sworn to by the witness and approved by the Commission. </section><section prefix="2">All state agencies and institutions shall cooperate with the Commission to effectuate the purposes of KRS 7.090 to 7.110 and shall submit copies of their annual or biennial reports to the Commission. </section><section prefix="3">The Commission shall encourage and arrange conferences with officials of other states and of other units of government; carry forward the participation of this state as a member of the Council of State Governments, both regionally and nationally, and formulate proposals for cooperation between this state and other states. The Legislative Research Commission shall function as Kentucky's commission on interstate cooperation in carrying out the program of the Council of State Governments as it relates to Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">The Commission shall designate persons to represent Kentucky at the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws. The Commission shall report the findings and recommendations of the national conference to the General Assembly. Any funds appropriated to the commissioners on uniform state laws shall be paid out on vouchers approved by the director of the Commission. </section><section prefix="5">The Commission may establish such subcommittees and advisory citizens' committees as may be convenient or desired for the proper and efficient performance of its functions. Members of the General Assembly other than those who are members of the Commission designated to serve on subcommittees shall receive the same travel allowances and compensation for attending meetings as they do for attending meetings during a session of the General Assembly, except that each General Assembly member who is a chairman of a joint interim committee of the Legislative Research Commission shall be paid, in addition to such allowances and compensation, ten dollars ($10) per day for each committee meeting that he chairs. </section><section prefix="6">The Commission shall report its findings, either with or without recommendations, to the Governor of the Commonwealth, and to each member of the General Assembly at least thirty (30) days prior to the convening of each regular session of the General Assembly. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 131,sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 12, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1954. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1948. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=458</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>