<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.250</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of board members -- Vacancies. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided for in subsection (5) of this section, each land surveyor appointment to the board shall be made from a list of not less than three (3) nominees to be submitted to the Governor jointly by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers and the Kentucky Association of Professional Surveyors, with input from other professional societies. All other appointments to the board shall be made from a list of not less than three (3) nominees to be submitted to the Governor by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers with input from other professional societies. </section><section prefix="2">The nominations shall be submitted to the Governor at least sixty (60) days prior to the appointment date. </section><section prefix="3">The term of office for all full-term appointments shall begin January 1. </section><section prefix="4">Board members shall be allowed to succeed themselves but shall be limited to not more than two (2) consecutive terms. A former member may be reappointed to the board if the member has not served in the preceding four (4) years. </section><section prefix="5">If a vacancy on the board occurs for any reason resulting in an unexpired term, if not filled within three (3) months by official action of the Governor, the board may appoint a provisional member to serve in the interim until the Governor acts. </section><section prefix="6">Every unexpired term shall be filled only for the remainder of that term. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 22, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 18. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-3, 1599e-6. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31444</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>