<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.156</section_number><catch_line>Third parties to labor/management negotiations or arbitration -- Duties -- Regulations by secretary. </catch_line><order_by>156</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any individual, partnership, association or corporation who represents, advises or acts as consultant or spokesman for any party to labor/management negotiations or arbitration conducted in Kentucky shall be, for the purposes of this section, known as third parties. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to representing or agreeing to represent any party to any labor/management negotiations or arbitration, all third parties shall notify the secretary of such intent. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall require third parties to labor/management negotiations or arbitration to report such information as may assist the cabinet in determining whether such third party is to be certified to engage in or render advice on negotiations or any matter under arbitration. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall offer mediation and arbitration services elsewhere provided by law to all parties to negotiations or arbitration where third party intervention is contemplated. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement the requirements of this section; regulations are to include but not be limited to: definitions, filing requirements, notification procedures and reasonable penalties for failure to comply. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall not apply to full-time employees of any party to negotiations or arbitration nor to any third party licensed to do business in Kentucky under any other section of Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="7">No third party shall participate in or offer advice on negotiations or arbitration in the Commonwealth of Kentucky until the provisions of this section have been met. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1715, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32008</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>