<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.25-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subchapter. </catch_line><order_by>25-010</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter: <section prefix="1">"Activation date" means a date selected by an approved company and set forth in the jobs retention agreement at any time within a three (3) year period after the date of final approval of the agreement by the authority upon which the required investment shall be made and the jobs retention project completed; </section><section prefix="2">"Agreement" means a jobs retention agreement entered into pursuant to KRS 154.25-030 on behalf of the authority and an approved company with respect to a jobs retention project; </section><section prefix="3">"Approved company" means any eligible company approved by the authority pursuant to KRS 154.25-030 for a jobs retention project; </section><section prefix="4">"Approved costs" means that portion of the eligible costs approved by the authority that an approved company may recover through the inducements authorized by KRS 154.25-030, being a percentage of eligible costs as approved by the authority; </section><section prefix="5">"Assessment" means the wage assessment fee authorized by KRS 154.25-040; </section><section prefix="6">"Authority" means the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority created by KRS 154.20-010; </section><section prefix="7">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="8">"Eligible company" means any corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, business trust, or any other entity designated by the United States Department of Commerce, United States Census Bureau North American Industry Classification System Code of 325211, 325510, 326199, 327211, 327212, 327215, 331111, 331221, 331521, 332312, 332813, 33299, 333415, 335110, 335221, 335222, 335224, 335228, 335911, 335912, 336211, 336111, 336112, 336120, 423510, 493110, 541614, 551114, or 561439, that employs a minimum of one thousand (1,000) full-time persons engaged in automobile, automobile parts or supplies, household appliance, or household appliance parts or supplies manufacturing, has been operating within the Commonwealth on a continuous basis for at least five (5) years preceding the request for approval by the authority of the project which meets the standards set forth in KRS 154.25-020, and that has been previously approved for economic development incentives from the Commonwealth related to one (1) or more of its facilities; </section><section prefix="9">"Eligible costs" means: <section prefix="a">Obligations incurred for labor and to vendors, contractors, subcontractors, builders, suppliers, deliverymen, and materialmen in connection with the acquisition, construction, equipping, rehabilitation, and installation of a jobs retention project; </section><section prefix="b">The cost of contract bonds and of insurance of all kinds that may be required or necessary during the course of a jobs retention project which is not paid by the vendor, supplier, deliveryman, contractor, or otherwise provided; </section><section prefix="c">All costs of architectural and engineering services, including estimates, plans and specifications, preliminary investigations, and supervision of construction, rehabilitation, and installation, as well as for the performance of all the duties required by or consequent upon the acquisition, construction, equipping, rehabilitation, and installation of a jobs retention project; </section><section prefix="d">All costs required to be paid under the terms of any contract for the acquisition, construction, equipping, rehabilitation, and installation of a jobs retention project; </section><section prefix="e">All costs required for the installation of utilities, including but not limited to water, sewer, sewer treatment, gas, electricity, communications, and railroads, and including off-site construction of the facilities paid for by the approved company; and </section><section prefix="f">All other costs comparable with those described above; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Final approval" means the action taken by the authority authorizing the eligible company to receive inducements under this subchapter; </section><section prefix="11">"Inducements" means the Kentucky tax credit and the wage assessment fee as prescribed in KRS 154.25-030 and 154.25-040; </section><section prefix="12">"Jobs retention project" or "project" means the acquisition, construction, and installation of new equipment and, with respect thereto, the construction, rehabilitation, and installation of improvements to facilities necessary to house the acquisition, construction, and installation of new equipment, including surveys; installation of utilities, including water, sewer, sewage treatment, gas, electricity, communications, and similar facilities; off-site construction of utility extensions to the boundaries of the real estate on which the facilities are located; and shall contain eligible costs of not less than one hundred million dollars ($100,000,000), all of which are utilized to improve the economic and operational situation of an approved company to allow the approved company to reinvest in its operations and retain a significant number of existing jobs within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="13">"Kentucky gross profits" means Kentucky gross profits as defined in KRS 141.0401; </section><section prefix="14">"Kentucky gross receipts" means Kentucky gross receipts as defined in KRS 141.0401; </section><section prefix="15">"Manufacturing" means any activity involving the manufacturing, processing, assembling, or production of any property, including the processing that results in a change in the condition of the property and any related activity or function, together with the storage, warehousing, distribution, and related office facilities; </section><section prefix="16">"Preliminary approval" means the action taken by the authority conditioning final approval by the authority upon satisfaction by the eligible company of the requirements under this subchapter; </section><section prefix="17">"Supplemental project" means an additional jobs retention project proposed by the approved company or its affiliate during the term of a previously approved jobs retention project, which may be included in the jobs retention agreement by way of amendment and which may result in increased inducements and an extension of the original project term as set forth in KRS 154.25-050; and </section><section prefix="18">"Transferred credits" means unused approved costs as determined by the Department of Revenue from a previously approved, independent, active project under a different incentive program governed by the Cabinet for Economic Development that may be transferred to a jobs retention project and used by the approved company pursuant to a jobs retention agreement. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>