<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.485</section_number><catch_line>Exemption of food items -- Definitions.</catch_line><order_by>485</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided, the terms "retail sale," "use," "storage," and "consumption" as used in this chapter shall not include the sale, use, storage or consumption of food and food ingredients for human consumption. </section><section prefix="2">The term "food and food ingredients" as used in subsection (1) of this section means substances, whether in liquid, concentrated, solid, frozen, dried, or dehydrated form, that are sold for ingestion or chewing by humans and are consumed for their taste or nutritional value. "Food and food ingredients" shall not include: <section prefix="a">Alcoholic beverages; </section><section prefix="b">Tobacco; </section><section prefix="c">Candy; </section><section prefix="d">Dietary supplements; </section><section prefix="e">Soft drinks; and </section><section prefix="f">Prepared food. </section></section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Alcoholic beverages" means beverages that are suitable for human consumption and contain one-half of one percent (0.5%) or more of alcohol by volume; </section><section prefix="b">"Tobacco" means cigarettes, cigars, chewing or pipe tobacco, or any other item that contains tobacco; </section><section prefix="c">"Candy" means a preparation of sugar, honey, or other natural or artificial sweeteners in combination with chocolate, fruits, nuts, or other ingredients or flavorings in the form of bars, drops, or pieces. "Candy" shall not include: <section prefix="1">Any preparation containing flour; or </section><section prefix="2">Any item requiring refrigeration; </section></section><section prefix="d">"Dietary supplement" means any product, other than tobacco, intended to supplement the diet that: <section prefix="1">Contains one (1) or more of the following dietary ingredients: <section prefix="a">A vitamin; </section><section prefix="b">A mineral; </section><section prefix="c">An herb or other botanical; </section><section prefix="d">An amino acid; </section><section prefix="e">A dietary substance for use by humans to supplement the diet by increasing the total dietary intake; or </section><section prefix="f">A concentrate, metabolite, constituent, extract, or combination of any ingredient described above; </section></section><section prefix="2">Is intended for ingestion in tablet, capsule, powder, softgel, gelcap, or liquid form or, if not intended for ingestion in such a form, is not represented as conventional food and is not represented for use as a sole item of a meal or of the diet; and </section><section prefix="3">Is required to be labeled as a dietary supplement, identifiable by the "Supplement facts" box found on the label as required pursuant to 21 C.F.R. 101.36; </section></section><section prefix="e">"Soft drinks" means nonalcoholic beverages that contain natural or artificial sweeteners. "Soft drinks" does not include beverages that contain milk or milk products, soy, rice, or similar milk substitutes, or greater than fifty percent (50%) of vegetable or fruit juice by volume; </section><section prefix="f">"Food sold through vending machines" means food dispensed from a machine or other mechanical device that accepts payment; </section><section prefix="g">"Prepared food" means: <section prefix="1">Food sold in a heated state or heated by the retailer; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) or more food ingredients mixed or combined by the retailer for sale as a single item except food that is only cut, repackaged, or pasteurized by the retailer, eggs, fish, meat, poultry, and foods containing these raw animal foods requiring cooking by the consumer as recommended by the Food and Drug Administration in Chapter 3, Part 401.11 of the FDA Food Code so as to prevent food-borne illnesses; or </section><section prefix="3">Food sold with eating utensils provided by the retailer, including plates, knives, forks, spoons, glasses, cups, napkins, or straws; </section></section><section prefix="h">Notwithstanding paragraph (g) of this subsection, "prepared food" shall not include the following items if sold without eating utensils provided by the seller: <section prefix="1">Food sold by a seller whose proper primary North American Industry Classification System classification is manufacturing in sector 311, except subsector 3118; or </section><section prefix="2">Bakery items, including bread, rolls, buns, biscuits, bagels, croissants, pastries, donuts, danishes, cakes, tortes, pies, tarts, muffins, bars, cookies, and tortillas. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, "food and food ingredients" sold through vending machines or nonmechanical self-service vending systems shall be subject to the tax imposed by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 10, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 22, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 62, Pt. I, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1972 </history><metadata><effective> Ju1y 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28898</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>