<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates KRS 230.070 or KRS 230.080(3) shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 230.090 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates KRS 230.680 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who refuses to make any report or to turn over sums as required by KRS 230.361 to 230.373 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="5">Any person failing to appear before the racing commission at the time and place specified in the summons issued pursuant to KRS 230.260(12), or refusing to testify, shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. False swearing on the part of any witness shall be deemed perjury and punished as such. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A person is guilty of tampering with or interfering with a horse race when, with the intent to influence the outcome of a horse race, he uses any device, material, or substance not approved by the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission on or in any participant involved in or eligible to compete in a horse race to be viewed by the public. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who, while outside the Commonwealth and with intent to influence the outcome of a horse race contested within the Commonwealth, tampers with or interferes with any equine participant involved in or eligible to compete in a horse race in the Commonwealth is guilty of tampering with or interfering with a horse race. </section><section prefix="c">Tampering with or interfering with a horse race is a Class C felony. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 494, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 45, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 37, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 463, sec. 26, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 224, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 15, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 209. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 17. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1326, 1327, 1328, 3990a-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(e) and (h), the Reviser of Statutes has changed a reference to "KRS 230.260(13)" to read "KRS 230.260(12)," in order to correct an error resulting from the renumbering of subsections in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 3. (7/14/2000). KRS 230.680, referenced in subsection (3) of this statute, was repealed by 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 40, effective March 20, 1992. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10937</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>