<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.375</section_number><catch_line>Policy to cover entire liability of employer -- Separate policy for specified plant or location may be authorized. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text>Every policy or contract of workers' compensation insurance under this chapter, issued or delivered in this state, shall cover the entire liability of the employer for compensation to each employee subject to this chapter, except as otherwise provided in KRS 216.2960, 342.020, 342.345, or 342.352. However, if specifically authorized by the commissioner, a separate insurance policy may be issued for a specified plant or work location if the liability of the employer under this chapter to each employee subject to this chapter is otherwise secured and provided that no employee transferred from one plant or work location to another within the employment of the same employer shall thereby lose any benefit rights accumulated under the average weekly wage concept. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1826, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 6, sec. 24, effective April 4, 1994; and ch. 512, Part 6, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 44, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4953. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>