<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.801</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for placement of children who are in custody of department -- Statewide and district placement coordinators -- Cases of unmet need -- Information and recommendations -- State resource plan -- Assistance in developing facilities services plan. </catch_line><order_by>801</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall establish a procedure throughout the state that is designed to determine and expedite the placement of children who are in the custody of the department. The procedure shall utilize a statewide placement coordinator and district placement coordinators who may be state employees or employees of a contracted entity, and who shall be assigned and located in each of the department's districts. </section><section prefix="2">Upon determining that a child shall be removed from the current living arrangement, the social service worker with responsibility for the child shall contact the district placement coordinator to facilitate the placement. In consultation with the social service worker, the district placement coordinator shall determine the appropriate type of placement according to the child's circumstances and needs and shall attempt to locate the appropriate placement within the child's home county. </section><section prefix="3">The living arrangement and placement selected for the child shall be the type of facility that is determined to be the best alternative for the child that is in the closest proximity to the child's home county. </section><section prefix="4">If the type of placement that best suits the child's needs is not available in the child's home county, the district placement coordinator shall document the circumstance as an unmet need and may seek a placement in another county located within the home district of the child. </section><section prefix="5">If the type of placement that best suits the child's needs is not available in the child's home district, the district placement coordinator shall document the circumstance as an unmet need and may seek a placement in surrounding districts by contacting the statewide placement coordinator. </section><section prefix="6">If the type of placement that best suits the child's needs is not available in the districts surrounding the child's home district, the district placement coordinator shall document the circumstance as an unmet need and may seek a placement in any district within the state by contacting the statewide placement coordinator. </section><section prefix="7">If the type of placement that best suits the child's needs is not available within the state, the statewide placement coordinator shall contact the commissioner of the department or the commissioner's designee to explore placement options. </section><section prefix="8">The statewide placement coordinator and every district placement coordinator shall compile information that identifies the unmet needs for their jurisdiction, and shall submit the data and recommendations for meeting the unmet needs to the commissioner of the department. </section><section prefix="9">The commissioner shall develop a state placement resource plan that identifies areas of unmet need and strategies to meet the need. The plan shall be used to guide and, if necessary, restrict the development of new facilities, the expansion of existing facilities, and the geographic location of placement alternatives. </section><section prefix="10">The commissioner and the statewide planning coordinator shall assist the Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement, created in KRS 194A.146, in the development of a statewide facilities services plan. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 46, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 60, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>