<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="232" order_by="232">NUDIST SOCIETIES </unit></structure><section_number>232.021</section_number><catch_line>License required for operation of society -- Application -- Fee -- Expiration -- Renewal. </catch_line><order_by>021</order_by><text>No person shall own or operate a nudist society unless he first secures a license from the county judge/executive in the county in which the nudist society will be located. Any person who desires a license shall file an application with the county clerk setting forth the name and address of the owner of the premises upon which the nudist society will be located and the name of the operator, the occupation of the owner or operator, the reason for forming the society and its purpose, the location of the area of the proposed nudist society, and a description of the physical facilities and precautions to be taken which will assure privacy of members and concealment and reasonable isolation of the nudists from the public. If the county judge/executive finds that the character of the applicant is good, the nudist society is proposed to be conducted for religious or health purposes, the facilities appear adequate and the nudist society will be so located or screened or housed, and so operated, as to give reasonable assurance that its activities will be effectively concealed and its members reasonably isolated from the ordinary view and presence of the general public, the county judge/executive shall issue the license upon payment of a fee of one hundred dollars ($100). Each license to operate a nudist society shall expire one (1) year from issuance but may be renewed annually upon payment of a renewal fee of fifty dollars ($50). </text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 371, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 2. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>