<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.7991</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations. </catch_line><order_by>7991</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The General Assembly finds and declares that the integration of the arts and foreign languages into the school curriculum benefits students by increasing their motivation to learn; improves attendance; fosters multicultural understanding; and develops neurological cognitive potential through higher-order thinking skills, creativity, and problem solving. Further, the General Assembly finds and declares that arts and foreign language education can renew and invigorate faculty and can foster greater parent and community participation and support. </section><section prefix="b">The General Assembly notes that it created a system of public education that allows and assists all students to acquire certain capacities provided under KRS 158.645, including communication skills necessary to function in a complex and changing civilization and sufficient grounding in the arts to enable each student to appreciate his or her cultural and historical heritage. </section><section prefix="c">The General Assembly further notes that its goals for public schools under KRS 158.6451 include: to develop students’ abilities to use basic communication and mathematics skills for purposes and situations they will encounter throughout their lives; to apply core concepts and principles from mathematics, the sciences, the arts, the humanities, and social studies; and to connect and integrate experiences and new knowledge from all subject matter fields with what they have previously learned and build on past learning experiences to acquire new information through various sources. </section></section><section prefix="2">It is the intent of the General Assembly in enacting KRS 158.7992 to address the findings and declarations set out in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3596</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>