<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-607</section_number><catch_line>Liability to other persons of person dissociated as general partner. </catch_line><order_by>2-607</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person's dissociation as a general partner does not of itself discharge the person's liability as a general partner for a limited partnership's obligation incurred before dissociation. Except as otherwise provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the person is not liable for a limited partnership's obligation incurred after dissociation. </section><section prefix="2">A person whose dissociation as a general partner resulted in a dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership's activities is liable to the same extent as a general partner under KRS 362.2-404 on an obligation incurred by the limited partnership under KRS 362.2-804. </section><section prefix="3">A person that has dissociated as a general partner but whose dissociation did not result in a dissolution and winding up of the limited partnership's activities is liable on a transaction entered into by the limited partnership after the dissociation, only if: <section prefix="a">A general partner would be liable on the transaction; and </section><section prefix="b">At the time the other party enters into the transaction: <section prefix="1">Less than two (2) years have passed since the dissociation; and </section><section prefix="2">The other party does not have notice of the dissociation and reasonably believes that the person is a general partner. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">By agreement with the limited partnership's creditor and the limited partnership, a person dissociated as a general partner may be released from liability for a limited partnership's obligation. </section><section prefix="5">A person dissociated as a general partner is released from liability for a limited partnership's obligation if a limited partnership's creditor, with notice of the person's dissociation as a general partner but without the person's consent, agrees to a material alteration in the nature or time of payment of the limited partnership's obligation. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 144, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>