<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.100</section_number><catch_line>Consultant's license -- Fee -- Qualifications -- Waiver. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall perform services as a pest control consultant without first procuring from the department a license in the classifications he has applied for under KRS 217B.060. Application for a license shall be on a form prescribed by the department and shall include the applicable information stipulated in KRS 217B.060(2). The application for a license shall be accompanied by an annual fee of fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="2">Each applicant for a pest control consultant's license shall be required to present to the department satisfactory evidence of training and experience providing a basic background to understand pest control principles. The applicant shall be required to pass satisfactorily a written examination to be prescribed by the department to demonstrate the applicant's specific knowledge under KRS 217B.060(3). </section><section prefix="3">If an applicant provides a copy of a valid Kentucky Certified Crop Advisor certification to the department, the test and fee for a consultant license may be waived. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 9. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9533</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>