<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.1901</section_number><catch_line>Minimum requirements for positions created under KRS 16.187. </catch_line><order_by>1901</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At the time of appointment by the department or the secretary, officers shall meet the minimum requirements established by this subsection: <section prefix="a">Commercial vehicle enforcement officers shall: <section prefix="1">Meet at least one (1) of the following education or experience requirements: <section prefix="a">Have completed at least fifty-four (54) semester hours with a college or university; </section><section prefix="b">Possess at least two (2) years experience as a commercial vehicle inspector under the North American Standard Requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Possess at least two (2) years experience as a full-time sworn law enforcement officer; or </section><section prefix="d">Possess at least two (2) years experience in military duty; </section></section><section prefix="2">Be of good moral character and capable of successfully meeting the physical fitness standards established by the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="3">Meet the minimum qualifications for becoming a certified peace officer as provided by KRS 15.382; </section></section><section prefix="b">Arson investigator officers shall: <section prefix="1">Possess at least one (1) year of law enforcement, police, criminal, fire, or arson investigation experience; and </section><section prefix="2">Meet the minimum qualifications for becoming a certified peace officer as provided by KRS 15.382; </section></section><section prefix="c">Hazardous devices investigator officers shall: <section prefix="1">Possess at least five (5) years of experience involving explosives or hazardous devices used in the areas of law enforcement, the military, or firefighting; and </section><section prefix="2">Meet the minimum qualifications for becoming a certified peace officer as provided by KRS 15.382; and </section></section><section prefix="d">Facilities security officers shall be commissioned as special law enforcement officers under KRS 61.900 to 61.930. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon completion of a probationary period of one (1) year: <section prefix="a">Commercial vehicle enforcement officers, arson investigator officers, and hazardous devices investigator officers shall have successfully completed the Peace Officer Professional Standards (POPS) certification process through the Kentucky State Police Academy or through the Department of Criminal Justice Training; and </section><section prefix="b">Commercial vehicle enforcement officers shall successfully complete and pass a certified course in General Hazardous Materials and North American Standard Driver/Vehicle Inspection. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1119</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>