<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.466</section_number><catch_line>Availability of net metering -- Type, expense, and installation of meter -- Calculation of electricity billed -- Rules applicable to billing -- Safety and power quality standards -- Transferability of installation. </catch_line><order_by>466</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each retail electric supplier shall make net metering available to any eligible customer-generator that the supplier currently serves or solicits for service. If the cumulative generating capacity of net metering systems reaches one percent (1%) of a supplier's single hour peak load during the previous year, the obligation of the supplier to offer net metering to a new customer-generator may be limited by the commission. </section><section prefix="2">Each retail electric supplier serving a customer with eligible electric generating facilities shall use a standard kilowatt-hour meter capable of registering the flow of electricity in two (2) directions. Any additional meter, meters, or distribution upgrades needed to monitor the flow in each direction shall be installed at the customer-generator's expense. If additional meters are installed, the net metering calculation shall yield the same result as when a single meter is used. </section><section prefix="3">The amount of electricity billed to the eligible customer-generator using net metering shall be calculated by taking the difference between the electricity supplied by the retail electric supplier to the customer and the electricity generated and fed back by the customer. If time-of-day or time-of-use metering is used, the electricity fed back to the electric grid by the eligible customer-generator shall be net-metered and accounted for at the specific time it is fed back to the electric grid in accordance with the time-of-day or time-of-use billing agreement currently in place. </section><section prefix="4">Each net metering contract or tariff shall be identical, with respect to energy rates, rate structure, and monthly charges, to the contract or tariff to which the same customer would be assigned if the customer were not an eligible customer-generator. </section><section prefix="5">The following rules shall apply to the billing of net electricity: <section prefix="a">The net electricity produced or consumed during a billing period shall be read, recorded, and measured in accordance with metering practices prescribed by the commission; </section><section prefix="b">If the electricity supplied by the retail electric supplier exceeds the electricity generated and fed back to the supplier during the billing period, the customer-generator shall be billed for the net electricity supplied in accordance with subsections (3) and (4) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">If the electricity fed back to the retail electric supplier by the customer-generator exceeds the electricity supplied by the supplier during a billing period, the customer-generator shall be credited for the excess kilowatt hours in accordance with subsections (3) and (4) of this section. This electricity credit shall appear on the customer-generator's next bill. Credits shall carry forward for the life of the customer-generator's account; </section><section prefix="d">If a customer-generator closes his account, no cash refund for residual generation-related credits shall be paid; and </section><section prefix="e">Excess electricity credits are not transferable between customers or locations. </section></section><section prefix="6">Electric generating systems and interconnecting equipment used by eligible customer-generators shall meet all applicable safety and power quality standards established by the National Electrical Code (NEC), Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), and accredited testing laboratories such as Underwriters Laboratories. </section><section prefix="7">An eligible customer-generator installation is transferable to other persons or service locations upon notification to the retail electric supplier and verification that the installation is in compliance with the applicable safety and power quality standards in KRS 278.467 and in subsection (6) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">Any upgrade of the interconnection between the retail electric supplier and the customer-generator that is required by commission-approved tariffs for the purpose of allowing net metering shall be made at the expense of the customer-generator. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14123</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>