<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.12-090</section_number><catch_line>Unknown claims against dissolved limited cooperative association.   </catch_line><order_by>12-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dissolved limited cooperative association may publish notice of its dissolution and request persons having claims against the association to present them in accordance with the notice. </section><section prefix="2">A notice under subsection (1) of this section shall: <section prefix="a">Be published at least once in a newspaper of general circulation in the county in which the dissolved limited cooperative association’s principal office is located or, if the association does not have a principal office in the Commonwealth, in the county in which the association’s registered office is or was last located; </section><section prefix="b">Provide the name of the association and describe the information required to be contained in a claim and provide an address to which the claim is to be sent; and </section><section prefix="c">State that a claim against the association is barred unless an action to enforce the claim is commenced not later than two (2) years after publication of the notice. </section></section><section prefix="3">If a dissolved limited cooperative association publishes a notice in accordance with subsection (2) of this section, the claim of each of the following claimants is barred unless the claimant commences an action to enforce the claim not later than three (3) years after the first publication date of the notice: <section prefix="a">A claimant that is entitled to but did not receive notice in a record under KRS 272A.12-080; or </section><section prefix="b">A claimant whose claim is contingent or based on an event occurring after the effective date of dissolution. </section></section><section prefix="4">A claim not barred under this section may be enforced: <section prefix="a">Against a dissolved limited cooperative association, to the extent of its undistributed assets; or </section><section prefix="b">If the association’s assets have been distributed in connection with winding up, against a member or holder of financial rights to the extent of that person’s proportionate share of the claim or the association’s assets distributed to the person in connection with the winding up, whichever is less. The person’s total liability for all claims under this paragraph shall not exceed the total amount of assets distributed to the person as part of the winding up of the association. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 96, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>