<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">JUDICIAL RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>21.540</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board of trustees -- Qualified domestic relations orders -- Intent to conform with federal law -- Availability of information on Web site -- Conflicts of interest -- Prohibition against fees for unregulated placement agents.   </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 21.550, 21.560, and subsection (3) of this section, the board of trustees of the Judicial Form Retirement System shall be charged with the administration of that system and of KRS 21.350 to 21.510, and shall have all powers necessary thereto, including the power to promulgate all reasonable administrative regulations, pass upon questions of eligibility and disability, make employments for services, and to contract for fiduciary liability insurance, and for investment counseling, actuarial, auditing, and other professional services as required without the limitations of KRS 45A.045. The administrative expenses shall be paid out of an administrative account which shall be funded by transfers of the necessary money, in appropriate ratio, from the funds provided for in KRS 21.550 and 21.560. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A qualified domestic relations order issued by a court or administrative agency shall be honored by the Judicial Form Retirement System if the order is in compliance with the requirements established by the retirement system. </section><section prefix="b">Except in cases involving child support payments, the Judicial Form Retirement System may charge reasonable and necessary fees and expenses to the participant and the alternate payee of a qualified domestic relations order for the administration of the qualified domestic relations order by the retirement system. All fees and expenses shall be established by administrative regulations promulgated by the board of trustees of the retirement system. The qualified domestic relations order shall specify whether the fees and expenses provided by this subsection shall be paid: <section prefix="1">Solely by the participant; </section><section prefix="2">Solely by the alternate payee; or </section><section prefix="3">Equally shared by the participant and alternate payee. </section></section><section prefix="c">For purposes of this subsection, a "qualified domestic relations order" shall mean any judgment, decree, or order, including approval of a property settlement agreement, that: <section prefix="1">Is issued by a court or administrative agency; and </section><section prefix="2">Relates to the provision of child support, alimony payments, or marital property rights to a spouse, former spouse, child, or other dependent of a member. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other evidence of legislative intent, it is hereby declared to be the controlling legislative intent that the provisions of KRS 21.345 to 21.580 and 6.500 to 6.577 shall conform with federal statutes or regulations and meet the qualification requirements under 26 U.S.C. sec. 401(a), applicable federal regulations, and other published guidance, and the board shall have the authority to promulgate administrative regulations, with retroactive effect if required under federal law, to conform the Legislators' Retirement Plan and the Judicial Retirement Plan with federal statutes and regulations and to meet the qualification requirements under 26 U.S.C. sec. 401(a). </section><section prefix="4">The Judicial Form Retirement System shall make available on a public Web site, a listing of all system expenditures and a listing of each individual employed by the systems along with the employee's salary or wages. The system may provide the information through a Web site established by the executive or judicial branch to inform the public about executive or judicial branch agency expenditures and public employee salaries and wages. Nothing in this subsection shall require or compel the Judicial Form Retirement System to disclose information specific to the account of an individual member of the Legislators' Retirement Plan or the Judicial Retirement Plan. </section><section prefix="5">No trustee or employee of the board shall: <section prefix="a">Have any interest, direct or indirect, in the gains or profits of any investment or transaction made by the board, provided that the provisions of this paragraph shall not prohibit a member or retiree of one (1) of the retirement plans administered by the system from serving as a trustee; </section><section prefix="b">Directly or indirectly, for himself or herself or as an agent, use the assets of the system, except to make current and necessary payments authorized by the board; </section><section prefix="c">Become an endorser, surety, or obligor for moneys loaned by or borrowed from the board; </section><section prefix="d">Have a contract or agreement with the retirement system, individually or through a business owned by the trustee or the employee; </section><section prefix="e">Use his or her official position with the retirement system to obtain a financial gain or benefit or advantage for himself or herself or a family member; </section><section prefix="f">Use confidential information acquired during his or her tenure with the systems to further his or her own economic interests or that of another person; or </section><section prefix="g">Hold outside employment with, or accept compensation from, any person or business with which he or she has involvement as part of his or her official position with the system. The provisions of this paragraph shall not prohibit: <section prefix="1">A trustee from serving as a judge or member of the General Assembly; or </section><section prefix="2">A trustee from serving on the board if the compensation is de minimus and incidental to the trustee's outside employment. If the compensation is more than de minimus, the trustee shall disclose the amount of the compensation to the other trustees and recuse himself or herself from any matters involving hiring or retaining a person or a business from whom more than de minimus amounts are received by the trustee. For purposes of this section, "de minimus" means an insignificant amount that does not raise a reasonable question as to the trustee's objectivity. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any other provision of KRS 6.500 to 6.577 and 21.345 to 21.580 to the contrary, no funds of the Legislators' Retirement Plan or the Judicial Retirement Plan, including fees and commissions paid to an investment manager, private fund, or company issuing securities, who manages systems assets, shall be used to pay fees and commissions to unregulated placement agents. For purposes of this subsection, "unregulated placement agent" means an individual or firm who solicits investments on behalf of an investment manager, private fund, or company issuing securities, who is prohibited by federal securities laws and regulations promulgated thereunder from receiving compensation for soliciting a government agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 7, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 148, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 30, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 407, sec. 20, effective July 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013</effective><lrc-note>(4/11/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 18, provides that the amendments made to subsection (6) of this statute regarding unregulated placement agents by 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 7, "shall apply to contracts established or contracts renewed on or after July 1, 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42082</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>