<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="346" order_by="346">COMPENSATION OF CRIME VICTIMS </unit></structure><section_number>346.050</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for benefits. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the following persons shall be eligible for awards pursuant to this chapter: <section prefix="a">A victim of criminally injurious conduct; </section><section prefix="b">A surviving spouse, parent, or child of a victim of criminally injurious conduct who died as a direct result of such conduct; </section><section prefix="c">Any other person dependent for his principal support upon a victim of criminally injurious conduct who died as a direct result of such crime; and </section><section prefix="d">Any person who is legally responsible for the medical expenses or funeral expenses of a victim. </section></section><section prefix="2">No victim or dependent shall be denied compensation solely because he is a relative of the offender or was living with the offender as a family or household member at the time of the injury or death. However, the board may award compensation to a victim or dependent who is a relative, family or household member of the offender only if the board can reasonably determine the offender will not receive significant economic benefit or unjust enrichment from the compensation. </section><section prefix="3">No compensation of any kind shall be awarded when injury occurred while the victim was confined in any state, county, urban-county, or city jail, prison, or other correctional facility, or any state institution maintained and operated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 612, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 567, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>