<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="165" order_by="165">CITY UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES </unit></structure><section_number>165.150</section_number><catch_line>Law school buildings for municipal university -- Erection of. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city of the first class may, if the necessary ground is conveyed to the city without cost and free of all liens and encumbrances, erect law school buildings, with necessary appurtenances, for the purpose of supplying the municipal university of the city with adequate buildings necessary to carry out its powers and duties. The city shall proceed under the provisions of KRS 162.160 to 162.280. When so applied, KRS 162.160 to 162.280 shall be so read that: <section prefix="a">"School building" means "law school building." </section><section prefix="b">"Board of education of the school district" means "board of trustees of the municipal university." </section><section prefix="c">"KRS 162.150 to 162.280" means "KRS 165.150." </section><section prefix="d">"From the public works administration or other agency of the federal government," in KRS 162.170, is replaced by "secured by a lien on the revenues derived from the building." </section><section prefix="e">"Thirty (30) years," in KRS 162.180, means "fifty (50) years." </section><section prefix="f">"KRS 162.150," in KRS 162.160 and 162.170, means "KRS 165.150." </section><section prefix="g">"And to the Superintendent of Public Instruction," in KRS 162.160, is omitted. </section><section prefix="h">The period of the lease contemplated by KRS 162.160 shall not exceed a maximum of fifty (50) years, and the insurance required in the lease shall at least equal the value of the improvements. </section></section><section prefix="2">This section creates an additional and alternate method for the erecting of law school buildings for municipal universities in cities of the first class, and does not affect any other statute. No proceedings shall be required for the erection of any law school building under this section or the issuance of bonds therefor except those prescribed by this section. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2948c-1 to 2948c-16. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>