<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.2-502</section_number><catch_line>Buyer's right to goods on seller's repudiation, failure to deliver, or insolvency. </catch_line><order_by>2-502</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsections (2) and (3) of this section and even though the goods have not been shipped a buyer who has paid a part or all of the price of goods in which he has a special property under the provisions of the immediately preceding section may on making and keeping good a tender of any unpaid portion of their price recover them from the seller if: <section prefix="a">In the case of goods bought for personal, family, or household purposes, the seller repudiates or fails to deliver as required by contract; or </section><section prefix="b">In all cases, the seller becomes insolvent within ten (10) days after receipt of the first installment on their price. </section></section><section prefix="2">The buyer's right to recover the goods under subsection (1)(a) of this section vests upon acquisition of a special property, even if the seller had not then repudiated or failed to deliver. </section><section prefix="3">If the identification creating his special property has been made by the buyer he acquires the right to recover the goods only if they conform to the contract for sale. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 161, effective July 1, 2001. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 2-502, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33293</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>