<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.080</section_number><catch_line>Establishment and alteration of public roads, bridges and landings, upon petition. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any person desires the establishment or alteration of a public road, bridge or landing, he shall petition the fiscal court setting forth in his petition specifically the nature and location of the proposed work. The court shall thereupon appoint two (2) viewers who, together with the county road engineer, shall view the ground and report in writing the advantages and disadvantages which, in their opinion, will result to the individual and to the public from the proposed work and the grades and bearings of the proposed road, and other facts and circumstances that may enable the fiscal court to determine whether the work ought to be undertaken by the county. </section><section prefix="2">If the petition is for the establishment or alteration of a public road leading from a main public road, the report shall set out whether such road should be established, stating specifically whether it would be necessary to take any burying ground, garden, yard, orchard, or any part thereof, or to injure or destroy any buildings and the probable cost of the work, the names of the landowners whose property would have to be taken or injured, which of them would require compensation and the probable amount to which each would be entitled. They shall make careful examination of routes or locations other than that proposed or petitioned for, keeping in view the possible future development of the county and the accommodations of the general traveling public, and shall report to the fiscal court at a public meeting in favor of the one they prefer, giving reasons for the preference. A map giving the grades and bearings of the routes or locations shall be returned with the report. </section><section prefix="3">If it appears to the fiscal court that the interests of the general public may be furthered thereby, the fiscal court shall personally examine the proposed work. If the court decides to undertake the proposed work the county judge/executive shall appoint a day for hearing the parties interested, and cause notices thereof to be given to all interested parties. </section><section prefix="4">If the county judge/executive at any time has sufficient evidence before him to enable him to ascertain what would be a just compensation to the proprietors and tenants, and if the proprietors and tenants are willing to accept what the county judge/executive deems just, the county judge/executive, upon such acceptance being reduced to writing and signed by the proprietors and tenants, may determine to undertake the work, subject to the consent and approval of the fiscal court. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 306, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 167, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4301. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>