<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.870</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 61.872 to 61.884.   </catch_line><order_by>870</order_by><text>As used in KRS 61.872 to 61.884, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Public agency" means: <section prefix="a">Every state or local government officer; </section><section prefix="b">Every state or local government department, division, bureau, board, commission, and authority; </section><section prefix="c">Every state or local legislative board, commission, committee, and officer; </section><section prefix="d">Every county and city governing body, council, school district board, special district board, and municipal corporation; </section><section prefix="e">Every state or local court or judicial agency; </section><section prefix="f">Every state or local government agency, including the policy-making board of an institution of education, created by or pursuant to state or local statute, executive order, ordinance, resolution, or other legislative act; </section><section prefix="g">Any body created by state or local authority in any branch of government; </section><section prefix="h">Any body which, within any fiscal year, derives at least twenty-five percent (25%) of its funds expended by it in the Commonwealth of Kentucky from state or local authority funds. However, any funds derived from a state or local authority in compensation for goods or services that are provided by a contract obtained through a public competitive procurement process shall not be included in the determination of whether a body is a public agency under this subsection; </section><section prefix="i">Any entity where the majority of its governing body is appointed by a public agency as defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (j), or (k) of this subsection; by a member or employee of such a public agency; or by any combination thereof; </section><section prefix="j">Any board, commission, committee, subcommittee, ad hoc committee, advisory committee, council, or agency, except for a committee of a hospital medical staff, established, created, and controlled by a public agency as defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), or (k) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="k">Any interagency body of two (2) or more public agencies where each public agency is defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), (h), (i), or (j) of this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Public record" means all books, papers, maps, photographs, cards, tapes, discs, diskettes, recordings, software, or other documentation regardless of physical form or characteristics, which are prepared, owned, used, in the possession of or retained by a public agency. "Public record" shall not include any records owned or maintained by or for a body referred to in subsection (1)(h) of this section that are not related to functions, activities, programs, or operations funded by state or local authority; </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">"Software" means the program code which makes a computer system function, but does not include that portion of the program code which contains public records exempted from inspection as provided by KRS 61.878 or specific addresses of files, passwords, access codes, user identifications, or any other mechanism for controlling the security or restricting access to public records in the public agency's computer system. </section><section prefix="b">"Software" consists of the operating system, application programs, procedures, routines, and subroutines such as translators and utility programs, but does not include that material which is prohibited from disclosure or copying by a license agreement between a public agency and an outside entity which supplied the material to the agency; </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">"Commercial purpose" means the direct or indirect use of any part of a public record or records, in any form, for sale, resale, solicitation, rent, or lease of a service, or any use by which the user expects a profit either through commission, salary, or fee. </section><section prefix="b">"Commercial purpose" shall not include: <section prefix="1">Publication or related use of a public record by a newspaper or periodical; </section><section prefix="2">Use of a public record by a radio or television station in its news or other informational programs; or </section><section prefix="3">Use of a public record in the preparation for prosecution or defense of litigation, or claims settlement by the parties to such action, or the attorneys representing the parties; </section></section></section><section prefix="5">"Official custodian" means the chief administrative officer or any other officer or employee of a public agency who is responsible for the maintenance, care and keeping of public records, regardless of whether such records are in his actual personal custody and control; </section><section prefix="6">"Custodian" means the official custodian or any authorized person having personal custody and control of public records; </section><section prefix="7">"Media" means the physical material in or on which records may be stored or represented, and which may include, but is not limited to paper, microform, disks, diskettes, optical disks, magnetic tapes, and cards; and </section><section prefix="8">"Mechanical processing" means any operation or other procedure which is transacted on a machine, and which may include, but is not limited to a copier, computer, recorder or tape processor, or other automated device. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40138</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>