<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.212</section_number><catch_line>Distilled spirits and wine supplier's license authorizing importation of distilled spirits and wine -- Nonresident entities eligible for license -- Licenses, limited licenses, and micro licenses -- Exemption from notice requirements of KRS 243.360.   </catch_line><order_by>212</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An out-of-state distiller, wholesaler, rectifier, winery, small farm winery, importer for a distillery, winery, or small farm winery, or importer of a non-United States brand of distilled spirits or wine may obtain a distilled spirits and wine supplier's license for importing distilled spirits and wine into Kentucky if it is: <section prefix="a">Licensed to do business in the state in which it is located; and </section><section prefix="b">Registered with the Kentucky Department of Revenue. </section></section><section prefix="2">An entity listed in subsection (1) of this section who wishes to import more than fifty thousand (50,000) gallons of distilled spirits or wine shall: <section prefix="a">Apply for an out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license on an application provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Submit documentation required by the application; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay the annual fee required by KRS 243.030. </section></section><section prefix="3">An entity listed in subsection (1) of this section who wishes to import at least two thousand (2,000) gallons but less than fifty thousand (50,000) gallons of distilled spirits or wine shall: <section prefix="a">Apply for a limited out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license on an application provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Submit documentation required by the application; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay the annual fee required by KRS 243.030. </section></section><section prefix="4">An entity listed in subsection (1) of this section who wishes to import less than two thousand (2,000) gallons of distilled spirits or wine shall: <section prefix="a">Apply for a micro out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license on an application provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Submit documentation required by the application; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay the annual fee required by KRS 243.030. </section></section><section prefix="5">An out-of-state applicant shall be exempt from the notice requirements of KRS 243.360. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 35, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42470</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>