<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.100</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocal licensing -- Continuing education or apprenticeship.   </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cosmetologist board may prescribe reasonable administrative regulations pertaining to the issuance of a license, upon payment of the prescribed license fee, to any person holding a comparable license issued by another state where the laws of that state, in the opinion of the cosmetologist board, provide comparable professional qualification, health, and safety standards;  </section><section prefix="2">A person who provides certification of licensure from a state board or appropriate agency, whose requirements are not comparable to those of Kentucky, who has held a license in good standing for more than two (2) years, shall be issued a Kentucky license after completion of an application, payment of a fee, and passage of the theory and practical examinations.  </section><section prefix="3">A person who provides certification of licensure from a state board or appropriate agency, whose requirements are not comparable to those of Kentucky, who has held a license in good standing for less than two (2) years, shall be able to cure the deficiency of comparability through continuing education or apprenticeship in Kentucky. The board may require completion of an application, payment of a fee, and passage of the theory and practical examinations. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40887</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>