<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.716</section_number><catch_line>Current issues seminars for legislators. </catch_line><order_by>716</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall design the general curriculum of a current issues seminar, which shall include, but not be limited to, discussion of changes in the ethics laws and administrative regulations, new advisory opinions, current ethical issues confronting public servants, practical application of ethics laws and principles to specific issues and situations, and development of problem-solving skills. The commission shall prepare the methods and materials necessary to implement the curriculum. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall: <section prefix="a">Administer the current issues seminars for legislators; </section><section prefix="b">Designate instructors to conduct their current issues courses who shall be trained by the commission; and </section><section prefix="c">Notify legislators regarding attendance in these seminars. </section></section><section prefix="3">The current issues seminars shall be conducted in January of each year. Each course shall be at least three (3) hours in length and shall be designed for approval by the Kentucky Bar Association for continuing legal education ethics credits which the bar association may require. </section><section prefix="4">To facilitate participant interaction, those portions of the seminars dedicated to group participation may be closed to the public. </section><section prefix="5">Each legislator, after completion of an orientation training course, shall complete one (1) current issues seminar annually. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 36, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43304</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>