<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-125</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against promulgating administrative regulations or imposing permit conditions based on Kyoto Protocol without state or federal legislation. </catch_line><order_by>20-125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall not promulgate administrative regulations or impose permit conditions on the emission of carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, hydrofluorocarbons, perfluorocarbons, or sulfur hexafluoride pursuant to the Kyoto Protocol for the purpose of reducing global warming until authorized by the General Assembly or by federal statute. The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations or impose permit conditions on the emission of carbon dioxide, methane, nitrous oxide, hydrofluorocarbons, perfluorocarbons, or sulfur hexafluoride for any other reason authorized by this chapter or required under federal statute or administrative regulation as long as the administrative regulations or permit conditions are not promulgated or imposed pursuant to the Kyoto Protocol. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or to impede state, local, or private participation in voluntary initiatives to reduce emissions of greenhouse gases, such as the United States Environmental Protection Agency's Green Lights program and the United States Department of Energy's climate change program. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10353</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>