<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.2847</section_number><catch_line>Waiver of tuition and mandatory student fees for Kentucky foster or adopted children.   </catch_line><order_by>2847</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Tuition and mandatory student fees for any undergraduate program of any Kentucky public postsecondary institution, including all four (4) year universities and colleges and institutions of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, shall be waived for a Kentucky foster or adopted child who is a full-time or part-time student if the student meets all entrance requirements and maintains academic eligibility while enrolled at the postsecondary institution, and if: <section prefix="a">The student's family receives state-funded adoption assistance under KRS 199.555; </section><section prefix="b">The student is currently committed to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services under KRS 610.010(5) and placed in a family foster home or is placed in accordance with KRS 605.090(3); </section><section prefix="c">The student is in an independent living program and the placement is funded by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="d">The student who is an adopted child was in the permanent legal custody of and placed for adoption by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. A student who meets the eligibility criteria of this paragraph and lives outside of Kentucky at the time of application to a Kentucky postsecondary institution may apply for the waiver up to the amount of tuition for a Kentucky resident; or </section><section prefix="e">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services was the student's legal custodian on his or her eighteenth birthday. </section></section><section prefix="2">Tuition and mandatory student fees for any undergraduate program of any Kentucky public postsecondary institution, including all four (4) year universities and colleges and institutions of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, shall be waived for a Department of Juvenile Justice foster child who is a full-time or part-time student if the student meets all entrance requirements and maintains academic eligibility while enrolled at the postsecondary institution and obtains a recommendation for participation from an official from the Department of Juvenile Justice, and if: <section prefix="a">The student has not been sentenced to the Department of Juvenile Justice under KRS Chapter 640; </section><section prefix="b">The student has been committed to the Department of Juvenile Justice for a period of at least twelve (12) months; </section><section prefix="c">The student is in an independent living program and placement is funded by the Department of Juvenile Justice; </section><section prefix="d">The parental rights of the student's biological parents have been terminated; or </section><section prefix="e">The student was committed to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services prior to a commitment to the Department of Juvenile Justice. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon request of the postsecondary institution, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall confirm the eligibility status under subsection (1) of this section and the Department of Juvenile Justice shall confirm the eligibility status and recommendations under subsection (2) of this section of the student seeking to participate in the waiver program. Release of this information shall not constitute a breach of confidentiality required by KRS 199.570, 610.320, or 620.050. </section><section prefix="4">The student shall complete the Free Application for Federal Student Aid to determine the level of need and eligibility for state and federal financial aid programs. If the sum of the tuition waiver plus other student financial assistance, except loans and the work study program under 42 U.S.C. secs. 2751-2756b, from all sources exceeds the student's total cost of attendance, as defined in 20 U.S.C. sec. 1087ll, the tuition waiver shall be reduced by the amount exceeding the total cost of attendance. </section><section prefix="5">The student shall be eligible for the tuition waiver: <section prefix="a">For entrance to the institution for a period of no more than four (4) years after the date of graduation from high school; and </section><section prefix="b">For a period of five (5) years after first admittance to any Kentucky institution if satisfactory progress is achieved or maintained, except when extended in accordance with subsection (6) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="6">The expiration of a student's five (5) year eligibility under subsection (5)(b) of this section shall be extended upon a determination by the institution that the student was unable to enroll for or complete an academic term due to serving: <section prefix="a">On active duty status in the United States Armed Forces; </section><section prefix="b">As an officer in the Commissioned Corps of the United States Public Health Service; or </section><section prefix="c">On active service in the Peace Corps Act or the Americorps. </section></section> The original expiration date shall be extended by the total number of years during which the student was on active duty status. The number of months served on active duty status shall be rounded up to the next higher year to determine the maximum length of eligibility extension allowed. <section prefix="7">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall report the number of students participating in the tuition waiver program under subsection (1) of this section and the Department of Juvenile Justice shall report the number of students participating in the tuition waiver program under subsection (2) of this section on October 1 each year to the Council on Postsecondary Education and the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="8">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall report nonidentifying data on graduation rates of students participating in the tuition waiver program by November 30 each year to the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in this section shall be construed to: <section prefix="a">Guarantee acceptance of or entrance into any postsecondary institution for a foster or adopted child; </section><section prefix="b">Limit the participation of a foster or adopted student in any other program of financial assistance for postsecondary education; </section><section prefix="c">Require any postsecondary institution to waive costs or fees relating to room and board; or </section><section prefix="d">Restrict any postsecondary institution, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the Cabinet for Health and Family Services from accessing other sources of financial assistance, except loans, that may be available to a foster or adopted student. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 137, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>