<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.680</section_number><catch_line>Nonreimbursement of out-of-state providers of residential care for children -- Exception -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Community Based Services and the Department for Medicaid Services shall not reimburse an out-of-state provider of residential care for children whose care is paid by state general funds or state administered federal funds unless the Department for Medicaid Services or the Department for Community Based Services or a designated agent thereof has determined that there is no provider within the Commonwealth that is capable and willing to provide comparable services at a comparable cost per child to those that would be delivered by the out-of-state provider. An exception may be made if: <section prefix="a">The identified in-state resource is farther away from the child's parent or guardian than a similar out-of-state resource; or </section><section prefix="b">The services offered by the out-of-state resource is deemed by either department or a designated agent thereof to be more appropriate for the individual child than the services offered by the in-state provider. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to promulgating administrative regulations governing the determination of the availability of providers of residential care within the Commonwealth, the Department for Medicaid Services and the Department for Community Based Services shall establish uniform conditions, requirements, and exceptions for the determination of the availability of providers of residential care within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Each department shall promulgate an administrative regulation in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A that contains the uniform conditions, requirements, and exceptions for the determination of the availability of providers of residential care within the Commonwealth established under subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 22, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7223</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>