<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.250</section_number><catch_line>Certificates of librarianship -- To whom granted. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall grant certificates of librarianship to applicants who are graduates of library schools approved by the board and shall grant certificates to other applicants when it has satisfied itself that the applicant is qualified for library work. Applicants shall provide such information as required by the board to determine their qualifications. </section><section prefix="2">The board may issue renewals, determine the positions for which certificates of librarianship shall be required, and adopt rules and regulations for its own government and for carrying out the purposes of KRS 171.230 to 171.306. </section><section prefix="3">The board may issue certificates to qualified persons who are serving in libraries not supported from public funds. </section><section prefix="4">Librarians who were in service on May 31, 1938, and served one (1) year prior to such date shall be entitled to receive a life certificate in accordance with their qualifications, without examination, upon the payment of prescribed fee. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4618-130c, 4618-130d, 4618-130g. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4778</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>