<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.191</section_number><catch_line>Research requirements for comprehensive plan. </catch_line><order_by>191</order_by><text>All elements of the comprehensive plan shall be based upon but not limited to, the following research, analysis, and projections: <section prefix="1">An analysis of the general distribution and characteristics of past and present population and a forecast of the extent and character of future population as far into the future as is reasonable to foresee; </section><section prefix="2">An economic survey and analysis of the major existing public and private business activities, and a forecast of future economic levels, including a forecast of anticipated necessary actions by the community to increase the quality of life of its current and future population through the encouragement of economic development as far into the future as is reasonable to foresee; </section><section prefix="3">Research and analysis as to the nature, extent, adequacy, and the needs of the community for the existing land and building use, transportation, and community facilities in terms of their general location, character and extent, including, the identification and mapping of agricultural lands of statewide importance and analysis of the impacts of community land use needs on these lands; and </section><section prefix="4">Additional background information for the elements of the comprehensive plan may include any other research analysis, and projections which, in the judgment of the planning commission, will further serve the purposes of the comprehensive plan. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 26. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26713</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>