<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.410</section_number><catch_line>Sentencing level relating to probation or other nonimposition of sentence. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>The sentencing level of the system shall consist of at least the following information in regard to probation or other nonimposition of the sentence: <section prefix="1">List separately any conviction for which sentence was imposed but was probated, suspended, or otherwise not imposed; </section><section prefix="2">Was probation or nonimposition of the sentence conditioned in any manner: <section prefix="a">List the conditions; and </section><section prefix="b">What is the method of monitoring compliance with the conditions; </section></section><section prefix="3">If a portion of a fine or other cost was probated or otherwise not imposed: <section prefix="a">List for each offense the amount of the fine not imposed; and </section><section prefix="b">List for each offense the amount of court costs or other costs or fees not imposed; </section></section><section prefix="4">If a sentence of imprisonment was not imposed or a portion thereof was not imposed: <section prefix="a">List the offense, the sentence, and the amount not imposed; and </section><section prefix="b">If return to confinement or other imprisonment was a condition of nonimposition of a sentence, list the conditions thereof. </section></section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>