<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.130</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 138.130 to 138.205.      </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>As used in KRS 138.130 to 138.205, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="2">"Manufacturer" means any person who manufactures or produces cigarettes, or tobacco products within or without this state; </section><section prefix="3">"Retailer" means any person who sells to a consumer or to any person for any purpose other than resale; </section><section prefix="4">"Sale at retail" means a sale to any person for any other purpose other than resale; </section><section prefix="5">"Cigarettes" means any roll for smoking made wholly or in part of tobacco, or any substitute for tobacco, irrespective of size or shape and whether or not the tobacco is flavored, adulterated, or mixed with any other ingredient, the wrapper or cover of which is made of paper or any other substance or material, excepting tobacco. "Cigarettes" shall not mean reference cigarettes; </section><section prefix="6">"Reference cigarettes" means cigarettes made by a manufacturer specifically for a state public university to be held by the university until sale or transfer to a laboratory, hospital, medical center, institute, college or university, manufacturer, or other institution. A reference cigarette package shall carry a marking labeling the contents as research cigarettes to be used only for tobacco-health research and experimental purposes, which shall not be offered for sale, sold, or distributed to consumers; </section><section prefix="7">"Sale" or "sell" means any transfer for a consideration, exchange, barter, gift, offer for sale, advertising for sale, soliciting an order for cigarettes or tobacco products, and distribution in any manner or by any means whatsoever; </section><section prefix="8">"Tax evidence" means any stamps, metered impressions, or other indicia prescribed by the department by administrative regulation as a means of denoting the payment of tax; </section><section prefix="9">"Person" means any individual, firm, copartnership, joint venture, association, municipal or private corporation whether organized for profit or not, the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any of its political subdivisions, an estate, trust, or any other group or combination acting as a unit, and the plural as well as the singular; </section><section prefix="10">"Resident wholesaler" means any person who purchases at least seventy-five percent (75%) of all cigarettes purchased by the wholesaler directly from the manufacturer on which the tax provided for in KRS 138.140(1), (2), and (3) is unpaid, and who maintains an established place of business in this state where the wholesaler attaches cigarette tax evidence, or receives untaxed cigarettes; </section><section prefix="11">"Nonresident wholesaler" means any person who purchases cigarettes directly from the manufacturer and maintains a permanent location or locations outside this state where Kentucky cigarette tax evidence is attached or from where Kentucky cigarette tax is reported and paid; </section><section prefix="12">"Sub-jobber" means any person who purchases cigarettes from a resident wholesaler, nonresident wholesaler, or unclassified acquirer licensed under KRS 138.195 on which the tax imposed by KRS 138.140(1), (2), and (3) has been paid and makes them available to retailers for resale. No person shall make cigarettes available to retailers for resale unless the person certifies and establishes to the satisfaction of the department that firm arrangements have been made to regularly supply at least five (5) retail locations with Kentucky tax-paid cigarettes for resale in the regular course of business; </section><section prefix="13">"Vending machine operator" means any person who operates one (1) or more cigarette vending machines; </section><section prefix="14">"Transporter" means any person transporting untax-paid cigarettes obtained from any source to any destination within this state, other than cigarettes transported by the manufacturer thereof; </section><section prefix="15">"Unclassified acquirer" means any person in this state who acquires cigarettes from any source on which the tax imposed by KRS 138.140(1), (2), and (3) has not been paid, and who is not a person otherwise required to be licensed under the provisions of KRS 138.195; </section><section prefix="16">"Tobacco products" means any smokeless tobacco products, smoking tobacco, chewing tobacco, and any kind or form of tobacco prepared in a manner suitable for chewing or smoking, or both, or any kind or form of tobacco that is suitable to be placed in an individual's oral cavity, except: <section prefix="a">Cigarettes; and </section><section prefix="b">Reference cigarettes; </section></section><section prefix="17">"Distributor" means any person within this state in possession of tobacco products for resale within this state on which the tax imposed under KRS 138.140(4) has not been paid; </section><section prefix="18">"Retail distributor" means a retailer who has obtained a retail distributor's license under KRS 138.195(7)(b); </section><section prefix="19">"Chewing tobacco" means any leaf tobacco that is not intended to be smoked and includes loose leaf chewing tobacco, plug chewing tobacco, and twist chewing tobacco, but "chewing tobacco" does not include snuff; </section><section prefix="20">"Single unit" means a consumer-sized container, pouch, or package: <section prefix="a">Containing less than four (4) ounces of chewing tobacco by net weight; </section><section prefix="b">Produced by the manufacturer to be sold to consumers as a single unit and not produced to be divided or sold separately; and </section><section prefix="c">Containing one (1) individual container, pouch, or package; </section></section><section prefix="21">"Half-pound unit" means a consumer-sized container, pouch, or package: <section prefix="a">Containing at least four (4) ounces but not more than eight (8) ounces of chewing tobacco by net weight; </section><section prefix="b">Produced by the manufacturer to be sold to consumers as a half-pound unit and not produced to be divided or sold separately; and </section><section prefix="c">Containing one (1) individual container, pouch, or package; </section></section><section prefix="22">"Pound unit" means a consumer-sized container, pouch, or package: <section prefix="a">Containing more than eight (8) ounces but not more than sixteen (16) ounces of chewing tobacco by net weight; </section><section prefix="b">Produced by the manufacturer to be sold to consumers as a pound unit and not produced to be divided or sold separately; and </section><section prefix="c">Containing one (1) individual container, pouch, or package; and </section></section><section prefix="23"><section prefix="a">"Snuff" means tobacco that: <section prefix="1">Is finely cut, ground, or powdered; and </section><section prefix="2">Is not for smoking. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Snuff" includes snus. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective August 1, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 7, effective June 1, 2006; ch. 251, sec. 48, effective April 25, 2006; and ch. 252, Pt. XXXIII, sec. 1, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 346, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 80, effective June 1, 2005. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 19, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4281e-1. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/1/2006).  This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 6, sec. 7; 252, Pt. XXXIII, sec. 1, and 251, sec. 48, which specifically amends this statute as it appears in Section 1 of Part XXXIII of 2006 Regular Session HB 380/EN. These do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42709</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>