<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="440" order_by="440">ESCAPES, FUGITIVES FROM JUSTICE, AND EXTRADITION </unit></structure><section_number>440.380</section_number><catch_line>Waiver of extradition -- Procedure -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a person charged with commission of a felony in this state or with having been convicted of a felony here and having escaped from confinement or broken the terms of his bail, probation or parole is arrested in another state and waives extradition proceedings, the county judge/executive of the county in which the felony was committed, or from which the escape was made, may, upon filing of a verified application by the Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney setting forth the fact of waiver and making all statements required by subsection (1) or subsection (2) of KRS 440.370, enter an order designating an officer to return the fugitive to this state without benefit of any procedure incidental to extradition proceedings. Upon entry of such order the officer so designated shall be authorized to go after and return the fugitive as the agent of this state and shall receive from the State Treasury the same payment for his expenses as is provided by KRS 440.090 for agents acting under requisition of the Governor. If, in attempting to reclaim the fugitive, the agent is acting within the course and scope of his employment, the amount due shall be paid over to the agent's employer instead of the agent. Claims for reimbursement of expenses under this subsection shall be accompanied by certified copies of the verified application for appointment of the agent and the order of appointment, together with a copy of any process showing delivery of the fugitive to the jailer upon return to this state. If the agent is not given possession of the fugitive for reasons beyond the agent's control, he, or his employer, shall nevertheless be reimbursed as provided herein, if it is shown that prior to his appointment as agent and before departure from the state the fugitive had executed in the presence of any officer authorized to administer an oath a written waiver stating that he consents to return to this state without extradition. </section><section prefix="2">All legal costs incurred in apprehending and securing in this state a fugitive wanted in another state shall be paid by the agent of the state demanding him before the agent is permitted to remove him or receive him into custody. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 25, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>