<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.107</section_number><catch_line>Application and implementation requirements for districts of innovation.   </catch_line><order_by>107</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A district which is an applicant to be designated as a district of innovation under KRS 156.108 shall: <section prefix="a">Establish goals and performance targets for the district of innovation proposal, which may include: <section prefix="1">Reducing achievement gaps among groups of public school students by expanding learning experiences for students who are identified as academically low-achieving; </section><section prefix="2">Increasing pupil learning through the implementation of high, rigorous standards for pupil performance; </section><section prefix="3">Increasing the participation of students in various curriculum components and instructional components within selected schools to enhance students' preparation at each grade level; </section><section prefix="4">Increasing the number of students who are college and career-ready; and </section><section prefix="5">Motivating students at different grade levels by offering more curriculum choices and student learning opportunities to parents and students within the district; </section></section><section prefix="b">Identify changes needed in the district and schools to lead to better-prepared students for success in life and work; </section><section prefix="c">Have a district-wide plan of innovation that describes and justifies which schools and innovative practices will be incorporated; </section><section prefix="d">Provide documentation of community, educator, parental, and the local board's support of the proposed innovations; </section><section prefix="e">Provide detailed information regarding the rationale of requests for waivers from Kentucky Revised Statutes and administrative regulations, and exemptions for selected schools regarding waivers of local board of education policies; </section><section prefix="f">Document the fiscal and human resources the board will provide throughout the term of the implementation of the innovations within its plan; and </section><section prefix="g">Provide other materials as required by the Kentucky Department of Education in compliance with the state board's administrative regulations and application procedures. </section></section><section prefix="2">The district and all schools participating in a district's innovation plan shall: <section prefix="a">Ensure the same health, safety, civil rights, and disability rights requirements as are applied to all public schools; </section><section prefix="b">Ensure students meet compulsory attendance requirements under KRS 158.030 and 158.100; </section><section prefix="c">Ensure that high school course offerings meet or exceed the minimum required under KRS 156.160 for high school graduation or meet early graduation requirements that may be enacted by the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="d">Ensure the student performance standards meet or exceed those adopted by the Kentucky Board of Education as required by KRS 158.685, including compliance with the statewide assessment system specified in KRS 158.6453; </section><section prefix="e">Adhere to the same financial audits, audit procedures, and audit requirements as are applied under KRS 156.265; </section><section prefix="f">Require state and criminal background checks for staff and volunteers as required of all public school employees and volunteers within the public schools and specified in KRS 160.380 and 161.148; </section><section prefix="g">Comply with open records and open meeting requirements under KRS Chapter 61; </section><section prefix="h">Comply with purchasing requirements and limitations under KRS Chapter 45A and KRS 156.074 and 156.480; </section><section prefix="i">Provide overall instructional time that is equivalent to or greater than that required under KRS 158.070, but which may include on-site instruction, distance or virtual learning, and work-based learning on nontraditional school days or hours; and </section><section prefix="j">Provide data to the Kentucky Department of Education as deemed necessary to generate school and district reports. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Only schools that choose to be designated as schools of innovation shall be included in a district's application. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">As used in this paragraph, "eligible employees" means employees that are regularly employed at the school and those employees whose primary job duties will be affected by the plan. </section><section prefix="2">A vote shall be taken among eligible employees in a school to determine if the school shall be an applicant as a school of innovation in a district's proposal and to approve the school's plan of innovation before it is submitted to the district. At least seventy percent (70%) of those casting votes shall vote in the affirmative in order for the school to request inclusion in the district's plan and to approve the school's plan of innovation. </section><section prefix="3">The school-based decision making council shall be responsible for conducting the vote provided for in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, which shall be by secret ballot. </section></section><section prefix="c">Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (a) of this subsection, a local board of education may require a school that has been identified as a persistently low-achieving school under KRS 160.346 to participate in the district's plan of innovation. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">With approval of the state board, a school of innovation may request and be granted waivers from all or selected provisions of KRS 160.345 relating to school-based decision making. </section><section prefix="b">To be exempt from KRS 160.345, a school-based decision making council shall vote by secret ballot to determine if it wishes to request a waiver from KRS 160.345 or specific provisions within that statute. Only a school that has seventy percent (70%) or more of the teachers and staff in the school voting to waive its rights and responsibilities under KRS 160.345 shall be eligible. </section><section prefix="c">No local board of education or superintendent nor the Kentucky Board of Education may compel a school to waive its rights under KRS 160.345, except as provided in KRS 160.346. </section><section prefix="d">Before the provisions of KRS 160.345 are waived by the Kentucky Board of Education for a specific school, there shall be assurances that teachers, parents, and staff in the affected school will be actively involved in the management and decision-making operations of the schools, including input into employment matters and selection of personnel. </section></section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding any statutes to the contrary, the Kentucky Board of Education may approve the requests of districts of innovation to: <section prefix="a">Use capital outlay funds for operational costs; </section><section prefix="b">Hire persons for classified positions in nontraditional school and district assignments who have bachelor's and advanced degrees from postsecondary education institutions accredited by a regional accrediting association as defined in KRS 164.740; </section><section prefix="c">Employ teachers on extended employment contracts or extra duty contracts and compensate them on a salary schedule other than the single salary schedule; </section><section prefix="d">Extend the school days as is appropriate within the district with compensation for the employees as determined locally; </section><section prefix="e">Establish alternative education programs and services that are delivered in nontraditional hours and which may be jointly provided in cooperation with another school district or consortia of districts; </section><section prefix="f">Establish a virtual school within the district for delivering alternative classes to meet high school graduation requirements; </section><section prefix="g">Use a flexible school calendar; </section><section prefix="h">Convert existing schools into schools of innovation; and </section><section prefix="i">Modify the formula under KRS 157.360(2) for distributing support education excellence in Kentucky funds for students in average daily attendance in nontraditional programming time, including alternative programs and virtual programs. Funds granted to a district shall not exceed those that would have otherwise been distributed based on average daily attendance during regular instructional days. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). The internal numbering of subsection (3)(b) of this statute has been modified by the Reviser of Statutes from the way it appeared in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). The words in the text were not changed.  </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40162</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>