<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="454" order_by="454">MISCELLANEOUS CIVIL PRACTICE PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>454.430</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 454.430 to 454.435. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text>As used in KRS 454.430 to 454.435: <section prefix="1">"Annuity issuer" means an insurer that has issued an annuity contract to be used to fund periodic payments under a structured settlement; </section><section prefix="2">"Payee" means an individual who is receiving tax-free damage payments under a structured settlement and who wants to make a transfer of payment rights under the structured settlement agreement; </section><section prefix="3">"Protected parties" means, with respect to any structured settlement, the payee, any named beneficiary designated in the annuity contract or structured settlement to receive payments following the payee's death, or, if the named beneficiary is a minor, the named beneficiary's parent or guardian, the annuity issuer, and the structured settlement obligor; </section><section prefix="4">"Qualified assignment agreement" means an agreement providing for a qualified assignment that meets the requirements of Section 130 of the Internal Revenue Code, 26 U.S.C. sec. 130, as amended from time to time; </section><section prefix="5">"Settled claim" means the original tort claim resolved by a structured settlement; </section><section prefix="6">"Structured settlement" means an arrangement for periodic payment of damages for personal injuries established by settlement or judgment in resolution of a tort claim; </section><section prefix="7">"Structured settlement obligor" means, with respect to any structured settlement, the party that has the continuing periodic payment obligation to the payee under a structured settlement agreement or a qualified assignment agreement; </section><section prefix="8">"Structured settlement payment rights" means rights to receive periodic payments, including lump sum payments under a structured settlement, whether from the settlement obligor or the annuity issuer, where: <section prefix="a">The payee or any other protected party is domiciled in this state; or </section><section prefix="b">The settled claim was pending before the courts of this state when the structured settlement was reached; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Transfer" means any sale, assignment, pledge, hypothecation, or other form of alienation or encumbrance made for consideration; and </section><section prefix="10">"Transfer agreement" means the agreement providing for transfer of structured settlement payment rights from a payee to a transferee. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19614</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>