<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.352</section_number><catch_line>Screening committee -- Minority representation -- Recommendations for superintendent. </catch_line><order_by>352</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section the term "minority" means American Indian; Alaskan native; African-American; Hispanic, including persons of Mexican, Puerto Rican, Cuban, and Central or South American origin; Pacific islander; or other ethnic group underrepresented in a local school district. </section><section prefix="2">Each board of education shall appoint a superintendent of schools after receiving the recommendations of a screening committee. A screening committee shall be established within thirty (30) days of a determination by a board of education that a vacancy has occurred or will occur in the office of superintendent, except that when the board determines a vacancy will not occur before six (6) months from the date of determination, the board shall establish a screening committee at least ninety (90) days before the first date on which the position may be filled. </section><section prefix="3">A screening committee shall be composed of: <section prefix="a">Two (2) teachers, elected by the teachers in the district; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) board of education member, appointed by the board chairman; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) principal, elected by the principals in the district; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) parent, elected by the presidents of the parent-teacher organizations of the schools in the district; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) classified employee, elected by the classified employees in the district; and </section><section prefix="f">If a minority member is not elected or appointed to a screening committee in districts with a minority population of eight percent (8%) or more, as determined by the enrollment on the preceding October 1, the committee membership shall be increased to include one (1) minority parent. This minority parent member shall be elected by the parents in an election conducted by the local school board. Parents in the district shall be given adequate notice of the date, time, place, and purpose of the election. </section></section><section prefix="4">Prior to appointing a superintendent of schools, the board of education shall consider the recommendations of the screening committee, but the board shall not be required to appoint a superintendent from the committee's recommendations. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 1, effective April 1, 1994; ch. 255, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 400, sec. 1, effective April 11, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 76, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3721</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>