<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.680</section_number><catch_line>Written plan governing consultation with patients and medical emergencies -- Treatment of patients with serious disorders or conditions -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every licensed acupuncturist shall develop a written plan for consultation, emergency transfer, and referral to appropriate health-care facilities or to other health-care practitioners operating within the scope of their authorized practices, which meets the requirements contained in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. The written plan shall be filed with the board and maintained at the acupuncturist's practice location and updated as appropriate to meet current regulatory requirements. </section><section prefix="2">If, in the course of conducting an interview regarding the patient's medical history, the patient discloses that he or she suffers from one (1) of the potentially serious disorders or conditions listed in subsection (3) of this section, the acupuncturist shall verify that the patient is currently under the care of a physician and consult with the treating physician before providing acupuncture treatment. If the patient refuses to provide a medical history or disclose information regarding any of the conditions listed below, acupuncture treatment shall not be provided. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section, "potentially serious disorder or condition" means: <section prefix="a">Hypertension and cardiac conditions; </section><section prefix="b">Acute, severe abdominal pain; </section><section prefix="c">Undiagnosed neurological changes; </section><section prefix="d">Unexplained weight loss or gain in excess of fifteen percent (15%) of the patient's body weight in less than a three (3) month period; </section><section prefix="e">Suspected fracture or dislocation; </section><section prefix="f">Suspected systemic infections; </section><section prefix="g">Serious hemorrhagic disorder; </section><section prefix="h">Acute respiratory distress without a previous history; </section><section prefix="i">Pregnancy; </section><section prefix="j">Diabetes; or </section><section prefix="k">Cancer. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>