<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.220</section_number><catch_line>Conditions of home incarceration. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text>The conditions of home incarceration shall include the following: <section prefix="1">The home incarceree shall be confined to his home at all times except when: <section prefix="a">Working at approved employment or traveling directly to and from such employment; </section><section prefix="b">Seeking employment; </section><section prefix="c">Undergoing available medical, psychiatric, or mental health treatment or approved counseling and after care programs; </section><section prefix="d">Attending an approved educational institution or program; </section><section prefix="e">Attending a regularly scheduled religious service at a place of worship; and </section><section prefix="f">Participating in an approved community work service program; </section></section><section prefix="2">Violation of subsection (1) of this section may subject the home incarceree to prosecution under KRS 520.030 (escape); </section><section prefix="3">The home incarceree shall conform to a schedule prepared by a designated officer of the supervising authority specifically setting forth the times when he may be absent from the home and the locations where he may be during those times; </section><section prefix="4">The home incarceree shall not commit another offense during the period of time for which he is subject to the conditions of home incarceration; </section><section prefix="5">The home incarceree shall not change the place of home incarceration or the schedule without prior approval of the supervising authority; </section><section prefix="6">The home incarceree shall maintain a telephone or other approved monitoring device in the home or on his person at all times; </section><section prefix="7">Any other reasonable conditions set by the court or the supervising authority including: <section prefix="a">Restitution under KRS 533.030; </section><section prefix="b">Supervision fees under KRS 439.315; and </section><section prefix="c">Any of the conditions imposed on persons on probation or conditional discharge under KRS 533.030(2); </section></section><section prefix="8">A written and notarized consent agreement shall be filed with the court by every adult who will share the offender's home during the term of home incarceration; and </section><section prefix="9">Any supervision fee or other monetary condition, except restitution, shall be paid by the defendant directly to the person or organization specified by the court in a written order, except that any such fees or monetary conditions owed to the Department of Corrections shall be paid through the circuit clerk. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 32, effective August 1, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>