<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.670</section_number><catch_line>Process of locating routes of trails. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text>The process of locating routes of trails in the system shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">For state scenic trails, the department shall select a route. The selected route shall be compatible with the preservation and enhancement of the environment it traverses. Reasonable effort shall be made to minimize any adverse effects upon adjacent landowners and users. Notice of the selected route shall be published by the department in a newspaper of general circulation in the area in which the trail is located, together with appropriate maps and descriptions. </section><section prefix="2">For state recreation trails and for connecting or side trails, the department shall select the route; provided, however, that when a route shall traverse land within the jurisdiction of a governmental unit or political subdivision, the department shall consult with such unit or such subdivision prior to its final determination for the location of the route. </section><section prefix="3">In selecting routes and implementing KRS 148.610 to 148.780, the department is encouraged to confer with the recognized and established organizations primarily interested in trail development, conservation, and outdoor recreation. Furthermore, the General Assembly encourages citizen participation in trail acquisition, construction, development, and maintenance where such activities will not conflict with the purpose of KRS 148.610 to 148.780. </section><section prefix="4">In the selection of the route for any trail, when the trail reaches an area of crop or fenced pasture land, the trail shall be so located as not to interfere in the growing of crops, or with the livestock, or pasture land, and such trail may then follow existing farm roads. The owner of such farm lands may enter a written agreement with the department to grant permission for the crossing of such crop or pasture land. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 8. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1781</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>