<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.310</section_number><catch_line>Revocation of voluntary dissolution proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text>A corporation may, at any time prior to the filing of articles of dissolution with the Secretary of State, revoke the action theretofore taken to dissolve the corporation, in the following manner: <section prefix="1">If there are members entitled to vote thereon, the board of directors shall adopt a resolution recommending that the voluntary dissolution proceedings be revoked, and directing that the question of such revocation be submitted to a vote at a meeting of members entitled to vote thereon, which may be either an annual or a special meeting. Written notice stating that the purpose, or one (1) of the purposes, of such meeting is to consider the advisability of revoking the voluntary dissolution proceedings, shall be given to each member entitled to vote at such meeting, within the time and in the manner provided in KRS 273.161 to 273.390 for the giving of notice of meetings of members. A resolution to revoke the voluntary dissolution proceedings shall be adopted upon receiving at least two-thirds (2/3) of the votes which members present at such meeting or represented by proxy are entitled to cast. </section><section prefix="2">If there are no members, or no members entitled to vote thereon, a resolution to revoke the voluntary dissolution proceedings shall be adopted at a meeting of the board of directors upon receiving the vote of a majority of the directors in office. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the adoption of such resolution by the members, or by the board of directors where there are no members or no members entitled to vote thereon, the corporation may thereupon again conduct its affairs. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 206, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 47. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>