<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.190</section_number><catch_line>Citizen foster care review boards -- Local citizen foster care review boards. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be established within each judicial district a citizen foster care review board to be appointed by the Chief District Judge or family court judge. The Chief District Judge or family court judge may authorize the creation of additional local citizen foster care review boards as needed. </section><section prefix="2">Each local citizen foster care review board shall consist of not less than three (3) members and shall be appointed according to the following guidelines: <section prefix="a">All members shall have an interest in foster care or child welfare; </section><section prefix="b">At least two (2) members of each local citizen foster care review board shall, as far as practicable, be chosen from among the following professions: law, medicine, psychology, social work, and education; </section><section prefix="c">Each local citizen foster care review board shall, as far as practicable, include a foster parent; </section><section prefix="d">All members of each local citizen foster care review board shall, as far as practicable, be representative of the socioeconomic, racial, and ethnic composition of the area served; </section><section prefix="e">Employees of the cabinet shall be prohibited from serving on the local citizen foster care review board; </section><section prefix="f">All appointed board members shall serve a term of three (3) years, except that if a vacancy occurs, a successor shall be appointed to serve the unexpired term. The term of each member shall expire on August 1 of the appropriate year. Members may be reappointed and shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed; and </section><section prefix="g">All members shall be certified prior to appointment by the state citizen foster care review board or its designee. For the purposes of this section, "certified" means acknowledgment of completion of initial training approved by the state citizen foster care review board. </section></section><section prefix="3">Local citizen foster care review board members may be removed for nonparticipation, failure to meet training requirements, or other cause as determined by the state citizen foster care review board in compliance with its constitution and bylaws. </section><section prefix="4">Each local citizen foster care review board shall annually elect a chairman and vice chairman to serve in the absence of the chairman. </section><section prefix="5">Each local citizen foster care review board shall meet, at a place designated by the Chief District Judge or family court judge, as often as is deemed necessary to carry out the duties of the board. The local citizen foster care review board shall meet no less than four (4) times annually. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 412, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 56, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 80, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20208</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>