<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="378" order_by="378">A KENTUCKY UNIFORM VOIDABLE TRANSACTIONS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>378A.060</section_number><catch_line>When transfer is made or obligation is incurred.  </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>For the purposes of this chapter:(1)A transfer is made:(a)With respect to an asset that is real property other than a fixture, butincluding the interest of a seller or purchaser under a contract for the saleof the asset, when the transfer is so far perfected that a good-faithpurchaser of the asset from the debtor against which applicable lawspermit the transfer to be perfected cannot acquire an interest in the assetthat is superior to the interest of the transferee; and(b)With respect to an asset that is not real property or that is a fixture, whenthe transfer is so far perfected that a creditor on a simple contract cannotacquire a judicial lien otherwise than under this chapter that is superior tothe interest of the transferee.(2)If applicable law permits the transfer to be perfected as provided in subsection(1) of this section, and the transfer is not so perfected before thecommencement of an action for relief under this chapter, the transfer isdeemed made immediately before the commencement of the action.(3)If applicable law does not permit the transfer to be perfected as provided insubsection (1) of this section, the transfer is made when it becomes effectivebetween the debtor and the transferee.(4)A transfer is not made until the debtor has acquired rights in the assettransferred.(5)An obligation is incurred:(a)If oral, when it becomes effective between the parties; or(b)If evidenced by a record, when the record, signed by the obligor, isdelivered to or for the benefit of the obligee.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 6, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44726</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>