<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.190</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction for enforcement actions. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Circuit Court where the violation occurs shall have jurisdiction and venue in all civil and injunctive actions instituted by the department for the enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 318 and the State Plumbing Code and the orders issued thereunder. </section><section prefix="2">The Franklin Circuit Court shall hold concurrent jurisdiction and venue in all civil and injunctive actions instituted by the department, or upon the secretary's request by the Attorney General, for the enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 318, the State Plumbing Code and the orders issued thereunder and other rules and regulations of the department. </section><section prefix="3">The District Court where the violation occurs shall have jurisdiction and venue in all criminal actions for the enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 318 and the State Plumbing Code and the orders issued thereunder. The Franklin Circuit Court shall hold concurrent jurisdiction and venue on all appeals of criminal actions for the enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 318 and the State Plumbing Code and the orders issued thereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1692, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 6; and ch. 299, sec. 76. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31213</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>