<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.140</section_number><catch_line>Juvenile Court Advisory Board. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Chief District Judge may appoint a board of not less than six (6) nor more than ten (10) reputable inhabitants of the county to be called the Advisory Board of the Juvenile Court. The members of the board shall hold office during the pleasure of the judge and shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall visit at least once a year all facilities in the county receiving children under KRS Chapters 600 to 645. At least two (2) of the members of the board shall go together on the visits and shall make a report to the board. The board shall report to the court from time to time the condition of the children in the facilities and shall make an annual report to the court. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall advise and cooperate with the Chief District Judge upon all matters affecting the workings of KRS Chapters 600 to 645 and shall recommend to the court any needful measures for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of KRS Chapters 600 to 645. The appointment and utilization of such advisory boards by each District Judge is recommended by the General Assembly as a matter of policy. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 12, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 17, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20124</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>