<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.065</section_number><catch_line>Fees -- Disposition of fee -- Exceptions.   </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall establish by regulation and collect the following fees for certification or licensure as an appraiser for: <section prefix="a">Federally related transactions: <section prefix="1">Initial application fee in an amount not to exceed two hundred twelve dollars ($212), which shall include a fee for the current edition of the Uniform Standards of Professional Practice; </section><section prefix="2">Examination fee in an amount not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200); </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">An annual certificate or licensure fee in an amount not to exceed two hundred twelve dollars ($212), which shall include a fee for the current edition of the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice; </section><section prefix="b">Duplicate certificate fee in an amount not to exceed ten dollars ($10); and </section><section prefix="c">Certificate correction fee in an amount not to exceed ten dollars ($10); and </section></section><section prefix="4">Roster fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50); and </section></section><section prefix="b">Nonfederally related transactions: <section prefix="1">Initial application fee in an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section><section prefix="2">Examination fee in an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">An annual certificate or licensure renewal fee in an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section><section prefix="b">Duplicate certificate fee in an amount not to exceed five dollars ($5); and </section><section prefix="c">Certificate correction fee in an amount not to exceed five dollars ($5); and </section></section><section prefix="4">Roster fee not to exceed twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">All fees and charges collected by the board under the provisions of this chapter shall be paid into the Real Estate Appraisers Board's trust and agency account in the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="b">All expenses incurred by the board under the provisions of this chapter, including compensation to the board members and staff, shall be paid out of this account, subject to approval of the board. </section><section prefix="c">The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the fee charged pursuant to KRS 324A.155, which is required to be included in the appraisal management company recovery fund and which shall be paid into that fund. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 8, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has modified the internal numbering of this statute from the way it appeared in 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 14. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42101</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>