<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-526</section_number><catch_line>Filing-office rules. </catch_line><order_by>9-526</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement this article as it relates to the Secretary of State. The filing-office administrative regulations must be: <section prefix="a">Consistent with this article; and </section><section prefix="b">Promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="2">To keep the filing-office administrative regulations and practices of the filing office in harmony with the rules and practices of filing offices in other jurisdictions that enact substantially this part of this article, and to keep the technology used by the filing office compatible with the technology used by filing offices in other jurisdictions that enact substantially this part of this article, the Secretary of State, so far as is consistent with the purposes, policies, and provisions of this article, in promulgating, amending, and repealing filing-office administrative regulations, shall: <section prefix="a">Consult with filing offices in other jurisdictions that enact substantially this part of this article; and </section><section prefix="b">Consult the most recent version of the model rules promulgated by the International Association of Corporate Administrators or any successor organization; and </section><section prefix="c">Take into consideration the rules and practices of, and the technology used by, filing offices in other jurisdictions that enact substantially this part of this article. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 117, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33831</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>