<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.080</section_number><catch_line>Nonelective city offices and officers -- Appointment -- Removal -- Statement of reason for removal -- Prohibition against creating or altering elected office. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All nonelected city offices shall be created by ordinance which shall specify: <section prefix="a">Title of office; </section><section prefix="b">Powers and duties of office; </section><section prefix="c">Oath of office; and </section><section prefix="d">Bond, if required. </section></section><section prefix="2">A city may create nonelected offices other than those referred to in this subsection. For purposes of the requirements of this section, the following shall be considered nonelected offices: <section prefix="a">City clerk; </section><section prefix="b">City manager; </section><section prefix="c">City administrator; </section><section prefix="d">Chief of police; and </section><section prefix="e">Fire chief, other than a volunteer fire chief. </section></section><section prefix="3">All nonelected city officers shall be appointed by the executive authority of the city and, except in cities of the first class, all these appointments shall be with approval of the city legislative body if separate from the executive authority. The officers may be removed by the executive authority at will unless otherwise provided by statute or ordinance. Upon removal of a nonelected officer at will, the executive authority shall give the officer a written statement setting forth the reason or reasons for the removal. However, this requirement shall not be construed as limiting in any way the at-will dismissal power of the executive authority. </section><section prefix="4">Each appointed and elected city office existing upon adoption of this chapter shall continue until abolished by ordinance, except that the offices of mayor and legislative body members may not be abolished. No abolition of any elected office shall take effect until expiration of the term of the current holder of the office. No ordinance abolishing any elected office shall be enacted later than two hundred forty (240) days preceding the regular election for that office, except in the event of a vacancy in the office. </section><section prefix="5">No city may create any elected office. Existing elected offices may be continued under provision of subsection (4) of this section, but no existing elected office may be changed. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (6/21/2001).  A reference to "subsection (3)" in subsection (5) of this statute has been changed in codification to "subsection (4)" under KRS 7.136(1)(e) and (h). In 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, subsection (3) was renumbered as subsection (4), but an internal reference in the existing language of this statute was overlooked. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25174</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>