<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.362</section_number><catch_line>Agreement permitting peace officers to patrol private residential property to enforce state and local traffic and motor vehicle laws. </catch_line><order_by>362</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any public police department, sheriff's office, or the Department of Kentucky State Police may, upon written agreement with a residential property owner or a residential property owners' association, patrol the roadways and parking lots of private residential communities within the jurisdiction of the public police department, sheriff's office, or the Department of Kentucky State Police and enforce the traffic and motor vehicle laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and local traffic and motor vehicle ordinances, on that residential private property. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not permit a public police department, sheriff's office, or the Department of Kentucky State Police to enforce the private rules or regulations of the residential property owner. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not limit any peace officer from coming on residential private property for the enforcement of the law, provided that the entry upon residential private property is consistent with the provisions of the Constitution of the United States, the Constitution of Kentucky, the Kentucky Revised Statutes, and applicable court decisions. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 129, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 587, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22924</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>