<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.230</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for participation in fund. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text>Each local government which meets the following requirements shall be eligible to share in the distribution of funds from the fund: <section prefix="1">Employs one (1) or more firefighters. </section><section prefix="2">Pays every firefighter a minimum annual salary of eight thousand dollars ($8,000). </section><section prefix="3">Maintains the minimum educational requirement of a high school degree, or its equivalent as determined by the commission, for employment of firefighters on or after August 1, 1980. All firefighters employed prior to August 1, 1980, shall be deemed to have met requirements of this subsection. </section><section prefix="4">Requires all firefighters employed on or after July 15, 1982, to successfully complete a basic training course of a minimum of four hundred (400) hours duration as mandated by the commission as to subject matter and number of hours for each subject, within one (1) year of the date of employment at a school or method certified or recognized by the commission. </section><section prefix="5">Requires all firefighters, whether originally employed before or after August 1, 1980, to successfully complete in each calendar year an in-service training program appropriate to the firefighters rank and responsibility, of at least one hundred (100) hours duration at a school certified or recognized by the commission. This requirement shall be waived for the period of time that a professional firefighter is serving on active duty in the United States Armed Forces. This waiver shall be retroactive for professional firefighters from the date of September 11, 2001. </section><section prefix="6">Requires compliance with all provisions of law applicable to local firefighters. </section><section prefix="7">Requires compliance with all rules and regulations, appropriate to the size and location of the local fire department or fire prevention district, issued by the commission to facilitate the administration of the fund and further the provisions of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26141</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>