<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.707</section_number><catch_line>Community early childhood councils.   </catch_line><order_by>707</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Early Childhood Advisory Council may recognize and fund a community early childhood council. A council shall be composed of no fewer than seven (7) and no more than twenty-seven (27) members. Each council shall be composed of at least one (1) member representing local agencies or organizations from profit, nonprofit, or family child care, Head Start or Early Head Start, and each school district in its designated service area. Other members may be appointed who represent local agencies and organizations, including, but not limited to, the organizations or agencies listed: <section prefix="a">Early childhood advocate; </section><section prefix="b">Faith community; </section><section prefix="c">Family resource center; </section><section prefix="d">Military establishment; </section><section prefix="e">Child-care resource and referral agency or child-care subsidy agent; </section><section prefix="f">Child-care consumer or parent; </section><section prefix="g">County cooperative extension service; </section><section prefix="h">Department for public health; </section><section prefix="i">University, college, or technical school; </section><section prefix="j">United Way; </section><section prefix="k">Kentucky Early Intervention System; </section><section prefix="l">Agency administering services to children with disabilities; </section><section prefix="m">Home visitation agency; </section><section prefix="n">Family literacy agency; </section><section prefix="o">Civic organization; </section><section prefix="p">Public library; </section><section prefix="q">Regional training center; </section><section prefix="r">Community action agency; </section><section prefix="s">Government; </section><section prefix="t">Business community; </section><section prefix="u">Home schooling association; </section><section prefix="v">Health care professional; </section><section prefix="w">Foster care parent; or </section><section prefix="x">Adoptive parent. </section></section><section prefix="2">Members shall serve on a community early childhood council on a voluntary basis and receive no compensation or expense reimbursement for their service. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Members shall serve for a term of two (2) years and until their successors are appointed, except that for those members initially appointed, the terms shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">One-third (1/3) of the members shall be appointed for three (3) years; </section><section prefix="2">One-third (1/3) shall be appointed for two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="3">One-third (1/3) shall be appointed for one (1) year. </section></section><section prefix="b">Vacancies shall be appointed for unexpired terms in the same manner as original appointments. </section></section><section prefix="4">A community early childhood council shall collaborate with the District Early Intervention Committee, the Preschool Interagency Planning Council, and other existing interagency groups in the service area. </section><section prefix="5">A community early childhood council may apply for a competitive grant from the Early Childhood Advisory Council, consistent with a state plan for grant participation as established by the Early Childhood Advisory Council. Grant proposals shall: <section prefix="a">Include a needs assessment and budget proposal for the respective service area served by a community early childhood council; </section><section prefix="b">Not include administrative costs that exceed five percent (5%); and </section><section prefix="c">Contain a signed statement from each member of the community early childhood council certifying that no program, agency, or individual that may receive part of an award would constitute a conflict of interest under KRS Chapter 11A for the council member. Issues concerning conflicts of interest shall be submitted to the Executive Branch Ethics Commission for resolution. </section></section><section prefix="6">A community early childhood council shall submit an annual report to the Early Childhood Advisory Council that details the activities and services of the community early childhood council, including the progress that the community early childhood council has made toward addressing the early childhood development and school readiness goals for its designated service area and recommendations that may be included in the state plan. </section><section prefix="7">Any records that are in the custody of a community early childhood council, a designated service provider, or a grantee that contain personal and identifying information relating to a family or children receiving services through the council shall be confidential and not subject to public disclosure, except as otherwise authorized by law. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>