<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="68" order_by="68">COUNTY FINANCE AND COUNTY TREASURER </unit></structure><section_number>68.202</section_number><catch_line>License fee on cable television systems in counties containing a designated city -- Use of proceeds.   </catch_line><order_by>202</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county containing a designated city may levy a license fee not to exceed two percent (2%) on the gross receipts of all cable television systems within its boundaries, including systems franchised by cities within the county. </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court shall provide for collection of the license fee in the ordinance by which the license fee is levied. The revenues shall be deposited in an account to be known as the cable television license fee account. </section><section prefix="3">The county shall use the proceeds of the license fee only to provide teleconferencing facilities and equipment and television production services, equipment, and facilities pursuant to an arrangement with the Kentucky Authority for Educational Television, as specifically authorized by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="4">A county which has adopted the license fee authorized by subsection (1) of this section, and any cities within the county, shall not levy a franchise fee exceeding three percent (3%) of the gross receipts of its franchised cable television system. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">As used in this section, "designated city" means a city on the registry maintained by the Department for Local Government pursuant to this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">On or before January 1, 2015, the Department for Local Government shall create and maintain a registry of cities that, as of August 1, 2014, were classified as cities of the second class. The Department for Local Government shall make the information included on the registry available to the public by publishing it on its Web site. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 41, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43626</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>