<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.018</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Proud™ Advisory Council. </catch_line><order_by>018</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Proud™ Advisory Council is hereby created for the purpose of advising the department concerning the implementation and administration of the Kentucky Proud™ Program authorized by KRS 260.017. The council shall consist of the following twelve (12) members: <section prefix="1">Commissioner, or the Commissioner's designee, who shall serve as chair and who shall appoint the members in subparagraphs 3. to 11. of this paragraph; </section><section prefix="2">Dean, University of Kentucky College of Agriculture, or the dean's representative; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) farmer member of the Kentucky Proud™ Program; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) Kentucky food retailer; </section><section prefix="5">One (1) Kentucky food distributor; </section><section prefix="6">One (1) Kentucky food processor; </section><section prefix="7">One (1) Kentucky agritourism venue operator; </section><section prefix="8">One (1) representative of a Kentucky agriculture commodity organization; </section><section prefix="9">One (1) Kentucky restaurateur; </section><section prefix="10">One (1) producer of a Kentucky Proud™ product; and </section><section prefix="11">Two (2) at-large members. </section></section><section prefix="b">Each appointed member of the council shall serve for a term of two (2) years or until a successor is appointed and may be reappointed for additional terms. </section><section prefix="c">The chair or a majority of the members may call a meeting to order, and the council may meet as often as necessary for the conduct of its business. A majority of the membership shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. </section><section prefix="d">The council shall: <section prefix="1">Advise the department concerning the implementation and administration of the Kentucky Proud™ Program; and </section><section prefix="2">Make recommendations to the department regarding the content of administrative regulations promulgated by the department in accordance with KRS 260.016 to 260.019. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Appointed council members may be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses incurred while engaged in carrying out the official duties of the council. </section><section prefix="3">The council shall be attached to the Department of Agriculture for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12532</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>