<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63">RESIGNATIONS, REMOVALS, AND VACANCIES </unit></structure><section_number>63.100</section_number><catch_line>Removal of peace officers for neglect -- Charges -- Notice. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A peace officer guilty of neglect of duty shall be removed from office in the manner prescribed by KRS 63.100 to 63.130. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall sign written charges setting forth the grounds for removal of the officer. The charges, when considered collectively, must be supported by the affidavit of at least two (2) witnesses, but it shall not be necessary to support each separate count or individual charge embraced in the charges by two (2) affidavits. The affidavits must be filed by the Governor as a part of the record in the proceedings. The charges need not possess the formalities and exactness of an indictment. The charges shall be recorded in the Executive Journal and an attested copy thereof shall be made by the Secretary of State, and served upon the officer sought to be removed. No response shall be filed to the charges, but they shall stand traversed of record. </section><section prefix="3">Notice must be given to the officer sought to be removed, stating the time and place of the hearing, and giving him at least twenty (20) days to prepare his defense. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766a-6, 3766a-7, 3766a-13. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23160</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>