<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.211</section_number><catch_line>Return of Kentucky residents from other states. </catch_line><order_by>211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Legal residents of the state who have become public charges in other states and have been returned to Kentucky because they have been involuntarily hospitalized may be immediately admitted to a hospital at the request of the secretary or his designated representative.  </section><section prefix="2">Within seventy-two (72) hours (excluding weekends and holidays) of the admission date, the staff of the hospital shall determine the need of the person for further hospitalization.  If two (2) qualified mental health professionals, at least one (1) of whom is a physician, conclude that the patient shall be involuntarily hospitalized, they shall file in the appropriate court a certification requesting involuntary hospitalization procedures be initiated under the provisions of this chapter unless the patient has agreed to remain voluntarily. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was enacted in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>