<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.400</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Transportation Cabinet -- Administration of laws. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The administration of the provisions of KRS 186.400 to 186.640 not specifically vested in the Transportation Cabinet or the circuit clerks shall be vested in the Transportation Cabinet. The Transportation Cabinet may prescribe regulations for the enforcement of KRS 186.400 to 186.640, except that rules concerned with the functions and duties of the Transportation Cabinet provided in subsection (3) of this section shall be prescribed by the Transportation Cabinet. The Transportation Cabinet also shall enforce regulations governing the acts of the circuit clerks and motor vehicle operators under KRS 186.400 to 186.640 and require reports which it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall provide or cause to be provided to appropriate persons or officials an adequate supply of forms for the administration of KRS 186.400 to 186.640. The style of those forms and the method of their use shall be prescribed by the cabinet and shall be adequate to protect the safety interests of the state. The Transportation Cabinet shall prescribe the method of financial control. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Transportation Cabinet shall collect all moneys due the state from the circuit clerks for operators' licenses issued, and shall deposit those moneys with the state treasurer. </section><section prefix="b">At least once each year the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet shall cause a reconciliation to be made between the record of receipts by the Transportation Cabinet and the receipt of applications by the Transportation Cabinet. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. X, sec. 11, effective September 1, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739m-55, 2739m-70. </history><metadata><effective>September 1, 1956 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6041</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>