<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-523</section_number><catch_line>Information from filing office -- Sale or license of records. </catch_line><order_by>9-523</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a person that files a written record requests an acknowledgment of the filing, the filing office shall send to the person an image of the record showing the number assigned to the record pursuant to KRS 355.9-519(1)(a) and the date and time of the filing of the record. However, if the person furnishes a copy of the record to the filing office, the filing office may instead: <section prefix="a">Note upon the copy the number assigned to the record pursuant to KRS 355.9-519(1)(a) and the date and time of the filing of the record; and </section><section prefix="b">Send the copy to the person. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a person files a record other than a written record, the filing office shall communicate to the person an acknowledgment that provides: <section prefix="a">The information in the record; </section><section prefix="b">The number assigned to the record pursuant to KRS 355.9-519(1)(a); and </section><section prefix="c">The date and time of the filing of the record. </section></section><section prefix="3">The filing office shall communicate or otherwise make available in a record the following information to any person that requests it: <section prefix="a">Whether there is on file on a date and time specified by the filing office, but not a date earlier than three (3) business days before the filing office receives the request, any financing statement that: <section prefix="1">Designates a particular debtor; </section><section prefix="2">Has not lapsed under KRS 355.9-515 with respect to all secured parties of record; and </section><section prefix="3">If the request so states, has lapsed under KRS 355.9-515 and a record of which is maintained by the filing office under KRS 355.9-522(1); </section></section><section prefix="b">The date and time of filing of each financing statement; and </section><section prefix="c">The information provided in each financing statement. </section></section><section prefix="4">In complying with its duty under subsection (3) of this section, the filing office may communicate information in any medium. However, if requested, the filing office shall communicate information by issuing its written certificate. </section><section prefix="5">The filing office shall perform the acts required by subsections (1) to (4) of this section at the time and in the manner prescribed by filing-office rule, but not later than two (2) business days after the filing office receives the request. </section><section prefix="6">At least weekly, the Secretary of State shall offer to sell or license to the public on a nonexclusive basis, in bulk, copies of all records filed in it under this part of this article, in every medium from time to time available to the filing office. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 114, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33828</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>