<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.195</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against racial profiling -- Model policy -- Local law enforcement agencies' policies. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No state law enforcement agency or official shall stop, detain, or search any person when such action is solely motivated by consideration of race, color, or ethnicity, and the action would constitute a violation of the civil rights of the person. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, in consultation with the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council, the Attorney General, the Department of Criminal Justice Training, the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, the Department of Kentucky State Police, the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, and the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet, shall design and implement a model policy to prohibit racial profiling by state law enforcement agencies and officials. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Law Enforcement Council shall disseminate the established model policy against racial profiling to all sheriffs and local law enforcement officials, including local police departments, city councils, and fiscal courts. All local law enforcement agencies and sheriffs' departments are urged to implement a written policy against racial profiling or adopt the model policy against racial profiling as established by the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet within one hundred eighty (180) days of dissemination of the model policy. A copy of any implemented or adopted policy against racial profiling shall be filed with the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council and the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Each local law enforcement agency that participates in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund under KRS 15.420 in the Commonwealth shall implement a policy banning the practice of racial profiling that meets or exceeds the requirements of the model policy disseminated under subsection (3) of this section. The local law enforcement agency's policy shall be submitted by the local law enforcement agency to the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet within one hundred eighty (180) days of dissemination of the model policy by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council under subsection (3) of this section. If the local law enforcement agency fails to submit its policy within one hundred eighty (180) days of dissemination of the model policy, or the secretary rejects a policy submitted within the one hundred and eighty (180) days, that agency shall not receive Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program funding until the secretary approves a policy submitted by the agency. </section><section prefix="b">If the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet approves a local law enforcement agency's policy, the agency shall not change its policy without obtaining approval of the new policy from the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. If the agency changes its policy without obtaining the secretary's approval, the agency shall not receive Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Program funding until the secretary approves a policy submitted by the agency. </section></section><section prefix="5">Each local law enforcement agency shall adopt an administrative action for officers found not in compliance with the agency's policy. The administrative action shall be in accordance with other penalties enforced by the agency's administration for similar officer misconduct. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 48, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1053</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>