<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.901</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations for licensed athletic trainers -- Educational requirements -- Kentucky Athletic Trainers Advisory Council.   </catch_line><order_by>901</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to the licensure and regulation of athletic trainers. The regulations shall include but shall not be limited to the establishment of fees and continuing education requirements. The board shall require, as a part of any continuing educational requirement, that persons licensed as athletic trainers complete an educational course on the transmission, control, treatment, and prevention of the human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. The course on the human immunodeficiency virus shall be approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created the Kentucky Athletic Trainers Advisory Council, composed of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor. The council shall review and make recommendations to the board regarding all matters relating to athletic trainers that come before the board, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Applications for athletic training licensure; </section><section prefix="b">Licensure renewal requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Approval of supervising physicians; </section><section prefix="d">Disciplinary investigations or action, when specifically requested by one (1) of the board's panels established under KRS 311.591; and </section><section prefix="e">Promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="3">Except for initial appointments, members of the council shall be appointed by the board for four (4) year terms and shall consist of: <section prefix="a">Five (5) practicing licensed athletic trainers who shall each be selected by the board from a list of three (3) licensed athletic trainers submitted by the Kentucky Athletic Trainers Society, Inc. for each vacancy; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) supervising physicians; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member of the board; and </section><section prefix="d">One (1) citizen at large. </section></section><section prefix="4">The chair of the council shall be elected by a majority vote of the council members and shall preside over meetings. The meetings shall be held quarterly. Additional meetings may be held on the call of the chair or upon the written request of four (4) council members. </section><section prefix="5">Initial appointments shall be for staggered terms. Three (3) members shall serve a four (4) year term, two (2) members shall serve a three (3) year term, two (2) members shall serve a two (2) year term, and two (2) members shall serve a one (1) year term. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the council shall not be compensated for their service but shall receive reimbursement for expenditures relating to attendance at committee meetings, consistent with state policies for the reimbursement of travel expenses for state employees. </section><section prefix="7">A council member may be removed by the board for good cause or if he or she misses two (2) consecutive council meetings without good cause. </section><section prefix="8">Upon the death, resignation, or removal of any member, the vacancy for the unexpired term shall be filled by the board in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="9">The quorum required for any meeting of the council shall be five (5) members. No action by the council or its members shall have any effect unless a quorum of the council is present at the meeting where the action is taken. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall not be required to implement or adopt the recommendations of the council. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44613</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>