<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.1231</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for protesting special fund assessments -- Expenses of audits, how paid. </catch_line><order_by>1231</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The funding commission may mail to the taxpayer a notice of any assessment assessed by it. The assessment shall be final if not protested in writing to the funding commission within thirty (30) days from the date of notice. The protest shall be accompanied by a supporting statement setting forth the grounds upon which the protest is made. Upon written request, the funding commission may extend the time for filing the supporting statement if it appears the delay is necessary and unavoidable. The refusal of such extension may be reviewed in the same manner as a protested assessment. </section><section prefix="2">After a timely protest has been filed, the taxpayer may request a conference with the funding commission. The request shall be granted in writing stating the date and time set for the conference. The taxpayer may appear in person or by representative. Further conferences may be held by mutual agreement. </section><section prefix="3">After considering the taxpayer's protest, including any matters presented at the final conference, the funding commission shall issue a final ruling on any matter still in controversy, which shall be mailed to the taxpayer. The ruling shall state that it is a final ruling of the funding commission, generally state the issues in controversy, the funding commission's position thereon and set forth the procedure for prosecuting an appeal to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals. </section><section prefix="4">The taxpayer may request in writing a final ruling at any time after filing a timely protest and supporting statement. When a final ruling is requested, the funding commission shall issue such ruling within thirty (30) days from the date the request is received by the funding commission. </section><section prefix="5">After a final ruling has been issued, the taxpayer may appeal to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals pursuant to the provisions of KRS 131.340. </section><section prefix="6">The expenses incurred by the funding commission in conducting audits required in this chapter shall be paid by the insurance companies in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the funding commission. </section><section prefix="7">"Taxpayer" as used in this section means insurance carrier, self-insured group, and self-insured employer. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 38, effective March 1, 2005. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32415</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>