<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.420</section_number><catch_line>Collection by aggrieved party from recovery fund. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An aggrieved party may commence an administrative action which may result in collection from the recovery fund by first filing a complaint with the commission on a form prepared by the commission. The complaint shall constitute a prima facie case that a licensee is in violation of KRS 324.160 and is subject to the same conditions set forth in KRS 324.150. If the complaint constitutes a prima facie case and the matter is not settled, the commission shall hold a hearing pursuant to the requirements set forth in the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13B to determine if a violation of this chapter has in fact occurred. If a violation of fraud is so found, the commission shall determine if the violation resulted in damages to complainant and in what amount. If damages cannot be accurately determined, then the amount of damages shall be determined by a Circuit Court in the county where the violation took place. In the event the question of damages is referred to the Circuit Court, the decision of the commission will not be final and appealable until the question of damages is certifiable. </section><section prefix="2">Upon final order by the commission or upon certification to the commission by the Circuit Court on the issue of damages, and after the licensee has refused to pay the claim within a period of twenty (20) days of entry of a final order, the aggrieved party or parties shall be paid the amount or amounts by the commission from the recovery fund. </section><section prefix="3">The license of the licensee against whom the claim was made by the aggrieved party shall be suspended or may be permanently revoked until such time as the licensee has reimbursed the recovery fund in full for all amounts paid, plus interest at the rate of ten percent (10%) per annum. </section><section prefix="4">Any party aggrieved by a final order of the commission may appeal to the Circuit Court where the licensee has his principal place of business or where the applicant resides in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="5">Upon the final order of the court, and after the commission has paid from the real estate education, research, and recovery fund any sum to the aggrieved party, the commission shall be subrogated to all of the rights of the aggrieved party to the extent of the payment. The aggrieved party shall to the extent of the payment assign his right, title and interest in the judgment to the commission. After such assignment, the commission may challenge in bankruptcy court any attempt by a former licensee to discharge the debt, if proper notice is given. Any funds recovered by the commission shall be deposited in the real estate education, research, and recovery fund. </section><section prefix="6">No aggrieved party shall be entitled to recover compensation from the real estate education, research, and recovery fund unless the action against the licensee is commenced within two (2) years from actual knowledge of the cause of action or from the time when circumstances should reasonably have put the aggrieved party on notice of the cause of action. </section><section prefix="7">An aggrieved party shall not be entitled to recover compensation from the real estate education, research, and recovery fund, unless the compensation is for the actual financial harm suffered by the aggrieved party, and this financial harm is specifically and directly related to the property. </section><section prefix="8">For purposes of this section, an "aggrieved party" shall mean either: <section prefix="a">A member of the consumer public who stands in a direct relationship to the licensee, i.e., one who demonstrates an interest in purchasing, leasing, renting, or otherwise securing an interest in real estate through a licensee and who believes that the licensee is in violation of the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">A member of the consumer public who directly engages the services of a licensee for purposes of selling, leasing, renting, or otherwise dealing in his or her own property. </section></section><section prefix="9">If at any time the money on deposit in the real estate education, research and recovery fund is insufficient to satisfy any duly-authorized claim or portion thereof, the commission shall, when sufficient money has been deposited in the real estate education, research, and recovery fund, satisfy such unpaid claim or portions thereof, in the order that such claims or portions were originally filed, plus accumulated interest at the rate of ten percent (10%) per annum. </section><section prefix="10">Any funds in excess of the four hundred thousand dollar ($400,000) level which are not being currently used, may be invested and reinvested as set forth in subsection (2) of KRS 324.410. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 32, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 292, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31619</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>