<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.355</section_number><catch_line>Indigent Veterans' Burial Program -- Funding -- Administration. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established an Indigent Veterans' Burial Program and there is hereby created in the State Treasury a fund entitled the indigent veterans' burial trust fund to provide funds to defray the costs of funeral expenses for indigent veterans in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The fund may receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and any other funds both public and private. Moneys deposited in the fund shall be disbursed by the State Treasurer upon the warrant of the commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs or his or her representative. Any unallocated or unencumbered balances in the fund shall be invested as provided in KRS 42.500(9), and any income earned from the investments along with the unallotted or unencumbered balances in the fund shall not lapse and shall be deemed a trust and agency account and made available solely for the purposes and benefits of the Indigent Veterans' Burial Program. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall be used to defray the costs of funeral expenses for indigent veterans by allocating the funds to pay for the burial or cremation and burial honors of an indigent veteran of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or by allocating the funds to reimburse a veterans' service organization that paid for the cost of the burial or cremation and burial honors of an indigent veteran of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall oversee the Indigent Veterans' Burial Program and trust fund. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21856</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>