<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.455</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 205.460 and 205.465. </catch_line><order_by>455</order_by><text>As used in KRS 205.460 and 205.465: <section prefix="1">"Chore services" means the performance of heavy housecleaning, minor household repairs, yard tasks, and other activities needed to assist in the maintenance of a functionally impaired elderly person in his own home. </section><section prefix="2">"Core services" means those services, including but not limited to client assessment and case management services, designed to identify a functionally impaired elderly person's needs, develop a plan of care, arrange for services, monitor the provision of services, and reassess the person's needs on a regular basis. </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="4">"District" means an area development district designated pursuant to KRS 147A.050. </section><section prefix="5">"Escort services" means the accompaniment of a person who requires such assistance for reasons of safety or protection to or from his physician, dentist, or other necessary services. </section><section prefix="6">"Essential services" means those services which are most needed to prevent unnecessary institutionalization of functionally impaired elderly persons. Essential services shall include chore services, home-delivered meals, home-health aide services, homemaker services, respite services, escort services, and home repair services. </section><section prefix="7">"Functionally impaired elderly person" means any person, sixty (60) years of age or older, with physical or mental limitations which restrict individual ability to perform the normal activities of daily living and which impede individual capacity to live independently, thus rendering such person at risk of entering an institution. Functional impairment shall be determined through a functional assessment developed by the cabinet and delivered to each applicant for essential services. </section><section prefix="8">"Home-delivered meals" means the provision of a nutritionally sound meal, that meets at least one-third (1/3) of the current daily recommended dietary allowance, to a functionally impaired elderly person who is homebound by reason of illness, incapacity, or disability. </section><section prefix="9">"Home-health aide services" means the performance of simple procedures, including but not limited to personal care, ambulation, exercises, household services essential to health care at home, assistance with medications that are ordinarily self-administered, reporting changes in the patient's condition and needs, and completing appropriate records. </section><section prefix="10">"Homemaker services" means general household activities, including but not limited to nonmedical personal care, shopping, meal preparation, and routine household care, provided by a trained homemaker when the person regularly responsible for these activities is temporarily absent or unable to manage the home and care for himself or others in the home. </section><section prefix="11">"Home repair services" means the provision of minor home adaptations, additions, or modifications to enable the elderly to live independently or safely or to facilitate mobility including, where appropriate, emergency summons systems. </section><section prefix="12">"Respite services" means care provided by an approved caregiver or agency for a designated time period because of absence or need for relief of a primary caregiver. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 226, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 24, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 193, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>