<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-710</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </catch_line><order_by>20-710</order_by><text>As used in KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Compliance certificate" means an official emission inspection certificate issued by the cabinet or a county, air pollution control district, contractor, or fleet operator authorized by the cabinet, indicating that a vehicle has been tested in accordance with KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765 and complies with all applicable emission standards; </section><section prefix="2">"Independent contractor" means any person, business firm, partnership, or corporation with whom the cabinet or a fiscal court may negotiate an agreement providing for construction, equipment, maintenance, personnel, management, and operation of an official emission inspection station; </section><section prefix="3">"Control system" means equipment designed for installation or installed on a motor vehicle for the purpose of reducing the air contaminants emitted from the vehicle or a system or engine adjustment or modification which causes a reduction of air contaminants emitted from the vehicle; </section><section prefix="4">"Exemption certificate" means an official exemption certificate issued by the cabinet or a county, contractor, or fleet operator authorized by the cabinet, indicating that a vehicle is exempt from certain requirements of KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765; </section><section prefix="5">"Inspection station" means an official vehicle emission inspection facility whether placed in a permanent structure or in a mobile unit for conveyance among various locations within this Commonwealth, to conduct emission inspections of vehicles required to be inspected pursuant to KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765; </section><section prefix="6">"Reciprocal certificate" means an official certificate issued by the cabinet or a county, air pollution control district, contractor, or fleet operator authorized by the cabinet, honoring an out-of-state certificate that indicates the vehicle was tested and either successfully passed the inspection or was exempt from the inspection in a state that is required to conduct vehicle emission testing by the Federal Environmental Protection Agency. A reciprocal certificate shall be valid for one (1) year from the date it is issued; </section><section prefix="7">"Vehicle" means any automobile or truck registered in this Commonwealth having a combined manufacturer's weight of vehicle and maximum load to be carried of up to eighteen thousand (18,000) pounds, which is equivalent to eight thousand one hundred eighty-two (8,182) kilograms, or less and used upon the public highways of the Commonwealth for the purpose of transporting persons or property. The term "vehicle" shall not include a motorcycle, as defined in KRS 189.285(6); and </section><section prefix="8">"Vehicle emission control program" means a program developed by the cabinet pursuant to KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765 which provides for the control of vehicle emissions of any air contaminant. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 226, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.462. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 66 and 226, which do not appear to be in conflict and  have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>