<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.018</section_number><catch_line>Driving history records of operators -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>018</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of maintaining driving history records of operators of motor vehicles of the Commonwealth, the files of the Transportation Cabinet shall be used to ascertain the driving history record of each person who is licensed to operate a motor vehicle within the Commonwealth. Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the Transportation Cabinet shall destroy, and shall not maintain, records of moving traffic convictions that are more than five (5) years old. Notwithstanding, for any licensee who now holds, who has applied for, or has ever held a Class A, B, or C license issued pursuant to KRS 281A.170, the cabinet shall keep conviction records indefinitely. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet shall not release information on the driving history record of a person under the age of twenty-one (21) whose operator license has been suspended pursuant to KRS 189A.010(6). The cabinet shall destroy, and shall not maintain, the record of the suspension of a person's operator's license if the license was suspended pursuant to KRS 189A.010(6), within five (5) working days of the person's operator's license being reinstated. This subsection shall not apply to a person who holds, or is required to hold, a commercial driver's license. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall charge a fee of three dollars ($3) for any driving history record, ten cents ($0.10) of which shall be deposited in a special account within the road fund to be used exclusively by the Transportation Cabinet for the state driver education program as designated in KRS 186.535. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 20, effective October 1, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 11, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 9, effective April 7, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5916</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>