<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">E IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL HAZARDOUS MATERIALS PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39E.040</section_number><catch_line>Duties -- Appointment of committees. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>The commission shall: <section prefix="1">Appoint local emergency planning committees and revise these committees as it deems appropriate. The committees shall include, as a minimum, representatives from each of the following groups: <section prefix="a">Elected local officials; </section><section prefix="b">Law enforcement; </section><section prefix="c">Emergency management; </section><section prefix="d">Fire service; </section><section prefix="e">First aid; </section><section prefix="f">Health service; </section><section prefix="g">Local environmental; </section><section prefix="h">Hospital; </section><section prefix="i">Transportation; </section><section prefix="j">Broadcast and print media; </section><section prefix="k">Community groups; and </section><section prefix="l">Owners and operators of facilities subject to this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="2">Adopt standards and procedures for the operations of local committees; </section><section prefix="3">Develop reporting requirements and procedures consistent with those of Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499, for individuals, businesses, and governmental agencies that manufacture, use, store, or transport hazardous substances; </section><section prefix="4">Develop guidance and standards for plans related to hazardous substances; </section><section prefix="5">Approve, disapprove, and, where necessary, make recommendations to improve plans developed by local emergency planning committees; </section><section prefix="6">Recommend administrative regulations to the director for issuance by the Division of Emergency Management to implement provisions of this chapter, consistent with Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499; </section><section prefix="7">Receive from any source and authorize the expenditure of funds; </section><section prefix="8">Develop policies relating to the training of committees and persons subject to respond to releases of hazardous substances; </section><section prefix="9">Develop policies relating to exercising and testing plans developed by local emergency planning committees; </section><section prefix="10">Specify a warning point to which all required emergency notifications shall be made; </section><section prefix="11">Develop a procedure by which facilities may report the presence and inventories of hazardous substances and by which members of the public may obtain these reports; </section><section prefix="12">Annually review all commission policies and procedures and update them as necessary; and </section><section prefix="13">Adopt policies for the conduct of the business and duties of the commission. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 61, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>