<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.520</section_number><catch_line>Supplementation of residents' rights. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text>For the purpose of supplementing the rights of residents in long-term-care facilities, such facilities shall take the following actions: <section prefix="1">Every long-term-care facility shall conspicuously post throughout the facility a listing of the residents' rights and responsibilities as defined in KRS 216.515 to 216.525. </section><section prefix="2">Every long-term-care facility shall develop and implement a mechanism which will allow each resident and the responsible party or his responsible family member or his guardian to participate in the planning of the resident's care. Each resident shall be encouraged and provided assistance in the planning of his care. </section><section prefix="3">All long-term-care facilities shall establish written procedures for the submission and resolution of complaints and recommendations by the resident and the responsible party or his responsible family member or his guardian. Such policies shall be conspicuously displayed throughout the facility pending approval of their adequacy by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Every long-term-care facility shall prepare a written plan and provide appropriate staff training to implement each of the residents' rights as defined in KRS 216.515 to 216.525. </section><section prefix="5">All long-term-care facilities shall maintain in their facilities one (1) copy of the most recent inspection report as prepared by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. The cabinet shall provide all long-term-care facilities with one (1) copy of the most recent inspection report. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 484, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 428, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 75, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 79 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9062</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>