<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.050</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors shall provide the president with private-sector perspectives on the operation of a large marketing enterprise. The board shall: <section prefix="a">Approve, disapprove, amend, or modify the budget recommended by the president for the operation of the corporation; </section><section prefix="b">Approve, disapprove, amend, or modify the terms of major lottery procurements recommended by the president; </section><section prefix="c">Serve as a board of appeal for any denial, revocation, or cancellation by the president of a contract with a lottery retailer; and </section><section prefix="d">Adopt, from time to time, administrative regulations which shall be subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A, as may be necessary to carry out and implement its powers and duties, the operation of the corporation, the conduct of lottery games in general, and any other matters necessary or desirable for the efficient and effective operation of the lottery or convenience of the public. The board may adopt, without recourse to the administrative regulation process unless it so desires, rules for the conduct of specific lottery games, including but not limited to, rules specifying: <section prefix="1">The types of games to be conducted; </section><section prefix="2">The sale price of tickets; </section><section prefix="3">The number and amount of prizes; </section><section prefix="4">The method and location of selecting or validating winning tickets; </section><section prefix="5">The frequency and the means of conducting drawings which shall be open to the public; </section><section prefix="6">The manner of payment of prizes; </section><section prefix="7">The frequency of games and drawings; </section><section prefix="8">The manner and amount of compensation to lottery retailers, except all compensation shall be uniform; and </section><section prefix="9">Any other matters necessary or desirable for the efficient and effective operation of the lottery or for the convenience of the public. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">In all other matters, the board shall advise and make recommendations. However, the board shall: <section prefix="a">Conduct hearings upon complaints charging violations of this chapter or of administrative regulations adopted by the corporation and shall conduct such other hearings as may be provided by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">Review the performance of the corporation and: <section prefix="1">Advise the president and make recommendations to him regarding operations of the corporation; and </section><section prefix="2">Identify potential improvements in this chapter, the administrative regulations of the corporation, and the management of the corporation; </section></section><section prefix="c">Request from the corporation any information the board determines to be relevant to its duties; and </section><section prefix="d">Report to the president of the corporation, the Governor, the President of the Senate, and the Speaker of the House of Representatives regarding its findings and recommendations. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 77, effective July 1, 1990. -- Created 1988 (lst Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 5, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>