<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.290</section_number><catch_line>Policing of State Horse Park -- Speed limits. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission may enter into agreements with the law enforcement agency of any urban-county or counties in which the State Horse Park is located or in any adjacent county or with the Department of Kentucky State Police for proper policing of the State Horse Park. If authorized to do so by the commission and subject to KRS 61.300, the executive director may commission employees of the park as patrol officers. These patrol officers shall have all the powers of peace officers upon the property of the State Horse Park and the public property and roads traversing or immediately adjacent thereto. </section><section prefix="2">The commission is authorized to establish by resolution speed limits governing the operation of motor vehicles on horse park property. Notice to the public of such speed limits shall be posted by signs or markings. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may by administrative regulation establish restrictions on the use of golf cart-type vehicles, all-terrain vehicles as defined by KRS 189.010(24), and horse trailers operated on State Horse Park property. The commission may prohibit the use of all-terrain vehicles on State Horse Park property. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may by administrative regulation establish a permit system, including a fee schedule, for golf cart-type vehicles, require owners to purchase usage permits, and require that the usage permit be displayed on the vehicle when operated on State Horse Park property. </section><section prefix="5">The commission may by administrative regulation establish a trailer permit system, including a fee schedule, for horse owners participating in events but not renting stalls at the State Horse Park. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 161, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1743</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>