<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.899</section_number><catch_line>Market-rate survey to determine rates for child-care services receiving public funds. </catch_line><order_by>899</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall conduct a market-rate survey at least biennially to set the minimum rates paid by the cabinet for child-care services receiving public funds in the Commonwealth. The market-rate survey shall: <section prefix="a">Survey all child-care programs in the Commonwealth licensed pursuant to KRS 199.896 or certified pursuant to KRS 199.8982; </section><section prefix="b">Determine market rates; and </section><section prefix="c">Make public its findings. </section></section><section prefix="2">In counties containing no more than two (2) child-care programs of the same type regulated by the cabinet, the cabinet shall pay the rate charged by the program up to the maximum allowable market rate, set in accordance with federal regulations, paid to a program of the same type in that area development district. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall evaluate, at least annually, the adequacy of the child-care subsidy to enable low income families in need of child-care services to obtain child care. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 196, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 20, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 160, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7246</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>