<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.066</section_number><catch_line>Design and availability of forms relating to purchases of metals and objects containing metal -- Charges for copies -- Copyright -- Use of other facsimiles. </catch_line><order_by>066</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall design the electronic and paper forms utilized in KRS 433.890(1) and any other forms and instructions necessary to implement KRS 433.890. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall make the forms and instructions utilized in subsection (1) of this section available on the department's Internet Web site for downloading by any person. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall make single copies of the forms and instructions utilized in subsection (1) of this section available as public records, at the same rate charged for other public records. The department shall not be required to make multiple copies of the forms or instructions for any person, but may do so at the same rate charged for other public records. </section><section prefix="4">Any person may make copies of the forms and instructions required by subsection (1) of this section and may charge for the copies. No person, other than the Commonwealth, shall apply for a copyright on the forms or instructions provided by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The Department of Kentucky State Police may, in the name of the Commonwealth, apply for a copyright on the forms and instructions which it produces pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="5">A purchaser required to generate, maintain, and transmit records pursuant to KRS 433.890: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">May utilize the forms designed by the Department of Kentucky State Police; or </section><section prefix="2">May generate his or her own forms which shall contain at least the information required by KRS 433.890 and which may contain additional information required by a local government or by the purchaser; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Shall use a form specified by a local government which has adopted an ordinance in accordance with KRS 65.871 provided the form contains at least the information required by KRS 433.890 and which may contain additional information required by the local government. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered subsection (5) of this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1095</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>