<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.1055</section_number><catch_line>Mine Equipment Review Panel -- Membership -- Recommendations.   </catch_line><order_by>1055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a Mine Equipment Review Panel attached to the Department for Natural Resources in the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Mine Equipment Review Panel shall be a permanent panel of recognized experts who shall review and make recommendations annually to the director of the division and the Interim Joint Committee on Natural Resources and Environment regarding best available mine safety technologies, including but not limited to wireless tracking and communications devices for use by miners in underground mines. Subject to budgetary constraints and approval by the United States Mine Safety and Health Administration (MSHA), if there is no existing law to the contrary, the commissioner may implement the recommendations of the panel. Based on the recommendations provided by the panel, the director shall comprise a list of commercially available mine safety equipment, including wireless tracking and communications devices that may be approved for use by coal miners. </section><section prefix="3">The panel shall meet at the call of the chair. The chair of the panel shall be the director of the division. Members of the panel shall serve without pay, but shall be entitled to reimbursement of travel-related expenses. </section><section prefix="4">The Mine Equipment Review Panel shall be composed of the following members, who shall be appointed by the commissioner not less than thirty (30) days after July 12, 2006: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall represent the National Institute of Occupational Safety and Health; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall represent the federal Mine Safety and Health Administration; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall represent the coal industry; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be appointed from the membership of the United Mine Workers of America and shall represent mine labor, preferably a member of a Kentucky mine rescue team; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall represent the Department of Mining Engineering at the University of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member shall be the director of the division. </section></section><section prefix="5">Periodically, the panel shall review and make recommendations to the director on changes to or innovations in mine safety equipment that could be deployed in coal mines. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1899, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 135, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44531</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>