<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-878</section_number><catch_line>Grant for project that manages tires -- Application -- Prioritization -- Revocation. </catch_line><order_by>50-878</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If money in the waste tire trust fund established by KRS 224.50-880 is not otherwise obligated, the cabinet may award a grant to a person for a project that will manage waste tires in accordance with the purposes of the waste tire program as appropriate to protect human health, safety, and the environment, or to develop markets for waste tires. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant for a grant shall meet the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Have the legal authority to construct and operate the project; </section><section prefix="b">Have the ability to construct and operate the project in compliance with this chapter and the grant conditions; and </section><section prefix="c">The applicant and the persons who will be managing the project shall not have received a final judgment or conviction of a state or federal environmental statute or regulation in the five (5) years before submitting the application and shall not have any outstanding violations of state or federal environmental statutes or regulations. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall prioritize the applications based on the following factors: <section prefix="a">The project's consistency with the purposes of the waste tire program; </section><section prefix="b">The project's costs and forecasted benefits; </section><section prefix="c">The applicant's credit history; and </section><section prefix="d">The applicant's and key personnel's environmental compliance record. </section></section><section prefix="4">A person awarded a grant shall: <section prefix="a">Construct and operate the project in compliance with this chapter and the grant conditions; </section><section prefix="b">Remain responsible for complying with this chapter and the grant conditions, even if the project is managed by someone else; </section><section prefix="c">Retain ownership of all real and personal property purchased with grant funds unless the cabinet approves their transfer; </section><section prefix="d">Submit to the cabinet monthly an itemized list of expenditures, with copies of invoices or similar documentation; </section><section prefix="e">Submit to the cabinet periodic progress reports; and </section><section prefix="f">Not change the project without the cabinet's approval. </section></section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may revoke a grant and seek recovery of any grant funds dispersed if the person awarded the grant does not comply with this chapter or the grant conditions. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10502</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>