<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.095</section_number><catch_line>Owner-user inspectors -- Issuance of commission -- Requirements -- Reports -- State salary prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to boiler inspectors authorized by KRS 236.070, the department shall issue an owner-user inspector commission to any inspector commissioned by a company operating a pressure vessel within the Commonwealth, provided that: <section prefix="a">The company has an established and regular inspection program; </section><section prefix="b">The company is listed as an accredited Owner-User Inspection Organization in compliance with the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors Accreditation of Owner-User Inspection Organizations; </section><section prefix="c">The inspection program, personnel, equipment, and supervision meet the requirements established by the department after recommendation by the board; and </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">The owner-user inspector applicant has successfully passed the examination provided for in KRS 236.090; or </section><section prefix="2">The owner-user inspector applicant holds a commission as an inspector of boilers and pressure vessels issued by the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A commission as an owner-user inspector shall be issued only if, in addition to meeting the requirements of this section, the inspector is continuously employed by the company for the purpose of making inspections of pressure vessels used or to be used by the company, not of pressure vessels to be resold. </section><section prefix="3">A licensed owner-user inspector is not authorized to inspect boilers within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">A licensed owner-user inspector may inspect all pressure vessels insured by the inspector’s employing company. When the vessels are inspected and reported as required, the owners and users of insured pressure vessels shall be exempt from payment to the state of inspection fees as provided in KRS 236.130. </section><section prefix="5">Each company employing a licensed owner-user inspector shall, within thirty (30) days following each certificate of inspection, file a report of inspection with the department. Reports are to be submitted upon forms prescribed by the department. </section><section prefix="6">No reporting of inspections other than the certificate of inspection reports shall be required unless an inspection reveals that the pressure vessel is in a dangerous condition. </section><section prefix="7">A licensed owner-user inspector shall receive no salary from, nor shall any expenses be paid by, the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="8">Continuance of an owner-user inspector’s commission shall be conditioned upon the inspector continuing employment for an owner-user company meeting requirements of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40112</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>