<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.177</section_number><catch_line>Operation and administration of Kentucky Blue Alert System -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>177</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police in cooperation with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, Transportation Cabinet, the Division of Emergency Management of the Department of Military Affairs, broadcasters, and the news media shall operate a system to notify the public when a peace officer has been killed, injured, or is missing in the line of duty and the department determines that public notification might aid in the apprehension of a suspect or the recovery of the officer. The system shall be known as the Kentucky Blue Alert System. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Blue Alert System shall utilize existing resources, including but not limited to electronic highway signs; the Amber Alert System; law enforcement communications systems; electronic media; local, regional, and statewide media providers; and the Emergency Alert System, if authorized and under conditions permitted by the federal government. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations for the operation and administration of the Kentucky Blue Alert System. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 3, provides that the Act, which created this statute and KRS 16.179, shall be known as the "Trooper Jonathan K. Leonard Kentucky Blue Alert System Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40565</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>