<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.060</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for licensure. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall issue a license as an "electrical contractor" to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Has paid to the department the application fee not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) and the appropriate examination fee, which shall not exceed the actual cost of examination; </section><section prefix="b">Has achieved a passing score, as set by the department, on all portions of the examination required by the department. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to specify who shall take the examination if the applicant is a business entity; and </section><section prefix="c">Has submitted proof that he or she has complied with workers' compensation and unemployment insurance laws and administrative regulations and has obtained a general liability insurance policy of not less than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall issue a license as a "master electrician" to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Has paid to the department the application fee not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) and the appropriate examination fee not to exceed the actual cost of the examination; </section><section prefix="b">Has completed: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Six (6) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade since his or her sixteenth birthday; and </section><section prefix="b">A training course in electrical work, acceptable to the department, or an additional two (2) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade; or </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Five (5) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade since his or her sixteenth birthday; and </section><section prefix="b">An associate's degree or diploma program in electrical technology at a college within the Kentucky Community and Technical College System after 1998; and </section></section></section><section prefix="c">Has achieved a passing score, as set by the department, on all portions of the examination required by the department. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department shall issue a license as an "electrician" to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Has paid to the department the application fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50) and the appropriate examination fee not to exceed the actual cost of the examination; </section><section prefix="b">Has completed: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Four (4) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade since his or her sixteenth birthday; and </section><section prefix="b">A training course in electrical work, acceptable to the department, or an additional two (2) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade; or </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Three (3) years of verifiable experience in the electrical trade since his or her sixteenth birthday; and </section><section prefix="b">An associate's degree or diploma program in electrical technology at a college within the Kentucky Community and Technical College System after 1998; and </section></section></section><section prefix="c">Has achieved a passing score, as set by the department, on all portions of the examination required by the department. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 19, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 433, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39814</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>