<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6925</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited acts. </catch_line><order_by>6925</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An athlete agent, with the intent to induce a student-athlete to enter into an agency contract, may not: <section prefix="a">Give any materially false or misleading information or make a materially false promise or representation; </section><section prefix="b">Furnish anything of value to a student-athlete before the student-athlete enters into the agency contract; or </section><section prefix="c">Furnish anything of value to any individual other than the student-athlete or another registered athlete agent. </section></section><section prefix="2">An athlete agent shall not intentionally: <section prefix="a">Initiate contact with a student-athlete unless registered under KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935; </section><section prefix="b">Refuse or fail to retain or permit inspection of the records required to be retained by KRS 164.6923; </section><section prefix="c">Fail to register when required by KRS 164.6907; </section><section prefix="d">Provide materially false or misleading information in an application for registration or renewal of registration; </section><section prefix="e">Predate or postdate an agency contract; or </section><section prefix="f">Fail to notify a student-athlete before the student-athlete signs or otherwise authenticates an agency contract for a particular sport that the signing or authentication may make the student-athlete ineligible to participate as a student-athlete in that sport. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><former-codification>KRS 164.683. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>