<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.090</section_number><catch_line>Drainage directors -- Election. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In every county where an improvement has been made under former laws or is made under this chapter, except those counties having seventy-five (75) or more separate drainage districts or those counties availing themselves of the provisions of KRS 267.390(3)(b) and 267.490 as provided in KRS 267.495, the county judge/executive shall annually call an election in each district, to be held in the courthouse at the county seat on some day in May designated by him. At this election the taxpayers of each district shall elect a director to represent the district on the board of drainage commissioners. The county judge/executive shall preside at the election of each district, which shall be by viva voce vote of each member present at the hour designated by the county judge/executive. The districts of the county shall be numbered by the county judge/executive, and the elections shall take place in the numerical order of the districts. If any district is not represented at the election, the county judge/executive shall appoint a taxpayer of that district as director to represent the district. The county judge/executive shall fill all vacancies by appointment. The call for election shall be made at least ten (10) days before the election by posting notice at the courthouse door and by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="2">If the county judge/executive fails to carry out any of the provisions of this section, any five (5) taxpayers in any drainage district coming under the provisions of this chapter may call an election, and shall upon the day of the election designate one of their number to act in place of the county judge/executive, with all the rights of the county judge/executive under this section. </section><section prefix="3">In counties having seventy-five (75) or more separate drainage districts or in counties availing themselves of the provisions of KRS 267.390(3)(b) and 267.490 as provided in KRS 267.495, the provisions of KRS 267.010 and 267.490 shall be followed. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 404, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 180. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2380-7, 2380c-1. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>