<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.553</section_number><catch_line>Construction subdistrict established -- Petition -- Procedure -- Judicial review. </catch_line><order_by>553</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The district may establish a construction subdistrict when twenty-five percent (25%) or more of the freeholders of land sought to be included in the construction subdistrict file their petition with the district. The petition shall describe the territory intended to be included in the construction subdistrict and the sewer and drainage conditions and facilities existing in this territory. The territory of the construction subdistrict may be noncontiguous to other territory of the district. Tenants in common, joint tenants with or without right of survivorship, and tenants by the entireties shall be deemed one (1) freeholder or property owner. </section><section prefix="2">When the petition is filed with the district, said district shall give notice of the filing by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. Within thirty (30) days after the publication, any resident or freeholder of the proposed construction subdistrict may file objections and the district shall set the case for hearing within thirty (30) days. If the district finds that the establishment of the construction subdistrict is reasonably necessary for the public health, convenience and comfort of the residents of the subdistrict, it shall make an order establishing the construction subdistrict, and designating it by name and number. </section><section prefix="3">If the district finds that the construction subdistrict is not necessary, it may dismiss the petition. If the district finds that any part of the proposed territory will not be benefited, it may strike such part. If the district strikes a certain portion of the area, the signature of the freeholders of that portion shall not be counted in determining whether the necessary twenty-five percent (25%) have petitioned for the creation of the subdistrict. A copy of the order of the board establishing a construction subdistrict shall be published in accordance with KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="4">An order of the district rejecting or dismissing the petition shall be deemed a final order of the district appealable to the Circuit Court under the procedure set forth in KRS 220.563 within sixty (60) days. Appeals to the Circuit Court from the order establishing a construction subdistrict or striking or refusing to strike any territory from a construction subdistrict shall be made only as provided in KRS 220.563, and only after following the procedures required in KRS 220.563. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9834</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>