<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.410</section_number><catch_line>Purposes for issuance of hardship license -- Prerequisite to court's granting of hardship driving privileges -- Prohibition against issuance when alcohol or substance test was refused.   </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At any time following the expiration of the minimum license suspension periods enumerated in: <section prefix="a">KRS 189A.010(6); or </section><section prefix="b">KRS 189A.070 for a violation of: <section prefix="1">KRS 189A.010(1)(c) or (d); or </section><section prefix="2">KRS 189A.010(1)(a), (b), or (e) for a first offense within a five (5) year period if, at the time of the offense, none of the aggravating circumstances enumerated under KRS 189A.010(11) were present while the person was operating or in control of a motor vehicle; </section></section> the court may grant the person hardship driving privileges for the balance of the suspension period imposed by the court, upon written petition of the defendant, if the court finds reasonable cause to believe that revocation would hinder the person's ability to continue his employment; continue attending school or an educational institution; obtain necessary medical care; attend driver improvement, alcohol, or substance abuse education programs; or attend court-ordered counseling or other programs. </section><section prefix="2">Before granting hardship driving privileges, the court shall order the person to: <section prefix="a">Provide the court with proof of motor vehicle insurance; </section><section prefix="b">If necessary, provide the court with a written, sworn statement from his or her employer, on a form provided by the cabinet, detailing his or her job, hours of employment, and the necessity for the person to use the employer's motor vehicle either in his or her work at the direction of the employer during working hours, or in travel to and from work if the license is sought for employment purposes; and </section><section prefix="c">If the person is self-employed, to provide the information required in paragraph (b) of this subsection together with a sworn statement as to its truth; </section><section prefix="d">Provide the court with a written, sworn statement from the school or educational institution which he attends, of his or her class schedule, courses being undertaken, and the necessity for the person to use a motor vehicle in his travel to and from school or other educational institution if the license is sought for educational purposes. Licenses for educational purposes shall not include participation in sports, social, extracurricular, fraternal, or other noneducational activities; </section><section prefix="e">Provide the court with a written, sworn statement from a physician, or other medical professional licensed but not certified under the laws of Kentucky, attesting to the person's normal hours of treatment, and the necessity to use a motor vehicle to travel to and from the treatment if the license is sought for medical purposes; </section><section prefix="f">Provide the court with a written, sworn statement from the director of any alcohol or substance abuse education or treatment program as to the hours in which the person is expected to participate in the program, the nature of the program, and the necessity for the person to use a motor vehicle to travel to and from the program if the license is sought for alcohol or substance abuse education or treatment purposes; </section><section prefix="g">Provide the court with a copy of any court order relating to treatment, participation in driver improvement programs, or other terms and conditions ordered by the court relating to the person which require him or her to use a motor vehicle in traveling to and from the court-ordered program. The judge shall include in the order the necessity for the use of the motor vehicle; and </section><section prefix="h">Provide to the court any information as may be required by administrative regulation of the Transportation Cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="3">The court shall not issue a hardship license to a person who has refused to take an alcohol concentration or substance test or tests offered by a law enforcement officer. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 16, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 17, effective October 1, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 16, effective October 1, 1996. -- Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 25, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44693</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>