<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="107" order_by="107">MUNICIPAL IMPROVEMENTS -- ALTERNATE METHODS </unit></structure><section_number>107.410</section_number><catch_line>Lease of buildings and facilities to governmental units -- Sublease. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any governmental unit within the territorial limits of the county shall be authorized to lease all or any part of the buildings and related facilities from the district, subject to constitutional limitations, and the district shall have the power to lease buildings or any part thereof to said governmental units. Any governmental unit which enters into such contract of lease may sublease a part or parts of such leased premises to other governmental units within the territorial limits of the county. No such contract of lease or any sublease to another governmental unit of a particular building shall be entered into for a period of more than forty (40) years but said contract of lease and each such sublease may be renewable for a like or lesser period. The rentals to be paid to the district by the lessee shall be specified in the lease agreement, and the district may agree to contribute a portion or all of such payments from its own funds. The district shall be bound for the amount of the contribution agreed upon, provided, however, that such contribution will be payable only from such income and revenue as actually has been provided to the district.  </section><section prefix="2">In determining the amount of the contribution which the board agrees to pay the board shall take into consideration any previous contributions which may have been allowed to the particular lessee, previous contributions which may have been allowed to other governmental units, and the relative assessed values of the property in the various governmental units in the county. </section></text><history>Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 5. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 9. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27186</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>