<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.450</section_number><catch_line>Department procedures and regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall establish: <section prefix="a">Procedures for the compilation and submission to the department of lists and schedules of public records proposed for disposal; </section><section prefix="b">Procedures for the disposal or destruction of public records authorized for disposal or destruction, including appropriate procedures to protect against unauthorized access to or use of personal information as defined by KRS 61.931; </section><section prefix="c">Standards and procedures for recording, managing, and preserving public records and for the reproduction of public records by photographic or microphotographic process; and </section><section prefix="d">Procedures for collection and distribution by the central depository of all reports and publications, except the Kentucky Revised Statutes editions, issued by any department, board, commission, officer or other agency of the Commonwealth for general public distribution after July 1, 1958. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall enforce the provisions of KRS 171.410 to 171.740 by appropriate rules and regulations. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall make copies of such rules and regulations available to all officials affected by KRS 171.410 to 171.740 subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="4">Such rules and regulations when approved by the department shall be binding on all state and local agencies, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. The department shall perform any acts deemed necessary, legal and proper to carry out the duties and responsibilities imposed upon it pursuant to the authority granted herein. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 8, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 34. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 10 provided that "the provisions of this Act shall not impact the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884." That proviso applies to this statute as amended in Section 8 of that Act.  (10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, รยง 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43582</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>