<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="454" order_by="454">MISCELLANEOUS CIVIL PRACTICE PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>454.435</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction of the Circuit Court -- Notice and hearing requirements -- Nonwaiverability of KRS 454.430 to 454.435. </catch_line><order_by>435</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Circuit Court in the county in which the original action was or could have been filed, or the county where the applicant resides, shall have jurisdiction over any application for approval of a transfer of structured settlement payment rights under KRS 454.431. </section><section prefix="2">Not less than twenty (20) days prior to the scheduled hearing on any application for court approval of a transfer of structured settlement payment rights under KRS 454.431, the payee or transferee shall file with the court and serve on all protected parties a notice of the proposed transfer and the application for its approval, including in the notice: <section prefix="a">A copy of the transferee's application to the court; </section><section prefix="b">A copy of the disclosure statement required under KRS 454.431(2); and </section><section prefix="c">Notification of the time and place of the hearing and notification of the manner in which and the time by which written responses to the application must be filed, which shall be not less than ten (10) days after service of the transferee's notice, in order to be considered by the court. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of KRS 454.430 to 454.435 may not be waived. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19616</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>