<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.570</section_number><catch_line>Depository of board -- Bond -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each board of education shall appoint a bank, trust company, or savings and loan association to serve as its depository, and if its annual receipts from all sources exceed one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), it may designate three (3) depositories, except boards of education of school districts in counties containing cities of the first class may designate up to six (6) depositories. The depository may be designated for a period not to exceed two (2) years, and before entering upon its duties shall agree with the board as to the rate of interest to be paid on average daily or monthly balances. </section><section prefix="2">The depository selected shall, before entering upon its duties, provide collateral in accordance with KRS 41.240, to be approved by the local board of education in accordance with Kentucky Board of Education administrative regulations, and to be approved by the commissioner of education. A board of education may enter into an agreement with its depository whereby the premium on collateral guaranteed by a surety company may be paid either by the board or by the depository. If the board pays the premium, the depository shall allow the board not less than two percent (2%) interest on its average daily or average monthly balances. </section><section prefix="3">The depository shall hold for the board all funds deposited by the treasurer of the board or its tax collector or duly authorized agent, subject to withdrawal by the board at any time, and shall pay all funds so deposited to such person and in such manner as the board directs. The depository shall keep full and complete accounts of all of the board's funds, and make reports to the board or its authorized agents upon request. The depository shall keep all records relating to the transactions and duties of the office and turn them over to the successor of its office along with all school funds in hand. The board of education may at any time require a due and proper audit of the depository's records of the funds of the board by a competent outside agent. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 236, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-43. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>