<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.465</section_number><catch_line>Client-outcome study -- Follow-up reports. </catch_line><order_by>465</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All inpatient, residential, or outpatient treatment centers or programs licensed as a chemical dependency treatment service pursuant to KRS 216B.105 or this chapter and receiving state or federal funds, shall participate in a client-outcome study conducted by the cabinet. This scientifically-conducted client-oriented evaluation study shall measure the relative change in a client as a result of the client's participation in specific treatment modalities. The client-outcome study shall measure the client's length of stay in each treatment modality and the client's change in behavior one (1) year after being discharged from a treatment program. </section><section prefix="2">Follow-up reports on a scientifically-based sample of clients discharged from chemical dependency treatment programs shall be gathered by an independent organization qualified to conduct outcome evaluation and submitted to the cabinet in a format to be determined by administrative regulations of the cabinet. The follow-up report shall measure the client's current alcohol or drug use patterns, employment status, educational status, and involvement in the criminal justice system. Follow-up reports may be conducted through telephone or mail surveys of clients and the cost of reports shall be borne by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Clients who refuse to participate in the follow-up report or who cannot reasonably be located shall be noted in the follow-up report. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9953</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>