<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-864</section_number><catch_line>"Preference" defined. </catch_line><order_by>3-864</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A preference is a transfer of any of the property of the bank: <section prefix="a">To or for the benefit of a creditor; </section><section prefix="b">For or on account of an antecedent debt owed by the bank before such transfer was made; </section><section prefix="c">Made while the bank was insolvent; </section><section prefix="d">Made: <section prefix="1">On or within ninety (90) days before the date of the closing of a bank under KRS 286.3-854 if such creditor had reasonable cause to believe the bank was insolvent at the time of such transfer; or </section><section prefix="2">On or within one (1) year before the date of the closing of a bank under KRS 286.3-854 if such creditor was a director, officer or person in control of the state bank and had reasonable cause to believe the bank was insolvent at the time of such transfer; and </section></section><section prefix="e">That enables such creditor to obtain a greater percentage of his debt than some other creditor of the same class. </section></section><section prefix="2">A preference does not include a transfer: <section prefix="a">To the extent that such transfer was a substantially contemporaneous exchange for new value given to the bank; or </section><section prefix="b">To the extent that such transfer was made in payment of a debt incurred in the ordinary course of the bank's business made not later than forty-five (45) days after such debt was incurred. </section></section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 48, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.864. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14613</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>