<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.221</section_number><catch_line>Licensure by endorsement for veterinarians licensed in other jurisdictions. </catch_line><order_by>221</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who, upon applying to the board and remitting a fee set by the board, demonstrates to the board that he has met the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The applicant is a graduate of a veterinary college approved by the board; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">The applicant holds a valid license to practice veterinary medicine and has practiced veterinary medicine in another state of the United States, the District of Columbia, or a territory of the United States for at least one (1) year immediately preceding application, if the requirements for licensure in the issuing state are equal to or higher than the standards required for the issuance of a new license under the provisions of this chapter; and </section><section prefix="d">The applicant has passed an examination given by the board on the laws and administrative regulations of the Commonwealth of Kentucky governing the practice of veterinary medicine. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall not issue a license by endorsement to any applicant who is under investigation in another state, territory, or the District of Columbia for an act which could result in disciplinary action in that jurisdiction until the investigation and disciplinary proceedings have been completed. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31387</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>