<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="77" order_by="77">AIR POLLUTION CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>77.070</section_number><catch_line>Air pollution control board, membership -- Qualifications -- Vacancies -- Removal -- Effect of compact -- Membership of board upon establishment of consolidated local government.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a county containing a consolidated local government or a city with a population equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, the air pollution control board of the air pollution control district shall consist of seven (7) members, three (3) of whom shall be appointed by the county judge/executive, subject to the approval of the fiscal court, and four (4) of whom shall be appointed by the mayor. The mayoral appointments shall be subject to the approval of the legislative body of the city. </section><section prefix="2">The mayor shall appoint, subject to the approval of the legislative body of the city, one (1) member for a term of one (1) year, one (1) member for a term of two (2) years, one (1) member for a term of three (3) years, and one (1) member for a term of four (4) years, and the county judge/executive, subject to the approval of the fiscal court, shall appoint one (1) member for a term of two (2) years, one (1) member for a term of three (3) years, and one (1) member for a term of four (4) years, and upon the expiration of each of said terms respectively, and thereafter, the term of each of such members shall be four (4) years, and until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="3">All air pollution control board members appointed pursuant to this section must be freeholders within the district; those appointed by the county judge/executive must be residents of such county, and those appointed by a mayor must be residents of their respective city or consolidated local government. </section><section prefix="4">Not more than four (4) of the seven (7) board members appointed pursuant to this section shall be of the same political party affiliation, nor shall an officer or employee of such city, consolidated local government, or county, whether holding a paid or unpaid position, be eligible for appointment to the board. </section><section prefix="5">A member of the air pollution control board is eligible to succeed himself or herself. A vacancy in the membership shall be filled by an appointee of the mayor or of the county judge/executive as the case may be, for the unexpired portion of the term. An appointee to a vacancy shall have the same qualifications as any regularly appointed member. </section><section prefix="6">Any member of the board appointed by a mayor may be removed, for cause, after a hearing, by the legislative body of such city or consolidated local government, and after ten (10) days' notice in writing shall have been given to the member, which notice shall embrace the charges preferred against him. At the hearing he may be represented by counsel. The finding of the legislative body shall be final and removal results in vacancy in such office. </section><section prefix="7">Any member of the board appointed by a county judge/executive may be removed, for cause, after a hearing, by the fiscal court of such county, and after ten (10) days' notice in writing shall have been given to the member, which notice shall embrace the charges preferred against him. At the hearing he may be represented by counsel. The finding of the fiscal court shall be final and removal results in vacancy in such office. </section><section prefix="8">As used in this section "mayor" means the chief executive of the city or consolidated local government whether the official designation of his office is mayor, city manager, or otherwise. </section><section prefix="9">Notwithstanding subsections (1) and (2) of this section, when a city of the first class and a county containing such city have in effect a compact under KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the air pollution control board shall consist of seven (7) members, four (4) of whom shall be appointed by the county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court and three (3) of whom shall be appointed by the mayor, with the approval of the legislative body, of the first-class city within such county. The terms of such members shall be three (3) years, and until their successors are appointed and qualified. Upon the effective date of the compact, the mayor, and county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court, shall adjust the terms of the sitting members so that the term of one (1) of each of their appointments expires in one (1) year, the term of one (1) of each of their appointments expires in two (2) years, and the term of one (1) of each of their appointments expires in three (3) years. The term of the then remaining member who was previously appointed by the mayor shall terminate immediately and the county judge/executive with approval of the fiscal court shall appoint a member for a one (1) year term. Upon the expiration of these staggered terms, successors shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years. Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing that city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, all members of the board shall be appointed by the mayor of the consolidated local government pursuant to the provisions of KRS 67C.139 for a term of three (3) years. Incumbent members upon the establishment of the consolidated local government shall continue to serve as members of the board for the time remaining of their current term of appointment. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 68, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 80, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 16, effective March 14, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>