<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.160</section_number><catch_line>Construction and interpretation of chapter. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to preclude any coal interest holder from removing support of the surface and any structure or facilities thereon and other strata as such rights may exist in any severance deed or other contract. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this chapter is intended to or shall be construed as superseding, impairing, abridging, or affecting any specific contractual rights or obligations now or hereafter existing between the respective owners of coal, oil, gas, or other minerals, or any interests therein. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to, or be used or interpreted to, determine ownership. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to, or be used or interpreted to, apply to any well otherwise permitted, approved, or regulated under KRS Chapter 353 except for the wells that are to be converted to or operated as coalbed methane wells. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any limitation of production of coalbed methane from any coalbed methane well, lease, drilling unit, pool, field, or property to prevent or control economic waste or to limit production to market demand. </section><section prefix="6">This chapter shall be liberally construed so as to effectuate the declaration of public policy set forth in KRS 349.005. </section><section prefix="7">Coalbed methane wells shall not be subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 353, except as expressly provided in this chapter. </section><section prefix="8">Gathering lines associated with coalbed methane wells shall be regulated under KRS 353.500(2) and the regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 32, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>