<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.800</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 353.800 to 353.812. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text>As used in KRS 353.800 to 353.812, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Carbon dioxide" means anthropogenic carbon dioxide of sufficient purity and quality as to not compromise the safety and efficiency of the reservoir to securely contain it; </section><section prefix="3">"Carbon injection well" means a well drilled or converted and operated for the purpose of injecting carbon dioxide into subsurface rock formations for geologic storage; </section><section prefix="4">"Division" means the Division of Oil and Gas within the Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="5">"Geologic storage" means permanent or temporary underground storage of carbon dioxide in a reservoir; </section><section prefix="6">"Permeability" means a measure of the capacity of reservoir strata to accept and transmit fluids, including carbon dioxide; </section><section prefix="7">"Pore space" means the voids in subsurface reservoir strata suitable to contain stored carbon dioxide; </section><section prefix="8">"Pore space owner" means the surface owner unless the pore space has been severed from the surface estate, in which case the pore space owner shall include all persons reasonably known to own an interest in the pore space; </section><section prefix="9">"Reservoir" means a subsurface volume of rock with sufficient porosity and permeability to be suitable for the injection and storage of carbon dioxide, and that has adequate seals to prevent leakage of carbon dioxide; </section><section prefix="10">"Seal" means a subsurface stratum or formation sufficiently impermeable to prevent vertical or lateral movement of injected carbon dioxide out of the storage reservoir; </section><section prefix="11">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="12">"Storage facility" means the underground reservoir, underground equipment, and surface buildings and equipment utilized in the storage operation, excluding pipelines used to transport the carbon dioxide to the storage and injection site. The reservoir component of the storage facility shall include a necessary and reasonable areal buffer and subsurface monitoring zones as required by the permit issued by the USEPA for the demonstration carbon injection well; </section><section prefix="13">"Storage operator" means any person holding a permit from the USEPA to operate a storage facility; and </section><section prefix="14">"USEPA" means the United States Environmental Protection Agency. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>