<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">B KENTUCKY PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175B.100</section_number><catch_line>Annual report by state authority -- Annual audit of state authority. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within ninety (90) days after the expiration of each fiscal year, the state authority shall make an annual report of its activities for the preceding fiscal year to the Controller of the Commonwealth within the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Transportation Cabinet, and the Legislative Research Commission. The report shall set forth a complete operating and financial statement covering its operation during the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The state authority shall cause an audit of its books and accounts to be made at least once each year. </section><section prefix="b">A request shall be made to the Auditor of Public Accounts for the performance of an annual audit. If the Auditor of Public Accounts declines in writing to assume responsibility for performing the audit or fails to respond in writing within thirty (30) days of receiving the request, the state authority may enter into a contract with a certified public accountant for an audit. </section><section prefix="c">Any contract with a certified public accountant entered into as a result of the Auditor of Public Accounts either declining to assume responsibility of performing the audit or failing to respond within thirty (30) days of receipt of a written request for an audit shall specify the following: <section prefix="1">That the certified public accountant shall forward a copy of the audit report and management letters to the Auditor of Public Accounts for review; </section><section prefix="2">That the Auditor of Public Accounts may review the certified public accountant's work papers; and </section><section prefix="3">That after review of the certified public accountant's work papers, if discrepancies are found, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall notify the authority of the discrepancies. If the certified public accountant does not correct these discrepancies prior to the release of the audit, the Auditor of Public Accounts may conduct its own audit to verify the findings of the certified public accountant's report. </section></section><section prefix="d">If an audit verifying the findings of the certified public accountant's report is conducted by the Auditor of Public Accounts, the total audit expense incurred shall be an allowable expenditure and shall be paid to the Auditor of Public Accounts. If the audit conducted by the Auditor of Public Accounts discloses discrepancies in the audit by the certified public accountant, the findings of the Auditor of Public Accounts shall be deemed official for all purposes. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 94, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>  (6/26/2009). The internal numbering of subsection (2) of this statute has been altered in codification by the Reviser of Statutes from the way it appeared in 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 94, under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5153</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>