<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.6452</section_number><catch_line>School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council. </catch_line><order_by>6452</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council is hereby created to study, review, and make recommendations concerning Kentucky's system of setting academic standards, assessing learning, identifying academic competencies and deficiencies of individual students, holding schools accountable for learning, and assisting schools to improve their performance. The council shall advise the Kentucky Board of Education and the Legislative Research Commission on issues related to the development and communication of the academic expectations and core content for assessment, the development and implementation of the statewide assessment and accountability program, recognition of high performing schools, imposition of sanctions, and assistance for schools to improve their performance under KRS 158.6453, 158.6455, 158.782, and 158.805. </section><section prefix="2">The School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council shall be composed of seventeen (17) voting members appointed by the Governor. On making appointments to the council, the Governor shall assure broad geographical representation and representation of elementary, middle, and secondary school levels; assure equal representation of the two (2) sexes, inasmuch as possible; and assure that appointments reflect the minority racial composition of the Commonwealth. The members shall serve terms of two (2) years with no member serving more than two (2) consecutive terms, except that seven (7) of the initial appointments shall be for four (4) year terms. The members shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) parents from recommendations submitted by organizations representing school councils and parents; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) teachers from recommendations submitted by organizations representing teachers; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) superintendents from recommendations submitted by organizations representing superintendents; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) principals from organizations representing school administrators; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) local school board members from recommendations submitted by organizations representing school boards; </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) school district assessment coordinators from recommendations submitted by organizations representing district assessment coordinators; </section><section prefix="g">Two (2) employers in the state from recommendations submitted by organizations representing business and industry; </section><section prefix="h">Two (2) university professors with expertise in assessment and measurement; and </section><section prefix="i">One (1) at-large member. </section></section><section prefix="3">The School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council shall elect a chair annually from its membership. </section><section prefix="4">The members shall be remunerated for actual and necessary expenses incurred while attending meetings of the council or while serving as representative of the council. </section><section prefix="5">The School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council shall meet at least four (4) times each year at times and places as it determines by resolution. </section><section prefix="6">The School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council shall be attached to the Department of Education for administrative purposes. It shall be provided appropriate staff and resources to conduct its work. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 3, effective March 25, 2009. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 5, effective April 14, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>