<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.443</section_number><catch_line>Use of federal funds. </catch_line><order_by>443</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any funds made available under the federal act shall be used by each grantee of the funds:  <section prefix="a">To provide a range of services and activities having a measurable and potentially major impact on causes of poverty in the community or those areas of the community where poverty is a particularly acute problem;  </section><section prefix="b">To provide activities designed to assist low-income participants including the elderly poor:  <section prefix="1">To secure and retain meaningful employment;  </section><section prefix="2">To attain an adequate education;  </section><section prefix="3">To make better use of available income;  </section><section prefix="4">To obtain and maintain adequate housing and a suitable living environment;  </section><section prefix="5">To obtain emergency assistance through loans or grants to meet immediate and urgent individual and family needs, including the need for health services, nutritious food, housing and employment related assistance;  </section><section prefix="6">To remove obstacles and solve problems which block the achievement of self-sufficiency;  </section><section prefix="7">To achieve greater participation in the affairs of the community; and  </section><section prefix="8">To make more effective use of other programs related to the purposes of KRS 273.405 to 273.453;  </section></section><section prefix="c">To coordinate and establish linkages between governmental and other social programs to assure the effective delivery of such services to low-income individuals;  </section><section prefix="d">To encourage the use of entities in the private sector of the community in efforts to ameliorate poverty in the community;  </section><section prefix="e">To develop, promote or otherwise encourage economic development activities which result in assisting low-income persons to become economically productive members of their community;  </section><section prefix="f">To provide education, counseling and technical assistance on compliance with equal opportunity legislation for individuals and community organizations, both public and private.  </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to required services and activities to be provided with funds made available under the federal act, these funds may be used to provide on an emergency basis for the provision of such supplies and services to meet immediate essential needs of low-income persons including the elderly poor.  </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13744</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>