<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.410</section_number><catch_line>County building inspectors -- Building permits -- Fees -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of any county may appoint a qualified and competent person to administer such regulations. His official title shall be "Building Inspector of .... County, Kentucky." His salary shall be fixed by the fiscal court, and paid out of the county levy. He shall have such deputies and assistants as the fiscal court deems necessary, and their salaries shall likewise be fixed by the fiscal court and paid out of the county levy. The fiscal court shall also pay out of county funds the necessary expenses of his office. The fiscal court may contract with individuals or corporations for the performance of technical or scientific services required for the proper enforcement and administration of its building regulations.  </section><section prefix="2">No person shall build, erect, construct, reconstruct, remodel, relocate, alter or repair any building within the county without first obtaining a building permit from the building inspector.  </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court shall establish a system of reasonable fees to be charged every applicant for such permit, but such fees shall not exceed the cost of the service provided.  </section><section prefix="4">Any person aggrieved by any ruling, order, or decision of such building inspector may appeal using the procedures provided in KRS 198B.070.  </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 58, effective August 31, 1979. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>August 31, 1979</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23737</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>