<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.5621</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 205.5621 to 205.5625. </catch_line><order_by>5621</order_by><text>As used in KRS 205.5621 to 205.5625: <section prefix="1">"Asset test" means the asset limits as defined by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, Pub. L. No. 108-173; </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Contractor" means the person, partnership, or corporate entity that has an approved contract with the department to administer the Kentucky Pharmaceutical Assistance Program; </section><section prefix="4">"Department" means the Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="5">"Enrollee" means a resident of this state who meets the conditions relating to eligibility for the Kentucky Pharmaceutical Assistance Program and whose application for enrollment has been approved by the department; </section><section prefix="6">"Federal poverty guidelines" means the federal poverty guidelines updated annually in the Federal Register by the United States Department of Health and Human Services under the authority of 42 U.S.C. sec. 9902(2); </section><section prefix="7">"Liquid assets" means assets used in the eligibility determination process and defined by the MMA; </section><section prefix="8">"Medicaid dual eligible" or "dual eligible" means a person who is eligible for Medicare and Medicaid as defined by the MMA; </section><section prefix="9">"Medicare Modernization Act" or "MMA" means the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, Pub. L. No. 108-173; </section><section prefix="10">"Medicare Part D prescription drug benefit" means the prescription benefit provided under the MMA, as it may vary from one (1) PDP to another; </section><section prefix="11">"Participating pharmacy" means a pharmacy that elects to participate as a pharmaceutical provider and enters into a participating network agreement with the department; </section><section prefix="12">"Prescription drug plan" or "PDP" means a nongovernmental drug plan under contract with the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to provide prescription benefits under the MMA; </section><section prefix="13">"Program" means the Kentucky Pharmaceutical Assistance Program established in KRS 205.5621 to 205.5625; and </section><section prefix="14">"Resident" means a person who has lived within this state for a period of at least ninety (90) consecutive days and who meets the conditions as set forth in KRS 205.5625. A person shall be considered a resident until the person establishes a permanent residence outside of the state. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  Although 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 6 had a citation to "Sections 6 to 11 of this Act" in the introductory clause and subsection (13) of this statute, it is clear that "Sections 6 [this statute] to 10 [codified as KRS 205.5625] of this Act" was intended, since there was no Section 11 in the enacted version. This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected in codification pursuant to KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7713</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>