<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.515</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on operation of all-terrain vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for vehicles authorized to operate on a public highway as of July 15, 1998, and except as provided in subsection (6) of this section, a person shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle upon any public highway or roadway or upon the right-of-way of any public highway or roadway. </section><section prefix="2">A person shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle on private property without the consent of the landowner, tenant, or individual responsible for the property. </section><section prefix="3">A person shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle on public property unless the governmental agency responsible for the property has approved the use of all-terrain vehicles. </section><section prefix="4">Except for vehicles authorized to operate on a public highway, a person sixteen (16) years of age or older operating an all-terrain vehicle on public property shall wear approved protective headgear, in the manner prescribed by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, at all times that the vehicle is in motion. The approved headgear requirement shall not apply when the operator of any all-terrain vehicle is engaged in: <section prefix="a">Farm or agriculture related activities; </section><section prefix="b">Mining or mining exploration activities; </section><section prefix="c">Logging activities; </section><section prefix="d">Any other business, commercial, or industrial activity; </section><section prefix="e">Use of that vehicle on private property; or </section><section prefix="f">The crossing of a public roadway with a posted speed limit of fifty-five (55) miles per hour or less. The crossing of a public roadway outlined in this paragraph shall be in compliance with subsection (6)(a) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A person under the age of sixteen (16) years shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle with an engine size exceeding ninety (90) cubic centimeters displacement, and a person under the age of sixteen (16) years shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle except under direct parental supervision. </section><section prefix="b">A person under the age of twelve (12) years shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle with an engine size exceeding seventy (70) cubic centimeters displacement. </section><section prefix="c">A person under the age of sixteen (16) years, when operating or riding as a passenger on an all-terrain vehicle, shall wear approved protective headgear, in the manner prescribed by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, at all times that the vehicle is in motion. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A person may operate an all-terrain vehicle on any two (2) lane public highway in order to cross the highway. In crossing the highway under this paragraph, the operator shall cross the highway at as close to a ninety (90) degree angle as is practical and safe, and shall not travel on the highway for more than two-tenths (2/10) of a mile. </section><section prefix="b">A person may operate an all-terrain vehicle on any two (2) lane public highway, if the operator is engaged in farm or agricultural related activities, construction, road maintenance, or snow removal. </section><section prefix="c">The Transportation Cabinet may designate, and a city or county government may designate, those public highways, segments of public highways, and adjoining rights-of-way of public highways under its jurisdiction where all-terrain vehicles that are prohibited may be operated. </section><section prefix="d">A person operating an all-terrain vehicle on a public highway under this subsection shall possess a valid operator's license. </section><section prefix="e">A person operating an all-terrain vehicle on a public highway under this subsection shall comply with all applicable traffic regulations. </section><section prefix="f">A person shall not operate an all-terrain vehicle under this subsection unless the all-terrain vehicle has at least one (1) headlight and two (2) taillights, which shall be illuminated at all times the vehicle is in operation. </section><section prefix="g">A person operating an all-terrain vehicle under this subsection shall restrict the operation to daylight hours, except when engaged in snow removal or emergency road maintenance. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 400, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>