<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.375</section_number><catch_line>State employee workers' compensation fund.   </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a state employee workers' compensation fund which shall be administered by the Personnel Cabinet's Office of Employee Relations. The purpose of this fund shall be to self-insure workers' compensation benefits for state employees. </section><section prefix="2">All moneys contributed by participants of the fund, or derived from federal funds, shall be credited to and constitute a part of the state employee workers' compensation fund. </section><section prefix="3">The State Treasurer, with the approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, may invest the state employee benefit workers' compensation fund. Any income derived from these investments, or dividends, shall be credited to and become a part of the general fund. Any moneys remaining in the fund after all claims, premiums or subscription charges, and other expenses have been paid, shall be retained in the fund. All moneys remaining in the state employee workers' compensation fund on July 1, or deposited thereafter, shall be deemed a trust and agency account and shall not lapse, but shall be continuously appropriated only for the purposes specified in KRS 18A.375 to 18A.385. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 490, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40101</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>