<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.652</section_number><catch_line>Benefits not to be reduced or impaired for members who began participating before January 1, 2014 -- Exceptions -- Amendment of benefits and rights.   </catch_line><order_by>652</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For members who begin participating in the State Police Retirement System prior to January 1, 2014, it is hereby declared that in consideration of the contributions by the member, and in further consideration of benefits received by the state from the member's employment, KRS 16.510 to 16.645, except as provided in KRS 6.696 effective September 16, 1993, shall constitute an inviolable contract of the Commonwealth, and the benefits provided therein shall, except as provided in KRS 6.696, not be subject to reduction or impairment by alteration, amendment or repeal. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">For members who begin participating in the State Police Retirement System on or after January 1, 2014, the General Assembly reserves the right to amend, suspend, or reduce the benefits and rights provided under KRS 16.505 to 16.652 if, in its judgment, the welfare of the Commonwealth so demands, except that the amount of benefits the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction shall not be affected. </section><section prefix="b">For purposes of this subsection, the amount of benefits the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction shall be limited to the accumulated account balance the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction. </section><section prefix="c">The provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to limit the General Assembly's authority to change any other benefit or right specified by KRS 16.505 to 16.652, for members who begin participating in the State Police Retirement System on or after January 1, 2014, except the benefits specified by paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall not be construed to limit the General Assembly's authority to amend, reduce, or suspend the benefits and rights of members of the State Police Retirement System as provided by KRS 16.505 to 16.652 that the General Assembly had the authority to amend, reduce, or suspend, prior to July 1, 2013. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 44, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 75, effective September 16, 1993. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 537, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>