<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.240</section_number><catch_line>Supervisors' terms -- Nomination and election -- Vacancies -- Compensation -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A supervisor's term begins on January 1 following his election. The two (2) supervisors elected in the general election of 1974 shall be elected for a term of two </section><section prefix="2">years. In 1976 a general election shall be conducted for seven (7) supervisors. </section>The four (4) supervisors elected with the highest number of votes in the general election of 1976 shall serve for four (4) years; the other three (3) supervisors elected in 1976 shall serve for two (2) years. In the event only seven (7) nominating petitions for supervisors are filed, the commission shall declare the nominees elected without an election, and shall name four (4) of the nominees to serve terms of four (4) years, and three (3) to serve terms of two (2) years. Thereafter supervisors shall be elected for four (4) years as their terms expire. Nominating petitions for supervisors shall be filed with the county clerk not later than the last date prescribed by the election law generally for filing certificates and petitions of nomination. No such nominating petition shall be accepted by the clerk unless it is signed by twenty-five (25) or more qualified resident voters of the district. Qualified resident voters may sign more than one (1) nominating petition to nominate more than one (1) candidate for supervisor. In the event nominating petitions for only the number of supervisors to be elected are filed, the commission shall declare the nominees elected without holding an election. The county clerk shall examine the petition of each candidate to determine whether it is regular on its face.  If there is an error, the county clerk shall notify the candidate by certified mail within twenty-four (24) hours of filing.  (2) A supervisor shall hold office until his successor has been elected and has qualified. Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term by appointment by the commission.  <section prefix="3">A supervisor may be reimbursed for expenses necessarily incurred in the discharge of his duties and may be paid a per diem for attending meetings or otherwise discharging the obligations of his office.  </section><section prefix="4">A supervisor shall be a resident of the county or district in which he serves as a supervisor, and upon moving from the county or district, the supervisor shall be ineligible to serve as a supervisor and his office shall be vacant.  </section><section prefix="5">A supervisor who has been declared elected without an election pursuant to subsection (1) of this section may be removed from office by the commission in the same manner as provided by KRS 65.007 for removal of an appointed member of the governing body of a special district. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 30, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 6. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. XIV, sec. 5. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 9. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42i-7. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12733</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>