<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.070</section_number><catch_line>Appropriation for public library -- Disposition of revenue -- Report to legislative body. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide funds for the establishment and maintenance of a library established as provided in KRS 173.030, the legislative body of a city of the first class shall annually appropriate from the general fund of the city such sum as in the judgment of the legislative body shall be reasonably necessary for such purposes. Moneys so appropriated shall be credited to the library fund of the city, and may be paid over to the board of trustees by the director of finance of such city in regular monthly installments. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall make a report to the city legislative body each July, showing the use of the library for the fiscal year ending the last day of June preceding, the receipts and expenditures of all money handled by it during the year, and giving such other information as may promote the usefulness of the library to the public, or as is called for by the city legislative body. No portion of the property or fund held for library purposes under this section shall ever be applied to the support of any library not exclusively under the control of the board of trustees. </section></text><history>Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 7. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2801b-6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4909</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>