<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="37" order_by="37">ACTIVE MILITIA </unit></structure><section_number>37.240</section_number><catch_line>Active service -- How and when ordered into -- Direction -- Powers. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text>The Governor is hereby authorized to call and to assign any part of the Kentucky active militia to active service for the purpose of resisting invasion, suppressing rebellions, insurrections, riots, or threats thereof; to suppress any active, unlawful, or threatened violence to persons or property in this state; to authorize the arrest of all persons engaged in aiding or abetting therein; to investigate any acts of treason, sabotage, or attempted sabotage and to cause the arrest of such persons engaged therein for aiding and abetting; to protect life and property in the event of any emergency or disaster. The Governor may by his order prescribe the duty to be performed by the troops thus called into active field service. The Governor may direct the commanding officer of such military forces thus ordered into service to report to any of the following named civil officers of the judicial circuit, county, city, or town: Circuit Judge, sheriff, county judge/executive, or mayor; and such civil officers may direct the specific object to be accomplished by such military force, but the tactical direction and disposition of the troops and the particular means to be employed to accomplish the object shall be left solely to the officers of the Kentucky active militia. Troops shall not be relieved from active field service except by order of the Governor. </text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 48. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 9. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21514</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>