<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="339" order_by="339">CHILD LABOR </unit></structure><section_number>339.225</section_number><catch_line>Minors eleven and over as golf caddies -- Restrictions. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 339.220 to the contrary notwithstanding, minors age eleven (11) years and over may be employed as caddies at golf courses subject to the following provisions: <section prefix="a">A "caddy" is an individual who offers his or her services to golfers at golf clubs both private and public. His or her duties during course of play include the carrying of golf clubs, direction to the golfer, assistance to the player in the general maintenance and upkeep of golf courses, including replacement of divots, repair of ball marks, raking of sand traps, location of golf balls and control of the pin. Duties normally referred to as "fore-caddying" or "shagging" of golf balls are not within the scope of this definition; </section><section prefix="b">No minor under eleven (11) years of age shall be employed, or suffered to work as a caddy for hire; </section><section prefix="c">Caddies under fourteen (14) years of age are restricted to caddying one (1) round of eighteen (18) holes in any one (1) day; </section><section prefix="d">Minors eleven (11) and twelve (12) years of age may not carry golf bags and are restricted to caddying with a "pull cart" only; </section><section prefix="e">Minors thirteen (13), fourteen (14), and fifteen (15) years of age may be employed to carry golf bags provided the bags do not exceed thirty-five (35) pounds in weight; </section><section prefix="f">No minor under sixteen (16) years of age shall be employed, permitted, or suffered to operate power-driven golf carts in the course of their employment, or any power-driven maintenance equipment; and </section><section prefix="g">All persons employing minors as caddies are subject to all provisions of this chapter and the regulations issued hereunder. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department of Workplace Standards shall promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1772, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 26, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 193, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32184</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>