<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.0205</section_number><catch_line>Priority of application and use of tax credits. </catch_line><order_by>0205</order_by><text>If a taxpayer is entitled to more than one (1) of the tax credits allowed against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020, 141.040, and 141.0401, the priority of application and use of the credits shall be determined as follows: <section prefix="1">The nonrefundable business incentive credits against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020 shall be taken in the following order: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, the corporation income tax credit permitted by KRS 141.420(3)(a); </section><section prefix="2">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2006, the limited liability entity tax credit permitted by KRS 141.0401; </section></section><section prefix="b">The economic development credits computed under KRS 141.347, 141.381, 141.384, 141.400, 141.401, 141.402, 141.403, 141.407, 141.415, 154.12-2088, and 154.27-080; </section><section prefix="c">The qualified farming operation credit permitted by KRS 141.412; </section><section prefix="d">The certified rehabilitation credit permitted by KRS 171.397(1)(a); </section><section prefix="e">The health insurance credit permitted by KRS 141.062; </section><section prefix="f">The tax paid to other states credit permitted by KRS 141.070; </section><section prefix="g">The credit for hiring the unemployed permitted by KRS 141.065; </section><section prefix="h">The recycling or composting equipment credit permitted by KRS 141.390; </section><section prefix="i">The tax credit for cash contributions in investment funds permitted by KRS 154.20-263 in effect prior to July 15, 2002, and the credit permitted by KRS 154.20-258; </section><section prefix="j">The coal incentive credit permitted under KRS 141.0405; </section><section prefix="k">The research facilities credit permitted under KRS 141.395; </section><section prefix="l">The employer GED incentive credit permitted under KRS 164.0062; </section><section prefix="m">The voluntary environmental remediation credit permitted by KRS 141.418; </section><section prefix="n">The biodiesel and renewable diesel credit permitted by KRS 141.423; </section><section prefix="o">The environmental stewardship credit permitted by KRS 154.48-025; </section><section prefix="p">The clean coal incentive credit permitted by KRS 141.428; </section><section prefix="q">The ethanol credit permitted by KRS 141.4242; </section><section prefix="r">The cellulosic ethanol credit permitted by KRS 141.4244; </section><section prefix="s">The energy efficiency credits permitted by KRS 141.436; </section><section prefix="t">The railroad maintenance and improvement credit permitted by KRS 141.385; </section><section prefix="u">The Endow Kentucky credit permitted by KRS 141.438;  </section><section prefix="v">The New Markets Development Program credit permitted by KRS 141.434; </section><section prefix="w">The food donation credit permitted by KRS 141.392; </section><section prefix="x">The distilled spirits credit permitted by KRS 141.389; and </section><section prefix="y">The angel investor credit permitted by KRS 141.396. </section></section><section prefix="2">After the application of the nonrefundable credits in subsection (1) of this section, the nonrefundable personal tax credits against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020 shall be taken in the following order: <section prefix="a">The individual credits permitted by KRS 141.020(3); </section><section prefix="b">The credit permitted by KRS 141.066; </section><section prefix="c">The tuition credit permitted by KRS 141.069; </section><section prefix="d">The household and dependent care credit permitted by KRS 141.067; and </section><section prefix="e">The new home credit permitted by KRS 141.388. </section></section><section prefix="3">After the application of the nonrefundable credits provided for in subsection (2) of this section, the refundable credits against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020 shall be taken in the following order: <section prefix="a">The individual withholding tax credit permitted by KRS 141.350; </section><section prefix="b">The individual estimated tax payment credit permitted by KRS 141.305; </section><section prefix="c">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2004, and before January 1, 2007, the corporation income tax credit permitted by KRS 141.420(3)(c); </section><section prefix="d">The certified rehabilitation credit permitted by KRS 171.3961 and 171.397(1)(b); and </section><section prefix="e">The film industry tax credit allowed by KRS 141.383. </section></section><section prefix="4">The nonrefundable credit permitted by KRS 141.0401 shall be applied against the tax imposed by KRS 141.040. </section><section prefix="5">The following nonrefundable credits shall be applied against the sum of the tax imposed by KRS 141.040 after subtracting the credit provided for in subsection (4) of this section, and the tax imposed by KRS 141.0401 in the following order: <section prefix="a">The economic development credits computed under KRS 141.347, 141.381, 141.384, 141.400, 141.401, 141.402, 141.403, 141.407, 141.415, 154.12-2088, and 154.27-080; </section><section prefix="b">The qualified farming operation credit permitted by KRS 141.412; </section><section prefix="c">The certified rehabilitation credit permitted by KRS 171.397(1)(a); </section><section prefix="d">The health insurance credit permitted by KRS 141.062; </section><section prefix="e">The unemployment credit permitted by KRS 141.065; </section><section prefix="f">The recycling or composting equipment credit permitted by KRS 141.390; </section><section prefix="g">The coal conversion credit permitted by KRS 141.041; </section><section prefix="h">The enterprise zone credit permitted by KRS 154.45-090, for taxable periods ending prior to January 1, 2008; </section><section prefix="i">The tax credit for cash contributions to investment funds permitted by KRS 154.20-263 in effect prior to July 15, 2002, and the credit permitted by KRS 154.20-258; </section><section prefix="j">The coal incentive credit permitted under KRS 141.0405; </section><section prefix="k">The research facilities credit permitted under KRS 141.395; </section><section prefix="l">The employer GED incentive credit permitted under KRS 164.0062; </section><section prefix="m">The voluntary environmental remediation credit permitted by KRS 141.418; </section><section prefix="n">The biodiesel and renewable diesel credit permitted by KRS 141.423; </section><section prefix="o">The environmental stewardship credit permitted by KRS 154.48-025; </section><section prefix="p">The clean coal incentive credit permitted by KRS 141.428; </section><section prefix="q">The ethanol credit permitted by KRS 141.4242; </section><section prefix="r">The cellulosic ethanol credit permitted by KRS 141.4244; </section><section prefix="s">The energy efficiency credits permitted by KRS 141.436; </section><section prefix="t">The ENERGY STAR home or ENERGY STAR manufactured home credit permitted by KRS 141.437; </section><section prefix="u">The railroad maintenance and improvement credit permitted by KRS 141.385; </section><section prefix="v">The railroad expansion credit permitted by KRS 141.386; </section><section prefix="w">The Endow Kentucky credit permitted by KRS 141.438; </section><section prefix="x">The New Markets Development Program credit permitted by KRS 141.434; </section><section prefix="y">The food donation credit permitted by KRS 141.392; and </section><section prefix="z">The distilled spirits credit permitted by KRS 141.389. </section></section><section prefix="6">After the application of the nonrefundable credits in subsection (5) of this section, the refundable credits shall be taken in the following order: <section prefix="a">The corporation estimated tax payment credit permitted by KRS 141.044; </section><section prefix="b">The certified rehabilitation credit permitted by KRS 171.3961 and 171.397(1)(b); and </section><section prefix="c">The film industry tax credit allowed in KRS 141.383. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 46, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 131, sec. 33, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 15, effective June 4, 2010. -- Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 14, effective February 25, 2010 -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 30, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 27, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 7, effective March 23, 2007. -- Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 2, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 13, effective March 4, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 6, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 499, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007." (3/6/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 30, provides that this section applies retroactively for taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005.  (7/15/1994).  This statute applies "to taxable years beginning after December 31, 1993." 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 4. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43410</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>