<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.900</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 205.905 to 205.920. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text>As used in KRS 205.905 to 205.920: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">"Evaluation team" means at least three (3) individuals employed as such by a qualified agency or organization. </section><section prefix="3">"Personal care assistance services" means services which are required by an adult with a severe physical disability to achieve greater physical independence and which include, but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Routine bodily functions, such as bowel or bladder care; </section><section prefix="b">Dressing; </section><section prefix="c">Housecleaning and laundry; </section><section prefix="d">Preparation and consumption of food; </section><section prefix="e">Moving in and out of bed; </section><section prefix="f">Routine bathing; </section><section prefix="g">Ambulation; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other similar activity of daily living. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Qualified agency or organization" means an agency or organization whose purpose is to provide services to severely physically disabled adults to enable them to live as independently as possible and a majority of whose governing board are consumers of these services. If no qualified agency or organization exists, an agency or organization may become a qualified provider when consumers of personal care assistance services are a majority of its advisory council. </section><section prefix="5">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="6">"Severely physically disabled adult" means a person eighteen (18) years of age or older with permanent or temporary, recurring functional loss of two (2) or more limbs. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 288, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 235, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 405, sec. 61, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/94). This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 229, 405, and 416. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. These three Acts conflict as to subsection (4) of this section, and Acts ch. 416, which was the last of the three Acts enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7870</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>