<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.951</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Auto and Truck Recyclers Licensing Advisory Board -- Members -- Meetings -- Functions. </catch_line><order_by>951</order_by><text>There is hereby established the Kentucky Auto and Truck Recyclers Licensing Advisory Board: <section prefix="1">The membership of the board shall consist of twelve (12) members who are appointed by the Governor. Each member shall represent one (1) of each of the Kentucky state highway districts and shall reside in that district and shall also be a member of the Kentucky Auto and Truck Recyclers Association, Incorporated. The term of each member shall be four (4) years. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall meet a minimum of twice annually, at times to be determined by the majority of the members. </section><section prefix="3">The action of the majority of the members shall be deemed the action of the board. No person may act as a member of the board while holding any other elective or appointive state or federal office. </section><section prefix="4">All members shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall report to the commissioner any violations of KRS 177.905 to 177.950 and shall advise with the commissioner upon the issuance of any licenses hereunder. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5398</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>