<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.150</section_number><catch_line>State officials as voting members of citizens' councils. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>When federal programs require a particular citizens' council within or attached to the cabinet to include state officials as voting members, the secretary shall, for the specific purposes of those federal programs, be authorized to vote in those council meetings and shall further be authorized to call upon either the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the chief state school officer, the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet, the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development, the executive director of the Council on Higher Education, or any combination of the above as may be appropriate, to be voting members of expanded citizens' councils for the purposes of these federal programs. The secretary shall exercise this prerogative only when the federal programs specifically require that state officials be voting members of the citizens' councils. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 241, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 219, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 157, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6657</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>