<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.306</section_number><catch_line>Obligations of library science scholarship recipient. </catch_line><order_by>306</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be eligible for a scholarship, an applicant shall contract in writing with the state librarian that he or she will graduate in an agreed to period of time and within six (6) months from the date of completing the program of study, accept employment with a library or archival services program approved by the state librarian for a period of at least two (2) years. The recipient shall agree to the terms of employment established by the employing library or archival services program. </section><section prefix="2">If the recipient of a scholarship fails to fulfill the obligations agreed to under the contract for a scholarship the entire amount of scholarship benefits received shall become immediately due and payable to the Library Science Scholarship Fund. Repayment of benefits received under this program shall be due in a lump sum or through a payment schedule determined by the state librarian on the advice of the Library Science Scholarship Fund Advisory Committee, and in accordance with current interest rates applicable to similar debts collected by other financial assistance entities. </section><section prefix="3">Upon recommendation of the state librarian, the Attorney General shall institute proceedings for the purpose of recovering any amount due the Commonwealth under the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 5. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. VIII, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>