<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.040</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions to chapter. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prevent, restrict, or otherwise interfere with the sale of nonprescription drugs in their original packages by any retailer. No rule or regulation shall be adopted by the Board of Pharmacy under this chapter which shall require the sale of nonprescription drugs by a licensed pharmacist or under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this chapter shall interfere with the professional activities of any licensed practicing physician, or prevent the physician from keeping any drug or medicine that he or she may need in his or her practice, from compounding the physician's own medications, or from dispensing or supplying to patients any article that seems proper to the physician. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to interfere with the activities of a midlevel health care practitioner as provided in KRS 216.925. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this chapter pertaining to the use of collaborative care agreements shall apply in any hospital or other health facility operated by a hospital without the express written permission of the hospital's governing body. Collaborative care agreements may be restricted by the policies and procedures of the facility. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this chapter shall interfere with the activities of a physician assistant as authorized in KRS Chapter 311. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in this chapter shall interfere with the activities of an advanced practice registered nurse as authorized in KRS Chapter 314. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 67, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 22, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1376t, 2625, 2632. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30995</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>