<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.225</section_number><catch_line>Removal, transfer, or abandonment of rented or leased personal property -- Attempt to defraud lessor. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section the following words shall have the following meanings:  <section prefix="a">"Person" means an individual, partnership, association or corporation;  </section><section prefix="b">"Address" means the place at which the rented or leased personal property is located;  </section><section prefix="c">"Personal property" means household furnishings and appliances.  </section></section><section prefix="2">A person who rents or leases personal property under an agreement to relinquish possession of such property to the lessor at the expiration of the lease or rental period, shall not, prior to the expiration of such period, remove the personal property to any other address and relinquish custody of such property without first giving the lessor at least ten (10) days' written notice, delivered in person or by certified mail with a return receipt requested.  </section><section prefix="3">Removing the personal property, or any part thereof, to a new or different location and relinquishing custody of such property, or permitting another person, not a party to the lease agreement, to take possession of the personal property, or any part thereof, or moving from the address and abandoning the personal property shall constitute prima facie evidence of the lessee's intention to defraud the lessor.  </section><section prefix="4">Any lease under subsection (2) of this section shall recite verbatim subsections (1), (2), (3), and (4) of this section.  </section><section prefix="5">Failure of lessor to comply with subsection (4) of this section shall void lessor's relief herein.  </section><section prefix="6">Any person described in subsection (2) of this section who attempts to defraud a lessor of leased personal property shall be fined not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200), or imprisoned for thirty (30) days, or both.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18856</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>