<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.358</section_number><catch_line>Motorcycle safety education program fund. </catch_line><order_by>358</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The motorcycle safety education program fund is established as a restricted fund in the State Treasury. Moneys in the fund are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in KRS 15A.350 to 15A.366. Moneys in the fund shall be utilized to provide motorcycle training courses as established in KRS 15A.352 and for implementation of the program, including reimbursement of entities that offer approved motorcycle rider education courses. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall not deduct administrative costs from the motorcycle safety education program fund. </section><section prefix="2">If at the end of each fiscal year money remains in the fund, it shall be retained in the fund. The interest and income earned on money in the fund, after deducting any applicable charges, shall be credited to the motorcycle safety education program fund. </section><section prefix="3">The following revenue shall be credited to the fund: <section prefix="a">Four dollars ($4) of the annual registration fee for each registered motorcycle as provided in KRS 186.050; </section><section prefix="b">Four dollars ($4) of the application fee for a motorcycle instruction permit as provided in KRS 186.531; </section><section prefix="c">Four dollars ($4) of the fee for each original or renewal motorcycle driver's license or endorsement as provided in KRS 186.531; and </section><section prefix="d">Any federal or state motorcycle safety funds granted to the program. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 52, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 5, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(7/1/2005).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h), during codification a manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected. In the second sentence of 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 5(2), the phrase "motorcycle safety education fund" has been corrected to read "motorcycle safety education program fund" as it is clear from the context that the word "program" was erroneously omitted in that sentence. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1077</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>