<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.600</section_number><catch_line>Complaint on discriminatory housing practice -- Investigation. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">An aggrieved person may, not later than one (1) year after an alleged discriminatory housing practice has occurred or terminated, file a complaint with the commission alleging a discriminatory housing practice. All other complaints of an alleged discrimination practice must be filed pursuant to the procedure described in KRS 344.200. The commission, on its own initiative, or the Attorney General may also file a complaint alleging a discriminatory housing practice. </section><section prefix="2">The complaint shall be in writing and shall contain the information and be in a form required by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may also investigate housing practices to determine whether a complaint should be brought under this section. </section></section><section prefix="b">Upon the filing of the discriminatory housing practice complaint: <section prefix="1">The commission shall within five (5) days serve written notice upon the aggrieved person acknowledging the filing and advising the aggrieved person of the time limits and choice of forums provided in KRS 344.635. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall, not later than ten (10) days after the filing or the identification of an additional respondent under subsection (2) of this section, serve on the respondent a written notice identifying the alleged discriminatory housing practice and advising the respondent of the procedural rights and obligations of respondents under this chapter, together with a copy of the original complaint; </section><section prefix="3">Each respondent shall file, not later than ten (10) days after receipt of notice from the commission, an answer to the complaint; and </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall commence an investigation of the alleged discriminatory housing practice within thirty (30) days of filing the complaint and complete the investigation within one hundred (100) days after the filing of the complaint, unless it is impracticable to do so. </section></section><section prefix="c">If the commission is unable to complete the investigation within one hundred (100) days after the filing of the complaint, the commission shall notify the complainant and respondent in writing of the reasons for not doing so. </section><section prefix="d">Complaints and answers shall be under oath or affirmation, and may be reasonably and fairly amended at any time. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A person who is not named as a respondent in a complaint, but who is identified as a respondent in the course of investigation, may be joined as an additional or substitute respondent upon written notice, under subsection (1) of this section, to that person, from the commission. </section><section prefix="b">The notice, in addition to meeting the requirements of subsection (1) of this section, shall explain the basis for the commission's belief that the person to whom the notice is addressed is properly joined as a respondent. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 16, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>