<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.340</section_number><catch_line>Issuance, duration, posting of permits -- Fees -- Permits not transferable. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fee for a permit to operate a manufactured or mobile home community shall be assessed according to the following fee schedule: </section> Number of Spaces Initial Fee Maximum Fee  10 spaces or less $50.00 $50.00  11 - 50 spaces $150.00 $185.00  51 - 100 spaces $160.00 $195.00  101 - 200 spaces $170.00 $225.00  201 or more spaces $180.00 $250.00  The cabinet may, by administrative regulation, beginning July 1, 2003, increase the annual fee to operate a manufactured or mobile home community by not more than five percent (5%) per year, not to exceed the maximum fee on the fee schedule. Upon receipt of an application for a permit to operate, accompanied by a permit fee, the cabinet shall issue a permit, provided the community meets the standards and requirements of KRS 219.310 to 219.410 and the regulations adopted by the secretary. <section prefix="2">Each permit to operate, unless sooner suspended or revoked, shall expire on June 30 following its issuance, and be renewable annually, upon application and payment of a renewal fee established by the cabinet, provided the community is maintained and operated in compliance with KRS 219.310 to 219.410 and the administrative regulations adopted by the secretary. </section><section prefix="3">Each permit to operate shall be issued only for the person and premises, including number of spaces, named in the application and shall not be transferable. </section><section prefix="4">The person holding an operating permit shall post it conspicuously within the community or have it readily available for examination upon request by agents of the cabinet or prospective community occupants. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(22). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9757</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>