<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.924</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for tanning facilities. </catch_line><order_by>924</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A tanning facility shall give each customer a written statement pursuant to 21 C.F.R. 1040.20. The written statement shall include warnings stating that: <section prefix="a">Failure to use eye protection provided to the customer by the tanning facility may result in damage to the eyes; </section><section prefix="b">Overexposure to ultraviolet light causes burns; </section><section prefix="c">Repeated exposure may result in premature aging of the skin and skin cancer; </section><section prefix="d">Abnormal skin sensitivity or burning may be caused by reactions of the following to ultraviolet light: <section prefix="1">Food; </section><section prefix="2">Cosmetics; or </section><section prefix="3">Medications, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Tranquilizers; </section><section prefix="b">Diuretics; </section><section prefix="c">Antibiotics; </section><section prefix="d">High blood pressure medicines; or </section><section prefix="e">Birth control pills; </section></section></section><section prefix="e">Any person taking a prescription or over-the-counter drug should consult a physician before using a tanning device. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each tanning facility shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain the written or electronic consent forms of the parents or guardians for a period of not less than two (2) years, and make the forms available to cabinet personnel for inspection upon request; and </section><section prefix="b">Make written or electronic records showing the dates and duration of use of a tanning device at the tanning facility by children fourteen (14) years of age to eighteen (18) years of age, maintain those records for a period of not less than two (2) years, and make the records available for cabinet or health department personnel for inspection upon request. </section></section><section prefix="3">Before July 1, 2007, all indoor tanning facilities shall register with the local health department in the district or county in which the facility is operating. Registration shall be valid for one (1) year and applicants shall pay a fee of twenty dollars ($20) to the district or county health department. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9487</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>