<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.550</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 45A.550 to 45A.554 and KRS 11A.130. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>As used in KRS 45A.550 to 45A.554 and KRS 11A.130, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Privatize" means to contract out in order to procure the services of a private vendor to provide a service that is similar to, and in lieu of, a service provided by state employees of the privatizing agency; </section><section prefix="2">"Privatization contract" means an agreement or combination of a series of agreements by which a private vendor agrees to provide services that are substantially similar to, and in lieu of, services previously provided, in whole or in part, by at least ten (10) permanent, full-time, budgeted employees of the state agency. This term includes but is not limited to concession contracts. This term does not include personal service contracts as defined in KRS 45A.690, contracts entered into pursuant to KRS Chapter 176, 177, 178, 179, 180, or 181, Medicaid provider contracts, architect and engineering contracts entered into pursuant to KRS 45A.800 to 45A.835, price contracts, construction contracts, or memoranda of understanding or memoranda of agreements or program administration contracts with the Cabinet for Human Resources, including contracts for child support collections and enforcement with contracting officials as authorized by KRS 205.712; and </section><section prefix="3">"Services" shall not include administration and support functions of government. "Administration and support functions" shall include, but not be limited to, construction contracts, bond counsel and bond underwriting services, architect and engineering services, price contracts, personal service contracts, and memoranda of understanding and memoranda of agreement. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 492, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22445</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>