<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6678</section_number><catch_line>Department to appoint and assign qualified inspectors to counties. </catch_line><order_by>6678</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall appoint and assign heating, ventilation, and air conditioning inspectors to each county subject to the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689 and in numbers sufficient to implement the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be appointed as a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning inspector unless he or she has at least six (6) years' experience as a licensed heating ventilation, and air conditioning journeyman mechanic or a licensed master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor, unless he or she is a certified building inspector who has successfully passed the examinations relating to heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems. At the time of his or her appointment, the inspector shall be licensed or certified in accordance with the provisions of KRS 198B.650 to 198B.689. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 295, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 8, effective July 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 8, to be effective July 1, 2008, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be January 1, 2011. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>