<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.550</section_number><catch_line>Applicability of KRS 56.440 to 56.540 to certain projects. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in KRS 56.440 to 56.540 shall be construed to apply to the construction of roads or bridges or the acquisition of rights-of-way or real estate in connection therewith now under the jurisdiction of the Department of Highways or the Turnpike Authority of Kentucky, or for any other expenditure made from the state road fund or by said turnpike authority. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided by KRS 56.467, 162.520 to 162.620, nothing in KRS 56.440 to 56.540 shall be construed to apply to school districts, or to affect the rights, powers, and duties of the governing authorities of such districts; provided, however, that the acquisition of sites, and the acquisition, purchase, construction, leasing, and operation of television or related facilities as an aid to education or as an aid to any other proper public function, shall be deemed to be matters of statewide jurisdiction and interest, and any or all of such activities on the part of the commission shall not be deemed to constitute encroachment upon the authority of any school district. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 289, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 5, effective April 8, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 9. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 10. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 4. -- Created 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22659</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>