<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.7-240</section_number><catch_line>Corporation's acceptance of votes and persons authorized to vote shares. </catch_line><order_by>7-240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the name signed on or submitted with a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment corresponds to the name or electronic signature of a shareholder, the corporation if acting in good faith shall be entitled to accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder. For purposes of this section, a telegram or cablegram appearing to have been transmitted by the proper person, or a photographic, photostatic, or equivalent reproduction of a writing appointing a proxy may be accepted by the corporation, if acting in good faith, as a sufficient, signed appointment form. </section><section prefix="2">If the name signed on or submitted with a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment does not correspond to the name or electronic signature of its shareholder, the corporation if, acting in good faith, shall nevertheless be entitled to accept the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment and give it effect as the act of the shareholder if: <section prefix="a">The shareholder is an entity and the name signed purports to be that of an officer or agent of the entity; </section><section prefix="b">The name signed purports to be that of an administrator, executor, guardian, or conservator representing the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence of fiduciary status acceptable to the corporation has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment; </section><section prefix="c">The name signed purports to be that of a receiver or trustee in bankruptcy of the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence of this status acceptable to the corporation has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment; </section><section prefix="d">The name signed purports to be that of a pledgee, beneficial owner, or attorney-in-fact of the shareholder and, if the corporation requests, evidence acceptable to the corporation of the signatory's authority to sign for the shareholder has been presented with respect to the vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment; or </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) or more persons are the shareholder as cotenants or fiduciaries and the name signed purports to be the name of at least one (1) of the co-owners and the person signing appears to be acting on behalf of all the co-owners. </section></section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall be entitled to reject a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment if the secretary or other officer or agent authorized to tabulate votes, acting in good faith, has reasonable basis for doubt about the validity of the signature on it or about the signatory's authority to sign for the shareholder or, in the case of an electronic record, to affix the shareholder's electronic signature to the electronic record. </section><section prefix="4">The corporation and its officer or agent who accepts or rejects a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment in good faith and in accordance with the standards of this section or KRS 271B.7-220(2) shall not be liable in damages to the shareholder for the consequences of the acceptance or rejection. </section><section prefix="5">Corporate action based on the acceptance or rejection of a vote, consent, waiver, or proxy appointment under this section or KRS 271B.7-220(2) shall be valid, unless a court of competent jurisdiction determines otherwise. </section><section prefix="6">Shares standing in the name of another corporation, domestic or foreign, may be voted by either the president of such corporation or by proxy appointed by him, unless the board of directors of such other corporation authorizes another person to vote such shares. </section><section prefix="7">Shares held by an administrator, executor, guardian, or conservator may be voted by him, either in person or by proxy, without a transfer of such shares into his name. Shares standing in the name of a trustee may be voted by him, either in person or by proxy, but no trustee shall be entitled to vote shares held by him without a transfer of such shares into his name. </section><section prefix="8">Where shares are held jointly by three (3) or more fiduciaries acting under an instrument becoming effective after June 30, 1946, the will of the majority of such fiduciaries shall control the manner of voting or the giving of a proxy, unless the instrument or order appointing the fiduciaries otherwise directs. Where, in any case, fiduciaries are equally divided upon the manner of voting shares jointly held by them, any court of competent jurisdiction may, upon petition filed by any of the fiduciaries, or by any beneficiary, appoint an additional person to act with the fiduciaries in determining the manner in which the shares shall be voted upon the particular questions as to which the fiduciaries are divided. </section><section prefix="9">Shares standing in the name of a receiver may be voted by such receiver, and shares held by or under the control of a receiver may be voted by such receiver without the transfer thereof into his name if authority so to do be contained in an appropriate order of the court by which such receiver was appointed. </section><section prefix="10">A shareholder whose shares are pledged shall be entitled to vote such shares until the shares have been transferred into the name of the pledgee, and thereafter the pledgee shall be entitled to vote the share so transferred. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 60, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13364</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>