<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-707</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of pre-effective-date financing statement. </catch_line><order_by>9-707</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "pre-effective-date financing statement" means a financing statement filed before July 1, 2001. </section><section prefix="2">On or after July 1, 2001, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend information provided in, a pre-effective-date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Part 3 of this Article. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, if the law of this Commonwealth governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective-date financing statement may be amended on or after July 1, 2001, only if: <section prefix="a">The pre-effective-date financing statement and an amendment are filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501; </section><section prefix="b">An amendment is filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501 concurrently with, or after the filing in that office of, an initial financing statement that satisfies KRS 355.9-706(3); or </section><section prefix="c">An initial financing statement that provides the information as amended and satisfies KRS 355.9-706(3) is filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the law of this Commonwealth governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement may be continued only under KRS 355.9-705(4) and (6) or 355.9-706. </section><section prefix="5">Whether or not the law of this Commonwealth governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement filed in this Commonwealth may be terminated on or after July 1, 2001, by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective-date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies KRS 355.9-706(3) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in Part 3 of this article as the office in which to file a financing statement. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 153, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33867</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>