<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.375</section_number><catch_line>Director action without meeting.   </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws provide otherwise, action required or permitted by KRS 273.161 to 273.390 to be taken at a board of directors meeting may be taken without a meeting if the action is taken by all members of the board. The action shall be evidenced by one (1) or more written consents describing the action taken, signed by each director, and included in the minutes or filed with the corporate records reflecting the action taken. </section><section prefix="2">Action taken under this section shall be effective when the last director signs the consent, unless the consent specifies a different effective date. </section><section prefix="3">A consent signed under this section shall have the effect of a meeting vote and may be described as such in any document. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 67, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). This section was created in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34. At the time 2015 House Bill 440, which became 2015 Acts ch. 34, was drafted and initially reviewed, the Reviser of Statutes deleted several occurrences of the phrase, "as amended by Sections 66 through 85 of this Act." One occurrence of this phrase was inadvertently left in the bill as enacted. The Reviser of Statutes has removed this phrase under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44380</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>