<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.10-070</section_number><catch_line>Limitations on distributions.   </catch_line><order_by>10-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited cooperative association may not make a distribution if, after the distribution: <section prefix="a">The association would not be able to pay its debts as they become due in the ordinary course of the association’s activities; </section><section prefix="b">The association’s assets would be less than the sum of its total liabilities; or </section><section prefix="c">The distribution violates the organic rules. </section></section><section prefix="2">A limited cooperative association may base a determination that a distribution is not prohibited under subsection (1) of this section on financial statements prepared on the basis of accounting practices and principles that are reasonable in the circumstances or on a fair valuation or other method that is reasonable in the circumstances. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, the effect of a distribution allowed under subsection (2) of this section is measured: <section prefix="a">In the case of distribution by purchase, redemption, or other acquisition of financial rights in the limited cooperative association, as of the date money or other property is transferred or debt is incurred by the association; and </section><section prefix="b">In all other cases, as of the date: <section prefix="1">The distribution is authorized, if the payment occurs not later than one hundred twenty (120) days after that date; or </section><section prefix="2">The payment is made, if payment occurs more than one hundred twenty (120) days after the distribution is authorized. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">If indebtedness is issued as a distribution, each payment of principal or interest on the indebtedness is treated as a distribution, the effect of which is measured on the date the payment is made. </section><section prefix="5">For purposes of this section, "distribution" does not include reasonable amounts paid to a member in the ordinary course of business as payment or compensation for commodities, goods, past or present services, or reasonable payments made in the ordinary course of business under a bona fide retirement or other benefits program. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 83, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>