<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.752</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for enhanced 911 emergency service -- Privacy of information. </catch_line><order_by>752</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any DPTS located in an area that has adopted enhanced 911 emergency service shall within three (3) years of the date of its adoption, or if already adopted within three (3) years after July 15, 1998, be able to: <section prefix="a">Operate effectively within an enhanced 911 system; </section><section prefix="b">Transmit a SIN for the station that directly dials the emergency number 911 to the service supplier; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide the service supplier with the following system information that shall be updated within five (5) business days if changes occur within the system: <section prefix="1">Number of incoming trunk connections to the enhanced 911 system; and </section><section prefix="2">SIN, sublocation, such as floor or apartment number, if applicable, and street address of each station that may originate an emergency call. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">In areas where fully enhanced 911 service has been implemented, the service supplier shall, at a minimum, make the verified ANI and ALI provided by the DPTS available to a PSAP for a fully enhanced 911 call. </section><section prefix="3">In areas where fully enhanced 911 service has been implemented, the service supplier shall maintain the confidentiality and privacy of all information contained in the ALI/DBS, including any information that identifies telephone calls made from extensions on DPTS, except when the release of the information is ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="4">In areas where enhanced 911 service has been implemented, an employee of a PSAP shall not retrieve or disclose ALI information except in response to a 911 call or for the purpose of maintaining the ALI database, unless ordered by a court of competent jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23496</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>