<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.455</section_number><catch_line>Reduction of operating expenses by G&amp;T or distribution cooperative -- Effect on rates -- Authority for administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>455</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, a G&amp;T or distribution cooperative may at any time decrease regulated operating revenues by an amount to be determined solely by the cooperative utility. If the revenue reduction is allocated among and within the consumer classes on a proportional basis that will result in no change in the rate design currently in effect, the revised rates and tariffs shall be authorized and made permanent on the proposed effective date. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other statute, any revenue increase authorized by the Public Service Commission or any revenue decrease authorized in subsection (1) of this section that is to flow through the effects of an increase or decrease in wholesale rates may, at the distribution cooperative's discretion, be allocated to each class and within each tariff on a proportional basis that will result in no change in the rate design currently in effect. In the event of an increase in the wholesale rates and tariffs of the wholesale supplier by the Public Service Commission, the rates and tariffs of the distribution cooperative that have been revised on a proportional basis to result in no change in the rate design shall be authorized and shall become effective on the same date as those of the wholesale supplier. In those cases where an interim increase in the power supplier's wholesale rates is authorized, the distribution cooperative's flow through rates shall be interim. The distribution cooperative's permanent rates and tariffs shall become effective on the date that the wholesale supplier's permanent rates become effective as ordered by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Any rate increase or decrease as provided for in subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall not apply to special contracts under which the rates are subject to change or adjustment only as stipulated in the contract. </section><section prefix="4">The Public Service Commission shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to establish filing requirements and notice requirements to the commission, the Attorney General, and the public under this section. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14119</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>