<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.023</section_number><catch_line>Multiyear federal grant project agreements -- Legislative discontinuation. </catch_line><order_by>023</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Department for Local Government, the Department of Military Affairs, and the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security may enter into multiyear contracts, memoranda of agreement, memoranda of understanding, grant agreements, or any other similar documents that exceed the biennium in which they are made for projects that are funded solely through federal grant money. </section><section prefix="2">All documents entered into in accordance with subsection (1) of this section shall contain a provision stating that the contract funding may be discontinued by the General Assembly in a subsequent budget. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 34, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 28, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). A reference to the "Office of Security Coordination" in subsection (1) of this section, as amended in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 3, has been changed in codification to read the "Kentucky Office of Homeland Security" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2005-563 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 14. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22328</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>