<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.150</section_number><catch_line>Offices, positions, and places of employment included in classified service. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The classified service covered by KRS 90.110 to 90.230, and hereby placed under the jurisdiction of the board, includes all offices, positions, and places of employment, except as herein provided, in the following departments and agencies in the service of the city, to wit: the department of public safety, the department of public health, the department of public welfare, and the civil service board. If any of such offices, positions or places of employment are transferred to or combined or consolidated with any other department or agency of or serving the city, the offices, positions or places of employment shall continue to be covered by KRS 90.110 to 90.230. The classified service also includes all other offices and positions and places of employment in other departments or agencies of the city or serving the city to which the classified service may be hereafter extended pursuant to the provisions of KRS 90.210, or any other law. </section><section prefix="2">The following offices, positions, and places of employment, in the departments and agencies hereinabove specifically named, are excluded from the classified service, to wit: <section prefix="a">The director of safety and the following positions in that department, to wit: the director of safety's staff, including, but not limited to assistants and his private secretary, the chief of police and his private secretary, assistant chief of police, chief of detectives, chaplain for the police department, chief of firefighters and his private secretary, assistant chief of firefighters, chaplain for the fire department; superintendent and animal catchers, and caretakers, in the division of city pound; supervising inspector of weights and measures, and inspector of weights and measures, and deputy inspector, in the division of weights and measures. </section><section prefix="b">The director of health and the following positions in that department, to wit: private secretary, kitchen helpers, cleaners, waitresses, housemaids, janitresses, laundresses, hospital resident medical staff, university visiting staff, student nurses, bona fide university students. </section><section prefix="c">The director of welfare and the following positions in that department, to wit: private secretary, janitors, cleaners, laundresses, night watchman, truck drivers, kitchen helpers, janitresses, park laborers, bona fide university students. </section><section prefix="d">Members of the civil service board and the personnel director. </section></section><section prefix="3">The offices, positions, and places of employment excluded by paragraphs (a), (b), (c) and (d) of subsection (2) from the classified service may be placed in the classified service, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 90.210, except that the offices or positions of director of safety including his staff, chief of police and his private secretary, assistant chief of police, chief of detectives, chaplain for the police department, chief of firefighters and his private secretary, assistant chief of firefighters, chaplain for the fire department, director of health, director of welfare, and members of the civil service board shall not be placed in the classified service. </section><section prefix="4">Any classified employee in the department of safety, who accepts an appointment and qualifies as chief of police or his private secretary, assistant chief of police, chief of detectives, chaplain for the police department, chief of firefighters or his private secretary, assistant chief of firefighters, or chaplain for the fire department, shall be deemed to have received a leave of absence from the classified service for and during the incumbency of any of those respective positions. If an individual should cease to serve in any of those positions, there shall be restored to him the same classification and rank which he held prior to his appointment. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 16, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 62. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 2. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25428</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>