<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.30-120</section_number><catch_line>Powers of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>30-120</order_by><text>In order to implement the purposes of KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190, the secretary may: <section prefix="1">Cause to be conducted a program of studies, research and monitoring related to environmental noise. </section><section prefix="2">Review and comment upon environmental impact statements regarding projects having any portion of their potential impact within the borders of this state and prepared by or for a federal agency in compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 prepared by or for a state agency, as such statements pertain to noise. </section><section prefix="3">Provide technical assistance to other state agencies and to political subdivisions of this state. </section><section prefix="4">Conduct programs of public education regarding the causes and effects of noise and means for its abatement and control and encourage the participation of professional, scientific, conservation and other public interest groups in related public information efforts. </section><section prefix="5">Coordinate the programs of all state and local agencies relating to noise studies and noise control. </section><section prefix="6">Cooperate with the appropriate agencies of the United States, or of other states or any interstate agencies with respect to the control, prevention and abatement of noise. </section><section prefix="7">Receive and disburse all funds pertaining to the state's noise control program from private and public sources. </section><section prefix="8">Contract for property and services, including consulting services. </section><section prefix="9">Upon presentation of proper credentials, enter any building, property, premises, or place, except a private dwelling, and inspect any noise source for the purpose of ascertaining the compliance or noncompliance with any regulation which may have been adopted by the cabinet hereunder. If, in connection with such inspection or investigation, noise measurements, recordings or tests of any type are taken for analysis, a duplicate of the analytical report shall be furnished to the person who is suspected of causing such noise pollution or is responsible therefor. </section><section prefix="10">Have access to, and require the production of, books and papers pertinent to any matter under investigation. </section><section prefix="11">Investigate complaints, institute and conduct surveys and testing programs, conduct general ambient noise sampling programs, make observations of conditions which may or do cause or affect noise pollution, make tests or other determinations of noise sources, and assess the degree of abatement required. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, secs. 1 and 13, effective June 21, 1974; and ch. 99, sec. 6, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><former-codification> KRS 224.730. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10381</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>