<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.752</section_number><catch_line>Safety inspection required for vehicles converted to the use of natural gas after January 1, 2013 -- Certification to owner and cabinet -- Administrative regulations -- Directions to cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>752</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The owner of a motor vehicle that has been converted after January 1, 2013, to operate on either CNG or LNG alone or in a bi-fuel system shall have the motor vehicle inspected to ascertain compliance with relevant federal safety standards covering the use of these fuels. The safety inspection shall occur: <section prefix="a">At the time of the conversion; </section><section prefix="b">Every three (3) years or thirty-six thousand (36,000) miles after the conversion, whichever occurs first; and </section><section prefix="c">Following any collision in which any vehicle involved is traveling at five (5) miles per hour or greater. </section></section><section prefix="2">The owner of a motor vehicle originally designed and manufactured to use compressed or liquid natural gas as a fuel shall have it inspected for safety following any collision in which any vehicle involved is traveling at five (5) miles per hour or greater. </section><section prefix="3">A person who performs the conversion of a motor vehicle to operate on either CNG or LNG alone or in a bi-fuel system shall certify to the owner of the motor vehicle and the cabinet that the conversion does not tamper with, circumvent, or otherwise affect any existing motor vehicle emissions or diagnostic systems, except as necessary to complete the conversion. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the provisions of this section to: <section prefix="a">Qualify persons to perform safety inspections on converted motor vehicles; </section><section prefix="b">Modify or adopt for state use any federal safety standards, if necessary; and </section><section prefix="c">Identify motor vehicles that have been converted to operate on clean transportation fuels and ensure compliance with the safety, emissions, and efficiency requirements of this section and applicable administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="5">In promulgating administrative regulations, the cabinet shall consider: <section prefix="a">Directing that inspections use equipment which is widely available in the state; and </section><section prefix="b">Creating a regulatory framework that encourages the conversion and sale of motor vehicles that operate on CNG, LNG, or a bi-fuel system. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42403</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>