<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.521</section_number><catch_line>Labeling required -- Content of label -- Commercial feed -- Customer-formula feed. </catch_line><order_by>521</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A commercial feed, except a customer-formula feed, shall be accompanied by a label bearing the following information: <section prefix="a">The product name and the brand name, if any, under which the commercial feed is distributed; </section><section prefix="b">The guaranteed analysis stated in terms the director by administrative regulation determines are required to advise the user of the composition of the feed or to support claims made in the labeling. In all cases the substances or elements shall be determinable by laboratory methods such as the methods published by the AOAC International; </section><section prefix="c">The common or usual name of each ingredient used in the manufacture of the commercial feed, unless the director by administrative regulation permits the use of a collective term for a group of ingredients which perform a similar function. The director may exempt such commercial feeds, or any group thereof, from this requirement of an ingredient statement if he finds that the statement is not required in the interest of consumers; </section><section prefix="d">The name and principal mailing address of the manufacturer or the person responsible for distributing the commercial feed; </section><section prefix="e">Adequate directions for use for all commercial feeds containing drugs and for other feeds as the director may require by administrative regulation as necessary for their safe and effective use; </section><section prefix="f">Warning or caution statements the director by administrative regulation determines are necessary for the safe and effective use of the commercial feed; and </section><section prefix="g">A quantity statement of net content stated in accordance with the Federal Fair Packaging and Labeling Act, 15 U.S.C. secs. 1451 et seq., and stipulated by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">A customer-formula feed shall be accompanied by a label, invoice, delivery slip, or other shipping document, bearing the following information: <section prefix="a">Name and address of the manufacturer; </section><section prefix="b">Name and address of the purchaser; </section><section prefix="c">Date of delivery; </section><section prefix="d">The product name and brand name, if any, and the net weight of each registered commercial feed used in the mixture, and the net weight of each other ingredient used; </section><section prefix="e">Adequate directions for use for all customer-formula feeds containing drugs and for other feeds as the director may require by administrative regulation as necessary for their safe and effective use; and </section><section prefix="f">Warning or caution statements the director by administrative regulation determines are necessary for the safe and effective use of the customer-formula feed. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12171</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>