<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.260</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations to make buildings accessible to and usable by persons with a disability -- Compliance required. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction shall promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, applicable to all new and altered buildings which shall establish requirements for making all buildings accessible to and usable by persons with a disability. Such regulations shall require, as a minimum, that all buildings, with the exception of one (1) and two (2) family dwellings, multifamily projects consisting of twenty-four (24) living units or less, church buildings, and historical structures whose historic significance would be threatened or destroyed, be accessible to persons with a disability. If multifamily projects are not exempt hereunder, only one (1) out of every twenty-five (25) units must be accessible to persons with a disability. The administrative regulations shall be incorporated into the Kentucky Building Code. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations promulgated by the board shall be consistent with the Federal 1991 Americans with Disabilities Act and the American Disabilities Act Guidelines. </section><section prefix="3">No building permit or other official authorization for construction of any building shall be valid unless the plans and specifications are in compliance with the accessibility requirements as stated in the Kentucky Building Code. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 51, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 405 and 416 which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 416, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6983</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>