<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-230</section_number><catch_line>Pre-existing condition exclusion in individual market -- Prohibition against use of genetic information -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>17A-230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A health insurer offering individual health benefit plan coverage in the individual market in the Commonwealth shall not impose any pre-existing conditions exclusions as to any eligible individual. </section><section prefix="2">Each health insurer offering individual health benefit plan coverage in the individual market in the Commonwealth that chooses to impose a pre-existing conditions exclusion on individuals who do not meet the definition of eligible individual shall comply with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-220, which establishes standards and requirements for pre-existing conditions exclusions for group health plans, including crediting previous coverage, and certification of coverage. Pregnancy may be considered to be a pre-existing condition. </section><section prefix="3">Genetic information shall not be treated as a pre-existing condition in the absence of a diagnosis of the condition related to the information. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Insurance shall promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and KRS 304.17A-220. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1219, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 5, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17396</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>