<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.290</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against termination of certain Transportation Cabinet employees for failure to hold commercial driver's license -- Exception -- Requirement for employment. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall not terminate the services of any employee in a job classification which requires a valid commercial driver's license if: <section prefix="a">The employee has never held an operator's license; </section><section prefix="b">The employee is not eligible for a medical waiver to operate a commercial vehicle; </section><section prefix="c">The employee's driving record as of March 31, 1992, precludes the issuance of a commercial driver's license; </section><section prefix="d">The employee's job description, as of April 1, 1992, does not require a commercial driver's license; </section><section prefix="e">The employee retires by December 31, 1992. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet may terminate the employment of any employee whose job classification requires a commercial driver's license as of April 1, 1992, if the employee holds a valid Kentucky driver's license, but has failed to apply for a commercial driver's license and refuses to make an effort to take the necessary tests to obtain a commercial driver's license. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall not require a person to possess a commercial driver's license at the time of employment, but any employee who is required to obtain a commercial driver's license as a requirement for a job classification shall obtain the license prior to the expiration of the employee's six (6) month probationary period. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 1, effective April 10, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14491</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>