<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-305</section_number><catch_line>Indemnity payable for services performed by optometrists, osteopaths, physicians, chiropractors, or podiatrists. </catch_line><order_by>17-305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any policy of health insurance issued in this state provides for reimbursement for any service which is within the lawful scope of practice of an optometrist duly licensed as provided in KRS Chapter 320, the insured or other person entitled to benefits under such policy shall be entitled to reimbursement for such services, whether such services are performed by a duly licensed physician, osteopath, or optometrist, notwithstanding any provision contained in such policy, or if the policy so provides, payment may be made directly to the provider of the services. </section><section prefix="2">When any policy of health insurance issued in this state provides for reimbursement for any service which is within the lawful scope of practice of a chiropractor duly licensed under KRS Chapter 312, the insured or other person entitled to benefits under such policy shall be entitled to reimbursement for such services, whether such services are performed by a duly licensed physician, osteopath or chiropractor, notwithstanding any provision contained in such policy; or if the policy so provides, payment may be made directly to the provider of the services. </section><section prefix="3">When any policy of health insurance issued in this state provides for reimbursement for any service which is within the lawful scope of practice of a podiatrist duly licensed under KRS Chapter 311, the insured or other person entitled to benefits under that policy shall be entitled to reimbursement for those services, whether those services are performed by a duly licensed physician, osteopath, chiropractor, or podiatrist, notwithstanding any provision contained in the policy, or if the policy so provides, payment may be made directly to the provider of the services. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 466, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 399, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>