<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.505</section_number><catch_line>Exemption from matriculation or tuition fee of dependents, widow, or widower of members of the Armed Forces or of members of the National Guard killed while in service or having died as a result of service-connected disability. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not be required to pay any matriculation or tuition fees upon admission to any state-supported university, junior college, or vocational training institution if the person's deceased parent or stepparent, or if the person's deceased spouse if the person has not remarried, was a resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon joining the Kentucky National Guard or upon entering military service and: <section prefix="a">Was killed while serving in state active duty, active duty for training, or inactive duty training with the Kentucky National Guard, or while on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States, during a national emergency, or wars declared by Congress, or actions of the United Nations, or was killed by hostile fire while on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States or the Kentucky National Guard; or </section><section prefix="b">Died as a result of a service-connected disability acquired while serving in state active duty, active duty for training, or inactive duty training with the Kentucky National Guard or Reserve Component, or while on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States, during a national emergency, or wars declared by Congress, or actions of the United Nations. </section></section><section prefix="2">In order to obtain the benefits conferred by subsection (1), the parent-child relationship must be shown by birth certificate, adoption papers, marriage certificate, or other documentary evidence. A stepchild must have been a member of the veteran's household at the time of the veteran's death. The spousal relationship must be shown by a marriage certificate or other documentary evidence. The parent's or spouse's service and the cause of death must be evidenced by certification from the records of the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs or the Veterans Administration Records, or the Department of Defense of the United States. In the event one so admitted to a state-supported university, junior college, or vocational training institution under the provisions of this section shall have obtained a cash scholarship paid or payable to the institution, from whatever source, the amount of the scholarship shall be applied to the credit of the applicant in the payment of incidental expenses of attendance at the institution, and any balance, if the terms of the scholarship permit, shall be returned to the applicant. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 1; and ch. 207, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4305</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>