<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.179</section_number><catch_line>When public alert may be issued -- Duties of requesting agency, department, and all law enforcement agencies in Kentucky.   </catch_line><order_by>179</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No public alert using the Kentucky Blue Alert System shall be issued unless requested by a law enforcement agency and, upon consultation with that agency, the department determines: <section prefix="a">That a peace officer has been killed, seriously injured, or is missing in the line of duty; </section><section prefix="b">That public notification is the most appropriate method of locating the officer or identifying and locating a suspected offender who poses an imminent threat to the public or other law enforcement personnel; </section><section prefix="c">That there is sufficient information available relating to the officer's last known location and the physical description of any suspected offender or vehicle involved that could be broadcast to assist in locating the officer or suspected offender; and </section><section prefix="d">The geographic area in which the notification shall be made. </section></section><section prefix="2">The requesting agency shall provide the information required by administrative regulation to the Department of Kentucky State Police prior to activation of the Kentucky Blue Alert System. </section><section prefix="3">If it is determined by the department that public notification shall be initiated, the department shall notify the public and private agencies and organizations that will provide the notification and provide those agencies and organizations with the information that the department deems necessary. </section><section prefix="4">All law enforcement agencies in the Commonwealth shall cooperate with the department in the provision and dissemination of information regarding any peace officer who has been killed, seriously injured, or is missing in the line of duty. </section><section prefix="5">No law enforcement agency, other than the department, shall activate the Kentucky Blue Alert System without the authority of the department. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 3, provides that the Act, which created this statute and KRS 16.177, shall be known as the "Trooper Jonathan K. Leonard Kentucky Blue Alert System Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40566</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>