<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.068</section_number><catch_line>Duties of department if child may be victim of human trafficking -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>068</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If, during the course of screening, assessing, or providing services to a child committed to or in the custody of the department, there is reasonable cause to believe that the child is a victim of human trafficking as defined in KRS 529.010, the department shall: <section prefix="a">File a report with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services pursuant to KRS 620.030; </section><section prefix="b">Notify the child's attorney that the child may be a victim of human trafficking; and </section><section prefix="c">If the child does not pose a threat to public safety, petition the court to transfer custody from the department to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></section><section prefix="2">After consultation with agencies serving victims of human trafficking, the department shall promulgate administrative regulations for the treatment of child victims of human trafficking who are committed to or in the custody of the department and pose a threat to public safety but do not qualify to be in the custody of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services under subsection (1)(c) of this section. The administrative regulations shall include provisions for appropriate screening, assessment, placement, treatment, and services for these children, the training of staff, and collaboration with service providers. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41835</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>