<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5304Duties</section_number><catch_line>of initiating tribunal.   </catch_line><order_by>5304Duties</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the filing of a petition authorized by KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902, an initiating tribunal of this state shall forward the petition and its accompanying documents: <section prefix="a">To the responding tribunal or appropriate support enforcement agency in the responding state; or </section><section prefix="b">If the identity of the responding tribunal is unknown, to the state information agency of the responding state with a request that they be forwarded to the appropriate tribunal and that receipt be acknowledged. </section></section><section prefix="2">If requested by the responding tribunal, a tribunal of this state shall issue a certificate or other document and make findings required by law of the responding state. If the responding tribunal is in a foreign country, upon request the tribunal of this state shall specify the amount of support sought, convert that amount into the equivalent amount in the foreign currency under applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported, and provide other documents necessary to satisfy the requirements of the responding foreign tribunal. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 4, effective March 23, 1998.-- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 28, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44093</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>