<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.793</section_number><catch_line>Quarterly status reports on incomplete capital projects to Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee. </catch_line><order_by>793</order_by><text>The Finance and Administration Cabinet and any institution that manages its own capital construction under KRS 164A.580 shall provide to the committee at its January, April, July, and October regular meetings a status report of any capital project, excluding items of equipment, not yet completed which received line item authorization by the Kentucky General Assembly or was authorized pursuant to KRS 45.760(7). The Capital Projects and Bond Oversight Committee shall prescribe data elements to be included in the quarterly status reports. For each capital project, the status report shall include but not be limited to the: <section prefix="1">Project title; </section><section prefix="2">County or counties in which the project is located; </section><section prefix="3">Current phase of the project; </section><section prefix="4">Estimated completion date of the project; </section><section prefix="5">Explanation of any delay or major change in the project, including deletion or modification of project components; and </section><section prefix="6">Any other information that the committee requests. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 32, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 1, (5) at 655. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>