<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.674</section_number><catch_line>Perinatal Advisory Committee -- Membership -- Meetings -- Report.   </catch_line><order_by>674</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The secretary shall appoint the Perinatal Advisory Committee to make recommendations for the improvement of the following statewide health status indicators that relate to pregnancy and perinatal care: <section prefix="1">Infant mortality; </section><section prefix="2">Preterm birth; </section><section prefix="3">Substance abuse during pregnancy; </section><section prefix="4">Neonatal withdrawal syndrome, also called neonatal abstinence syndrome (NAS); and </section><section prefix="5">Maternal mortality. </section></section><section prefix="b">The committee may make recommendations on evidence-based guidelines and programs to improve the outcomes of pregnancies, including ways to improve coordination of existing programs operated by the cabinet and private organizations. </section></section><section prefix="2">The advisory committee shall be attached to the cabinet for administrative purposes and be composed of the following members: <section prefix="a">The director of the Division of Maternal and Child Health, Department for Public Health, who shall serve as chair of the advisory committee; </section><section prefix="b">The director of the Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, University of Kentucky College of Medicine; </section><section prefix="c">The director of the Division of Maternal-Fetal Medicine, University of Louisville School of Medicine; </section><section prefix="d">The director of a maternal-fetal medicine program from a pediatric teaching hospital with a Level III NICU that has a minimum of thirty (30) beds, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="e">The director of the Division of Neonatology, University of Kentucky College of Medicine; </section><section prefix="f">The director of the Division of Neonatology, University of Louisville School of Medicine; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) practicing obstetrician from rural practice in a hospital with a Level I nursery, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) practicing obstetrician from rural practice in a hospital with a Level II neonatal intensive care unit (NICU), to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) practicing pediatrician from rural practice in a hospital with a Level I nursery, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) practicing pediatrician or one (1) practicing neonatologist from rural practice in a hospital with a Level II NICU, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) practicing pediatrician or one (1) practicing neonatologist from a non-university urban practice hospital with a Level II NICU, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) practicing pediatrician or one (1) practicing neonatologist from a pediatric teaching hospital with a Level III NICU that has a minimum of thirty (30) beds, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="m">The president of the Kentucky Perinatal Association or designee; </section><section prefix="n">The president of the Kentucky Academy of Family Practice or designee; </section><section prefix="o">The president of the Kentucky Chapter of the American Academy of Pediatrics or designee; </section><section prefix="p">The president of the Kentucky Section of the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists or designee; </section><section prefix="q">The president of the Kentucky Chapter of the Association of Women’s Health, Obstetric, and Neonatal Nurses or designee; </section><section prefix="r">The chair of the Kentucky Medical Association’s Committee on Maternal and Neonatal Health or designee; </section><section prefix="s">The chair of the Kentucky Medical Association’s Committee on Maternal Mortality or designee; </section><section prefix="t">One (1) board-certified pediatric surgeon, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="u">One (1) board-certified pediatrician specializing in medical genetics, to be selected by the secretary; </section><section prefix="v">One (1) perinatal social worker, to be selected by the secretary; and </section><section prefix="w">One (1) representative from a non-university hospital with a Level II or a Level III NICU, selected by the secretary. </section></section><section prefix="3">Other subject matter experts may be represented as members of the advisory committee at the discretion of the secretary. </section><section prefix="4">The advisory committee shall meet at least quarterly and shall hold its first meeting no later than thirty (30) days after June 25, 2013. </section><section prefix="5">The advisory committee shall submit an annual report of its activities and recommendations to the secretary and the commissioner. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>