<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.047</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of firearms or ammunition owned by state agency -- Disposition of proceeds upon sale -- Restriction on purchase of body armor for service animal.   </catch_line><order_by>047</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When an agency of Kentucky state government or a public university safety and security department organized pursuant to KRS 164.950 disposes of firearms or ammunition owned by that agency, the disposition shall be by: <section prefix="a">Public auction to persons who are eligible under federal law to purchase the type of firearm or ammunition; </section><section prefix="b">Trade to the federally licensed firearms dealer providing new firearms or ammunition to the agency; </section><section prefix="c">Transfer to another government agency or government-operated museum in Kentucky for official use or display; or </section><section prefix="d">Sale to a current or retiring employee as authorized by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the firearms or ammunition are sold, the proceeds of the sale shall be utilized solely for the purchase of body armor for officers meeting or exceeding National Institute of Justice standards, firearms, ammunition, or range facilities, or a combination thereof, by the agency of government. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to the Department of Fish and Wildlife. </section><section prefix="3">Body armor purchased for a service animal shall be purchased only for an animal owned by the law enforcement agency specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 129, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44238</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>