<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-130</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement. </catch_line><order_by>2-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner may invoke the aid of the courts through injunction or other proper process, mandatory or otherwise, to enjoin any existing or threatened violation of any provision of this code, or to enforce any proper order made by him or her or action taken by him or her. </section><section prefix="2">If the commissioner has reason to believe that any person has violated any provision of this code, or other law applicable to insurance operations, for which criminal prosecution is provided and in his or her opinion would be in order, the commissioner shall give the information relative thereto to the appropriate Commonwealth attorney or to the Attorney General. The Commonwealth attorney or Attorney General shall promptly institute such action or proceedings against such person as in his or her opinion the information may require or justify. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever the commissioner may deem it necessary, he or she may employ counsel, or call upon the Attorney General of this state for legal counsel and such assistance as may be necessary. </section><section prefix="4">The Attorney General upon request of the commissioner is authorized to proceed in the courts of any other state or in any federal court or agency to enforce an order or decision in any court proceeding or in any administrative proceeding before the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 928, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 13, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>