<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.672</section_number><catch_line>Rights of disabled child, parent, or guardian being served by the system. </catch_line><order_by>672</order_by><text>Kentucky's participation in Part C of the Federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act requires that an infant or toddler with a disability who is being served by the Kentucky Early Intervention System and the parent or guardian of that child shall have the following rights: <section prefix="1">To a timely, multidisciplinary evaluation and assessment; </section><section prefix="2">To appropriate early intervention services for children and families; </section><section prefix="3">To refuse evaluation, assessment, or services; </section><section prefix="4">To written notice before a change is made in the identification, evaluation, or placement of the child, or in the provision of services to the child or family; </section><section prefix="5">To written notice before a refusal of services is made in the identification, evaluation, or placement of the child, or in the provision of services to the child or family; </section><section prefix="6">To confidentiality of personally identifiable information, including the right of the parent or guardian to be provided written notice of, and written consent to, the exchange of information among agencies, consistent with federal and state laws; </section><section prefix="7">To determine if any family member will accept or decline an early intervention service under KRS 200.650 to 200.676, in accordance with state law, without jeopardizing other early intervention services under KRS 200.650 to 200.676; </section><section prefix="8">To review all records and, if appropriate, to amend records; </section><section prefix="9">To bring an advocate or attorney into any and all dealings with the early intervention system; and </section><section prefix="10">To administrative process and judicial review in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B to resolve complaints. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, secs. 92 and 95, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  This statute was amended by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, secs. 92 and 95, which are in conflict. Section 95 prevails as the last section in order of position. See Home Folks Mobile Homes, Inc. v. Revenue Cabinet, Ky. App., 700 S.W. 2d 75 (1985). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7332</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>