<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.035</section_number><catch_line>Rights of hospitalized child. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A child hospitalized under this chapter shall have the following rights: <section prefix="a">The right to due process, as defined in KRS 645.170, within the hospital; </section><section prefix="b">The right to convalescent leave status if appropriate; </section><section prefix="c">The right to be adequately informed as to his individual treatment program; </section><section prefix="d">The right to assist in the planning of his treatment program; </section><section prefix="e">The right to refuse treatment subject to the provisions of KRS 645.170; </section><section prefix="f">The right to maintain and use personal possessions and money; </section><section prefix="g">The right to receive visitors subject to the provisions of KRS 645.170; </section><section prefix="h">The right to receive payment for work performed on behalf of the hospital; </section><section prefix="i">The right to refuse intrusive treatment subject to the provisions of KRS 645.170; </section><section prefix="j">The right to be free from unreasonable use of seclusion and restraint subject to the provisions of KRS 645.170; </section><section prefix="k">The right to seek relief from participating in his treatment plan; and </section><section prefix="l">The right not to be transferred from one (1) facility to another, subject to the provisions of KRS 645.170. </section></section><section prefix="2">A child who is involuntarily hospitalized under this chapter shall have a right to a complete record of the court proceedings without charge for appeal purposes, the right to appeal without bond or filing fee, and the right of habeas corpus. </section><section prefix="3">Any child who believes that any right guaranteed by this chapter has been violated shall have the right to contact the court-designated worker in the county where the hospital is located to communicate with the worker and the court. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 111, effective April 10, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20325</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>