<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.332</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations -- Purpose -- Construction with other laws. </catch_line><order_by>332</order_by><text>The General Assembly finds, determines, and declares as follows: <section prefix="1">Healthy, sustainable forests that are ecologically sound provide economic opportunities and benefit the overall quality of life for all Kentuckians; </section><section prefix="2">High quality forests provide clean air and water and biodiversity; </section><section prefix="3">A diverse forest economy must include forest product industries, recreation, and tourism; </section><section prefix="4">Timber harvesting operations must be conducted in an ecologically sound manner; </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky must promote the stewardship of its public and private forest lands while recognizing the rights and responsibilities of private landowners; </section><section prefix="6">Comprehensive continuous forest inventories are needed to provide information to make decisions to meet present and future needs; </section><section prefix="7">Increased awareness of the economic, social, and ecological importance of Kentucky's forests is needed to: <section prefix="a">Educate the public and industry in order to make wise decisions for the future of the forest resource; and </section><section prefix="b">Recognize and respond to threats to the forest resource; </section></section><section prefix="8">It is the purpose of KRS 149.330 to 149.355 to provide private landowners and loggers with education, technical assistance, and incentives that encourage them to manage their properties and carry out timber harvesting operations that will assure sustainable forests in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="9">KRS 149.330 to 149.355 shall not be construed as affecting the requirements of any other laws of the Commonwealth relating to environmental protection, including water quality or forestry. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 555, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1879</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>