<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.090Requirements</section_number><catch_line>for cosmetology schools.   </catch_line><order_by>090Requirements</order_by><text>No license shall be renewed or issued by the cosmetologist board to any cosmetology school unless such school provides: <section prefix="1">The name of the proposed school; </section><section prefix="2">A statement that the proposed school is authorized to operate educational programs beyond secondary education; </section><section prefix="3">As a prerequisite of graduation, a prescribed course of instruction of not less than eighteen hundred (1,800) hours in the case of a cosmetology school to be given within an uninterrupted period with not more than eight (8) hours nor less than four </section><section prefix="4">hours of instruction a day, exclusive of Sundays; except that in the state area </section>vocational schools the eighteen hundred (1,800) hours of instruction may be offered according to the schedule for other vocational classes in the school; (4) Courses of instruction in histology of the hair, skin, nails, muscles, and nerves of the face and neck; elementary chemistry with emphasis on sterilization and antiseptics, diseases of the skin, hair, and glands, and massaging and manipulating of the muscles of the upper body; cutting, shaving, arranging, dressing, coloring, bleaching, and tinting the hair and such other courses as may be prescribed by administrative regulation of the board; <section prefix="5">Such facilities, equipment, materials, and qualified instructors and apprentice instructors as may be required by administrative regulations of the board adopted pursuant to this chapter, but in no event shall any cosmetology school have fewer than one (1) licensed instructor per twenty (20) students present for instruction; </section><section prefix="6">The fee for the initial license of a cosmetology school shall be one thousand dollars ($1,000); </section><section prefix="7">No cosmetology school, after being licensed for the first time, shall serve the public until three hundred (300) hours of instruction has been taught; and </section><section prefix="8">In compliance with KRS 317A.070, the board may revoke or suspend any license issued by it if, in the judgment of the board, the school is not following the requirements as set out in this chapter or such school does not comply with the administrative regulations promulgated by the board in order to regulate the conduct of the school and in order to supervise the proper education of the students. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch.188, sec. 259; and ch. 202, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44604</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>