<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.370</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 371.375 to 371.385. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>As used in KRS 371.375 to 371.385, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissions" means compensation accruing to a sales representative for payment by a principal, the rate of which is expressed as a percentage of the amount of orders or sales or as a specified amount per order or per sale. </section><section prefix="2">"Person" means an individual, corporation, partnership, association, estate, or trust. </section><section prefix="3">"Principal" means a person who does not have a permanent or fixed place of business in this state and who: <section prefix="a">Manufactures, produces, imports, or distributes a tangible product for wholesale; </section><section prefix="b">Contracts with a sales representative to solicit orders for the product; and </section><section prefix="c">Compensates the sales representative, in whole or in part, by commission. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Sales representative" means a person who: <section prefix="a">Contracts with a principal to solicit wholesale orders; </section><section prefix="b">Is compensated, in whole or in part, by commission; </section><section prefix="c">Does not place orders or purchase for his own account or for resale; and </section><section prefix="d">Does not sell or take orders for the sale of products to the ultimate consumer. </section></section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35253</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>