<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.245</section_number><catch_line>Salary for jailer who operates full-service jail -- Limitation. </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The jailer who operates a full-service jail shall receive a monthly salary pursuant to any salary schedule in KRS Chapter 64 applicable to jailers operating a full service jail from the county jail operating budget. </section><section prefix="2">No jailer holding office in the Commonwealth on or after January 6, 1999, shall receive an annual salary of less than twenty thousand dollars ($20,000). </section><section prefix="3">The salaries of jailers who are not subject to any salary schedule in KRS Chapter 64 may be set at a higher level if the salary does not exceed the constitutional salary limit applicable to jailers. These jailers' salaries shall at least equal the prior year's level and may be adjusted by the fiscal court for the change in the prior year's consumer price index according to the provisions of KRS 64.527. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 595, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 610, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.009.</former-codification><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 595 and 610. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 595, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19337</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>