<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.007</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>007</order_by><text>As used in KRS Chapter 158 unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Advanced placement" or "AP" means a college-level course that incorporates all topics and instructional strategies specified by the College Board on its standard syllabus for a given subject area and is licensed by the College Board. </section><section prefix="2">"Advanced science and mathematics" means Advanced Placement or AP biology, calculus, chemistry, computer science, environmental science, and physics, and International Baccalaureate or IB biology, chemistry, computer science, environmental systems, mathematical studies, further mathematics, and physics. </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Education. </section><section prefix="4">"College Board Advanced Placement examination" means the advanced placement test administered by the College Entrance Examination Board. </section><section prefix="5">"College Board" means the College Entrance Examination Board, a national nonprofit association that provides college admission guidance and advanced placement examinations. </section><section prefix="6">"Core curriculum" means at least one (1) course in science, one (1) course in mathematics, and at least one (1) course in two (2) of the following subject areas: English, social studies, foreign language, and the arts. </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Kentucky Department of Education. </section><section prefix="8">"Dual credit" means a college-level course of study developed in accordance with KRS 164.098 in which a high school student receives credit from both the high school and postsecondary institution in which the student is enrolled upon completion of a single class or designated program of study. </section><section prefix="9">"Dual enrollment" means a college-level course of study developed in accordance with KRS 164.098 in which a student is enrolled in a high school and postsecondary institution simultaneously. </section><section prefix="10">"International Baccalaureate" or "IB" means the International Baccalaureate Organization's Diploma Programme, a comprehensive two (2) year program designed for highly motivated students. </section><section prefix="11">"Kentucky Virtual High School" means secondary-level instructional programs or courses offered by the Kentucky Department of Education through the Internet and other on-line, computer-based methods. </section><section prefix="12">"Kentucky Virtual University" means a college-level instructional program offered by the Council on Postsecondary Education through the Internet or other on-line, computer-based methods. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>