<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-300</section_number><catch_line>Provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network -- Qualifications -- Fees -- Network subject to provisions of other subtitles. </catch_line><order_by>17A-300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network may be created by health care providers for the purpose of providing health care services. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall in this Commonwealth be, act as, or hold itself out as a provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network unless it holds a certificate of filing from the commissioner. Each provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network that seeks to offer services shall first be certified by the department. </section><section prefix="3">To qualify as a provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network, an applicant shall submit information acceptable to the department to satisfactorily demonstrate that the provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network: <section prefix="a">Is licensed and in good standing with the licensure boards for participating providers; </section><section prefix="b">Has demonstrated the capacity to administer the health plans it is offering; </section><section prefix="c">Has the ability, experience, and structure to arrange for the appropriate level and type of health care services; </section><section prefix="d">Has the ability, policies, and procedures to conduct utilization management activities; </section><section prefix="e">Has the ability to achieve, monitor, and evaluate the quality and cost effectiveness of care provided by its provider network; </section><section prefix="f">Is financially solvent; </section><section prefix="g">Has the ability to assure enrollees adequate access to providers, including geographic availability and adequate numbers and types; </section><section prefix="h">Has the ability and procedures to monitor access to its provider network; </section><section prefix="i">Has a satisfactory grievance procedure and the ability to respond to enrollees' inquiries and complaints; </section><section prefix="j">Does not limit the participation of any health care provider in its provider network in another provider network; </section><section prefix="k">Has the ability and policies that allow patients to receive care in the most appropriate, least restrictive setting; </section><section prefix="l">Does not discriminate in enrolling members; </section><section prefix="m">Participates in coordination of benefits; </section><section prefix="n">Uses standardized electronic claims and billing processes and formats; and </section><section prefix="o">Discloses to the cooperative reimbursement arrangements with providers. </section></section><section prefix="4">Fees for the following services shall be paid to the commissioner by every provider-sponsored integrated health delivery network, and the fees shall be the same as those for insurers as specified in Subtitle 4 of this chapter: <section prefix="a">For filing an application for a certificate of filing or amendment thereto; </section><section prefix="b">For filing an annual statement; and </section><section prefix="c">For other services deemed necessary by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="5">Provider-sponsored integrated health delivery networks shall be subject to the provisions of this subtitle, and to the following provisions of this chapter, to the extent applicable and not in conflict with the expressed provisions of this subtitle: <section prefix="a">Subtitle 1 -- Scope of Code; </section><section prefix="b">Subtitle 2 -- Commissioner of the Department of Insurance; </section><section prefix="c">Subtitle 3 -- Authorization of Insurers and General Requirements; </section><section prefix="d">Subtitle 4 -- Fees and Taxes; </section><section prefix="e">Subtitle 5 -- Kinds of Insurance--Limits of Risk--Reinsurance; </section><section prefix="f">Subtitle 6 -- Assets and Liabilities; </section><section prefix="g">Subtitle 7 -- Investments; </section><section prefix="h">Subtitle 8 -- Administration of Deposits; </section><section prefix="i">Subtitle 9 -- Agents, Consultants, Solicitors, and Adjusters; </section><section prefix="j">Subtitle 12 -- Trade Practices and Frauds; </section><section prefix="k">Subtitle 14 -- KRS 304.14-120 to 304.14-130 and 304.14-500 to 304.14-560; </section><section prefix="l">Subtitle 25 -- Continuity of Management; </section><section prefix="m">Subtitle 33 -- Insurers Rehabilitation and Liquidation; </section><section prefix="n">Subtitle 37 -- Insurance Holding Company Systems; and </section><section prefix="o">Subtitle 99 -- Penalties. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1222, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>