<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.260</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Medical Advisory Panel -- Membership -- Compensation -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Medical Advisory Panel is hereby created. </section><section prefix="2">The panel shall consist of three (3) to five (5) physicians appointed by the chair of the Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority with the consent of the full authority. Each physician shall be: <section prefix="a">Licensed to practice medicine in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="b">Knowledgeable regarding the kinds and types of injuries or conditions likely to be the result of boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, and wrestling. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each member of the panel shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each meeting of the panel and for each day or portion thereof that the member is engaged in carrying out the duties of the panel. </section><section prefix="4">The panel shall advise the Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority regarding: <section prefix="a">Health and safety issues and policy relating to the sports regulated by the authority; and </section><section prefix="b">The fitness of an individual referred to the panel for review to compete in the regulated sports. </section></section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10808</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>