<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.552</section_number><catch_line>Early termination of probation -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>552</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations in consultation with the Supreme Court to establish procedures to: <section prefix="a">Recommend to the court the early termination of probation for a supervised individual who has: <section prefix="1">Fulfilled the terms of his or her case plan; </section><section prefix="2">No new arrests; </section><section prefix="3">Demonstrated a reduction in criminal risk factors upon reassessment; and </section><section prefix="4">Fulfilled all restitution and substantially fulfilled all other financial obligations to the court; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Review the compliance of the supervised individual on probation with the requirements in paragraph (a) of this subsection. This review for compliance shall occur at the same time as the regular reassessment pursuant to KRS 439.3101 and 439.3104. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall petition the court with a request for early termination if the supervised individual on probation has: <section prefix="a">Complied with the requirements in subsection (1)(a) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Completed at least eighteen (18) months of his or her term of supervision; and </section><section prefix="c">Not violated the terms of his or her supervision in the last twelve (12) months. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department may establish by administrative regulation conditions for overriding the recommendation of early termination of probation. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 57, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39574</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>