<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.010Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140.   </catch_line><order_by>010Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Authorized local licensing program" means any city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government electrician and electrical contractor licensing program established by local ordinance for the purpose of licensing electrical workers. "Authorized local licensing program" shall include a licensing program established through a cooperative agreement between two (2) or more counties; </section><section prefix="2">"Committee" means the Electrical Advisory Committee as described in KRS 227.530; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="4">"Electrical" pertains to the installation, alteration, or repair of wires and conduits for the purpose of transmitting electricity, and the installation of fixtures and equipment in connection therewith; </section><section prefix="5">"Electrical contractor" means any licensed individual, partnership, or corporation that is licensed to engage in, offers to engage in, or advertises or holds itself out to be qualified to engage in designing, planning, superintending, contracting of, or assuming responsibility for the installation, alteration, or repair of any electrical system used for the purpose of furnishing heat, light, or power, and employs electrical workers to engage in this practice. If the electrical contractor is not a master electrician, the electrical contractor shall employ at least one (1) full-time master electrician; however, no master electrician shall act in this capacity for more than one (1) electrical contractor; </section><section prefix="6">"Electrical system" means any electrical work subject to standards provided within the National Electrical Code as adopted in the Uniform State Building Code, as promulgated by the Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction; </section><section prefix="7">"Electrician" means any person licensed by the department who is employed by an electrical contractor and is engaged in the construction, alteration, or repair of any electrical system used for the purpose of furnishing heat, light, or power; </section><section prefix="8">"Maintenance worker or maintenance engineer" means a person who is a regular, bona fide employee or agent of a property owner, property lessor, property management company, or firm that is not in the electrical business but has jurisdiction over the property where the routine maintenance of electrical systems is being performed; </section><section prefix="9">"Master electrician" means any individual licensed to engage in, and assume responsible charge, supervision, or direction of an electrician engaged in the construction, installation, alteration, or repair of any electrical system used to furnish heat, light, or power; </section><section prefix="10">"Repair" means the reconstruction or renewal of any part of an existing building for the purpose of its maintenance; and </section><section prefix="11">"Routine maintenance of electrical systems" means the routine and periodic servicing of electrical systems, including cleaning, inspecting, and making adjustments to ensure the proper operation and the removal or replacement of component parts. "Routine maintenance of electrical systems" does not include the installation of complete electrical systems. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 429, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 2, effective April 6, 2004. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2003).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136, the subsections in this section (2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1) have been renumbered. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>