<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.415</section_number><catch_line>Registered office and registered agent for foreign limited liability company. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text>Each foreign limited liability company authorized to transact business in this Commonwealth shall continuously maintain in this Commonwealth: <section prefix="1">A registered office that may be the same as any of its places of business; and </section><section prefix="2">A registered agent, who may be: <section prefix="a">An individual who resides in this Commonwealth and whose business office is identical with the registered office; </section><section prefix="b">A domestic corporation or not-for-profit domestic corporation whose business office is identical with the registered office; </section><section prefix="c">A foreign corporation or foreign not-for-profit corporation authorized to transact business in this Commonwealth whose business office is identical with the registered office; or </section><section prefix="d">A domestic limited liability company or a foreign limited liability company authorized to transact business in this Commonwealth whose business address is identical with the registered office. </section></section><section prefix="3">The registered agent shall execute and deliver to the Secretary of State a document accepting the agency appointment, and the appointment of the agent shall not be effective until delivered to the Secretary of State. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 83, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13916</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>