<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.160</section_number><catch_line>Control of concessions and exhibits -- Exception -- Lien on property -- Sale to satisfy lien. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Fair Board shall have exclusive control of concessions, exhibitions, shows, entertainments and attractions at any place on the state fairgrounds and exhibition center and may, in the discretion of the board, operate any or all of such concessions, exhibitions, shows, entertainments and attractions, but the board shall not allow the operation of any gambling device or game of chance therein. It may delegate such control or operation to any of its employees or agents, or to an executive committee. This section shall not apply to the sale of lottery tickets sold under the provisions of KRS Chapter 154A. </section><section prefix="2">The State Fair Board shall have a prior lien upon the property of any concessionaire, exhibitor or person, immediately upon its coming or being brought on the grounds, or the center, to secure existing or future indebtedness. </section><section prefix="3">Any designated employee or agent of the State Fair Board may sell the property to satisfy the indebtedness after giving ten (10) days' notice to the owner or agent of the owner or, if notice cannot be given to the owner, after a notice is posted for ten (10) days in the office of the State Fair Board on the grounds, announcing that the property is to be sold. The State Fair Board, through its designated agent, may bid and buy in the property offered for sale for the use and benefit of the State Fair. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 28, effective December 15, 1988. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 3. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 4. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618i-9. </history><metadata><effective>December 15, 1988</effective><lrc-note>.Although references to the sale of "shares" were deleted in the Senate committee substitute, due to a clerical error, such reference was not deleted in subsection (1) of this section. The Reviser of Statutes, pursuant to KRS 7.136, has removed the words "or shares" to conform. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11598</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>