<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">A ANNEXATION </unit></structure><section_number>81A.010</section_number><catch_line>Annexation of unincorporated territory or reduction of territory by first-class city -- Effect of compact. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The boundaries of cities of the first class, except for a city which has in effect a compact with the county pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, shall remain as established by law until changed as provided in this section or KRS 81A.020, 81A.440, or through merger with a contiguous city pursuant to KRS 81.410 to 81.440. Whenever such city of the first class desires to annex any unincorporated territory or to reduce the boundaries of the city, the city legislative body may enact an ordinance, defining accurately the boundary of the territory proposed to be annexed or stricken off. The ordinance shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. In not less than thirty (30) days after the enactment of the ordinance, if the publication has been made and no petition has been filed in the Circuit Court as provided in KRS 81A.020, the city legislative body may enact another ordinance annexing to the city or striking from the city the territory described in the ordinance. Upon the enactment of this ordinance, the territory shall become part of the city, or be stricken from the city. </section><section prefix="2">The boundaries of any city of the first class which has in effect a compact with the county pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330 shall remain as established by law unless changed pursuant to the procedure set out in KRS 81A.005. Upon the termination of such compact, boundary changes shall be governed by subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 37. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2760, 2761. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><former-codification> KRS 81.100. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24999</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>