<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.120</section_number><catch_line>Civil service board -- Membership -- Appointment -- Term -- Vacancies -- Ineligibility for other office -- Removals. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established in cities of the first class a civil service board to be known as .... Civil Service Board. The board consists of seven (7) members of whom six (6) shall be appointed by the mayor and the mayor is the seventh member ex officio. The mayor, as ex officio member, shall not have the right to vote except when necessary to break a tie. The appointive members shall be selected equally from the two (2) political parties casting the highest and the next highest number of votes at the last preceding general election. All members shall be appointed for a four (4) year term. Vacancies created by death, resignation and otherwise shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term only. Any member of the board appointed according to the provisions of this section shall be eligible for reappointment unless his reappointment would offend the equal political division of said board. </section><section prefix="2">No member of the board shall be eligible for any appointive office of the city while a member of the board, or for one (1) year thereafter. If a member of the board becomes a candidate for an elective office, he thereby vacates his position as a member of the board. </section><section prefix="3">Any member of the board may be removed by the mayor, for cause, after hearing by the mayor, and after at least ten (10) days' notice in writing has been given to the member, which notice shall contain a copy of charges preferred against him. At the hearing he may be represented by counsel. The finding of the mayor shall be final and removal results in vacancy in such office. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 61. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25425</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>