<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-335</section_number><catch_line>Environmental leadership program. </catch_line><order_by>46-335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall establish by administrative regulation an environmental leadership program for those facilities meeting the pollution prevention goal established in KRS 224.46-305. The program shall provide incentives to acknowledge the environmental leadership of those facilities. The program may include provisions to address: <section prefix="a">Public recognition of a facility for meeting "state of the art" standards for environmental leadership; </section><section prefix="b">Accelerated review of a facility's applications for permits, permit renewals, and permit modifications; </section><section prefix="c">"Green product" labeling for products produced by a facility; </section><section prefix="d">Compliance credit given in later enforcement action taken against a facility; </section><section prefix="e">Reduced frequency of monitoring or reporting by a facility; </section><section prefix="f">Consolidation of requirements into one (1) permit; </section><section prefix="g">Reduction or elimination of fees paid to the cabinet for permits, releases of toxic chemicals, or generation of hazardous waste; </section><section prefix="h">Access to the cabinet ombudsman who will assist in cutting red tape; and </section><section prefix="i">Offset of voluntary actions against future regulatory requirements. </section></section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations shall not violate a statutory or regulatory requirement or impair the cabinet's ability to administer a federally-delegated or federally-funded program. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10444</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>