<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.580</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Community and Technical College System -- Curricula -- Goals -- Degree programs. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Community and Technical College System is established. The Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall provide: <section prefix="a">A general two (2) year academic curriculum with credits transferable to two </section></section><section prefix="2">year and four (4) year colleges and universities; <section prefix="a">Increase the basic academic and literacy skills of adults through adult basic </section><section prefix="b">Increase the technical skills and professional expertise of Kentucky workers </section><section prefix="c">Increase the access for students to complete the prebaccalaureate associate </section><section prefix="d">Enhance the relationship of credentials between secondary and postsecondary </section><section prefix="e">Facilitate transfers of credit between certificate, diploma, technical, and </section><section prefix="f">Develop a pool of educated citizens to support the expansion of existing </section><section prefix="g">Enhance the flexibility and adaptability of Kentucky workers in an ever- </section><section prefix="h">Promote the cultural and economic well-being of the communities throughout </section><section prefix="i">Improve the quality of life for Kentucky's citizens. </section></section>(b) Technical and semiprofessional programs of two (2) years or less; (c) Within a two (2) year college curriculum, courses in general education, including adult education, not necessarily intended for transfer nor technically oriented; and (d) Services to Kentucky's employers and the general public to provide continuing education and customized training for purposes of improving the knowledge and skills of Kentucky workers and citizens in all regions of the state. (2) The Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall be responsive to the needs of students and employers in all regions of the Commonwealth with accessible education and training to support the lifelong learning needs of Kentucky citizens in order to: education and remedial education services; through associate and technical degrees, diploma, and certificate programs; degree in arts or associate degree in science for ease of transfer to four (4) year institutions; programs which permit secondary students to enter programs through early admission, advanced placement, or dual enrollment; associate degree programs; business and industry and the recruitment of new business and industry; changing and global economy through continuing education and customized training for business and industry; Kentucky; and <section prefix="3">Students attending a college under the administration of the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System may pursue three (3) kinds of degree programs: <section prefix="a">Associate degree programs approved by the board of trustees as of the effective date of the transfer of the management responsibilities of the University of Kentucky Community College System to the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="b">Associate degree programs developed by the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, approved by the board of regents and the Council on Postsecondary Education. The board of regents shall confer degrees and award diplomas for the approved programs; and </section><section prefix="c">Joint degree programs developed between the Kentucky Community and Technical College System and other institutions. </section></section><section prefix="4">University of Kentucky Community College System students who were officially enrolled on or before June 30, 1999, in associate degree programs approved by the board of trustees of the University of Kentucky and who complete the associate degree programs on or before June 30, 2004, shall have their degrees conferred by the University of Kentucky board of trustees. The degrees for all other students enrolled shall be awarded by the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section><section prefix="5">The board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall expedite, whenever possible, action on requests for any new technical or associate degree program of a vocational-technical or occupational nature. </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Community and Technical College System college faculty senates shall have the primary responsibility for determining academic policy and curricula development that shall be recommended to the president of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section><section prefix="7">Technical colleges, through their faculty and accrediting procedures, may develop degree programs that shall be considered for approval by the board of regents and the Council on Postsecondary Education. A graduate of a program within three (3) years of the program becoming an accredited degree program shall receive all or partial credit toward the degree, based on criteria established by the institution and approved by the board of regents. The board of regents shall confer degrees and award diplomas for these programs. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 111, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 6. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4325</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>