<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.040</section_number><catch_line>Corporate powers. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>The corporation shall have all of the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this chapter, including but without limiting the generality of the foregoing the power: <section prefix="1">To make or participate in the making of insured construction loans to sponsors of land development or residential housing; provided, however, that such loans shall be made only upon the determination by the corporation that construction loans have been refused in writing, wholly or in part, from private lenders in the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions; </section><section prefix="2">To make or participate in the making of insured mortgage loans to sponsors of residential housing; provided, however, that such loans shall be made only upon the determination by the corporation that mortgage loans have been refused in writing, wholly or in part, from private lenders in the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions; </section><section prefix="3">To purchase or participate in the purchase of insured mortgage loans made to sponsors of residential housing or to persons of lower and moderate income for residential housing; provided, however, that any such purchase shall be made only upon the determination by the corporation that mortgage loans have been refused in writing, wholly or in part, from private lenders in the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions; </section><section prefix="4">To make temporary loans from the housing development fund; </section><section prefix="5">To collect and pay reasonable fees and charges in connection with making, purchasing and servicing its loans, notes, bonds, commitments, and other evidences of indebtedness; </section><section prefix="6">To acquire real property, or any interest therein, by purchase, foreclosure, lease, sublease, or otherwise; to own, manage, operate, hold, clear, improve, and rehabilitate such real property; and to sell, assign, exchange, transfer, convey, lease, mortgage, or otherwise dispose of or encumber such real property where such use of real property is necessary or appropriate to the purpose of the Kentucky Housing Corporation; </section><section prefix="7">To sell, at public or private sale, all or any part of any mortgage or other instrument or document securing a construction, land development, mortgage, or temporary loan of any type permitted by this chapter; </section><section prefix="8">To procure insurance against any loss in connection with its operations in such amounts, and from such insurers, as it may deem necessary or desirable; </section><section prefix="9">To consent, whenever it deems it necessary or desirable in the fulfillment of its corporate purposes, to the modification of the rate of interest, time of payment of any installment of principal or interest, or any other terms of any mortgage loan, mortgage loan commitment, construction loan, temporary loan, contract, or agreement of any kind to which the corporation is a party; </section><section prefix="10">To acquire, establish, operate, lease, and sublease residential housing for persons and families of lower and moderate income and to enter into agreements or other transactions with any federal, state, or local governmental agency for the purpose of providing adequate living quarters for such persons and families in cities and counties where a need has been found for such housing and where no local housing authorities or other organizations exist to fill such need; </section><section prefix="11">To include in any borrowing such amounts as may be deemed necessary by the corporation to pay financing charges, interest on the obligations for a period not exceeding two (2) years from their date, consultant, advisory, and legal fees and such other expenses as are necessary or incident to such borrowing; </section><section prefix="12">To make and publish rules and regulations respecting its lending programs and such other rules and regulations as are necessary to effectuate its corporate purposes; </section><section prefix="13">To provide technical and advisory services to sponsors of residential housing and to residents and potential residents thereof, including but not limited to housing selection and purchase procedures, family budgeting, property use and maintenance, household management, and utilization of community resources; </section><section prefix="14">To promote research and development in scientific methods of constructing low cost residential housing of high durability; </section><section prefix="15">To encourage community organizations to participate in residential housing development; </section><section prefix="16">To make, execute, and effectuate any and all agreements or other documents with any governmental agency or any person, corporation, association, partnership, or other organization or entity, necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter; </section><section prefix="17">To accept gifts, devises, bequests, grants, loans, appropriations, revenue sharing, other financing and assistance, and any other aid from any source whatsoever and to agree to, and to comply with, conditions attached thereto; </section><section prefix="18">To sue and be sued in its own name and plead and be impleaded; </section><section prefix="19">To maintain an office in the city of Frankfort and at such other place or places as it may determine; </section><section prefix="20">To adopt an official seal and alter the same at pleasure; </section><section prefix="21">To adopt bylaws for the regulation of its affairs and the conduct of its business and to prescribe rules, regulations, and policies in connection with the performance of its functions and duties; </section><section prefix="22">To employ fiscal consultants, engineers, attorneys, real estate counselors, appraisers, and such other consultants and employees as may be required in the judgment of the corporation and to fix and pay their compensation from funds available to the corporation therefor, provided that any personal service contracts entered into shall be subject to review by the Government Contract Review Committee of the Legislative Research Commission; </section><section prefix="23">To invest any funds held in reserve or in sinking fund accounts or any moneys not required for immediate disbursement in obligations guaranteed by the Commonwealth, the United States, or their agencies or instrumentalities; provided, however, that the return on such investments shall not violate any rulings of the Internal Revenue Service regarding the investment of the proceeds of any federally tax exempt bond issue; </section><section prefix="24">To make or participate in the making of rehabilitation loans to the sponsors or owners of residential housing; provided, however, that any such rehabilitation loan shall be made only upon the determination by the corporation that the rehabilitation loan was not otherwise available wholly or in part from private lenders upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions; </section><section prefix="25">To insure or reinsure construction, mortgage, and rehabilitation loans on residential housing; provided, however, that any such insurance, reinsurance, or waiver shall be made only upon the determination by the corporation: <section prefix="a">That such insurance or reinsurance is not otherwise available wholly or in part from private insurers upon reasonably equivalent terms and conditions; and </section><section prefix="b">That such loan is a reasonably sound business investment; and provided further that insurance may be waived only where the corporation finds that the amount of the loan does not exceed eighty-five percent (85%) of the development costs, or eighty-five percent (85%) of the value of the property secured by the mortgage as determined by at least two (2) appraisers who are independent of the sponsors, builders, and developers; </section></section><section prefix="26">To make grants from appropriated funds, agency and trust funds, and any other funds from any source available to the corporation, to sponsors, municipalities, local housing authorities, and to owners of residential housing for the development, construction, rehabilitation, or maintenance of residential housing and such facilities related thereto as corporation shall deem important for a proper living environment, all on such terms and conditions as may be deemed appropriate by the corporation; </section><section prefix="27">To make periodic grants to reduce principal and interest payments on mortgages or rentals payable by persons and families of lower and moderate income; </section><section prefix="28"><section prefix="a">To make a grant to reduce principal and interest payments on a mortgage or a rental payable by a regular member of the United States Armed Forces who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes, during that member's deployment on active duty outside the United States, or payable by a member of a state National Guard or a Reserve component who names Kentucky as home of record for military purposes, during that member's federal active duty. To qualify for a grant, a member shall meet reasonable standards established by the corporation, including having family income equal to or less than two hundred percent (200%) of the state or area median income; and </section><section prefix="b">To provide a member identified in paragraph (a) of this subsection and that member's Kentucky resident spouse with the educational, technical, and ombudsman services that are necessary to maintain a mortgage during that member's federal active duty; </section></section><section prefix="29">To establish a program to assist persons and families of lower and moderate income to help defray the cost of assessment and decontamination services required under KRS 224.1-410. To qualify for the program, a person shall meet reasonable standards established by the corporation. A person shall not be eligible for the program if convicted of a felony or found by the corporation to be responsible for contamination of the relevant property through methamphetamine production. The corporation shall report on the establishment and use of this program to the Legislative Research Commission by October 1 of each year; </section><section prefix="30">To establish single-family mortgage-lending programs outside of the mortgage revenue bond funds. To qualify for these programs, a person shall meet reasonable standards established by the corporation and shall have a combined family income that is equal to or less than one hundred seventy-five percent (175%) of the greater of the state or area median income; and </section><section prefix="31">To perform the following activities for lenders, holders, housing finance agencies, or other third-party entities, who are located within or without the boundaries of the Commonwealth: <section prefix="a">Service mortgage loans; </section><section prefix="b">Administer federal or state program contracts; and </section><section prefix="c">Perform other housing activities to facilitate the delivery or preservation of affordable housing. </section></section>The Kentucky Housing Corporation shall be exempt from the regulations of the Department of Insurance and the laws of the Commonwealth relating thereto. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 2, effective March 15, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 244, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 83, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 7, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective March 23, 1982; and ch. 182, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 2. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 3. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>