<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.1106</section_number><catch_line>Membership on boards, task forces, and commissions and participation in programs consistent with the Federal Americans with Disabilities Act -- Disability awareness program. </catch_line><order_by>1106</order_by><text>To ensure that Kentuckians with disabilities and their families enjoy full partnership in all programs, services, and activities throughout the Commonwealth: <section prefix="1">Consistent with this subsection, consideration shall be given to persons with one (1) or more disabilities for membership on any board, task force, or commission established by the Legislative Research Commission or the General Assembly. Persons with one (1) or more disabilities shall not be discriminated against and shall be given an equal opportunity for membership on any board, task force, or commission established by the Legislative Research Commission or the General Assembly consistent with and to the extent required by the Federal Americans with Disabilities Act; </section><section prefix="2">Individuals with disabilities shall be given an equal opportunity to participate in programs, services, and activities established by the Legislative Research Commission consistent with and to the extent required by the Federal Americans with Disabilities Act; </section><section prefix="3">If not already a part of staff development training, a program shall be established within the Legislative Research Commission with a disability awareness component; and </section><section prefix="4">If program evaluation criteria are utilized by the Legislative Research Commission, the criteria may include in the measures of performance, the number of individuals served by the program, service, or activity. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 10, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>