<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.126</section_number><catch_line>Pharmacist recovery network committee -- Administrative regulations -- Assessment -- Confidentiality -- Reporting restrictions. </catch_line><order_by>126</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall establish a pharmacist recovery network committee to promote the early identification, intervention, treatment, and rehabilitation of pharmacists and pharmacist interns who may be impaired by reason of illness, alcohol or drug abuse, or as a result of any other physical or mental condition. </section><section prefix="2">The board may enter into a contractual agreement with a nonprofit corporation, pharmacy professional organization, or similar organization for the purpose of creating, supporting, and maintaining a pharmacist recovery network committee. </section><section prefix="3">The board may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to effectuate and implement the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Beginning July 15, 1998, the board shall collect an assessment of ten dollars ($10) to be added to each licensure renewal application fee payable to the board. This assessment shall be expended by the board on the operation of the pharmacist recovery network committee. </section><section prefix="5">Members of a pharmacist recovery network committee, any administrator, staff member, consultant, agent, volunteer, or employee of the committee acting within the scope of his or her duties and without actual malice and all other persons who furnish information to the committee in good faith and without actual malice shall not be liable for any claim or damages as a result of any statement, decision, opinion, investigation, or action taken by the committee or by any individual member of the committee. </section><section prefix="6">All information, interviews, reports, statements, memoranda, or other documents furnished to or produced by the pharmacist recovery network committee, all communications to or from the committee, and all proceedings, findings, and conclusions of the committee, including those relating to intervention, treatment, or rehabilitation, that in any way pertain or refer to a pharmacist or pharmacist intern who is or may be impaired shall be privileged and confidential. </section><section prefix="7">All records and proceedings of the committee that pertain or refer to a pharmacist or pharmacist intern who is or may be impaired shall be privileged and confidential, used by the committee and its members only in the exercise of the proper function of the committee, not be considered public records, and not be subject to court subpoena, discovery, or introduction as evidence in any civil, criminal, or administrative proceedings, except as described in subsection (8) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">The committee may only disclose the information relative to an impaired pharmacist or pharmacist intern if: <section prefix="a">It is essential to disclose the information to persons or organizations needing the information in order to address the intervention, treatment, or rehabilitation needs of the impaired pharmacist or pharmacist intern; </section><section prefix="b">The release is authorized in writing by the impaired pharmacist or pharmacist intern; or </section><section prefix="c">The committee is required to make a report to the board pursuant to KRS 315.121. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 531, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31010</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>