<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.732</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Information Technology Advisory Council -- Purposes -- Members.   </catch_line><order_by>732</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Information Technology Advisory Council to: <section prefix="a">Advise the executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology on approaches to coordinating information technology solutions among libraries, public schools, local governments, universities, and other public entities; </section><section prefix="b">Advise the executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology on coordination among and across the organizational units of the executive branch of state government to prepare for, respond to, and prevent attacks; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide a forum for the discussion of emerging technologies that enhance electronic accessibility to various publicly funded sources of information and services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Information Technology Advisory Council shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The state budget director or a designee; </section><section prefix="b">The state librarian or a designee; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative from the public universities to be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons submitted by the Council on Postsecondary Education; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) citizen members from the private sector with information technology knowledge and experience appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) representatives of local government appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) representative from the area development districts appointed by the Governor from a list of names submitted by the executive directors of the area development districts; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) member of the media appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="h">The executive director of the Kentucky Authority for Educational Television; </section><section prefix="i">The chair of the Public Service Commission or a designee; </section><section prefix="j">Two (2) members of the Kentucky General Assembly, one (1) from each chamber, selected by the Legislative Research Commission; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) representative of the Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) representative from the public schools system appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="m">One (1) representative of the Kentucky Chamber of Commerce; and </section><section prefix="n">The executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology. </section></section><section prefix="3">Appointed members of the council shall serve for a term of two (2) years. Members who serve by virtue of an office shall serve on the council while they hold the office. </section><section prefix="4">Vacancies on the council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointments. If a nominating organization changes its name, its successor organization having the same responsibilities and purposes shall be the nominating organization. </section><section prefix="5">Members shall receive no compensation but shall receive reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses in accordance with travel and subsistence requirements established by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 32, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.513. </former-codification><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 10 provided that "the provisions of this Act shall not impact the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884." That proviso applies to this statute as amended in Section 7 of that Act. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>