<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.775</section_number><catch_line>Auditing of returns -- Payment of additional tax -- Federal audit. </catch_line><order_by>775</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section and KRS 67.778, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Conclusion of the federal audit" means the date that the adjustments made by the Internal Revenue Service to net income or gross receipts as reported on the business entity's federal income tax return become final and unappealable; and </section><section prefix="b">"Final determination of the federal audit" means the revenue agent's report or other documents reflecting the final and unappealable adjustments made by the Internal Revenue Service. </section></section><section prefix="2">As soon as practicable after each return is received, the tax district may examine and audit it. If the amount of tax computed by the tax district is greater than the amount returned by the business entity, the additional tax shall be assessed and a notice of assessment mailed to the business entity by the tax district within five (5) years from the date the return was filed, except as otherwise provided in this subsection. <section prefix="a">In the case of a failure to file a return or of a fraudulent return the additional tax may be assessed at any time. </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a return where a business entity understates net profit or gross receipts, or omits an amount properly includable in net profit or gross receipts, or both, which understatement or omission or both is in excess of twenty-five percent (25%) of the amount of net profit or gross receipts stated in the return, the additional tax may be assessed at any time within six (6) years after the return was filed. </section><section prefix="c">In the case of an assessment of additional tax relating directly to adjustments resulting from a final determination of a federal audit, the additional tax may be assessed before the expiration of the times provided in this subsection, or six (6) months from the date the tax district receives the final determination of the federal audit from the business entity, whichever is later. </section></section> The times provided in this subsection may be extended by agreement between the business entity and the tax district. For the purposes of this subsection, a return filed before the last day prescribed by law for filing the return shall be considered as filed on the last day. Any extension granted for filing the return shall also be considered as extending the last day prescribed by law for filing the return. <section prefix="3">Every business entity shall submit a copy of the final determination of the federal audit within thirty (30) days of the conclusion of the federal audit. </section><section prefix="4">A tax district may initiate a civil action for the collection of any additional tax within the times prescribed in subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23791</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>