<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.540</section_number><catch_line>Council on Postsecondary Education designated agency of state for purposes of regional compact -- Commonwealth not to maintain educational institutions that are discriminatory. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Council on Postsecondary Education in Kentucky as defined in KRS 164.011 is hereby designated as the agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky charged with the responsibility and vested with all necessary authority, subject to the conditions and restrictions set out in subsection (2) of this section, to carry out the obligations, participate in the planning and negotiations, and administer the rights, benefits, and privileges, devolving upon the Commonwealth of Kentucky and its citizens pursuant to the regional compact referred to in KRS 164.530, and to do all such other acts and things as may be necessary or desirable to implement the provisions of said regional compact efficiently and impartially for the benefit of all citizens of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">In its participation in the regional compact, or in any other regional plan having a similar purpose, the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall not erect, acquire, develop, or maintain in any manner any educational institution within its borders to which any student would be refused entrance on the basis of race, national origin, gender, creed, or religion. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 110, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 20, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. XIV, sec. 3. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 255, secs.  2 and 3. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>