<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.6603Completion</section_number><catch_line>of chemical disclosure registry form.   </catch_line><order_by>6603Completion</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A vendor or service provider performing any part of a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment shall furnish the operator with the information required by subsection (2) of this section, as applicable, and with any information as needed for the operators to comply with this section. The information shall be provided as soon as possible and in no case later than forty-five (45) days after the completion of a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment. </section><section prefix="2">Within ninety (90) days of concluding a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment, the operator of the horizontal well shall complete the chemical disclosure registry form and post the form on the chemical disclosure registry. The following information shall be required to be furnished: <section prefix="a">Operator's name; </section><section prefix="b">The date of the high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment; </section><section prefix="c">The county in which the well is located; </section><section prefix="d">The API number for the well; </section><section prefix="e">The well name and number; </section><section prefix="f">The longitude and latitude of the wellhead; </section><section prefix="g">The true vertical depth of the well; </section><section prefix="h">The total water volume used; </section><section prefix="i">Each chemical additive used in the fracturing treatment, including the chemical abstract service number added, if applicable; </section><section prefix="j">The maximum concentration, in percent by mass, of each chemical intentionally added to the base fluid, if applicable; and </section><section prefix="k">The total amount of proppant used, if applicable. </section></section><section prefix="3">A vendor, service provider, or operator shall not be required to: <section prefix="a">Disclose any trade secrets under subsection (2)(j) of this section to the chemical disclosure registry; </section><section prefix="b">Disclose chemicals that are not disclosed to it by a third-party manufacturer of the chemicals; or </section><section prefix="c">Disclose chemicals that: <section prefix="1">Occur incidentally or are otherwise unintentionally present in trace amounts; </section><section prefix="2">May be the incidental result of a chemical reaction or chemical process; or </section><section prefix="3">May be constituents of naturally occurring materials that become part of a high-volume horizontal fracturing treatment, where the chemicals are unknown to the vendor, service provider, or operator. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44246</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>