<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="346" order_by="346">COMPENSATION OF CRIME VICTIMS </unit></structure><section_number>346.185</section_number><catch_line>Crime victims' compensation fund. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established in the State Treasury the "Crime Victims' Compensation Fund," hereinafter referred to as the "fund," to be administered by the Crime Victims' Compensation Board. Nothing herein shall be construed to limit the power of the court to order additional forms of restitution including public or charitable work or reparation to the victim, to the fund, or otherwise as authorized by law. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall consist of moneys from the following: appropriations by the General Assembly; the federal government; disbursements provided under KRS 42.320(2)(g); and any other public or private source. Any unexpended balance remaining in the fund at the end of the biennium shall not lapse and be transferred to the general fund, but shall remain in the crime victims' compensation fund. Any funds not utilized by the board shall be used to provide assistance to programs for victims and the board shall allocate such funds to any agency providing services to victims. In the event there are insufficient funds in the fund to pay all claims in full, all claims shall be paid at seventy percent (70%). If there are no moneys in the fund, then no claim shall be paid until moneys have again accumulated. In addition to payment of claims, moneys in the fund shall be used to pay all the necessary and proper expenses of the Crime Victims' Compensation Board. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 24, effective August 1, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 409, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 420, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>