<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.530</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Medical Licensure -- Membership.   </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created in state government an independent board to be known as the State Board of Medical Licensure which shall exercise all medical and osteopathic licensure functions heretofore exercised by the State Board of Health. The offices of the board shall be maintained at such place as is designated by the board.  </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of fifteen (15) members, including the commissioner of public health, the dean of the University of Kentucky College of Medicine, the vice dean for clinical affairs of the University of Louisville School of Medicine, the dean of the University of Pikeville School of Osteopathic Medicine, and eleven (11) members appointed by the Governor.  </section><section prefix="3">Of the Governor's appointees: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be a licensed osteopathic physician and shall be appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the Kentucky Osteopathic Association; </section><section prefix="b">Seven (7) members shall be licensed medical physicians and may be appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted for each position by the Kentucky Medical Association. In making appointments under this paragraph, the Governor shall ensure that the physician members represent different specialties from a broad cross section of the medical profession; and </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall be citizens at large who are representatives of any recognized consumer advocacy groups with an interest in the delivery of health care and are not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 9, effective July 20, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 413, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 535, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 148, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 4. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(10). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 20, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>