<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.095</section_number><catch_line>Procedure and requirements for drilling coalbed methane well. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A coalbed methane well penetrating one (1) or more workable coalbeds shall be drilled in a manner that will exclude, if practicable, all coalbed methane or coalbed methane pressure from the workable coalbed, except as is found in the workable coalbed itself. Each string of casing that is run through a workable coalbed shall be seated at least thirty (30) feet below the workable coalbed in twenty (20) feet of cement, mud, clay, or other nonporous material that will make an effective seal. If a second workable coalbed is found less than thirty (30) feet below the first workable coalbed, the casing shall be seated and mudded off as above provided at least thirty (30) feet below the second workable coalbed. If gas is found between the two (2) workable coalbeds, it shall be treated as prescribed by this chapter. After any such string of casing has been properly seated, drilling may proceed immediately. </section><section prefix="2">When a coalbed methane well is drilled through the horizon of a workable coalbed where the coal has been removed, the hole shall be drilled at least thirty (30) feet below the workable coalbed, and shall be of a size sufficient to permit the placing of a liner, which shall start not less than twenty (20) feet beneath the horizon of the workable coalbed and extend not less than twenty (20) feet above it. The largest sized casing to be used in the well shall be centrally placed within this liner. The liner may be welded to the casing to be used, and the space between the liner and the casing shall be filled with cement as the liner and casing are lowered into the hole. Cement shall be placed in the bottom of the hole to a depth of twenty (20) feet to form a sealed seat for both liner and casing. Following the setting of the liner, drilling may proceed. If it is necessary to drill through the horizon of two (2) or more workable coalbeds where the coal has been removed, the liner shall be started not less than twenty (20) feet below the lowest horizon penetrated and shall extend to a point not less than twenty (20) feet above the highest horizon penetrated. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 19, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32742</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>