<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.420</section_number><catch_line>Collection of fees after death of officer. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 64.050, if any officer dies before making out a fee-bill or collecting his fees, his deputy, or, if none, his personal representative, may, within two (2) years after the services were rendered, make out and sign a fee-bill therefor, and may list the fee-bill in due time for collection with the proper officer, and the fee-bill shall be collectible and distrainable as if issued by the deceased officer in his lifetime.  </section><section prefix="2">Any person against whom an illegal fee-bill is made by a deputy or personal representative shall be entitled to the same remedies against such deputy or personal representative as are given against an officer.  </section><section prefix="3">If any person against whom a fee-bill is issued under this section makes an affidavit that the fee was paid to the officer in his lifetime, and produces the affidavit to the officer having the fee-bill for collection, such officer shall forthwith return the fee-bill and affidavit to the person who issued it, and the same shall thereafter be collectible by action only, as other debts.  </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 11. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1750. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23245</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>