<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.420</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Employee" means any individual employed by any employer, including but not limited to individuals employed by the state or any of its political subdivisions, instrumentalities, or instrumentalities of political subdivisions. </section><section prefix="2">"Employer" means a person who has two (2) or more employees within the state in each of twenty (20) or more calendar weeks in the current or preceding calendar year and an agent of such a person. </section><section prefix="3">"Wage rate" means all compensation for employment, including payment in kind and amounts paid by employers for employee benefits, as defined by the commissioner in regulations issued under KRS 337.420 to 337.433 and 337.990(14). </section><section prefix="4">"Employ" includes to suffer or permit to work. </section><section prefix="5">"Occupation" includes any industry, trade, business, or branch thereof, or any employment or class of employment. </section><section prefix="6">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Workplace Standards under the direction and supervision of the secretary of the Labor Cabinet. </section><section prefix="7">"Person" includes one (1) or more individuals, partnerships, corporations, legal representatives, trustees, trustees in bankruptcy, or voluntary associations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1736, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32089</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>