<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.805</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth school improvement fund -- Purposes -- Criteria for grants to schools needing assistance. </catch_line><order_by>805</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Commonwealth school improvement fund to assist local schools in pursuing new and innovative strategies to meet the educational needs of the school's students and raise a school's performance level. The Kentucky Board of Education shall utilize the Commonwealth school improvement fund to provide grants to schools for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">To support teachers and administrators in the development of sound and innovative approaches to improve instruction or management, including better use of formative and summative, performance-based assessments; </section><section prefix="b">To assist in replicating successful programs developed in other districts including those calculated to reduce achievement gaps as defined in KRS 158.649; </section><section prefix="c">To encourage cooperative instructional or management approaches to specific school educational problems; and </section><section prefix="d">To encourage teachers and administrators to conduct experimental programs to test concepts and applications being advanced as solutions to specific educational problems. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall develop criteria for awards of grants from the Commonwealth school improvement fund to schools identified by the board as needing assistance under KRS 158.6455. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education shall have the sole authority to approve grants from the fund. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Board of Education may establish priorities for the use of the funds and, through the Department of Education, shall provide assistance to schools in preparing their grant proposals. The board shall require that no funds awarded under the Commonwealth school improvement fund are used to supplant funds from any other source. Requests for necessary equipment may be approved at the discretion of the state board, however the cost of equipment purchased by any grantee shall not exceed twenty percent (20%) of the total amount of money awarded for each proposal and shall be matched by local funds on a dollar for dollar basis. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Board of Education shall establish maximums for specific grant awards. All fund recipients shall provide the board with an accounting of all money received from the fund and shall report the results and conclusions of any funded projects to the Kentucky Board of Education. All fund recipients shall provide the board with adequate documentation of all projects to enable replication of successful projects in other areas of the state. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 11, effective March 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 13, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 10, effective October 18, 1985. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (7) at 629. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>