<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.480</section_number><catch_line>Property exempt.   </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text>Any other provision of this chapter to the contrary notwithstanding, the terms "sale at retail," "retail sale," "use," "storage," and "consumption," as used in this chapter, shall not include the sale, use, storage, or other consumption of: <section prefix="1">Locomotives or rolling stock, including materials for the construction, repair, or modification thereof, or fuel or supplies for the direct operation of locomotives and trains, used or to be used in interstate commerce; </section><section prefix="2">Coal for the manufacture of electricity; </section><section prefix="3">All energy or energy-producing fuels used in the course of manufacturing, processing, mining, or refining and any related distribution, transmission, and transportation services for this energy that are billed to the user, to the extent that the cost of the energy or energy-producing fuels used, and related distribution, transmission, and transportation services for this energy that are billed to the user exceed three percent (3%) of the cost of production. Cost of production shall be computed on the basis of plant facilities which shall mean all permanent structures affixed to real property at one (1) location; </section><section prefix="4">Livestock of a kind the products of which ordinarily constitute food for human consumption, provided the sales are made for breeding or dairy purposes and by or to a person regularly engaged in the business of farming; </section><section prefix="5">Poultry for use in breeding or egg production; </section><section prefix="6">Farm work stock for use in farming operations; </section><section prefix="7">Seeds, the products of which ordinarily constitute food for human consumption or are to be sold in the regular course of business, and commercial fertilizer to be applied on land, the products from which are to be used for food for human consumption or are to be sold in the regular course of business; provided such sales are made to farmers who are regularly engaged in the occupation of tilling and cultivating the soil for the production of crops as a business, or who are regularly engaged in the occupation of raising and feeding livestock or poultry or producing milk for sale; and provided further that tangible personal property so sold is to be used only by those persons designated above who are so purchasing; </section><section prefix="8">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other farm chemicals to be used in the production of crops as a business, or in the raising and feeding of livestock or poultry, the products of which ordinarily constitute food for human consumption; </section><section prefix="9">Feed, including pre-mixes and feed additives, for livestock or poultry of a kind the products of which ordinarily constitute food for human consumption; </section><section prefix="10">Machinery for new and expanded industry; </section><section prefix="11">Farm machinery. As used in this section, the term "farm machinery": <section prefix="a">Means machinery used exclusively and directly in the occupation of: <section prefix="1">Tilling the soil for the production of crops as a business; </section><section prefix="2">Raising and feeding livestock or poultry for sale; or </section><section prefix="3">Producing milk for sale; </section></section><section prefix="b">Includes machinery, attachments, and replacements therefor, repair parts, and replacement parts which are used or manufactured for use on, or in the operation of farm machinery and which are necessary to the operation of the machinery, and are customarily so used, including but not limited to combine header wagons, combine header trailers, or any other implements specifically designed and used to move or transport a combine head; and </section><section prefix="c">Does not include: <section prefix="1">Automobiles; </section><section prefix="2">Trucks; </section><section prefix="3">Trailers, except combine header trailers; or </section><section prefix="4">Truck-trailer combinations; </section></section></section><section prefix="12">Property which has been certified as a pollution control facility as defined in KRS 224.1-300, and all materials, supplies, and repair and replacement parts purchased for use in the operation or maintenance of the facilities used specifically in the steel-making process. The exemption provided in this subsection for materials, supplies, and repair and replacement parts purchased for use in the operation of pollution control facilities shall be effective for sales made through June 30, 1994; </section><section prefix="13">Tombstones and other memorial grave markers; </section><section prefix="14">On-farm facilities used exclusively for grain or soybean storing, drying, processing, or handling. The exemption applies to the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section><section prefix="15">On-farm facilities used exclusively for raising poultry or livestock. The exemption shall apply to the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities. The exemption shall apply but not be limited to vent board equipment, waterer and feeding systems, brooding systems, ventilation systems, alarm systems, and curtain systems. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section><section prefix="16">Gasoline, special fuels, liquefied petroleum gas, and natural gas used exclusively and directly to: <section prefix="a">Operate farm machinery as defined in subsection (11) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Operate on-farm grain or soybean drying facilities as defined in subsection (14) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">Operate on-farm poultry or livestock facilities defined in subsection (15) of this section; </section><section prefix="d">Operate on-farm ratite facilities defined in subsection (24) of this section; </section><section prefix="e">Operate on-farm llama or alpaca facilities as defined in subsection (26) of this section; or </section><section prefix="f">Operate on-farm dairy facilities; </section></section><section prefix="17">Textbooks, including related workbooks and other course materials, purchased for use in a course of study conducted by an institution which qualifies as a nonprofit educational institution under KRS 139.495. The term "course materials" means only those items specifically required of all students for a particular course but shall not include notebooks, paper, pencils, calculators, tape recorders, or similar student aids; </section><section prefix="18">Any property which has been certified as an alcohol production facility as defined in KRS 247.910; </section><section prefix="19">Aircraft, repair and replacement parts therefor, and supplies, except fuel, for the direct operation of aircraft in interstate commerce and used exclusively for the conveyance of property or passengers for hire. Nominal intrastate use shall not subject the property to the taxes imposed by this chapter; </section><section prefix="20">Any property which has been certified as a fluidized bed energy production facility as defined in KRS 211.390; </section><section prefix="21">Any property to be incorporated into the construction, rebuilding, modification, or expansion of a blast furnace or any of its components or appurtenant equipment or structures as part of an approved supplemental project, as defined by KRS 154.26-010. The exemption provided in this subsection shall be effective for sales made: <section prefix="a">On and after July 1, 2016; and </section><section prefix="b">During the term of a supplemental project agreement entered into pursuant to KRS 154.26-090; </section></section><section prefix="22">Beginning on October 1, 1986, food or food products purchased for human consumption with food coupons issued by the United States Department of Agriculture pursuant to the Food Stamp Act of 1977, as amended, and required to be exempted by the Food Security Act of 1985 in order for the Commonwealth to continue participation in the federal food stamp program; </section><section prefix="23">Machinery or equipment purchased or leased by a business, industry, or organization in order to collect, source separate, compress, bale, shred, or otherwise handle waste materials if the machinery or equipment is primarily used for recycling purposes; </section><section prefix="24">Ratite birds and eggs to be used in an agricultural pursuit for the breeding and production of ratite birds, feathers, hides, breeding stock, eggs, meat, and ratite by-products, and the following items used in this agricultural pursuit: <section prefix="a">Feed and feed additives; </section><section prefix="b">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other farm chemicals; </section><section prefix="c">On-farm facilities, including equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities. The exemption shall apply to incubation systems, egg processing equipment, waterer and feeding systems, brooding systems, ventilation systems, alarm systems, and curtain systems. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section></section><section prefix="25">Embryos and semen that are used in the reproduction of livestock, if the products of these embryos and semen ordinarily constitute food for human consumption, and if the sale is made to a person engaged in the business of farming; </section><section prefix="26">Llamas and alpacas to be used as beasts of burden or in an agricultural pursuit for the breeding and production of hides, breeding stock, fiber and wool products, meat, and llama and alpaca by-products, and the following items used in this pursuit: <section prefix="a">Feed and feed additives; </section><section prefix="b">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other farm chemicals; and </section><section prefix="c">On-farm facilities, including equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities. The exemption shall apply to waterer and feeding systems, ventilation systems, and alarm systems. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section></section><section prefix="27">Baling twine and baling wire for the baling of hay and straw; </section><section prefix="28">Water sold to a person regularly engaged in the business of farming and used in the: <section prefix="a">Production of crops; </section><section prefix="b">Production of milk for sale; or </section><section prefix="c">Raising and feeding of: <section prefix="1">Livestock or poultry, the products of which ordinarily constitute food for human consumption; or </section><section prefix="2">Ratites, llamas, alpacas, buffalo, cervids or aquatic organisms; </section></section></section><section prefix="29">Buffalos to be used as beasts of burden or in an agricultural pursuit for the production of hides, breeding stock, meat, and buffalo by-products, and the following items used in this pursuit: <section prefix="a">Feed and feed additives; </section><section prefix="b">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other farm chemicals; </section><section prefix="c">On-farm facilities, including equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities. The exemption shall apply to waterer and feeding systems, ventilation systems, and alarm systems. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section></section><section prefix="30">Aquatic organisms sold directly to or raised by a person regularly engaged in the business of producing products of aquaculture, as defined in KRS 260.960, for sale, and the following items used in this pursuit: <section prefix="a">Feed and feed additives; </section><section prefix="b">Water; </section><section prefix="c">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other farm chemicals; and </section><section prefix="d">On-farm facilities, including equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities and, any gasoline, special fuels, liquefied petroleum gas, or natural gas used to operate the facilities. The exemption shall apply, but not be limited to: waterer and feeding systems; ventilation, aeration, and heating systems; processing and storage systems; production systems such as ponds, tanks, and raceways; harvest and transport equipment and systems; and alarm systems. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section></section><section prefix="31">Members of the genus cervidae permitted by KRS Chapter 150 that are used for the production of hides, breeding stock, meat, and cervid by-products, and the following items used in this pursuit: <section prefix="a">Feed and feed additives; </section><section prefix="b">Insecticides, fungicides, herbicides, rodenticides, and other chemicals; and </section><section prefix="c">On-site facilities, including equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities. In addition, the exemption shall apply whether or not the seller is under contract to deliver, assemble, and incorporate into real estate the equipment, machinery, attachments, repair and replacement parts, and any materials incorporated into the construction, renovation, or repair of the facilities; </section></section><section prefix="32"><section prefix="a">Repair or replacement parts for the direct operation or maintenance of a motor vehicle, including any towed unit, used exclusively in interstate commerce for the conveyance of property or passengers for hire, provided the motor vehicle is licensed for use on the highway and its declared gross vehicle weight with any towed unit is forty-four thousand and one (44,001) pounds or greater. Nominal intrastate use shall not subject the property to the taxes imposed by this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">Repair or replacement parts for the direct operation and maintenance of a motor vehicle operating under a charter bus certificate issued by the Transportation Cabinet under KRS Chapter 281, or under similar authority granted by the United States Department of Transportation; and </section><section prefix="c">For the purposes of this subsection, "repair or replacement parts" means tires, brakes, engines, transmissions, drive trains, chassis, body parts, and their components. "Repair or replacement parts" shall not include fuel, machine oils, hydraulic fluid, brake fluid, grease, supplies, or accessories not essential to the operation of the motor vehicle itself, except when sold as part of the assembled unit, such as cigarette lighters, radios, lighting fixtures not otherwise required by the manufacturer for operation of the vehicle, or tool or utility boxes; and </section></section><section prefix="33">Food donated by a retail food establishment or any other entity regulated under KRS 217.127 to a nonprofit organization for distribution to the needy. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 6, effective August 1, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 14, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 173, Pt. XIX, sec. 2, effective August 1, 2005; and Pt. XVI, sec. 3, effective June 1, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 40, effective January 1, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1, effective April 8, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective August 1, 1998; ch. 35, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 125, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 264, sec. 1, effective August 1, 1998; ch. 265, sec. 1, effective August 1, 1998; ch. 366, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 536, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 333, sec. 1, effective April 10, 1996, retroactive to January 1, 1980. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 364, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 380, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 46, effective February 26, 1991. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 210, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 211, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 396, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 476, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; ch. 233, sec. 28, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 258, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 1; and ch. 286, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 47. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (4/8/2002).  The amendment made to this statute in 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec.1 which created subsection (31) of this statute, "applies to sales made on or after July 1, 2002." 2002 Ky. Acts ch.254, sec.3.  (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 29, 35, 125, 264, 265, 366, and 536. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between chs. 29 and 35 and ch. 536, Acts ch. 536, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43547</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>