<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.315</section_number><catch_line>Spacing of access control points on limited access facilities for those having limited rights or easement of access. </catch_line><order_by>315</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "partial control of access" means the limited right or easement of access granted by the Transportation Cabinet under subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet shall establish minimum spacing requirements for partial control of access to a limited access facility, and the manner that the access is to be provided, for the owners or occupants of land or other persons who have a limited right or easement of access under KRS 177.220. Minimum spacing between access points shall be one thousand two hundred (1,200) feet in rural areas and six hundred (600) feet in urban areas. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet may change the spacing of access control points if: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">An owner or occupant of land abutting a limited access facility requests the cabinet for the change; or </section><section prefix="2">A local government requests the cabinet for the change; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The change in spacing of access points is supported by an engineering and traffic study approved by the state highway engineer. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 26, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 528, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>