<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.460</section_number><catch_line>Property valuation administrator, or deputy, to attend hearing on appealed assessments -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text>The property valuation administrator, or an authorized deputy, shall attend all hearings before the county board of assessment appeals and before the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals relative to his assessment and submit to examination and fully disclose to them such information as he may have and any other matters pertinent to the inquiry being made. He shall be entitled to reimbursement from the county for expenses incurred in official business outside his county. If the Department of Revenue directs him to perform official duties outside of his county, the expenses shall be paid from the appropriation for the payment of the salaries of the property valuation administrators. Such reimbursement shall be paid on the same basis as employees of the Commonwealth are paid for travel expenses. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 200, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 14. -- Amended 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 8. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 131, secs. 21 and 32. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4042a-15. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28278</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>