<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.535</section_number><catch_line>Applicator license holder restrictions -- Licenses not transferable or assignable -- Effect of sale of pest control firm -- Annual registration. </catch_line><order_by>535</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be only one (1) applicator license holder per company with one (1) or more reserve applicator license holders allowed for each company.  </section><section prefix="2">A license issued by the department shall not be transferable or assignable. In the event of the death or incapacitation of a licensed operator, his heirs, representatives, other persons or legal entities, which may have an interest in the structural pest control business in which the deceased was the license holder, shall be allowed a maximum of twelve (12) months from such death to obtain a qualified licensed applicator to operate or manage said business under the provisions of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585.  A full-time certified applicator shall be employed by such business for the application and supervision of restricted use pesticides.  </section><section prefix="3">If a pest control firm is sold, the purchaser must comply with all state laws and regulations.  If the purchaser fails to comply he has ninety (90) days to dissolve the business.  The seller must notify the buyer that the department regulates the pest control industry in Kentucky. The seller must notify the department that the business has been sold within ten (10) days after the sale.  If the license holder for a pest control firm leaves or is terminated for reasons other than death or sale of the firm, the firm must notify the department of this change within ten (10) days and must acquire a license holder at the next testing period or must be granted an emergency license by the department for a period not to exceed the following scheduled examination.  If the pest control firm fails to meet these requirements, they must dissolve the business within ninety (90) days.  A full-time certified applicator shall be employed by such business for the application and supervision of restricted use pesticides.  </section><section prefix="4">It shall be illegal to solicit business or advertise without a valid commercial structural pest control applicator's license or commercial structural fumigation applicator's license.  </section><section prefix="5">Each applicator shall register annually and shall pay an annual fee of one hundred dollars ($100) for each place of business maintained in Kentucky.  Every nonresident owner shall designate a resident agent upon whom service of notice of process may be made to enforce the provisions of KRS 217B.515 to 217B.585.  </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9568</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>