<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-710</section_number><catch_line>Duties of county clerk. </catch_line><order_by>9-710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county clerk who receives a statement tendered by a secured party under Part 4 of the former Article 9, prior to July 1, 2001, that has not been filed or indexed on July 1, 2001, shall file and index the statement as soon as practicable. </section><section prefix="2">Every county clerk shall append to the pre-effective-date financing statement the copies of any initial financing statement or continuation statement received from a secured party under KRS 355.9-706(4). </section><section prefix="3">The county clerk shall maintain all records filed under Part 4 of the former Article 9 and subsection (2) of this section until the later of: <section prefix="a">One (1) year after the lapse of the initial financing statement; </section><section prefix="b">July 1, 2008; or </section><section prefix="c">Such other record-retention requirement as may be applicable under other Kentucky law or administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="4">The county clerk shall respond to requests for information with respect to records maintained under this article in accordance with KRS 355.9-523(3) and (4) and may charge the fee for issuing certificates authorized in KRS 355.9-525. </section><section prefix="5">When Internet access is available through the AVIS system or its successor, every county clerk shall provide a means within his or her office by which the Secretary of State's filing system for this article can be searched and through which electronic filings under this article can be made with the Secretary of State. This subsection shall not be construed to require a secured party to file through the means provided by a county clerk. The county clerk shall neither be required to conduct a search of the Secretary of State's filing system nor to issue a certificate as to the contents of the system. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 156, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33870</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>