<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.160</section_number><catch_line>Investigation.   </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No charge or specification shall be referred to a general court-martial for trial until a thorough and impartial investigation of all the matters set forth therein has been made. This investigation shall include inquiry as to the truth of the matter set forth in the charges, consideration of the form of charges, and a recommendation as to the disposition which should be made of the case in the interest of justice and discipline. </section><section prefix="2">The accused shall be advised of the charges against the accused and of the right to be represented at that investigation by counsel. The accused has the right to be represented at that investigation as provided in KRS 35.190 and in regulations prescribed under that section. At that investigation full opportunity shall be given to the accused to cross-examine witnesses against the accused if they are available and to present anything the accused may desire in the accused's own behalf, either in defense or mitigation, and the investigating officer shall examine available witnesses requested by the accused. If the charges are forwarded after such investigation, they shall be accompanied by a statement of the substance of the testimony taken on both sides and a copy thereof shall be given to the accused. </section><section prefix="3">If an investigation of the subject matter of an offense has been conducted before the accused is charged with the offense, and if the accused was present at the investigation and afforded the opportunities for representation, cross-examination, and presentation as prescribed in subsection (2) of this section, no further investigation of that charge is necessary under this section unless it is demanded by the accused after the accused is informed of the charge. A demand for further investigation entitles the accused to recall witnesses for further cross-examination and to offer any new evidence in the accused's own behalf. </section><section prefix="4">If evidence adduced in an investigation under this section indicates that the accused committed an uncharged offense, the investigating officer may investigate the subject matter of that offense without the accused having first been charged with the offense if the accused is: <section prefix="a">Present at the investigation; </section><section prefix="b">Informed of the nature of each uncharged offense investigated; and </section><section prefix="c">Afforded the opportunities for representation, cross-examination, and presentation prescribed in subsection (2) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="5">The requirements of this section are binding on all persons administering this code, but failure to follow them does not constitute jurisdictional error. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 33, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 21. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 31, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41907</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>