<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.020</section_number><catch_line>Declaration by state board of county's status as a preclearance county. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The State Board of Elections may declare a county to be a preclearance county for election purposes when that county has a history of voter fraud, noncompliance with election laws, or voter complaints about the integrity of a particular election. In a county designated as a preclearance county, all decisions of the county board of elections shall be reported to the State Board of Elections for its review. The failure of a county board of elections of a preclearance county to submit its decisions to the State Board of Elections for its review shall constitute a prima facie case for appointment of an election manager under KRS 117.022. The State Board of Elections may require a preclearance county to submit evidence or justification as required by the state board which is necessary to evaluate the county board's decisions. A county designated as a preclearance county shall retain that designation until it is removed by the State Board of Elections. </text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 63, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1478. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 117.020:</former-history-former-name><catchline-at-repeal>  Residence requirements; how determined. </catchline-at-repeal><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>