<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17C-080</section_number><catch_line>Plan for selection and reevaluation of providers. </catch_line><order_by>17C-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each insurer shall have a process for the selection of health care providers who will be on the plan's list of participating providers, with written policies and procedures for review and approval used by the plan. </section><section prefix="2">The plan shall establish minimum professional requirements for participating health care providers. An insurer may not discriminate against a provider solely on the basis of the provider's license by the state. </section><section prefix="3">The plan shall demonstrate that it has consulted with appropriately qualified health care providers to establish the minimum professional requirements. </section><section prefix="4">The plan's selection process shall include verification of each health care provider's license, history of license suspension or revocation, and liability claims history. </section><section prefix="5">An insurer shall establish a formal written, ongoing process for the reevaluation of each participating health care provider within a specified number of years after the provider's initial acceptance into the plan. The reevaluation shall include an update of the previous review criteria and an assessment of the provider's performance pattern based on criteria such as enrollee clinical outcomes, number of complaints, and malpractice actions. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>