<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.411</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of driver's license to person with a seizure condition -- Conditions -- Notice and hearing -- Option for determination of ability by medical review board. </catch_line><order_by>411</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a person with a seizure condition applies for an original, duplicate, modified, or renewal operator's license, or applies for an instruction permit, he shall be required by the cabinet to present to the Division of Driver Licensing certification by a physician that his condition is controlled by drugs, details of the drugs, dosages which the person takes, and that the person has been free of any seizures for ninety (90) days; his own statement that he has been free of any seizures for ninety (90) days before the date of the application, and that he is taking the medication prescribed by his physician. The division shall upon receipt of the required documentation issue him a letter of authorization to present to the circuit clerk. The circuit clerk shall not issue an operator's license to a person with a seizure condition who does not present the letter of authorization. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has a seizure condition who cannot present the certification that his condition is controlled by drugs or a statement that he has been seizure-free for ninety (90) days shall be notified in writing by the cabinet that the person's privilege to operate a motor vehicle is withdrawn and of his right to have an informal hearing on the matter of whether he is an unsafe driver as a result of having the seizure condition. The notice shall be mailed by first-class mail to the address of record of the person. The hearing shall be automatically waived if not requested within twenty (20) days after the cabinet mails notice. The hearing shall be scheduled as early as practical after receipt of the request at a time and place designated by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">A person whose seizure condition would impair his ability to operate a motor vehicle may present evidence of the condition to the Division of Driver Licensing's medical review board as established under KRS 186.444, including his own attested statement, physician's statement, and medical dosage details. If the board determines that the person's seizure condition would not impair his ability to operate a motor vehicle, the division shall issue the letter of authorization required by subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">A person whose seizure condition is of a nature that the seizure condition would not impair the ability to operate a motor vehicle may present evidence of this fact to the Division of Driver Licensing including the person's own attested statement, physician's statement, and medicine dosage details. If the division determines that the person's seizure condition does not impair the ability to operate a motor vehicle, the division shall issue the letter of authorization required by subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">Any physician shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability, absent a showing of bad faith, for providing any reports, records, examinations, opinions, or recommendations pursuant to this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 70, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 455, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 416 and 455. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 416, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6047</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>