<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.020</section_number><catch_line>Enumeration of departments, program cabinets, and administrative bodies.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>Departments, program cabinets and their departments, and the respective major administrative bodies that they include are enumerated in this section. It is not intended that this enumeration of administrative bodies be all-inclusive. Every authority, board, bureau, interstate compact, commission, committee, conference, council, office, or any other form of organization shall be included in or attached to the department or program cabinet in which they are included or to which they are attached by statute or statutorily authorized executive order; except in the case of the Personnel Board and where the attached department or administrative body is headed by a constitutionally elected officer, the attachment shall be solely for the purpose of dissemination of information and coordination of activities and shall not include any authority over the functions, personnel, funds, equipment, facilities, or records of the department or administrative body. I. Cabinet for General Government - Departments headed by elected officers: <section prefix="1">The Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Lieutenant Governor. </section><section prefix="3">Department of State. <section prefix="a">Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="b">Board of Elections. </section><section prefix="c">Registry of Election Finance. </section></section><section prefix="4">Department of Law. <section prefix="a">Attorney General. </section></section><section prefix="5">Department of the Treasury. <section prefix="a">Treasurer. </section></section><section prefix="6">Department of Agriculture. <section prefix="a">Commissioner of Agriculture. </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky Council on Agriculture. </section></section><section prefix="7">Auditor of Public Accounts. <section prefix="a">Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="b">Department of Criminal Justice Training. </section><section prefix="c">Department of Corrections. </section><section prefix="d">Department of Juvenile Justice. </section><section prefix="e">Office of the Secretary. </section><section prefix="f">Office of Drug Control Policy. </section><section prefix="g">Office of Legal Services. </section><section prefix="h">Office of the Kentucky State Medical Examiner. </section><section prefix="i">Parole Board. </section><section prefix="j">Kentucky State Corrections Commission. </section><section prefix="k">Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services. </section><section prefix="l">Office of Management and Administrative Services. </section><section prefix="m">Department for Public Advocacy. <section prefix="1">Client Assistance Program. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Administrative Services. </section><section prefix="3">Office of Employment and Training. </section></section><section prefix="n">Kentucky Office for the Blind State Rehabilitation Council. </section><section prefix="o">Kentucky Workforce Investment Board. </section><section prefix="p">Statewide Council for Vocational Rehabilitation. </section><section prefix="q">Statewide Independent Living Council. </section><section prefix="r">Unemployment Insurance Commission. </section><section prefix="s">Education Professional Standards Board. <section prefix="1">Division of Educator Preparation. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Certification. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Professional Learning and Assessment. </section><section prefix="4">Division of Legal Services. </section></section><section prefix="t">Kentucky Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing. </section><section prefix="u">Kentucky Educational Television. </section><section prefix="v">Kentucky Environmental Education Council. <section prefix="1">Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Affairs. </section><section prefix="2">Office of General Counsel. </section><section prefix="3">Office of Administrative Hearings. </section><section prefix="4">Mine Safety Review Commission. </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission. </section><section prefix="6">Kentucky Environmental Quality Commission. </section><section prefix="7">Kentucky Public Service Commission. </section><section prefix="8">Division of Forestry. </section><section prefix="9">Division of Conservation. </section><section prefix="10">Office of the Reclamation Guaranty Fund. </section><section prefix="11">Kentucky Mining Board. <section prefix="a">Office of Entrepreneurship. </section><section prefix="b">Office of Research and Public Affairs. </section><section prefix="c">Bluegrass State Skills Corporation. </section><section prefix="d">Compliance Division. </section><section prefix="e">Incentive Assistance Division. </section></section></section></section>II. Program cabinets headed by appointed officers: (1) Justice and Public Safety Cabinet: (2) Education and Workforce Development Cabinet: (a) Office of the Secretary.  1. Governor's Scholars Program. (b) Office of Legal and Legislative Services. (c) Office of Communication. (d) Office of Budget and Administration. 1. Division of Human Resources. (e) Office of Technology Services. (f) Office of Educational Programs. (g) Office for Education and Workforce Statistics. (h) Board of the Kentucky Center for Education and Workforce Statistics. (i) Board of Directors for the Center for School Safety. (j) Department of Education. 1. Kentucky Board of Education. 2. Kentucky Technical Education Personnel Board. (k) Department for Libraries and Archives. (l) Department of Workforce Investment. 1. Office for the Blind. 2. Office of Vocational Rehabilitation.  a. Division of Grant Management and Support.  b. Division of Workforce and Employment Services.  c. Division of Unemployment Insurance. (m) Foundation for Workforce Development. (3) Energy and Environment Cabinet: (a) Office of the Secretary. (b) Department for Environmental Protection. 1. Office of the Commissioner. 2. Division for Air Quality. 3. Division of Water. 4. Division of Environmental Program Support. 5. Division of Waste Management. 6. Division of Enforcement. 7. Division of Compliance Assistance. (c) Department for Natural Resources. 1. Office of the Commissioner. 2. Division of Technical and Administrative Support. 3. Division of Mine Permits. 4. Division of Mine Reclamation and Enforcement. 5. Division of Abandoned Mine Lands. 6. Division of Oil and Gas. 7. Division of Mine Safety. (d) Department for Energy Development and Independence. 1. Division of Efficiency and Conservation. 2. Division of Renewable Energy. 3. Division of Biofuels. 4. Division of Energy Generation Transmission and Distribution. 5. Division of Carbon Management. 6. Division of Fossil Energy Development. (4) Public Protection Cabinet. (a) Office of the Secretary. 1. Office of Communications and Public Outreach. 2. Office of Legal Services.  a. Insurance Legal Division.  b. Charitable Gaming Legal Division.  c. Alcoholic Beverage Control Legal Division.  d. Housing, Buildings and Construction Legal Division.  e. Financial Institutions Legal Division. (b) Crime Victims Compensation Board. (c) Board of Claims. (d) Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals. (e) Kentucky Boxing and Wrestling Authority. (f) Kentucky Horse Racing Commission. 1. Division of Licensing. 2. Division of Incentives and Development. 3. Division of Veterinary Services. 4. Division of Security and Enforcement. (g) Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control. 1. Division of Distilled Spirits. 2. Division of Malt Beverages. 3. Division of Enforcement. (h) Department of Charitable Gaming. 1. Division of Licensing and Compliance. 2. Division of Enforcement. (i) Department of Financial Institutions. 1. Division of Depository Institutions. 2. Division of Non-Depository Institutions. 3. Division of Securities. (j) Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. 1. Division of Fire Prevention. 2. Division of Plumbing. 3. Division of Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning. 4. Division of Building Code Enforcement. (k) Department of Insurance. 1. Property and Casualty Division. 2. Health and Life Division. 3. Division of Financial Standards and Examination. 4. Division of Agent Licensing. 5. Division of Insurance Fraud Investigation. 6. Consumer Protection Division. 7. Division of Kentucky Access. (l) Office of Occupations and Professions. (5) Labor Cabinet. (a) Office of the Secretary. 1. Division of Management Services. 2. Office of General Counsel. (b) Office of General Administration and Program Support for Shared Services. 1. Division of Human Resource Management. 2. Division of Fiscal Management. 3. Division of Budgets. 4. Division of Information Services. (c) Office of Inspector General for Shared Services. (d) Department of Workplace Standards. 1. Division of Employment Standards, Apprenticeship, and Mediation. 2. Division of Occupational Safety and Health Compliance. 3. Division of Occupational Safety and Health Education and Training. 4. Division of Workers' Compensation Funds. (e) Department of Workers' Claims. 1. Office of General Counsel for Workers' Claims. 2. Office of Administrative Law Judges. 3. Division of Claims Processing. 4. Division of Security and Compliance. 5. Division of Information and Research. 6. Division of Ombudsman and Workers' Compensation Specialist Services. 7. Workers' Compensation Board. 8. Workers' Compensation Advisory Council. 9. Workers' Compensation Nominating Commission. (f) Workers' Compensation Funding Commission. (g) Kentucky Labor-Management Advisory Council. (h) Occupational Safety and Health Standards Board. (i) Prevailing Wage Review Board. (j) Apprenticeship and Training Council. (k) State Labor Relations Board. (l) Employers' Mutual Insurance Authority. (m) Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission. (6) Transportation Cabinet: (a) Department of Highways. 1. Office of Project Development. 2. Office of Project Delivery and Preservation. 3. Office of Highway Safety. 4. Highway District Offices One through Twelve. (b) Department of Vehicle Regulation. (c) Department of Aviation. (d) Department of Rural and Municipal Aid. 1. Office of Local Programs. 2. Office of Rural and Secondary Roads. (e) Office of the Secretary. 1. Office of Public Affairs. 2. Office for Civil Rights and Small Business Development. 3. Office of Budget and Fiscal Management. 4. Office of Inspector General. (f) Office of Support Services. (g) Office of Transportation Delivery. (h) Office of Audits. (i) Office of Human Resource Management. (j) Office of Information Technology. (k) Office of Legal Services. (7) Cabinet for Economic Development: (a) Office of the Secretary. 1. Office of Legal Services. 2. Department for Business Development.  i. Commission on Small Business Advocacy. 3. Office of Financial Services. a. Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority. b. Division of Finance and Personnel. c. Division of Network Administration. <section prefix="8">Cabinet for Health and Family Services: <section prefix="a">Office of the Secretary. </section><section prefix="b">Office of Health Policy. </section><section prefix="c">Office of Legal Services. </section><section prefix="d">Office of Inspector General. </section><section prefix="e">Office of Communications and Administrative Review. </section><section prefix="f">Office of the Ombudsman. </section><section prefix="g">Office of Policy and Budget. </section><section prefix="h">Office of Human Resource Management. </section><section prefix="i">Office of Administrative and Technology Services. </section><section prefix="j">Department for Public Health. </section><section prefix="k">Department for Medicaid Services. </section><section prefix="l">Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities. </section><section prefix="m">Department for Aging and Independent Living. </section><section prefix="n">Department for Community Based Services. </section><section prefix="o">Department for Income Support. </section><section prefix="p">Department for Family Resource Centers and Volunteer Services. </section><section prefix="q">Kentucky Commission on Community Volunteerism and Service. </section><section prefix="r">Kentucky Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs. </section><section prefix="s">Governor's Office of Electronic Health Information. </section></section><section prefix="9">Finance and Administration Cabinet: <section prefix="a">Office of General Counsel. </section><section prefix="b">Office of the Controller. </section><section prefix="c">Office of Administrative Services. </section><section prefix="d">Office of Public Information. </section><section prefix="e">Office of Policy and Audit. </section><section prefix="f">Department for Facilities and Support Services. </section><section prefix="g">Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="h">Commonwealth Office of Technology. </section><section prefix="i">State Property and Buildings Commission. </section><section prefix="j">Office of Equal Employment Opportunity and Contract Compliance. </section><section prefix="k">Kentucky Employees Retirement Systems. </section><section prefix="l">Commonwealth Credit Union. </section><section prefix="m">State Investment Commission. </section><section prefix="n">Kentucky Housing Corporation. </section><section prefix="o">Kentucky Local Correctional Facilities Construction Authority. </section><section prefix="p">Kentucky Turnpike Authority. </section><section prefix="q">Historic Properties Advisory Commission. </section><section prefix="r">Kentucky Tobacco Settlement Trust Corporation. </section><section prefix="s">Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority. </section><section prefix="t">Kentucky River Authority. </section><section prefix="u">Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System Board of Trustees. </section><section prefix="v">Executive Branch Ethics Commission. </section></section><section prefix="10">Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet: <section prefix="a">Kentucky Department of Travel and Tourism. <section prefix="1">Division of Tourism Services. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Marketing and Administration. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Communications and Promotions. </section></section><section prefix="b">Kentucky Department of Parks. <section prefix="1">Division of Information Technology. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Human Resources. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Financial Operations. </section><section prefix="4">Division of Facilities Management. </section><section prefix="5">Division of Facilities Maintenance. </section><section prefix="6">Division of Customer Services. </section><section prefix="7">Division of Recreation. </section><section prefix="8">Division of Golf Courses. </section><section prefix="9">Division of Food Services. </section><section prefix="10">Division of Rangers. </section><section prefix="11">Division of Resort Parks. </section><section prefix="12">Division of Recreational Parks and Historic Sites. </section></section><section prefix="c">Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources. <section prefix="1">Division of Law Enforcement. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Administrative Services. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Engineering. </section><section prefix="4">Division of Fisheries. </section><section prefix="5">Division of Information and Education. </section><section prefix="6">Division of Wildlife. </section><section prefix="7">Division of Public Affairs. </section></section><section prefix="d">Kentucky Horse Park. <section prefix="1">Division of Support Services. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Buildings and Grounds. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Operational Services. </section></section><section prefix="e">Kentucky State Fair Board. <section prefix="1">Office of Administrative and Information Technology Services. </section><section prefix="2">Office of Human Resources and Access Control. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Expositions. </section><section prefix="4">Division of Kentucky Exposition Center Operations. </section><section prefix="5">Division of Kentucky International Convention Center. </section><section prefix="6">Division of Public Relations and Media. </section><section prefix="7">Division of Venue Services. </section><section prefix="8">Division of Personnel Management and Staff Development. </section><section prefix="9">Division of Sales. </section><section prefix="10">Division of Security and Traffic Control. </section><section prefix="11">Division of Information Technology. </section><section prefix="12">Division of the Louisville Arena. </section><section prefix="13">Division of Fiscal and Contract Management. </section><section prefix="14">Division of Access Control. </section></section><section prefix="f">Office of the Secretary. <section prefix="1">Office of Finance. </section><section prefix="2">Office of Research and Administration. </section><section prefix="3">Office of Governmental Relations and Tourism Development. </section><section prefix="4">Office of the Sports Authority. </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky Sports Authority. </section></section><section prefix="g">Office of Legal Affairs. </section><section prefix="h">Office of Human Resources. </section><section prefix="i">Office of Public Affairs and Constituent Services. </section><section prefix="j">Office of Creative Services. </section><section prefix="k">Office of Capital Plaza Operations. </section><section prefix="l">Office of Arts and Cultural Heritage. </section><section prefix="m">Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission. </section><section prefix="n">Kentucky Foundation for the Arts. </section><section prefix="o">Kentucky Humanities Council. </section><section prefix="p">Kentucky Heritage Council. </section><section prefix="q">Kentucky Arts Council. </section><section prefix="r">Kentucky Historical Society. <section prefix="1">Division of Museums. </section><section prefix="2">Division of Oral History and Educational Outreach. </section><section prefix="3">Division of Research and Publications. </section><section prefix="4">Division of Administration. </section></section><section prefix="s">Kentucky Center for the Arts. <section prefix="1">Division of Governor's School for the Arts. </section></section><section prefix="t">Kentucky Artisans Center at Berea. </section><section prefix="u">Northern Kentucky Convention Center. </section><section prefix="v">Eastern Kentucky Exposition Center. </section></section><section prefix="11">Personnel Cabinet: <section prefix="a">Office of the Secretary. </section><section prefix="b">Department of Human Resources Administration. </section><section prefix="c">Office of Employee Relations. </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky Public Employees Deferred Compensation Authority. </section><section prefix="e">Office of Administrative Services. </section><section prefix="f">Office of Legal Services. </section><section prefix="g">Governmental Services Center. </section><section prefix="h">Department of Employee Insurance. </section><section prefix="i">Office of Diversity and Equality. </section><section prefix="j">Center of Strategic Innovation. </section></section>III. Other departments headed by appointed officers: (1) Council on Postsecondary Education. (2) Department of Military Affairs. (3) Department for Local Government. (4) Kentucky Commission on Human Rights. (5) Kentucky Commission on Women. (6) Department of Veterans' Affairs. (7) Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs. (8) Office of Minority Empowerment. (9) Governor's Council on Wellness and Physical Activity. </text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014; ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 89, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013; ch. 18, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013, ch. 59, sec. 37, effective June 25, 2013; ch. 72, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013; ch. 78, sec. 9, effective March 22, 2013; and ch. 90, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; ch. 71, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; ch. 146, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010; ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009; ch. 12, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009; ch. 13, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; ch. 14, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; ch. 15, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; ch. 16, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 75, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 35, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007; ch. 24, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007; ch. 47, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 172, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 181, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 210, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 172, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 211, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 35, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 85, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 95, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 97, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 98, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 99, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 123, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 181, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003; ch. 29, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003; ch. 31, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003; ch. 40, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003; ch. 41, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003; and ch. 54, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002; ch.190, sec.1, effective July 15, 2002; ch.300, sec.1, effective July 15, 2002; and ch.338, sec.48, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 9, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 5, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 16, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 27, sec. 7, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 34, sec. 6, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 38, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 70, sec. 1, effective March 15, 2001; ch. 137, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001; ch. 149, sec. 13, effective March 20, 2001; and ch. 164, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 6, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 14, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 31, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 46, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 85, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 156, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 203, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 221, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 374, sec. 17, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 387, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 417, sec. 7, effective December 1, 2000; ch. 506, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 58, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 69, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 83, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 89, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 154, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 284, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 333, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 353, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 396, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 426, sec. 61, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 493, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 498, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 579, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 28, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 217, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 241, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 244, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 271, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 310, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 358, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 360, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 181, sec. 8, effective April 4, 1994; ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 209, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 215, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 216, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 227, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 405, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 422, sec. 1, effective April 16, 1994; ch. 469, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 499, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 508, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 38, effective March 30, 1992; ch. 159, sec. 2. effective July 14, 1992; ch. 211, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 288, sec. 47, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 321, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 325, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 377, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 378, sec. 3, effective July 13 1990; ch. 379, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 399, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 470, sec. 63, effective July 1, 1990; ch. 476, Part II, sec. 52, effective July 1, 1991; and ch. 484, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 64, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 474, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 388, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 381, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 382, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 393, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 399, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 447, sec. 5, effective April 12, 1982; and ch. 448, sec. 57, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1978; and ch. 155, secs. 2 and 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 6; ch. 299, sec. 1; and ch. 326, sec. 1. --Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. 1, sec. 6. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 3. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. I, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. I, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. I, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42i-4, 165-45, 938q-3, 1496-2, 4618-70. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has modified the internal numbering system in Units I., II., and III. of this statute to conform to the format used in the Kentucky Revised Statutes. The words in the text and the placement of the entities were not changed. (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44519</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>