<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="168" order_by="168">EDUCATIONAL TELEVISION </unit></structure><section_number>168.060</section_number><catch_line>Meetings -- Notice -- Quorum -- Organization. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall meet not less frequently than quarterly, and otherwise as often as necessary for the orderly conduct of its affairs. If it sees fit to do so, it may establish in its bylaws, or by resolution, four (4) or more fixed dates for regular meetings at one (1) or more specified places, in which event any proper business may come before the authority on such occasions, and it shall not be necessary that the members be given notice thereof unless the chairman shall deem it necessary or desirable that the day, place, or hour be changed, whereupon notice to such effect shall be mailed to each member by the chairman or secretary, by ordinary first-class mail, postage prepaid, not less than one (1) week in advance. Regular meetings may be adjourned to convene again at another time and place, if the facts are shown in a motion or resolution adopted by a majority of those present and entered upon the minutes; and if such be done, the adjourned session shall constitute a continuation of the regular session without notice to absent members; but the motion or resolution of adjournment may specify that every reasonable effort be made to give such notice to absent members as time and circumstances may permit, whereupon the secretary (or in his absence the chairman or any designated member) shall make such effort and report the same and the success or failure thereof as to each member, at the occasion of the adjourned session of the regular meeting. Special meetings may be called by the chairman, vice chairman, secretary, or any two (2) members upon notice of the time, place and business to be transacted, similarly given; and special meetings may be adjourned in like manner as in the case of regular meetings, except that the matters considered shall be limited to such as are set forth in the notice of the special meeting. </section><section prefix="2">Any member may waive notice orally or in writing at any time before, at, or after any meeting; and the presence of a member at any meeting shall constitute a waiver of notice unless such member tenders at such meeting a written protest on the ground of want of sufficient notice. </section><section prefix="3">Five (5) or more members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business at any meeting, and a majority vote thereof shall be sufficient to transact any business properly before the meeting. Any lesser number may adjourn to reconvene at another time for failure to muster a quorum. </section><section prefix="4">Immediately upon receiving notice of the election or appointment of all other members, the chief state school officer shall call a meeting for organizational purposes, to be held at Frankfort, Kentucky, at a time and place set forth in a written notice mailed to each member, as set forth above. At this meeting, the chief state school officer shall preside as temporary chairman, and the authority shall elect from among the members a chairman, a vice chairman, a secretary, and a treasurer, and define the duties thereof; or it may combine the office of treasurer with any other office of the authority or with any position created pursuant to KRS 168.080. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 281, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4731</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>