<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.130</section_number><catch_line>Transactions permitted to distillers, rectifiers, and wineries.   </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Sales and deliveries of distilled spirits and wine may be made at wholesale, and from the licensed premises only: <section prefix="a">By distillers to rectifiers, wineries, holders of special nonbeverage alcohol licenses so far as they may make the purchases, or other distillers; </section><section prefix="b">By rectifiers to wineries or to distillers if distilled spirits sold to distillers are packaged in retail containers; </section><section prefix="c">By wineries to rectifiers or other wineries, or to the holders of special nonbeverage alcohol licenses; </section><section prefix="d">By distillers, rectifiers, or wineries to wholesalers; or </section><section prefix="e">By distillers, rectifiers, or wineries for export out of the state. </section></section><section prefix="2">No distiller, rectifier, or winery shall sell or contract to sell, give away, or deliver any alcoholic beverages to any person who is not authorized by the law of the state of his or her residence, and of the United States government if located in the United States, to receive and possess those alcoholic beverages. No distiller, rectifier, or winery shall sell or contract to sell, give away, or deliver any of his or her products to any retailer or consumer in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">Distillers may purchase distilled spirits only from other licensed distillers in this state or in another state or province, but distillers may purchase from rectifiers licensed in Kentucky, distilled spirits which are packaged in retail containers.  </section><section prefix="4">Rectifiers may purchase distilled spirits and wine only from licensed distillers or wineries in Kentucky, or from nonresident distillers or wineries authorized by the law of the state of their residence and by the United States government, if the distillers or wineries are located in the United States, to make the sales. </section><section prefix="5">Wineries may purchase distilled spirits or wine only from licensed distillers or wineries in Kentucky, or from nonresident distillers or wineries authorized by law of the state of their residence, and by the United States government if located in the United States, to make the sales. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing shall prohibit the purchase or sale of warehouse receipts by any person, but this subsection does not authorize the owner of such a receipt to accept delivery of any distilled spirits unless the owner is a person who is permitted by law to receive the same. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 60, effective June 25, 2013. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-119. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>