<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.015</section_number><catch_line>License required to hold self out as private investigator -- Criminal background check. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>No person or company shall hold himself or herself out to the public as a private investigator or use any terms, titles, or abbreviations that express, infer, or imply that the person is licensed as a private investigator unless the person at the time holds a license to practice private investigating issued and validly existing under the laws of this Commonwealth as provided in this chapter. All applicants shall pass a criminal background check based on criteria established under KRS 329A.035. </text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2003).  2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 16, reads as follows:   "(1)  Notwithstanding KRS 7.123 to the contrary, any private investigating firm that has had its headquarters in the Commonwealth of Kentucky for at least two (2) years prior to July 15, 2002, shall receive a license issued under KRS Chapter 329A automatically upon filing the appropriate application and paying the appropriate fee to the board by October 1, 2003.   (2)  Notwithstanding KRS 7.123 to the contrary, any person actively engaged in full-time or part-time investigatory work in this state as a private investigator or as an investigator for a law enforcement agency for a continuous period of at least two (2) years prior to July 15, 2002, shall receive a license as a private investigator issued under KRS Chapter 329A upon:   (a)  Filing an application with the board prior to October 1, 2003, including supporting documentation;   (b)  Paying the licensure fee; and   (c)  Passing the examination administered by the board in accordance with KRS 329A.025 unless the board, in its discretion and on a case by case basis, waives the examination requirement." (4/21/2004).  2004 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 11, reads as follows:   "(1)  Notwithstanding KRS 7.123 to the contrary, any private investigating firm that has had its headquarters in the Commonwealth of Kentucky for at least two (2) years prior to July 15, 2002, shall receive a license issued under KRS Chapter 329A automatically upon filing the appropriate application and paying the appropriate fee to the board within sixty (60) days after the effective date of this Act.   (2)  Notwithstanding KRS 7.123 to the contrary, any person actively engaged in full-time or part-time investigatory work in this state as a private investigator or as an investigator for a law enforcement agency for a continuous period of at least two (2) years prior to July 15, 2002, shall receive a license as a private investigator issued under KRS Chapter 329A automatically upon:   (a)  Filing an application with the board within sixty (60) days after the effective date of this Act, including supporting documentation; and   (b)  Paying the licensure fee." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31759</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>