<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.200</section_number><catch_line>Court to notify cabinet of admission ordered to ICF/ID -- Refusal to receive by ICF/ID -- Transport of person.   </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The court which orders any person to an ICF/ID under the provisions of this chapter, shall at once notify the cabinet that the order has been made, advising of the sex and condition of the person. </section><section prefix="2">The ICF/ID may refuse to receive any person who has been ordered to be involuntarily admitted by a court order if appropriate programs and space are not available or the papers presented with the person at the ICF/ID do not comply with the provisions of this chapter or if it does not receive notification of the order of involuntary admission as required by this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">After the cabinet has been so notified, the court may order the sheriff of the county to transport the person from the county in which the person is located to the ICF/ID designated by the cabinet. The actual traveling expenses of persons transporting the person to the institution shall be paid by the cabinet. Each female admitted to an ICF/ID shall be accompanied by a female attendant, unless accompanied by her mother, father, sister, brother, husband, daughter, or son. </section><section prefix="4">In returning any person to the county from which that person is sent, the cost of returning the person shall be paid in the same manner, when necessary. </section><section prefix="5">If a person is involuntarily admitted by a court order, the person shall be transported to the ICF/ID designated by the cabinet and accompanied by the following documents: <section prefix="a">A copy of the petition for involuntary admission; </section><section prefix="b">The certificate of qualified professionals in the area of intellectual disabilities; </section><section prefix="c">A current physical examination that documents no serious medical issues; </section><section prefix="d">The psychological examination or assessment that documents a Full Scale IQ in the moderate to severe range of intellectual disability; and </section><section prefix="e">The order of involuntary admission. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 54, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 498, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40784</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>