<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.600Purchase</section_number><catch_line>of firearm by state employee -- Use of proceeds from sale.   </catch_line><order_by>600Purchase</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">When an agency of Kentucky state government or a public university safety and security department organized pursuant to KRS 164.950 transitions from the use of one (1) firearm owned by that agency to another, the agency may sell the firearm that is being replaced directly to an employee of the agency if: <section prefix="1">The firearm was issued to the employee in the course of employment; and </section><section prefix="2">The employee is otherwise authorized by law to own or possess the firearm. </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The agency shall notify employees of the intended replacement of firearms and that employees may purchase firearms pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">The employee desiring to purchase the firearm issued to the employee shall notify the head of the issuing agency of his or her intention not less than ten (10) days after receiving notice of the intended replacement. </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Upon retirement from state employment, a state employee to whom a firearm has been issued during the course of employment may purchase the firearm which was issued during the course of employment if the employee is otherwise authorized to privately own or possess the firearm. </section><section prefix="b">The employee desiring to purchase the firearm issued to the employee shall notify the head of the issuing agency of such intention not less than thirty (30) days prior to the scheduled date of retirement. </section></section><section prefix="3">The purchase price shall be the fair market value determined by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, Division of Personal Property. The proceeds from the sale of the firearm shall be deposited to the credit of an agency account for the issuing agency and shall be used for the purpose of purchasing replacement firearms. </section><section prefix="4">Any firearms that are not purchased by employees or retirees shall be disposed of pursuant to KRS 45A.047. </section><section prefix="5">This statute shall supersede other state laws with regard to the disposition of state property for the purpose stated in this section and for no other purpose. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective July 15,1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>.  Acts 1986, ch. 58, รยง 2 provides: KRS 45A.600 shall be retroactive to January 1, 1985. An employee who retired on or after January 1, 1985 may, within sixty (60) days after July 15, 1986 apply to the agency from which he retired to purchase the handgun which was issued to him subject to the conditions of subsection (2) of KRS 45A.600 and the availability of the handgun. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44237</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>