<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="71" order_by="71">JAILER </unit></structure><section_number>71.060</section_number><catch_line>Jail personnel. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The jailer shall be liable on his official bond for the conduct of his deputies. The deputies shall have all the powers and be subject to the same penalties as the jailer. </section><section prefix="2">The jailer shall be responsible for the appointment and removal of jail personnel, and the jailer may dismiss his deputies at any time with cause. The number of jail personnel shall be set by the fiscal court in the jail budget. The fiscal court shall establish education and training requirements as permitted by regulations adopted pursuant to KRS 441.055. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 262, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 172, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 1, effective May 18, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2237. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/92).  This section was amended by 1992 Acts chs. 95 and 262 which are in conflict. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 262 which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24269</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>