<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.320</section_number><catch_line>Examinations -- Certifications -- Preference points -- Eligible list.   </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The civil service commission shall prescribe and propound such examinations as are proper, commensurate with vacant positions within the various departments of the city, according to classification prescribed by ordinance, shall set such times and places for holding examinations as may be proper and shall give public notice of examinations by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="2">The civil service commission shall, as soon after examinations as is practicable, certify to the mayor or other appointing authority a list of the applicants so examined, with the one (1) having the highest average ranked first and all others ranked numerically according to the result of the examination. </section><section prefix="3">Any honorably discharged soldier, sailor, marine, member of the Air Force, or member of any other branch of the military service who was inducted into that service through voluntary or involuntary enlistment, and who is an applicant for any municipal civil service position, and a registered voter of that municipality, shall be entitled to a five percent (5%) increase on his examination score. Any Red Cross nurse who served during the period of hostilities between the United States and the Central Powers in World War I and between the United States and Japan and Germany in World War II, and who is a registered voter of that municipality, shall be entitled to the same percentages. Such percentages shall be added to examination scores only if the score is determined by the civil service commission to be a passing score and after verification of the required service. </section><section prefix="4">The civil service commission of cities shall maintain an eligible list of not less than three (3) for each position to be filled. </section><section prefix="5">The appointing authority may designate certain civil service positions and prescribe that for such positions the examinations shall first be given exclusively to current employees; provided, however, that if less than three (3) employees with a minimum of two (2) years seniority achieve a passing grade, the examination shall be held in accordance with subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 80, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 63. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 9. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3235h-3, 3480e-3. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43665</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>