<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-205</section_number><catch_line>Annual statement convention blank -- Immunity from prosecution. </catch_line><order_by>2-205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this section apply to all domestic, foreign, and alien insurers fraternal benefit societies, health maintenance organizations, and nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and health service corporations authorized to transact business pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each domestic, foreign, and alien insurer and fraternal benefit society, health maintenance organization, and nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and health service corporation authorized to transact business pursuant to this chapter shall annually on or before March 1 of each year file with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners a copy of its annual statement convention blank, along with additional filings as prescribed by the commissioner, for the preceding year. The information filed with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners shall be in the same format and scope as that required by the commissioner and shall include the signed jurat page and the life and health actuarial certification. Any amendments or additions to the annual statement filing subsequently filed with the commissioner shall also be filed with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners. </section><section prefix="b">Foreign insurers, health maintenance organizations, and fraternal benefit societies that are domiciled in states which have laws substantially similar to paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be deemed in compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="c">Nothing contained in this section shall be deemed to require anyone filing documents with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners to pay any filing fee for a filing. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, their duly authorized committees, subcommittees, and task forces, their delegates, National Association of Insurance Commissioners employees, and all others charged with the responsibility of collecting, reviewing, analyzing, or disseminating the information developed from the filing of the annual statement convention blanks shall not be subject to civil liability for defamation or any other cause of action by virtue of their collection, review, analysis, or dissemination of the data and information collected from the filings required by this section while acting in good faith. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 937, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>