<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.38-196</section_number><catch_line>Indemnity payable for services performed by chiropractors, physicians, osteopaths, or podiatrists. </catch_line><order_by>38-196</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any certificate, agreement or contract issued in this state by a health maintenance organization which provides coverage for any service which is within the lawful scope of practice of a chiropractor duly licensed under KRS Chapter 312, shall be deemed to provide benefits for such services whether performed by a duly licensed physician, osteopath, or chiropractor, notwithstanding any provision contained in the certificate, agreement or contract. An enrollee requesting chiropractic treatment for otherwise covered conditions shall not unreasonably be denied chiropractic treatment if treatment of the conditions is within the lawful scope of chiropractic practice. </section><section prefix="2">Any certificate, agreement, or contract issued in this state by a health maintenance organization which provides coverage for any service which is within the lawful scope of practice of a podiatrist duly licensed under KRS Chapter 311, shall be deemed to provide benefits for those services whether performed by a duly licensed physician, osteopath, chiropractor, or podiatrist, notwithstanding any provision contained in the certificate, agreement, or contract. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 466, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 399, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30000</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>