<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.125</section_number><catch_line>Condemnation of additional land adjacent to existing road -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the fiscal court of any county deems it to be in the best interest of the county to acquire additional land adjacent to an existing county road to provide for future widening and improvement of said road, and the fiscal court is unable to contract with the owners of the land required for such purposes for its purchase or to acquire the same by gift, the land may be condemned under the provisions set forth in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky.  </section><section prefix="2">The resolution authorizing condemnation shall set forth the facts of the proposed acquisition, including a description of the land sought to be acquired, which description may be stated in widths from the existing centerline of the road proposed to be improved. In condemnation for future improvement under this section it shall not be necessary for the county to have completed plans for actual construction; Provided, the property owner is furnished with an accurate description of the property sought to be condemned. The right-of-way thus obtained shall be for reasonably foreseeable future construction and improvement in conformity with the existing grade of said road and with free access to adjacent property. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 80. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>