<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.140</section_number><catch_line>Commission plan -- Duties of mayor and commission. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The form of government provided in this section shall be known as the commission plan and this section shall together with KRS 83A.010 to 83A.120 govern any city declared to be under the commission plan by KRS 83A.020 or which has adopted the commission plan pursuant to KRS 83A.160. </section><section prefix="2">Each city under this section shall be governed by an elected officer who shall be called mayor and by elected legislative body members who shall be called city commissioners and which together shall be known as the city commission and by such other officers and employees as may be provided for by statute or city ordinance. </section><section prefix="3">All legislative, executive and administrative authority of the city shall be vested in and exercised by the commission. The commission shall enforce the commission plan, ordinances and orders of the city and all applicable statutes. The commission shall maintain liaison with related units of local government respecting interlocal contracting and joint activities. The commission shall supervise all departments of city government and the conduct of all city officers and employees under its jurisdiction and may require each department to make such reports to it as it finds necessary. The commission shall report to the public on the condition and needs of the city government as provided by ordinance, but not less than annually. </section><section prefix="4">The mayor shall preside at all meetings of the commission and may vote in all proceedings. All bonds, notes, contracts and written obligations of the city authorized by ordinance or resolution shall be executed by the mayor on behalf of the city. The commission shall designate one (1) city commissioner to serve as mayor pro tem. The mayor pro tem shall act for the mayor whenever the mayor is unable to attend to the duties of his office and he shall then possess all rights, powers and duties of mayor. If the disability of the mayor to attend to his duties continues for sixty (60) consecutive days, the office of mayor may be declared vacant by a majority vote of the commission membership, and the provisions of KRS 83A.040 shall apply. </section><section prefix="5">In carrying out its duty to supervise the departments of city government and the conduct of all city officers and employees under its jurisdiction, the commission may require any city officer or employee to prepare and submit to it sworn statements regarding the performance of his official duties. </section><section prefix="6">All administrative and service functions of the city shall be classified under departments created by ordinance which shall prescribe the functions of the department and the duties and responsibilities of the department head and his employees. The commission shall at its first regular meeting in each year designate the commission member to have superintendence over each department established under this subsection, except the commission may delegate responsibility for overall supervision of any or all departments to a city administrative officer established pursuant to KRS 83A.090. </section><section prefix="7">Regular meetings of the commission shall be held at least once a month at such times and places as are fixed by ordinance. Special meetings may be called by the mayor or a majority of the city commissioners. In the call, the mayor or city commissioners shall designate the purpose, time and place of the special meeting with sufficient notice for the attendance of commission members and for compliance with KRS Chapter 61. At a special meeting no business may be considered other than that set forth in the designation of purpose. The minutes of every meeting shall be signed by the person responsible for maintaining city records provided under KRS 83A.060 and by the officer presiding at the meeting. </section><section prefix="8">The commission shall by ordinance establish all appointive offices and the duties and responsibilities of those offices and codes, rules and regulations for the public health, safety and welfare. The commission shall by ordinance provide for sufficient revenue to operate city government and shall appropriate such funds in a budget which shall provide for the orderly management of the city's resources. The commission shall promulgate procedures to insure orderly administration of the functions of city government and compliance with statute, ordinance or order. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25183</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>