<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.265</section_number><catch_line>Remedies for failure to report. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any employing unit refusing to make reports required under this chapter within ten (10) days after written notice sent by the cabinet to such employing unit's last known address by certified mail, notifying such employing unit that this section will be invoked unless such reports are filed, may be restrained or enjoined from continuing in business in this state or employing persons herein until such reports have been made. </section><section prefix="2">Any employing unit actively engaged in business in this state which is found delinquent in the payment of contributions by the cabinet, may, after ten (10) days' written notice by the cabinet sent to such employing unit's last known address by certified mail notifying such employing unit that this section will be invoked unless such delinquency is satisfied, be restrained or enjoined from continuing in business in this state or employing persons herein until such delinquency has been satisfied or until such employing unit shall have furnished bond with surety approved by the court in a sum equal to the amount of such delinquency, plus any other unpaid contributions due under this chapter and such further sum as the court shall deem adequate to protect the cabinet in the collection of contributions which may become due for the next ensuing six (6) months, said bond to be conditioned upon payment of such judgment and contributions upon such terms and at such time as the court may fix. </section><section prefix="3">Proceedings under the provisions of this section may be instituted upon complaint filed by the cabinet in the Franklin Circuit Court or any other court of competent jurisdiction in accordance with Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure, except that no bond shall be required of the Commonwealth or the cabinet. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(23). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 17. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 16, effective February 27, 1958. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32273</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>