<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.280</section_number><catch_line>Receiving alcoholic beverages from carrier in dry territory prohibited -- Exception for receiving or accepting alcoholic beverages to be sold in lawful territory within or without state -- Same prohibition on receiving alcoholic beverages in any moist territory unless sale of alcoholic beverages specifically authorized under limited local option election.   </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person of dry territory to receive or accept any alcoholic beverage from a common carrier or from any person who has transported the beverage in or into such territory for compensation, hire, or profit of any kind whatsoever either directly or indirectly. Each and every package of said alcoholic beverage so received or accepted shall constitute a separate offense. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any distiller or manufacturer of alcoholic beverages or any authorized agent of a distiller or manufacturer or wholesale dealer from receiving or accepting any alcoholic beverages which are to be sold in a territory where the sale of such beverages may be lawful either in or out of the state. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall apply to any moist territory unless the sale of the alcoholic beverage in question has been specifically authorized in that moist territory under a limited local option election. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 27, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 186, secs. 2 and 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554c-21. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>.  "Alcoholic beverage" has been substituted for "intoxicating liquor" in order to fit the definitions contained in KRS 242.010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42462</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>