<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.270</section_number><catch_line>Giving information to federal government -- Agreements with qualified parties to accept inspections of marine sanitation devices. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In accordance with any request duly made by an authorized official or agency of the United States, any information compiled or otherwise available to the department pursuant to KRS 235.250 shall be transmitted to said official or agency of the United States. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall enter into an agreement with the United States Coast Guard to accept Coast Guard inspections of vessels for the purpose of determining if the vessel's marine sanitation device is the proper kind for the water body where the vessel is kept or operated and that it is properly operating. The commissioner may enter into agreements with any other professional or qualified group, organization, or individual to accept certified inspections of vessels for the purpose of determining if the vessel's marine sanitation device is the proper kind for the water body where the vessel is kept or operated and that it is properly operating. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 71, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 19. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 29, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 23 and 71 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>