<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.030</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for registration -- Inactive status for previous registrants. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for registration shall file with the cabinet a written application for registration and submit evidence that the applicant: <section prefix="a">Has completed at least an approved four (4) year high school or the equivalent; and </section><section prefix="b">Has completed a four (4) year degree from a college or university, with a minor or twenty-four (24) semester hours in environmental health, biological science, or physical science. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant shall be required to pass a written examination in those subjects that the cabinet prescribes. Written examinations may be supplemented by an oral examination. Upon successfully passing these examinations, the applicant shall be issued a registration as an environmental health specialist or sanitarian. </section><section prefix="3">Those persons previously registered by the cabinet and not engaged in environmental health practice in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, but desiring to maintain the privilege to use the designation of environmental health specialist or "E.H.S." and sanitarian or "R.S." may apply and be granted inactive status by the cabinet in accordance with administrative regulations of the cabinet. Inactive status shall be renewed at least every two (2) years, and those persons granted inactive status shall not be governed by continuing education provisions contained in this chapter. A registered environmental health specialist or sanitarian on inactive status may petition the cabinet for renewal of registration. In that case the registrant shall meet the requirements of this chapter before being reclassified to active status. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 309, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9959</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>