<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.662</section_number><catch_line>Curation and science unit -- Functions -- Qualifications of associate director. </catch_line><order_by>662</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a curation and science unit within the Kentucky Natural History Museum. The curation and science unit shall: <section prefix="a">Collect specimens of Kentucky's extant and fossilized flora and fauna; </section><section prefix="b">Identify and inventory significant archeological sites; </section><section prefix="c">Collaborate with scientists in the state agencies, colleges and universities, and other members of the scientific community on sharing relevant data and creating common databases of biological, archeological, geological, and paleontological information; </section><section prefix="d">Catalog and maintain specimens and artifacts obtained by the museum; </section><section prefix="e">Assure the quality of specimens kept in storage, available through a loan, or displayed; </section><section prefix="f">Accept existing scientifically significant and well-preserved biological, archeological, geological, and paleontological collections that may be offered from private or public entities; and </section><section prefix="g">Conduct research and publish scientific papers related to the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666. </section></section><section prefix="2">The associate director of the curation and science unit shall have an earned doctorate in the biological, earth sciences, or anthropology with demonstrated experience in curation of biological or geological collections. </section><section prefix="3">Information that would endanger natural heritage resources by revealing their location shall be exempt from KRS 61.870 to 61.884 unless: <section prefix="a">The information is to be used for scientific research or in efforts to protect and preserve the resource; </section><section prefix="b">The person requesting the information agrees in writing to keep confidential the location of the resource; and </section><section prefix="c">The director determines that release of the information will not endanger the resource. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1554</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>