<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.491</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings regarding tax increment financing. </catch_line><order_by>491</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is found and declared that public improvements, and publicly promoted private improvements, in any development area that result in the increase in the value of property located in the development area or result in increased employment within the development area serve a public purpose for each taxing district possessing the authority, directly or indirectly, to impose ad valorem taxes, sales taxes, income taxes, or occupational license fees in the development area, and for the state with regards to its revenues from ad valorem taxes, sales taxes, and income taxes. The increment in revenues derived by each taxing district and the state from the development area is found and declared to be one of the benefits derived by each taxing district and the state from any local development project or public project undertaken by the agency; and </section><section prefix="2">It is found that the use of tax increment financing or a grant program based upon the use of increment financing as tax revenues has proved to be successful and of great benefit to areas in need of revitalization and development in other parts of the country; therefore, the development of a pilot program within the Commonwealth to test the usefulness of increment financing to assist local governments in restoring and revitalizing their communities is declared to be a most worthy public purpose. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 326, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>