<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.420</section_number><catch_line>Carrying of shipping papers and hazardous waste manifest. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person transporting hazardous materials in the Commonwealth shall carry a copy of the shipping papers required in 49 C.F.R. (1978), as amended, in the transporting vehicle while in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">In the event of an accident involving hazardous material, the operator of the vehicle shall: <section prefix="a">Notify the Department of Kentucky State Police of the accident within one (1) hour, who shall then notify the local jurisdiction and any other appropriate state agency with emergency action responsibility, and </section><section prefix="b">Provide the shipping papers to state and local emergency response authorities, and immediately bring to their attention the fact that the vehicle is transporting hazardous materials. </section></section><section prefix="3">In addition to the other requirements of this section, any person transporting hazardous wastes shall carry in the transporting vehicle a copy of a manifest in a form approved by the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 229, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 182, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>