<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="107" order_by="107">MUNICIPAL IMPROVEMENTS -- ALTERNATE METHODS </unit></structure><section_number>107.190</section_number><catch_line>Action by city with population of less than 20,000 where ordinances and proceedings encompass less than all the undertakings contemplated by KRS 107.020, where all are encompassed and city undertakes additional improvements.   </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>If the ordinances and proceedings authorized by this chapter shall encompass and include less than all of the undertakings authorized and contemplated by the definitions set forth in KRS 107.020, (i.e., a street improvement project with or without sidewalk, curb, gutter, and/or storm or surface water sewers or drains or sanitary sewers, or sewage treatment facilities or fire hydrant in cities with a population of less than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census), the city shall not be precluded from ordaining and requiring the omitted matters and structures to be constructed at the expense of the benefited properties at any time in the future, in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, or in accordance with any other applicable laws. If the improvement project shall encompass all of the elements included in the definition of "improvement" or "project" as set forth in this chapter, the city shall not thereafter undertake any project for any part of the improvements as herein defined except (a) at the exclusive cost of the city, or (b) at the cost of the benefited properties from and after fifteen (15) years after completion and acceptance of the project, or (c) from the proceeds of revenue bonds payable from service charges.  </text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 208, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 4. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 6. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43793</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>