<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.600</section_number><catch_line>Misbehavior before the enemy.   </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text>Any person subject to this code shall be punished as a court-martial may direct who, before or in the presence of the enemy or any hostile force: <section prefix="1">Runs away; </section><section prefix="2">Shamefully abandons, surrenders, or delivers up any command, unit, place, or military property which it is his or her duty to defend; </section><section prefix="3">Through disobedience, neglect, or intentional misconduct endangers the safety of any such command, unit, place, or military property; </section><section prefix="4">Casts away his or her arms or ammunition; </section><section prefix="5">Is guilty of cowardly conduct; </section><section prefix="6">Quits his or her place of duty to plunder or pillage; </section><section prefix="7">Causes false alarms in any command, unit, or place under control of the Armed Forces of the United States or the state military forces; </section><section prefix="8">Willfully fails to do his or her utmost to encounter, engage, capture, or destroy any enemy troops, combatants, vessels, aircraft, or any other thing, which it is his or her duty so to encounter, engage, capture, or destroy; or </section><section prefix="9">Does not afford all practicable relief and assistance to any troops, combatants, vessels, or aircraft of the Armed Forces belonging to the United States or their allies, to the state, or to any other state, when engaged in battle. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 103, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 76. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41984</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>