<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.290</section_number><catch_line>Failure to obey subpoena or investigative demand of Attorney General -- Revocation of corporate charter -- Revocation of licenses. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any person fails or refuses to file any statement or report, or to obey any subpoena or investigative demand issued by the Attorney General, the Attorney General may, after notice, apply to a Circuit Court and, after hearing thereon, request an order: <section prefix="a">Granting injunctive relief to restrain the person from engaging in the advertising or sale of any merchandise or the conduct of any trade or commerce that is involved in the alleged or suspected violation; and </section><section prefix="b">Vacating, annulling, or suspending the corporate charter of a corporation created by or under the laws of this Commonwealth or revoking or suspending the certificate of authority to do business in this Commonwealth of a foreign corporation or revoking or suspending any other licenses, permits or certificates issued pursuant to law to such person which are used to further the allegedly unlawful practice; and </section><section prefix="c">Granting such other relief as may be required, until the person files the statement or report, or obeys the subpoena or investigative demand. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to issuance of any final order the person charged with failing to answer the investigative demand or subpoena pursuant to KRS 367.240 or 367.250 shall be afforded an opportunity for a hearing on the merits of the demand or subpoena. Any disobedience of any final order entered under this section by any court shall be punished as a contempt thereof. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 19. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34929</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>