<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.170</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Agriculture Resources Development Authority. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Agriculture Resources Development Authority (KARDA) is created. KARDA shall serve to unify the efforts of agricultural groups working on behalf of farmers and agribusiness and shall be attached to the Office of the Governor for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The functions of KARDA shall be to: <section prefix="a">Advise the Governor and other state officials on economic development initiatives to improve the farm economy; </section><section prefix="b">Conduct long-range planning and provide continuity for agriculture and agribusiness; </section><section prefix="c">Work with the Executive Branch and the Legislative Branch on legislation, policies, and programs with specific emphasis on increasing farm income, strengthening rural communities, and ensuring the rights of all farmers; and </section><section prefix="d">Improve the flow of information from the federal and state governments and the university system to agricultural commodity organizations, their members, and the farm community in general. </section></section><section prefix="3">The membership of KARDA shall consist of twenty-three (23) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The Governor or the Governor's designee; </section><section prefix="b">Dean, College of Agriculture, University of Kentucky, or the dean's designee; </section><section prefix="c">Commissioner of Agriculture or the Commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="d">Chair, Senate Agriculture Committee; </section><section prefix="e">Chair, House Agriculture and Small Business Committee; </section><section prefix="f">President, Kentucky Farm Bureau, or the president's designee; </section><section prefix="g">Chair, Kentucky Agriculture Council, or the chair's designee; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) large-animal veterinarians nominated by the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association; </section><section prefix="i">Seven (7) members appointed by the Governor as follows: one (1) each from the seven (7) commodity-specific organizations that officially represent the agricultural commodities with the greatest cash receipts from farm marketings as reported by the Kentucky Agricultural Statistics Service by December 1 for the previous calendar year. Each of the commodity-specific organizations may submit its nomination to the Governor by March 1. If more than one (1) commodity-specific organization represents a commodity, each organization may submit a nominee, but the Governor shall determine the KARDA representative for that commodity; </section><section prefix="j">Four (4) members appointed by the Governor as follows: any Kentucky university offering a four (4) year agricultural degree or any agribusiness or agricultural association which is registered with the Secretary of State may submit one (1) nominee to the Governor by March 1. The Governor shall determine the four (4) members from the nominees submitted; and </section><section prefix="k">Four (4) members at large selected and appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="4">Initial terms of members, other than those serving ex officio, shall be staggered to provide continuity. Thereafter, terms of appointed members shall be for four (4) years, except for the representatives of the seven (7) commodity groups identified in subsection (3)(i) of this section, who shall serve one (1) year terms. </section><section prefix="5">The Governor shall designate one (1) of the members as chair. KARDA may elect by majority vote a vice chair and other officers as may be deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="6">No member of KARDA shall receive a salary, fee, or other remuneration for services as a member of KARDA, but each member shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred in the performance of duties incident to implementation of the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="7">KARDA shall meet at the call of the Governor or the chair. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="8">KARDA shall use, so far as practical, and subject to the approval of the Governor, staff of the Governor's Office to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 32, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (11/24/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 2, provides:  "To carry out the changes to the KARDA board as provided by Section 1 of this Act (this statute):  (1) The chair of the Kentucky Agriculture Council shall replace the President of the Kentucky National Farmers Organization, as required under subsection (3)(g) of Section 1 of this Act, on the effective date of this Act;  (2) The Governor shall, within 30 days of the effective date of this Act:   (a) Appoint a large animal veterinarian to replace the President of the Kentucky Bankers Association, as required under subsection (3)(h) of Section 1 of this Act;   (b) Appoint seven members representing commodity-specific organizations to replace the existing members representing agriculture commodity organizations, as required under subsection (3)(i) of Section 1 of this Act, whose terms shall expire on June 30, 2010;   (c) Appoint four members representing Kentucky universities, agribusinesses, or agricultural associations to replace the existing members representing agricultural organizations, as required by subsection (3)(j) of Section 1 of this Act, and who shall fill the unexpired terms of the existing members; and   (d) Appoint four members at large, as required by subsection (3)(k) of Section 1 of this Act; and  (3) (a) The Governor shall determine the lengths of the terms of the members appointed in accordance with subsection (2)(a) and (d) of this section in order to provide continuity of the staggered terms of the membership.   (b) The members appointed by the Governor in accordance with subsection (2)(b), (c), and (d) of this section may be existing members. It is not intended that existing members may not be appointed if they otherwise meet the qualifications required by Section 1 of this Act."  (6/25/2009).  This section was amended by 2009 Ky. Acts chs. 27 and 32, which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 27, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=544</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>