<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.610</section_number><catch_line>Payments to pension fund established under KRS 95.520 -- Disbursements -- Insufficient funds.   </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The officers of cities with pension funds established under KRS 95.520 that are designated by law to draw warrants on the city treasurer shall, on request in writing by the board of trustees of the pension fund, draw warrants on the city treasurer payable to the treasurer of the board of trustees of the pension fund for all funds belonging to the pension fund.  </section><section prefix="2">Moneys ordered paid from the pension fund to any person shall be paid by the treasurer of the board of trustees only upon warrant signed by the president of the board and countersigned by the secretary. No warrant shall be drawn except by order of the board of trustees duly entered on the records of the proceedings of the board.  </section><section prefix="3">If at any time there is not sufficient money in the pension fund to pay each beneficiary the full amount per month to which he is entitled, an equal percentage of the monthly payments due shall be paid to each until the fund is so replenished as to warrant payment in full to all beneficiaries.  </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 131, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 109. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3142b-10, 3142b-15, 3142b-16, 3351a-10, 3351a-15, 3351a-16. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>