<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.082</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary actions against license and certificate holders. </catch_line><order_by>082</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may suspend, revoke, or refuse to issue or renew a license; may accept an assurance of voluntary compliance; restrict, or place a credential holder on probation; or issue an administrative reprimand or private admonishment upon proof that the credential holder has: <section prefix="a">Committed any act involving moral turpitude, dishonesty, or corruption, relating to the practice of psychology, whether the act constitutes a crime or not. If the act constitutes a crime, conviction in a criminal proceeding is not a condition precedent to disciplinary action. Upon conviction of such a crime, the judgment and sentence is presumptive evidence at the ensuing disciplinary hearing of the guilt of the licensee or applicant of the crime described in the indictment or information and of the person's violation of the statute on which it is based. For the purpose of this subsection, conviction includes all instances in which a plea of guilty or nolo contendere is the basis for the conviction and all proceedings in which the sentence has been deferred or suspended; </section><section prefix="b">Misrepresented or concealed a material fact in obtaining a license, or in reinstatement thereof; </section><section prefix="c">Committed any unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive act or practice; </section><section prefix="d">Been incompetent or negligent in the practice of psychology; </section><section prefix="e">Practiced psychology while under the suspension, revocation, or restriction of the individual's license to practice by competent authority in any state, federal, or foreign jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="f">Violated any state statute or administrative regulation governing the practice of psychology; </section><section prefix="g">Unlawfully failed to cooperate with the board by: <section prefix="1">Not furnishing any papers or documents requested by the board; </section><section prefix="2">Not furnishing in writing a complete explanation covering the matter contained in the complaint filed with the board; </section><section prefix="3">Not appearing before the board at the time and place designated; or </section><section prefix="4">Not properly responding to subpoenas issued by the board; </section></section><section prefix="h">Failed to comply with an order issued by the board or an assurance of voluntary compliance; </section><section prefix="i">Aided or abetted an unlicensed person to practice when a license or certificate is required; </section><section prefix="j">Grossly overcharged for professional services; </section><section prefix="k">Practiced beyond the scope demonstrated by an appropriate combination of knowledge, skill, experience, training, and education; </section><section prefix="l">Failed to provide adequate supervision for certified psychologists, licensed psychological associates, applicants for licensure, or other staff; </section><section prefix="m">Been convicted of any misdemeanor or felony relating to the practice of psychology. For the purposes of this subsection, conviction includes all instances in which a plea of guilty or nolo contendere is the basis for conviction and all proceedings in which the sentence has been deferred or suspended; </section><section prefix="n">Physically abused or had sexual contact with a patient, client, student, or supervisee; </section><section prefix="o">Been convicted of a misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 510 involving a client, patient, or student, or a felony offense under KRS Chapter 510, 530.064(1)(a), or 531.310, or been found by the board to have had sexual contact as defined in KRS 510.010 with a client, patient, student, or supervisee; </section><section prefix="p">Improperly divulged confidential information; </section><section prefix="q">Exercised undue influence in such a manner as to exploit the client, patient, student, or supervisee for financial or other personal advantage to the practitioner or a third party; </section><section prefix="r">Showed an inability to practice psychology with reasonable skill and safety to patients or clients by reason of illness, misuse of drugs, narcotics, alcohol, chemicals, or any other substance, or as a result of any mental or physical condition; or </section><section prefix="s">Failed to comply with the requirements of the board for continuing education. </section></section><section prefix="2">Private admonishment shall not be subject to disclosure to the public under KRS 61.878(1)(l) and shall not constitute disciplinary action, but may be used by the board for statistical purposes or in subsequent disciplinary action against the credential holder or applicant. </section><section prefix="3">No unlawful act or violation of any provision of this chapter by any credential holder employed or supervised by a licensed psychologist shall be cause for the revocation of the supervisor's license, unless the board finds that the licensed psychologist had knowledge of it. </section><section prefix="4">Three (3) years from the date of a revocation, any person whose license has been revoked may petition the board for reinstatement. The board shall investigate his or her petition and may reinstate his or her license upon finding that the former licensee has complied with the provisions of this chapter and administrative regulations promulgated by the board and is again able to engage in the practice of psychology with reasonable skill, competency, and safety to the public. </section><section prefix="5">The board may, at its own discretion, reconsider, modify, or reverse its probations, suspensions, revocations, restrictions, or refusals to issue or renew licenses at any time. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 61, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 93, sec. 5, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 12, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  Although KRS 319.082 was included in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 8, and ch. 93, sec. 5, as having been amended, the amendment relettering paragraphs of this section in those acts became unnecessary when the Office of the Kentucky Attorney General requested that other changes be made to the rearrangement of the paragraphs of KRS 61.878, which was also amended in 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 45 and 93. The Statute Reviser made these changes under the authority of KRS 7.136.  (7/15/94).  This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>