<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5401Petition</section_number><catch_line>to establish support order.   </catch_line><order_by>5401Petition</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a support order entitled to recognition under KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902 has not been issued, a responding tribunal of this state with personal jurisdiction over the parties may issue a support order if: <section prefix="a">The individual seeking the order resides outside this state; or </section><section prefix="b">The support enforcement agency seeking the order is located outside this state. </section></section><section prefix="2">The tribunal may issue a temporary child support order if the tribunal determines that such an order is appropriate and the individual ordered to pay is: <section prefix="a">A presumed father of the child; </section><section prefix="b">Petitioning to have his paternity adjudicated; </section><section prefix="c">Identified as the father of the child through genetic testing; </section><section prefix="d">An alleged father who has declined to submit to genetic testing; </section><section prefix="e">Shown by clear and convincing evidence to be the father of the child; </section><section prefix="f">An acknowledged father as provided by KRS 213.046; </section><section prefix="g">The mother of the child; or </section><section prefix="h">An individual who has been ordered to pay child support in a previous proceeding and the order has not been reversed or vacated. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon finding, after notice and opportunity to be heard, that an obligor owes a duty of support, the tribunal shall issue a support order directed to the obligor and may issue other orders pursuant to KRS 407.5305. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 31, effective June 24, 2015. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 43, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44107</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>