<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.660</section_number><catch_line>Report required after termination of operations -- Contents -- Confidentiality of information -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person to whom a permit is issued pursuant to KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall file, within ninety (90) days after termination of operations conducted under the permit, with the department for transmittal to the Kentucky Geological Survey on forms to be furnished by the department the following information relating to the well: <section prefix="a">A copy of the driller's log certified to be true and accurate; </section><section prefix="b">The depth and thickness of all water zones encountered and logged; </section><section prefix="c">The depth of all showings of oil or gas; </section><section prefix="d">The depth and thickness of all coal seams encountered; and </section><section prefix="e">A true copy of all electrical surveys and similar logs and surveys taken. If the person to whom the permit is issued obtains a copy of the electrical survey or similar log or survey in electronic form, the operator shall submit the electrical survey or similar log in electronic form if requested by the department. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon request by the department, any person to whom a permit is issued shall save for the Kentucky Geological Survey samples of all cuttings from the well drilled or deepened pursuant to the permit for a period of ninety (90) days after completion thereof. </section><section prefix="3">Upon request by any person furnishing information under this section, the information shall be kept confidential, for a period of one (1) year after the information is furnished by such person. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall not apply to wells drilled or deepened as geological or structure test holes. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 15, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 4. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>