<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="514" order_by="514">THEFT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>514.040</section_number><catch_line>Theft by deception. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of theft by deception when the person obtains property or services of another by deception with intent to deprive the person thereof. A person deceives when the person intentionally: <section prefix="a">Creates or reinforces a false impression, including false impressions as to law, value, intention, or other state of mind; </section><section prefix="b">Prevents another from acquiring information which would affect judgment of a transaction; </section><section prefix="c">Fails to correct a false impression which the deceiver previously created or reinforced or which the deceiver knows to be influencing another to whom the person stands in a fiduciary or confidential relationship; </section><section prefix="d">Fails to disclose a known lien, adverse claim, or other legal impediment to the enjoyment of property which the person transfers or encumbers in consideration for the property obtained, whether the impediment is or is not valid or is or is not a matter of official record; or </section><section prefix="e">Issues or passes a check or similar sight order for the payment of money, knowing that it will not be honored by the drawee. </section></section><section prefix="2">The term "deceive" does not, however, include falsity as to matters having no pecuniary significance or puffing by statements unlikely to deceive ordinary persons in the group addressed. </section><section prefix="3">Deception as to a person's intention to perform a promise shall not be inferred from the fact alone that he did not subsequently perform the promise. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of subsection (1) of this section, a maker of a check or similar sight order for the payment of money is presumed to know that the check or order, other than a postdated check or order, would not be paid, if: <section prefix="a">The maker had no account with the drawee at the time the check or order was issued; or </section><section prefix="b">Payment was refused by the drawee for lack of funds, upon presentation within thirty (30) days after issue, and the maker failed to make good within ten (10) days after receiving notice of that refusal. Notice of the refusal may include a citation to this section and a description of this section's criminal penalties and shall be deemed properly addressed when mailed to the address printed or written on the check or sight order or provided by the drawer or maker upon issuance of the check or sight order. The notice, if mailed, shall be deemed received by the addressee seven (7) days after it is placed in the United States mail. The notice may be sent by first-class mail if supported by an affidavit of service setting out the contents of the notice, the address to which the notice was mailed, that correct postage was applied, and the date the notice was placed in the United States mail. A maker makes good on a check or similar sight order for the payment of money by paying to the holder the face amount of the instrument, together with any merchant's posted bad check handling fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50) and any fee imposed pursuant to subsection (5) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="5">If a county attorney issues notice to a maker that a drawee has refused to honor an instrument due to a lack of funds as described in subsection (4)(b) of this section, the county attorney may charge a fee to the maker of fifty dollars ($50), if the instrument is paid. Money paid to the county attorney pursuant to this section shall be used only for payment of county attorney office operating expenses. Excess fees held by the county attorney on June 30 of each year shall be turned over to the county treasurer before the end of the next fiscal year for use by the fiscal court of the county. </section><section prefix="6">A person is guilty of theft by deception when the person issues a check or similar sight order in payment of all or any part of any tax payable to the Commonwealth knowing that it will not be honored by the drawee. </section><section prefix="7">A person is guilty of theft by deception when the person issues a check or similar sight order in payment of all or any part of a child support obligation knowing that it will not be honored by the drawee. </section><section prefix="8">Theft by deception is a Class A misdemeanor unless the value of the property, service, or the amount of the check or sight order referred to in subsection (6) or (7) of this section is: <section prefix="a">Five hundred dollars ($500) or more but less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), in which case it is a Class D felony; or </section><section prefix="b">Ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more, in which case it is a Class C felony. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 465, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 451, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 305, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 120, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>