<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-020</section_number><catch_line>Advisory committee for agricultural chemical and chemical container disposal program. </catch_line><order_by>50-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the cabinet shall organize an advisory committee to assist in the creation and implementation of a statewide agricultural chemical and chemical container collection and disposal program. The advisory committee shall be composed of representatives from the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture, the Kentucky Department of Agriculture, conservation districts, and any other agricultural organizations such as the Kentucky Farm Bureau, or state or federal agency which the secretary believes would be beneficial to the program. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The advisory committee shall assist the Division of Waste Management in the development of a comprehensive, cost-effective program for the statewide collection and disposal of agricultural chemicals and containers. This program shall include definitions for the types and quantities of chemicals that will be accepted and those persons or groups qualified to participate. The division is authorized to receive and expend funds for implementation of this program as funds become available. </section><section prefix="b">No person shall be cited for a pesticide release that occurs in the course of a chemical collection and disposal program operated under this subchapter, unless the release is the result of gross negligence or intentional misconduct. </section></section></text><history> Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10464</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>