<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.35-020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Research and Development Infrastructure -- Location of research centers -- Integration of basic research centers and applied research centers. </catch_line><order_by>35-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc., is authorized to establish the Kentucky Research and Development Infrastructure in accordance with guidelines developed and adopted by the Cabinet for Economic Development and the council. The infrastructure, subject to qualification by the contracting universities in accordance with agreements between the council and the universities, shall consist of up to two (2) basic research centers and up to six (6) applied research centers located as follows: <section prefix="a">A basic research center under contract with the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">A basic research center under contract with the University of Louisville; </section><section prefix="c">An applied research center to serve the central Kentucky area under contract with the University of Kentucky and Eastern Kentucky University; </section><section prefix="d">An applied research center to serve the west central Kentucky area under contract with the University of Louisville and Kentucky State University; </section><section prefix="e">An applied research center to serve the eastern Kentucky area under contract with Morehead State University; </section><section prefix="f">An applied research center to serve the western Kentucky area under contract with Western Kentucky University; </section><section prefix="g">An applied research center to serve the far western Kentucky area under contract with Murray State University; and </section><section prefix="h">An applied research center to serve the northern Kentucky area under contract with Northern Kentucky University. </section></section><section prefix="2">The basic research centers under contract with the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville may be integrated with the applied research centers under contract with those institutions. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2905</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>