<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="43" order_by="43">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS </unit></structure><section_number>43.090</section_number><catch_line>Reports of audits and investigations -- Implementation by agency of audit recommendation. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Immediately upon completion of each audit and investigation, except those provided for in KRS 43.070, the Auditor shall prepare a report of his findings and recommendations. He shall furnish one (1) copy of the report to the head of the agency to which the report pertains, one (1) copy to the Governor, one (1) copy to the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, one (1) copy to the Legislative Research Commission, and one (1) copy to the state librarian. The agency to which an Auditor's draft report pertains shall respond in writing to any adverse or critical audit findings and to any recommendations contained in the draft report within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the draft report. The Auditor shall distribute the agency's response to those entitled by this subsection to a copy of the audit report. Within sixty (60) days of the completion of the final audit report, the agency to which an Auditor's report pertains shall notify the Legislative Research Commission and the Auditor of the audit recommendations it has implemented and of the audit recommendations it has not implemented. The agency shall state the reasons for its failure to implement any recommendation made in the final audit report. The Auditor shall prepare and transmit to each member of the General Assembly, by December 15 immediately preceding the convening of each regular session of the General Assembly, a printed report of his activities summarizing the findings and recommendations in his report on each audit or investigation made since the last preceding biennial report to the General Assembly listing, by state agency, the audit recommendations that have not been implemented and the reasons given by state agencies for nonimplementation, and presenting such other findings and recommendations as he sees fit to make. He shall file a copy of this report with the Governor and five (5) copies with the state librarian. All audit reports shall be public documents to which taxpayers shall have access. </section><section prefix="2">The Auditor shall, within a reasonable time after the examination of each county as provided in KRS 43.070, make a written report to the Governor, the General Assembly, the Attorney General, the state librarian, and the fiscal court and county attorney of the county examined, calling attention in specific terms to any mismanagement, misconduct, misapplication or illegal appropriation, or extravagant use of money received or disbursed by any officer of the county examined. In addition, said report shall be sent to a newspaper having general circulation in the county examined, and the letter of transmittal accompanying the report shall be published in said newspaper in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 424. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 25, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 9. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 52. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 139, secs. 1 and 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1992b-59, 4618-135, 4636-4. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22121</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>