<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.420</section_number><catch_line>Bond conditions for person, firm, or corporation offering textbooks. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text>The bond required by the person, firm, or corporation offering the books for adoption shall be so conditioned that: <section prefix="1">The person, firm, or corporation will furnish any of the books listed in the statement filed for the period of adoption from the date of the bond to any school district in Kentucky, or to any dealer appointed by the district, at the lowest wholesale price contained in the statement, f.o.b. the publisher's nearest shipping point; </section><section prefix="2">The person, firm, or corporation shall not bid and enter into a contract for an adoption period with the Commonwealth of Kentucky for books at a higher wholesale price than is being bid for the same adoption period elsewhere in the United States. </section><section prefix="3">The person, firm, or corporation will automatically reduce such prices in Kentucky whenever reductions are made anywhere in the United States, so that no book shall at any time be sold in Kentucky at a higher wholesale price than is received for that book elsewhere in the United States; </section><section prefix="4">If the person, firm, or corporation prepared an abridged or special edition of any book that has been listed and sells it elsewhere at a lower wholesale price than the wholesale price set out in the filed statement, the person will file a copy of the special edition with the price of the special edition in a supplemental statement with the chief state school officer; </section><section prefix="5">All books sold in Kentucky will be identical with the specimen books filed with the chief state school officer as regards size, paper, binding, print, illustrations, subject matter, and other particulars which may affect the value of the books; </section><section prefix="6">The person, firm, or corporation shall not enter into any agreement, understanding, or combination to control the price of textbooks or to restrict competition in their sale in Kentucky. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 150, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3181</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>