<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.150</section_number><catch_line>Lien of employees on property of a mine, railroad, public improvement company, manufacturing establishment or other business -- Of persons furnishing supplies for operation of a railroad. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the property or effects of any mine, railroad or canal, or other public improvement company, or of any rolling mill, foundry or other manufacturing establishment, or of any other business, whether incorporated or not, are assigned for the benefit of, or are to be distributed among creditors, whether by operation of law or by its own act, the employees of the owner or operator of the business shall have a lien upon the property and effects which have been involved in the business and upon the accessories connected therewith, including any interest in real property used in carrying on the business. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has furnished materials or supplies for carrying on or operating any railroad shall likewise have a lien upon the property of the company involved in the business and upon the accessories connected therewith, including the interest of the company in the real property used in carrying on the business. </section></text><history>Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2487. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1952</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35297</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>