<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.867</section_number><catch_line>Acquisition of billboards by state -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>867</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner of the Department of Highways is authorized to acquire by purchase, gift, or condemnation pursuant to the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky and shall pay just compensation upon the removal of the following advertising devices: <section prefix="a">Those lawfully in existence on October 22, 1965; </section><section prefix="b">Those lawfully on any highway designated a part of the interstate or federal-aid primary system on or after October 22, 1965, and before January 1, 1968; </section><section prefix="c">Those lawfully erected on or after January 1, 1968; </section><section prefix="d">Those lawfully in existence on January 1, 1976; and </section><section prefix="e">Those lawfully erected or maintained, or both, between January 1, 1976, and December 31, 1989. </section></section><section prefix="2">Compensation shall be paid for the following: <section prefix="a">The taking from the owner of any such advertising device of all right, title, leasehold, and interest in such advertising device; and </section><section prefix="b">The taking from the owner of the real property on which the advertising device is located, of the right to erect and maintain such advertising devices thereon. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 3, effective April 9, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective March 29, 1976; and ch. 140, sec. 77. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 3. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>April 9, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5382</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>