<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.800</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth Virtual University -- Distance Learning Advisory Committee -- Role of council -- Institutions involved in program. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth Virtual University shall be the academic programs made available to the citizens of the Commonwealth through the use of modern methods of communications and information dissemination as determined by the Council on Postsecondary Education after consideration of the recommendations of the Distance Learning Advisory Committee and the needs expressed by the regional advisory groups. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall establish a Distance Learning Advisory Committee to advise the council on matters relating to the Commonwealth Virtual University. The members of the advisory committee shall include the presidents of each of the nine (9) state postsecondary education institutions, the executive director of the Kentucky Educational Television Network, a representative of the Association of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities, and other representatives as the council deems appropriate. The committee shall elect its chair and other officers as it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="3">The council, after receiving the recommendations of the Distance Learning Advisory Committee, shall establish policies to control and promote the use of distance learning systems to be used by the Commonwealth Virtual University to increase the availability of all postsecondary education programs throughout the state in the most efficient manner. The comprehensive universities shall be the primary developers and deliverers of baccalaureate and master's degree programs to be delivered by the Commonwealth Virtual University; however, this does not preclude the University of Kentucky, the University of Louisville, or independent colleges from offering baccalaureate and master's degree programs or other course offerings, and community colleges and technical institutions from offering associate and technical degree programs or other courses through the Commonwealth Virtual University. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall determine the allocation of tuition, course offerings, source of courses, technology to be used, and other matters relating to the use of distance learning to promote education through the Commonwealth Virtual University. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 16, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4464</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>