<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.075</section_number><catch_line>Criminal Justice Council -- Membership -- Duties -- Administrative support. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Criminal Justice Council is hereby created within the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the council shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, who shall serve as the chair; </section><section prefix="b">The Attorney General or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">The chair of the Judiciary Committee of the House of Representatives or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="d">The chair of the Judiciary Committee of the Senate or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="e">The executive director of the Administrative Office of the Courts or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="f">The president of the Kentucky Association of Criminal Defense Lawyers or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="g">The deputy secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, who shall serve as the deputy chair; </section><section prefix="h">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="i">The commissioner of the Department of Criminal Justice Training or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="j">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="k">The commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="l">A representative of the County Attorneys Association; </section><section prefix="m">The Public Advocate of Kentucky or his or her designee; and </section><section prefix="n">A representative of the Commonwealth's Attorneys Association. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall undertake such research and other activities as may be authorized or directed by: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; or </section><section prefix="b">The General Assembly. </section></section><section prefix="4">Each member of the council shall have one (1) vote. Members of the council shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties. The council shall meet on the call of its chair. </section><section prefix="5">A simple majority of the members of the council shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business at a meeting. </section><section prefix="6">The council is authorized to establish committees and appoint additional persons who may not be members of the council, as necessary to effectuate its purposes. </section><section prefix="7">The council's administrative functions shall be performed by the executive director of the Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services, appointed by the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet and supported by the administrative, clerical, and other staff as allowed by budgetary limitations and as needed to fulfill the council's role and mission and to coordinate its activities. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 37, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 37, proposed to create this section relating to the Criminal Justice Council within the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet as a new section of KRS Chapter 15. However, since KRS Chapter 15 relates to the Department of Law and KRS Chapter 15A relates to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a), the Reviser of Statutes in codification has placed this section in KRS Chapter 15A rather than KRS Chapter 15. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1040</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>