<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.710</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 210.710 to 210.760.   </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">"Facility" means a hospital or other institution operated or utilized by the cabinet for the mentally ill, individuals with an intellectual disability, or respiratory disease patients. </section><section prefix="3">"Homestead" means a place where a family makes its home including the land, house and furnishings, outbuildings, vehicles, and tools of the trade formerly occupied by the patient which is exempted by KRS 210.710 to 210.760 from liability to meet patient charges for services rendered in a facility. </section><section prefix="4">"Means test" means a uniform method adopted by the secretary for determining the ability to pay of the patient or person responsible for the patient for board, maintenance and treatment at a facility operated or utilized by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="5">"Person responsible for the patient" includes parents, spouses, guardians, and committees within the scope of their fiduciary duties. </section><section prefix="6">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 94, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 337, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 281, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40822</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>