<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.9-010</section_number><catch_line>Authority to transact business required -- Certificate of authority required for award of state contract -- Exception for foreign insurer.   </catch_line><order_by>9-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A foreign entity shall not transact business in this Commonwealth until it obtains a certificate of authority from the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">The following activities, among others, shall not constitute transacting business within the meaning of subsection (1) of this section: <section prefix="a">Maintaining, defending, or settling any proceeding; </section><section prefix="b">Holding meetings of the board of directors, shareholders, partners, members, managers, beneficial owners, or trustees or carrying on other activities concerning the internal affairs of the foreign entity; </section><section prefix="c">Maintaining bank accounts; </section><section prefix="d">Maintaining offices or agencies for the transfer, exchange, and registration of the foreign entity's own securities or maintaining trustees or depositaries with respect to those securities; </section><section prefix="e">Selling through independent contractors; </section><section prefix="f">Soliciting or obtaining orders, whether by mail or through employees, agents, or otherwise, if the orders require acceptance outside this state before they become contracts; </section><section prefix="g">Creating or acquiring indebtedness, mortgages, and security interests in real, personal, or intangible property; </section><section prefix="h">Securing or collecting debts or enforcing mortgages and security interests in property securing the debts; </section><section prefix="i">Owning, without more, real or personal property; </section><section prefix="j">Conducting an isolated transaction that is completed within thirty (30) days and that is not one (1) in the course of repeated transactions of a like nature; and </section><section prefix="k">Transacting business in interstate commerce. </section></section><section prefix="3">The list of activities in subsection (2) of this section is not exhaustive. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in subsection (6) of this section, this section shall not apply to foreign general partnerships. Whether a foreign limited liability partnership is transacting business in this Commonwealth shall be determined under subsection (2) of this section. A foreign limited liability partnership that is transacting business in this Commonwealth shall file a statement of foreign qualification pursuant to KRS 362.1-951. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not apply in determining the contacts or activities that may subject a foreign entity to service of process or taxation in this Commonwealth or to regulation under any other law of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any other law to the contrary, a foreign entity, in order to be eligible for award of a state contract under KRS Chapter 45A or 176, shall have a certificate of authority or a statement of foreign qualification. </section><section prefix="7">A foreign insurer with a certificate of authority from the commissioner of the Department of Insurance is not subject to subsection (1) or (6) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 84, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 40, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  The word "contracts" in subsection (5) of this statute has been changed in codification to "contacts." This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>