<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-310</section_number><catch_line>Family expense health insurance. </catch_line><order_by>17-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Family expense health insurance is that provided under a policy issued to one (1) of the family members insured, who shall be deemed the policyholder, covering any two (2) or more eligible members of a family, including husband, wife, unmarried dependent children, to age nineteen (19), unmarried children from nineteen (19) to twenty-five (25) years of age who are full-time students enrolled in and attending an accredited educational institution and who are primarily dependent on the policyholder for maintenance and support, and any other person dependent upon the policyholder. Any authorized health insurer may issue the insurance. </section><section prefix="2">An individual hospital or medical expense insurance policy or hospital or medical service plan contract delivered or issued for delivery in this state more than 120 days after June 13, 1968, which provides that coverage of a dependent child shall terminate upon attainment of the limiting age for dependent children specified in the policy or contract shall also provide in substance that attainment of the limiting age shall not operate to terminate the coverage of the child while the child is and continues to be both (a) incapable of self-sustaining employment by reason of an intellectual or physical disability and (b) chiefly dependent upon the policyholder or subscriber for support and maintenance, provided proof of the incapacity and dependency is furnished to the insurer or corporation by the policyholder or subscriber within thirty-one (31) days of the child's attainment of the limiting age and subsequently as may be required by the insurer or corporation but not more frequently than annually after the two (2) year period following the child's attainment of the limiting age. </section><section prefix="3">Insurers offering family expense health insurance shall offer the applicant the option to purchase coverage for unmarried dependent children until age twenty-five (25). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 27, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 82, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 17, sec. 31, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17320</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>