<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.497</section_number><catch_line>Exemption for sales by schools, school-sponsored clubs and organizations or affiliated groups, certain nonprofit educational youth programs, and federally chartered education-related corporation at annual national convention held in state. </catch_line><order_by>497</order_by><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the taxes imposed herein do not apply to: <section prefix="1">Sales by elementary or secondary schools or nonprofit elementary or secondary school-sponsored clubs and organizations or any nonprofit, elementary, or secondary school-affiliated groups such as parent-teacher organizations and booster clubs, whose membership may be composed of individuals other than students, provided the net proceeds from the sales are used solely for the benefit of the elementary or secondary school or its students. Nontaxable sales shall include sales resulting from agreements or contracts entered into with resident or nonresident organizations to participate in fund-raising campaigns for a percentage of the gross receipts where students act as agents or salesmen for the organizations by selling or taking orders for the sale of tangible personal property, and no one shall be required to pay sales or use taxes on such sales; </section><section prefix="2">Sales made by nonprofit educational youth programs affiliated with a land grant university cooperative extension service, if the net proceeds from the sales are used solely for the benefit of the affiliated programs; or </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Sales of tangible personal property made by a federally chartered corporation at the corporation's annual national convention held in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="b">As used in this subsection, "federally chartered corporation" means a corporation federally chartered under Title 36 of the United States Code and whose stated purpose is to serve students and former students of vocational agriculture in middle and secondary schools to develop character, train for useful citizenship, and foster patriotism. </section><section prefix="c">The exemption provided in this subsection applies to sales made on and after October 1, 2014, but before December 31, 2021. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 361, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43427</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>