<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.140</section_number><catch_line>Certification for retired peace officer to carry concealed deadly weapon -- Administrative regulations -- Requirements -- Firearms instruction. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Certification for a retired peace officer to carry a concealed deadly weapon pursuant to KRS 237.138 to 237.142 shall be administered by the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="b">Costs of certification shall be paid for by moneys generated by the concealed deadly weapon license program under KRS 15.383 and collected by the Department of Kentucky State Police pursuant to that section. </section><section prefix="c">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A necessary to implement the provisions of KRS 237.138 to 237.142. The regulations shall allow the validity of any license or certifying documentation issued to the retired peace officer under this section to be extended in yearly increments not more than four (4) times. To facilitate this objective, the regulations may authorize the material required by subsection (2) of this section to be submitted to the person supervising the firearms qualifications under subsection (4)(b) of this section, with that person then submitting the material to the Department of Kentucky State Police and signing the license or certification in a manner that satisfies the requirements of federal law as to the retiree's passage of the required yearly firearms testing. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each retired peace officer who desires certification to carry a concealed deadly weapon shall annually submit: <section prefix="a">Evidence of retired status to the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police together with all information required by federal law, this section, and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this section; </section><section prefix="b">Evidence of successful completion of firearms qualification required under this section; and </section><section prefix="c">A notarized statement that he or she is not prohibited by state or federal law from possessing a firearm. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each law enforcement agency that employed the retired peace officer, or at which the retired peace officer served in an elected capacity, shall provide to the retired officer and the Department of Kentucky State Police the information required by federal law, this section, and the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this section in a prompt and efficient manner, without charge either to the Department of Kentucky State Police or the retiree. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Each retired peace officer shall annually fire twenty (20) rounds at an adult size silhouette target at a range of twenty-one (21) feet, with a handgun, and shall hit the target not less than eleven (11) times to obtain or maintain certification under KRS 237.138 to 237.142. </section><section prefix="b">The rounds fired pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be done under the supervision of: <section prefix="1">A firearms instructor of the retiree's former employing agency; </section><section prefix="2">A currently certified peace officer who has successfully completed a Kentucky Law Enforcement Council approved firearms instructor course; </section><section prefix="3">A Department of Criminal Justice Training certified police firearms instructor or instructor trainer; or </section><section prefix="4">A Department of Criminal Justice Training certified concealed carry instructor or instructor trainer. </section></section><section prefix="c">A firearms instructor may, if not compensated pursuant to paragraph (d) of this subsection, charge each participant a fee of not more than twenty dollars ($20), which shall include the cost of the range, firearms instructor, range personnel, targets, and all other costs associated therewith, but not the cost of ammunition. Ammunition, or the cost of ammunition, shall be provided by the retiree. </section><section prefix="d">A local or state law enforcement agency that desires to conduct firearms qualification for its retirees shall schedule not less than two (2) dates for firearms qualification per year, and those dates shall be approximately six (6) months apart. The local or state law enforcement agency may charge each participant a fee of not more than twenty dollars ($20), which shall include the cost of use of the range, firearms instructor, range personnel, targets, and all other costs associated therewith, but not the cost of ammunition. Ammunition, or the cost of ammunition, shall be provided by the retiree. </section><section prefix="e">No employer or appointing authority of a firearms instructor who has successfully completed a Kentucky Law Enforcement Council approved firearms instructor course, Department of Criminal Justice Training certified police firearms instructor or instructor trainer, or Department of Criminal Justice Training certified concealed carry instructor or instructor trainer shall prohibit or in any way limit the instructor from qualifying active or retired peace officers in conformity with KRS 237.138 or 237.142 while that instructor is off duty. No employer or appointing authority of an instructor specified in this paragraph shall be liable in civil damages for the actions or omissions of the instructor during qualification of active or retired peace officers when that instructor is off duty. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 270, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 12, effective March 31, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43446</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>