<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="109" order_by="109">LOCAL SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>109.011</section_number><catch_line>Findings and declaration of purpose -- Intent. </catch_line><order_by>011</order_by><text>The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby finds, determines, and declares, as follows: <section prefix="1">That an ever-increasing volume of solid waste both within and outside the Commonwealth is being generated as a result of increasing economic and commercial activity, continuing technological progress, and changes in methods of manufacturing, packaging, and marketing of consumer products, which results in additional solid wastes discarded by the users of these products; </section><section prefix="2">That the continued economic and population growth of the Commonwealth has required increased industrial and commercial expansion and has made necessary the demolition of obsolete structures, the construction of new structures, the provision of highways and other avenues of transportation, and the construction and installation of public works which, together with pre-existing commercial, industrial, and agricultural operations, have resulted in the generation of further volumes of solid waste; </section><section prefix="3">That the handling of solid wastes has been primarily carried out through the dumping of wastes on open soil and in landfills, which in some cases are inimical to the public health, safety, and welfare; </section><section prefix="4">That by the enactment by the Congress of the United States of the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act of 1976 (Public Law 94-580), as amended, the collection, sanitary disposal, and recovery of solid waste has been determined to be a matter of nationwide importance, recognizing that the management of solid waste should continue to be primarily the function of state, regional, and local agencies; and that pursuant to this federal law, the Commonwealth has taken and will take certain actions in respect to the planning and implementation of solid waste plans within the guidelines of time requirements set forth in this federal law; </section><section prefix="5">That as a result of the conditions described in the foregoing findings, problems of solid waste collection, management, and treatment, and resource recovery activities in connection therewith have become a matter of statewide concern necessitating action by the General Assembly to: <section prefix="a">Enable responsible planning and management agencies to be created to define solid waste management requirements, with all of the foregoing subject to regulation by the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Assist those units of government primarily responsible for the management of solid waste and the acquisition, financing and operation of facilities to dispose of solid waste to fulfill their functions in a responsible and proper manner with primary emphasis on the regionalization of these functions; and </section><section prefix="c">Reduce the amount of solid waste generated and disposed in Kentucky; </section></section><section prefix="6">That it is the intent of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that the primary responsibility for adequate solid waste collection, management, treatment, disposal, and resource recovery shall rest with combinations of counties and waste management districts, subject to standards set by administrative regulations adopted by the Energy and Environment Cabinet. In those cities currently operating solid waste management systems, the city and county may assume joint responsibility of preparing a solid waste management plan. If it is in the best public interest to do so and with the mutual agreement of both the county and city, a county may delegate responsibility for adequate collection, management, treatment, disposal, or materials recovery to a city. This delegation of responsibility is contingent upon the approval of a solid waste management plan by the cabinet. The purpose of delegating responsibilities shall be to effectuate the safe and sanitary management, use, and handling of solid waste, the protection of the health, welfare, and safety of the citizens and inhabitants of the Commonwealth, and for making the most efficient use of all resources for the benefit of the citizens and inhabitants of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="7">That the General Assembly recognizes the generation of solid waste is inevitable, but much of it is unnecessary and should be discouraged. However, where solid waste does exist, it should be considered to the extent possible as a valuable resource, and be made use of wherever and whenever desirable and economically justifiable. Therefore, it shall be the policy of the Commonwealth to, above all things, encourage resource conservation and preservation of our natural resources before waste contributes in a needless fashion to the volumes of solid waste and litter produced by our society; but in dealing with existing solid waste, materials recovery from the solid waste stream is deemed to be the most environmentally sound alternative for handling waste; </section><section prefix="8">It is not the intent of this chapter to prohibit or discourage the participation of the private sector in any aspect of solid waste management. Moreover, it is preferable for solid waste management functions to be performed by the private sector when it is in the best interests of the public and conforms with the policies and provisions in this chapter; </section><section prefix="9">It is the intent of the General Assembly that counties and waste management districts cooperate to develop and implement the solid waste management plans mandated by KRS Chapter 224 and the administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet with the goal of regionalizing the management of solid waste; </section><section prefix="10">It is the intent of the General Assembly that waste requiring disposal in municipal solid waste disposal facilities be reduced and that solid waste be managed in an environmentally protective manner; </section><section prefix="11">Notwithstanding any provision of KRS Chapters 82, 83, and 94, it is the intent of the General Assembly that this chapter and KRS 67.083(3)(o) provide counties with authority to develop a solid waste management system for solid waste generated within the geographical boundaries of the county, consistent with the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 224. It is further the intent of the General Assembly that cities be authorized to finance, own, and operate solid waste management systems with the consent of the county or by contract with the county, except that in the event a county fails to submit a solid waste management plan pursuant to KRS Chapter 224 cities may proceed to develop solid waste management systems consistent with administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet pursuant to KRS Chapter 224. Cities that develop solid waste management facilities pursuant to this section shall have all the powers and restrictions set forth for counties in KRS 109.041, 109.056, and 109.059; and </section><section prefix="12">It is the intent of the General Assembly that waste management districts which are formed and operated under this chapter shall comply with the standards set by administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet pursuant to KRS Chapter 224. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 89, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 29, effective February 26, 1991. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 60, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 398, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27245</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>