<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.920</section_number><catch_line>Additional powers. </catch_line><order_by>920</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The committee, while in the discharge of its official duties, shall have the following additional powers: <section prefix="a">To subpoena and examine witnesses; to require the appearance of any person and the production of any paper or document; to order the appearance of any person for the purpose of producing any paper or document; and to issue all process necessary to compel such appearance or production. When such process has been served, the committee may compel obedience thereto by the attachment of the person, papers or records subpoenaed; </section><section prefix="b">If any person fails or refuses to testify or furnish documentary evidence concerning any matter with respect to which the committee desires information pertaining to the studies in which it is engaged, the Franklin Circuit Court, on application of the committee, may compel obedience by proceedings for contempt as in the case of disobedience of a subpoena issued from the Circuit Court or a refusal to testify therein; </section><section prefix="c">To administer oaths to witnesses appearing before the committee when, by a majority vote, the committee deems the administration of an oath necessary and advisable as provided by law; and </section><section prefix="d">To determine that a witness has perjured himself by testifying falsely before the committee, and to institute appropriate penal proceedings as provided by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each witness who appears before the committee by its order, other than officer or employee of the state, shall be entitled to the fees and mileage provided for witnesses in civil cases in Circuit Courts, which shall be audited and paid upon the presentation of proper vouchers sworn to by such witnesses and approved by the chairman of the committee. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 4, effective March 30, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=416</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>