<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.335</section_number><catch_line>Reasons regulation found deficient shall not be considered deficient. </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An administrative regulation found deficient by a subcommittee shall not be considered deficient if: <section prefix="a">A subsequent amendment of that administrative regulation is filed with the Commission by the administrative body; </section><section prefix="b">The subcommittee that found the administrative regulation deficient approves a motion that the subsequent amendment corrects the deficiency; and </section><section prefix="c">Any subcommittee that reviews the administrative regulation under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A finds that the administrative regulation is not deficient. </section></section><section prefix="2">An administrative regulation found deficient by the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee shall not be considered deficient if: <section prefix="a">The administrative regulation is amended to correct the deficiency at a meeting of the subcommittee to which it was assigned by the Commission; </section><section prefix="b">That subcommittee does not determine that the administrative regulation is deficient for any other reason; and </section><section prefix="c">The Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee approves a motion that the deficiency has been corrected and that the administrative regulation should not be considered deficient. </section></section><section prefix="3">An administrative regulation found deficient by a subcommittee shall not be considered deficient if the subcommittee: <section prefix="a">Reconsiders the administrative regulation and its finding of deficiency; and </section><section prefix="b">Approves a motion that the administrative regulation is not deficient. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">If an existing administrative regulation has been amended and found deficient by a subcommittee, it shall not be considered deficient if the: <section prefix="1">Administrative regulation was found deficient due to the amendment; </section><section prefix="2">Promulgating administrative body has withdrawn the proposed amendment of the existing administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="3">Regulations compiler has not received the Governor's determination pursuant to KRS 13A.330 or 13A.331. </section></section><section prefix="b">If an administrative regulation has been found deficient by a subcommittee, the regulations compiler shall add the following notice to the administrative regulation: "This administrative regulation was found deficient by the [name of subcommittee] on [date]." This notice shall be the last section of the administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="c">If an administrative regulation has been found deficient by a subcommittee, subsequent amendments of that administrative regulation filed with the Commission shall contain the notice provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="d">If an administrative regulation that has been found deficient by a subcommittee has subsequently been determined not to be deficient under the provisions of this section, the regulations compiler shall delete the notice required by paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 23, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 21, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=776</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>