<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.472</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Traumatic Brain Injury Trust Fund Board. </catch_line><order_by>472</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Traumatic Brain Injury Trust Fund Board is hereby created for the purpose of administering the trust fund. The board shall be composed of nine (9) members including the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the secretary's designee, the executive director of the Brain Injury Association of Kentucky or the executive director's designee, the state medical epidemiologist, and the following members, to be appointed by the Governor: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be a neurosurgeon; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a neuropsychologist or psychiatrist; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a rehabilitation specialist; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be a social worker experienced in working with brain-injured individuals; and </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) members shall be family members of or individuals with a brain injury. </section></section><section prefix="2">Board members shall not be compensated for serving, but shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="3">The terms of appointed board members shall be four (4) years, except that the terms of initial members shall be staggered to end as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) on June 30, 2000; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) on June 30, 2001; and </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) on June 30, 2002. </section></section><section prefix="4">At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member who is appointed after a term has begun shall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member who serves two (2) consecutive four (4) year terms shall not be reappointed for four (4) years after completion of those terms. </section><section prefix="5">A majority of the full authorized membership shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall elect, by a majority vote, a director who shall be the presiding officer of the board, preside at all meetings, and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The director shall be elected or reelected for each calendar year. </section><section prefix="7">The board may establish any organizational structure it determines is necessary to accomplish its functions and duties, including the hiring of any necessary support personnel. The administrative costs of the board shall be limited to three percent (3%) of the proceeds from the trust fund. </section><section prefix="8">Meetings of the board shall be held at least twice a year but may be held more frequently, as deemed necessary, subject to call by the director or by the request of a majority of the board members. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall be attached to the cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 360, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8413</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>