<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.056</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions upon specified campaign contributors. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person who contributes more than the maximum legal contribution established by KRS 121.150 in any one (1) election to a slate of candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor that is elected to office shall hold any appointive state office or position, which shall be made by gubernatorial appointment, during the term of office following the campaign in which the contribution shall be made. </section><section prefix="2">No person who has contributed more than the maximum legal contribution established by KRS 121.150 in any one (1) election to a slate of candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor that is elected to office or any entity in which such a person has a substantial interest shall have any contract with the Commonwealth of Kentucky during the term of office following the campaign in which the contributions shall be made unless the contract shall be attained by competitive bidding and the person or entity shall have the lowest and best bid. <section prefix="a">"Substantial interest" means the person making the contribution owns or controls ten percent (10%) or more of an entity or a member of the person's immediate family owns or controls ten percent (10%) of the entity or the person and his immediate family together own or control ten percent (10%) or more of the entity. </section><section prefix="b">"Immediate family" means the spouse of the person, the parent of the person or spouse, or the child of the person or spouse. </section></section><section prefix="3">No person shall give or conspire to contribute money or property to any other person for the purpose of making a campaign contribution, in violation of this section. The restrictions established by subsections (1) and (2) of this section to a person who shall contribute in excess of the maximum legal contribution established by KRS 121.150 in any one (1) election as provided by those subsections, shall apply to a person who makes a total contribution in excess of the maximum legal contribution established by KRS 121.150 in any one (1) election to a slate of candidates for Governor and Lieutenant Governor that is elected to office as provided by this subsection. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 3, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 24, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective 1991. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27855</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>