<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.805</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of commission -- Duties and functions. </catch_line><order_by>805</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission shall be dedicated to the preservation and protection of all meaningful vestiges of Kentucky's African-American heritage. </section><section prefix="2">The duties and functions of the commission shall be to: <section prefix="a">Advise the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet and agencies within the cabinet on matters relating to African-American heritage; </section><section prefix="b">Encourage other public and private agencies within the areas of the arts, the humanities, and the sciences to incorporate the African-American influence when developing programs on the history and heritage of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Represent a network of groups and individuals interested or involved in promoting awareness of African-American heritage in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Advocate the preservation, conservation, and interpretation of significant buildings, sites, neighborhoods, documents, artifacts, and lifeways that represent and embody African-American heritage; </section><section prefix="e">Recognize and sanction projects which advance wider knowledge of African-Americans' impact on life in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="f">Coordinate an initiative to protect, preserve, and promote the history of the Underground Railroad in Kentucky, in accordance with KRS 171.812. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 48, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 112, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4864</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>