<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">A KENTUCKY UNIFORM UNINCORPORATED NONPROFIT ASSOCIATION ACT </unit></structure><section_number>273A.110</section_number><catch_line>Right of member or manager to information.   </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On reasonable notice and for a proper purpose, a member or manager of an unincorporated nonprofit association may inspect and copy during the unincorporated nonprofit association’s regular operating hours, at a reasonable location specified by the association, any record maintained by the association regarding its activities, financial condition, and other circumstances, to the extent the information is material to the member’s or manager’s rights and duties under the governing principles. </section><section prefix="2">An unincorporated nonprofit association may charge a person that makes a demand under this section reasonable copying costs, limited to the costs of labor and materials. </section><section prefix="3">The governing principles may impose reasonable limitations upon the inspection and use of any record of or information with respect to an unincorporated nonprofit association. Except as to limitations set forth in written governing principles to which a member or manager requesting information has assented, the association bears the burden of proof in demonstrating the reasonableness of any restrictions imposed. </section><section prefix="4">A former member or manager shall be entitled to information to which the member or manager was entitled while a member or manager if the information pertains to the period during which the person was a member or manager, the former member or manager seeks the information in good faith, and the former member or manager satisfies subsections (1) to (3) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 33, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44346</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>