<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.7-403</section_number><catch_line>Obligation of bailee to deliver -- Excuse.   </catch_line><order_by>7-403</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A bailee shall deliver the goods to a person entitled under a document of title if the person complies with subsections (2) and (3) of this section, unless and to the extent that the bailee establishes any of the following: <section prefix="a">Delivery of the goods to a person whose receipt was rightful as against the claimant; </section><section prefix="b">Damage to or delay, loss, or destruction of the goods for which the bailee is not liable; </section><section prefix="c">Previous sale or other disposition of the goods in lawful enforcement of a lien or on a warehouse's lawful termination of storage; </section><section prefix="d">The exercise by a seller of its right to stop delivery pursuant to KRS 355.2-705 or by a lessor of its right to stop delivery pursuant to KRS 355.2A-526; </section><section prefix="e">A diversion, reconsignment, or other disposition pursuant to KRS 355.7-303; </section><section prefix="f">Release, satisfaction, or any other fact affording a personal defense against the claimant; or </section><section prefix="g">Any other lawful excuse. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person claiming goods covered by a document of title shall satisfy the bailee's lien if the bailee so requests or the bailee is prohibited by law from delivering the goods until the charges are paid. </section><section prefix="3">Unless a person claiming the goods is one against which the document of title does not confer a right under KRS 355.7-503(1): <section prefix="a">The person claiming under a document shall surrender possession or control of any outstanding negotiable document covering the goods for cancellation or indication of partial deliveries; and </section><section prefix="b">The bailee shall cancel the document or conspicuously indicate in the document the partial delivery or be liable to any person to which the document is duly negotiated. </section></section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 28, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7-403, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40629</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>