<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.371</section_number><catch_line>Registration of brand and grade -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>371</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each brand and grade of fertilizer shall be registered in the name of that person whose name appears upon the label before being distributed in this state. The application for registration shall be submitted to the director on a form furnished by the director. For specialty fertilizers a registration fee of fifty dollars ($50) per each grade of each brand shall accompany the registration application. Upon approval by the director, a copy of the registration shall be furnished to the applicant. All registrations expire on December 31 of each year. The application shall include the following information: <section prefix="a">The net weight of packages; </section><section prefix="b">The brand and grade; </section><section prefix="c">The guaranteed analysis; and </section><section prefix="d">The name and address of the registrant. </section></section><section prefix="2">A distributor shall not be required to register any fertilizer which is already registered under KRS 250.361 to 250.451 by another person, if the label does not differ in any respect. </section><section prefix="3">A blender shall not be required to register each custom-mixed farm fertilizer, but shall be required to license his firm on a form furnished by the director and to label the fertilizer as provided in subsection (2) of KRS 250.376. The label of each custom-mixed fertilizer shall be maintained by the blender for one (1) year for inspection by the director. </section><section prefix="4">A distributor of custom-mixed specialty fertilizers or bulk specialty fertilizers for home lawns, golf courses, recreational areas, or other nonfarm areas shall not be required to register each grade distributed but shall license his firm on a form furnished by the director for an annual fee of one hundred dollars ($100) and label the fertilizers as provided in KRS 250.376(1). The label of each fertilizer distributed under this subsection shall be maintained by the distributor for one (1) year for inspection by the director. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12125</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>