<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.585</section_number><catch_line>Recognition of foreign adoptions -- Registration in Commonwealth -- When KRS 199.470 petition required. </catch_line><order_by>585</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth of Kentucky shall recognize a decree, judgment, or final order of adoption issued by a court or other governmental authority with appropriate jurisdiction in a foreign country when the child to be adopted has been approved for United States citizenship, or as otherwise provided by federal law. </section><section prefix="2">Upon presentation of an original decree, judgment, or final order of adoption issued by a court or other governmental authority with appropriate jurisdiction in a foreign country, the secretary or his or her designee shall issue, within thirty (30) days, a certified notice that the foreign adoption is registered in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The secretary or his or her designee may require a translated copy if the original decree, judgment, or final order is not in English. The cabinet shall maintain all records and notices of foreign adoptions in a manner similar to other adoption records. </section><section prefix="3">A petition for adoption under KRS 199.470 shall be required for a child born outside the United States without a decree, judgment, or final order of adoption issued by a court or other governmental authority with appropriate jurisdiction in a foreign country, or for any child born outside of the United States who does not qualify for United States citizenship upon entry into the United States. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 68, ch. 1, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 175, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(5/20/2005). This new section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes was enacted by both 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 68 and 175. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7196</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>