<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.390</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on hunting wild elk, deer, wild turkey, or bear -- Depredation permits -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall possess, take, pursue, or attempt to take or pursue or otherwise molest any wild elk, deer, wild turkey, or bear in any manner contrary to any provisions of this chapter or its regulations. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall use a dog to chase or molest wild elk or deer in any manner, at any time, or at any place. Any conservation officer, peace officer, sheriff, or constable may take necessary steps to stop, prevent, or bring under control any dog or dogs found chasing or molesting wild elk or deer at any time. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall establish by administrative regulation the conditions under which depredation permits may be issued without cost to persons suffering damage from wild elk to allow the taking of wild elk. </section><section prefix="4">If Kentucky's wild elk population reaches a level that will sustain limited hunting, the department may establish by administrative regulations the conditions and permits that would allow the controlled taking of wild elk. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective March 4, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 474, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 21. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 17. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 52. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 40. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1954d-61. </history><metadata><effective> March 4, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>