<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-230</section_number><catch_line>Delivery of policy. </catch_line><order_by>14-230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the insurer's requirements as to payment of premium, every policy shall be mailed or otherwise delivered to the insured or to the person entitled thereto within a reasonable period of time after its issuance, except where a condition required by the insurer has not been met by the insured. By agreement between the insurer and the insured or the person entitled to receive the policy, the policy may be delivered electronically. </section><section prefix="2">In the event the original policy is delivered or is so required to be delivered to or for deposit with any vendor, mortgagee, or pledgee of any motor vehicle or aircraft, and in which policy any interest of the vendee, mortgagor, or pledgor in or with reference to such vehicle or aircraft is insured, a duplicate of such policy, or memorandum thereof setting forth the name and address of the insurer, type of coverage, limit of liability, premiums for the respective coverages, and duration of the policy, shall be delivered by the vendor, mortgagee, or pledgee to each such vendee, mortgagor, or pledgor named in the policy or coming within the group of persons designated in the policy to be so included. If the policy does not provide coverage of legal liability for injury to persons or damage to the property of third parties, a statement of such fact shall be printed, written, or stamped conspicuously on the face of such duplicate policy or memorandum. This subsection does not apply to inland marine floater policies. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 14, sec. 23, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17143</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>