<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 250.021 to 250.111 or KRS 250.361 to 250.461 shall be fined not less than one hundred dollars ($100), nor more than seven hundred fifty dollars ($750). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who shall impede, hinder, or otherwise prevent, or attempt to prevent, the director or his duly authorized agent in the performance of his duty in connection with this chapter, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates subsection (6) of KRS 250.601 shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided by subsection (3) of this section, any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 250.491 to 250.631 may be fined up to one thousand dollars ($1,000) for the third and subsequent violations made within a twenty-four (24) month period. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 502, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 173, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 14, effective April 8, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 16. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 11(1), effective July 1, 1954. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42h-6, 1376b-24, 1719a-9, 1719a-10, 1822-4, 1822-9. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>