<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.230</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Licensure for Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors -- Membership -- Terms -- Oath. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Board of Licensure for Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor and two (2) ex officio members each with full voting rights. The ex officio members shall be the dean of the College of Engineering of the University of Kentucky and the dean of the J.B. Speed School of Engineering of the University of Louisville. </section><section prefix="2">The term of each member of the board shall be four (4) years. Each member shall hold office until the expiration of the term or until a successor has been appointed and has qualified. </section><section prefix="3">Before beginning a term of office, every member shall file with the Secretary of State a written oath for the faithful discharge of official duties. </section><section prefix="4">No member of the board shall serve as an employee of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 20, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 16. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 16. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 3 -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 17, provides: "One professional land surveyor who is appointed under KRS 322.230 to fill a position on the State Board of Licensure for Professional Engineers and Land surveyors after the previous term for that position has expired on December 31, 2010, shall serve a term of three years, after which appointments to this board position shall be for a term of four years." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31442</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>