<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8905</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for forming regional wastewater commission. </catch_line><order_by>8905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any two (2) or more member entities owning wastewater systems may jointly: <section prefix="a">Acquire and construct wastewater collection, transportation, and treatment facilities; </section><section prefix="b">Operate and manage those facilities; and </section><section prefix="c">Improve and extend those facilities in any manner permitted under law. </section></section><section prefix="2">The governing body of a member entity owning a wastewater system that wants to form a regional wastewater commission shall adopt a resolution or ordinance electing to participate with other member entities to perform any of the functions authorized under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the adoption of an ordinance or resolution by the governing body of each member entity or a decision by a local, state, or federal agency owning a wastewater system to participate in a commission, a certified copy of each member entity's action shall be filed with the organizing official. </section><section prefix="4">Prior to the adoption by the governing body of any member entity of a resolution or ordinance proposing participation in a commission, that governing body shall publish notice in accordance with KRS Chapter 424 and shall set a date for a public hearing regarding the creation of the commission and shall give at least thirty (30) days' prior notice of the hearing. The notice shall include, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">An explanation of the scope of the geographic area proposed to be served by a commission; and </section><section prefix="b">A description of the anticipated benefits to the residents in the geographic area served by the member entity of membership by that entity in a commission. </section></section> A resident, sewer customer, or citizen of the Commonwealth affected by a member entity proposing to establish a commission may submit written or oral comments and objections to the member entity, which shall provide a written statement of consideration of comments received. <section prefix="5">The member entity shall enter an order of decision along with specific findings for the decision. The organizing official among the member entities seeking to form a commission shall establish the commission, designating it as a "regional wastewater commission," if, after the public hearing and consideration of all comments and objections received, those member entities have adopted a resolution or ordinance, as appropriate, finding that: <section prefix="a">The establishment of a commission is in the furtherance of the public health, convenience, and benefit to the customers of the member entities proposing the creation of the commission; and </section><section prefix="b">The establishment of a commission can reasonably be expected to result in the improvement of the environment over that which would occur in the absence of the formation of the commission. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>