<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.045</section_number><catch_line>Contributions to certain candidates or slates of candidates by individuals prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text>No person and no agent of any person on his behalf, shall contribute, either directly or indirectly, any money, service, or other thing of value towards the nomination or election of any state, county, city, or district officer who, in his official capacity, is required by law to perform any duties peculiar to the person not common to the general public, or to supervise, regulate, or control in any manner the affairs of the person, or to perform any duty in assessing the property of the person for taxation. No person, and no agent of any person on his behalf, shall pay, promise, loan, or become liable in any way for any money or other valuable thing on behalf of any candidate or slate of candidates for any office at any election, primary, or nominating convention held in this state. No attorney or other person shall accept employment and compensation from any person with the understanding or agreement, either direct or implied, that he will contribute to any candidate or slate of candidates for any office, or on his behalf, any part or all of his compensation, towards the nomination or election of any candidate or slate of candidates. </text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 23, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 67, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 181. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>