<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.493</section_number><catch_line>On approval, notice to be given milk purchasers as to deduction required -- Disposition of collections. </catch_line><order_by>493</order_by><text>In the event a majority of the producers eligible for participation in such referendum and voting therein shall vote in favor of such assessment, then, upon the written request of the duly certified commission, council, board, association or other agency of producers of such agricultural commodity, the Commissioner shall notify forthwith, by certified mail, all persons engaged in the business of purchasing such agricultural commodities in this state, that on and after the date specified in such letter, the specified assessment shall be deducted from the producer's payment by the purchaser, or his agent or representative, from the purchase price of such agricultural commodity. The assessment so deducted shall, on or before the fifteenth day of the month following the end of the month in which such commodity is sold to the purchaser, be remitted by such purchaser to the duly certified commission, council, board, association or other agency of the producers entitled thereto. Such funds, including donations from individuals, concerns, corporations and grants from the state or governmental agencies, shall be used for the purpose of promoting and stimulating, by advertising, research and other methods, the increased use and sale, domestic and foreign, of such agricultural commodity. The books and records of all such purchasers of such agricultural commodity shall at all times during regular business hours be open for inspection by the Commissioner of Agriculture or his duly authorized agents. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>