<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.124</section_number><catch_line>Limited sale precinct election for sale of wine at an existing or proposed small farm winery located in a dry territory.   </catch_line><order_by>124</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a licensed small farm winery is located in a dry or moist territory, the small farm winery shall remain dry or moist unless sales at the small farm winery are approved through a local option election held in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A limited sale precinct election may be held in a precinct containing a licensed small farm winery or a proposed small farm winery located in a dry territory. The election shall be held in the same manner as prescribed by KRS 242.020 to 242.120. </section><section prefix="3">A petition seeking a local option election under this section shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of wine at (name of the licensed or proposed small farm winery or wineries)?'". </section><section prefix="4">If the precinct contains a licensed small farm winery or a proposed small farm winery, the proposition to be voted on in the limited local option election shall state, "Are you in favor of the sale of wine at the (name of the licensed or proposed small farm winery or wineries)?". </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>