<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-206</section_number><catch_line>Security interest arising in purchase or delivery of financial asset. </catch_line><order_by>9-206</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A security interest in favor of a securities intermediary attaches to a person’s security entitlement if: <section prefix="a">The person buys a financial asset through the securities intermediary in a transaction in which the person is obligated to pay the purchase price to the securities intermediary at the time of the purchase; and </section><section prefix="b">The securities intermediary credits the financial asset to the buyer’s securities account before the buyer pays the securities intermediary. </section></section><section prefix="2">The security interest described in subsection (1) of this section secures the person’s obligation to pay for the financial asset. </section><section prefix="3">A security interest in favor of a person that delivers a certificated security or other financial asset represented by a writing attaches to the security or other financial asset if: <section prefix="a">The security or other financial asset: <section prefix="1">In the ordinary course of business is transferred by delivery with any necessary indorsement or assignment; and </section><section prefix="2">Is delivered under an agreement between persons in the business of dealing with such securities or financial assets; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The agreement calls for delivery against payment. </section></section><section prefix="4">The security interest described in subsection (3) of this section secures the obligation to make payment for the delivery. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 36, effective July 1, 2001. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 22, effective July 1, 1964. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-206, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33749</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>