<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-280</section_number><catch_line>Cumulative environmental assessment and fee required before construction of facility for generating electricity -- Conditions imposed by cabinet -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>10-280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for a person that commenced construction of a facility prior to April 15, 2002, or that has received a certificate of public convenience and necessity from the Public Service Commission prior to April 15, 2002, no person shall commence to construct a facility to be used for the generation of electricity unless the person: <section prefix="a">Submits a cumulative environmental assessment to the cabinet with the permit application; and </section><section prefix="b">Remits a fee set pursuant to KRS 224.10-100(20) by the cabinet to defray the cost of processing the cumulative environmental assessment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The person may submit and the cabinet may accept documentation of compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) as satisfying the requirements to file a cumulative environmental assessment under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The cumulative environmental assessment shall contain a description, with appropriate analytical support, of: <section prefix="a">For air pollutants: <section prefix="1">Types and quantities of air pollutants that will be emitted from the facility; and </section><section prefix="2">A description of the methods to be used to control those emissions; </section></section><section prefix="b">For water pollutants: <section prefix="1">Types and quantities of water pollutants that will be discharged from the facility into the waters of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="2">A description of the methods to be used to control those discharges; </section></section><section prefix="c">For wastes: <section prefix="1">Types and quantities of wastes that will be generated by the facility; and </section><section prefix="2">A description of the methods to be used to manage and dispose of such wastes; and </section></section><section prefix="d">For water withdrawal: <section prefix="1">Identification of the source and volume of anticipated water withdrawal needed to support facility construction and operations; and </section><section prefix="2">A description of the methods to be used for managing water usage and withdrawal. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may impose such conditions regarding the timing, volume, duration, or type of pollutants on a permit, registration, general permit, or permit-by-rule for a facility subject to this section as are necessary to comply with applicable standards. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 10, effective April 24, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 24, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10323</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>