<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.50-326</section_number><catch_line>Membership of authority. </catch_line><order_by>50-326</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The members of the authority shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">If the authority is established by a city, the members shall be appointed by the mayor of the city; </section><section prefix="b">If the authority is established by a county, the members shall be appointed by the county judge/executive; </section><section prefix="c">If the authority is established as a joint city-county industrial development authority, one-half (1/2) of the members shall be appointed by the mayor and one-half (1/2) of the members by the county judge/executive. If the authority is composed of seven (7) members, the mayor and the county judge/executive shall jointly appoint the seventh member; </section><section prefix="d">If a combination of cities and/or counties establishes a joint industrial development authority, or if an established joint industrial development authority is altered by adding a new city or county as a participating member, the mayors and/or county judges/executive involved shall: <section prefix="1">Jointly choose the members, and shall jointly choose successors; or </section><section prefix="2">Choose the members and successors in a manner established by an agreement entered into between the legislative bodies of the affected cities and counties. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Members of the authority shall serve for a term of four (4) years each, and until their successors are appointed and qualified. If the authority is composed of six (6) members, initial appointments shall be made so that two (2) members are appointed for two (2) years, two (2) members for three (3) years, and two (2) members for four (4) years. If the authority is composed of seven (7) members, initial appointments shall be made so that two (2) members are appointed for two (2) years, two (2) members for three (3) years, and three (3) members for four (4) years. If the authority is composed of eight (8) members, initial appointments shall be made so that two (2) members are appointed for two (2) years, three (3) members for three </section><section prefix="3">years, and three (3) members for four (4) years. Upon expiration of these </section>staggered terms, successors shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. (3) An industrial development authority member may be replaced by the appointing authority upon a showing to the appointing authority of misconduct as an authority member or upon conviction of a felony. </text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><former-codification> KRS 152.860 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2965</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>