<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4025</section_number><catch_line>Continuing education requirements -- Waiver -- Revocation of program approval if continuing education records falsified.  </catch_line><order_by>4025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The renewal of all elevator contractor and elevator mechanic licenses shall be conditioned upon the submission of a certificate of completion of a continuing education course or courses that instruct licensees on new and existing applicable administrative regulations of the department. </section><section prefix="2">Licensed elevator contractors and licensed elevator mechanics shall complete at least eight (8) hours of continuing education annually. Continuing education for a renewal year shall be attended and completed during that renewal year. </section><section prefix="3">Continuing education courses shall be taught by instructors employed by continuing education providers that may include but shall not be limited to association seminars and labor training programs. Continuing education programs provided by the National Elevator Industry Educational Program or the National Association of Elevator Contractors shall be approved to meet the requirements for continuing education. The department may approve other education programs that meet its requirements established through administrative regulation under KRS 198B.4023(7). </section><section prefix="4">A licensee who is unable to complete the continuing education requirements for renewal under this section prior to the expiration of his or her license due to temporary disability may apply for a waiver from the department. The waiver shall be on a form provided by the department, with a notarized signature of the licensee, and accompanied by a certified statement from a physician attesting to the temporary disability. Application for medical waiver must be received by the department prior to the final day of the licensee's birth month. Upon termination of the temporary disability, the licensee shall submit a supplementary certified statement attesting to the termination of the temporary disability and proof of attendance of at least eight (8) hours of continuing education. </section><section prefix="5">Falsifying or knowingly allowing another to falsify continuing education attendance records or certificates of completion shall constitute grounds for revocation of program approval required under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 12, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011). References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 12, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36598</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>