<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.170</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Department of Vehicle Regulation in processing title applications.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall: <section prefix="a">Within five (5) working days following receipt by it of an application for a certificate of title in proper form, process the application and its supporting documents in the manner provided in this section, and unless it finds discrepancies with respect to it or its supporting documents, issue a certificate of title in the name of the owner and send it postpaid to such owner; and </section><section prefix="b">Within twenty-four (24) hours following electronic notification by a county clerk's office of an application for a certificate of title, issue a speed title which shall be held for pickup or returned to the owner by mail. The clerk shall take the application for title and process the appropriate paperwork as provided for in this chapter. The department may provide, by administrative regulation, for exceptions to the speed title procedure. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon receiving an application packet from a county clerk, the application receipt clerk of the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall: <section prefix="a">Cause the date and time of receipt to be stamped on both the department's copy and the acknowledgment copy of the application transmittal record and accompanying documents; </section><section prefix="b">Cause at least duplicate sets of images to be made of each transmittal record application and supporting document by a means that will provide rapid, selective, automated retrieval of individual document images by appropriate indexing methods or keys; and </section><section prefix="c">Compare the application transmittal record with the documents accompanying it and, if all applications shown upon the record are accompanying the record, endorse the department's copy of the transmittal record and the acknowledgment copy, and forward the acknowledgment copy to the clerk who issued it. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the event there is a discrepancy between the application transmittal record and the application attached to it, the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall note the discrepancy upon the department's copy and the acknowledgment copy, and shall promptly contact the issuing clerk and resolve the discrepancy. After resolving the discrepancy, the department shall note the nature of the disposition of the discrepancy and endorse the respective copies and forward the acknowledgment copy with the discrepancy disposition noted thereon to the issuing clerk. </section><section prefix="4">After executing the acknowledgment of receipt of applications, the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall carry out the following action with respect to each application: <section prefix="a">Examine the owner's application for legibility and proper execution, presence of required information, including required supporting documents, and the presence of required signatures. The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall ensure also that the required supporting documents are consistent in pertinent part with the information shown on the owner's application; </section><section prefix="b">The documents supporting an owner's application shall be examined as to authenticity and to determine if fraudulent alteration has occurred; </section><section prefix="c">Ensure that the vehicle identification number of the subject vehicle is apparently legitimate; </section><section prefix="d">Ensure that the vehicle identification number and any other appropriate information with respect to a vehicle for which a certificate of title has been applied for is compared against the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) computerized listings of vehicles reported stolen, unless NCIC is not operational and the department has official notification that it is not expected to be operational within four (4) working days following the day on which an application for a certificate of title is received by it; and </section><section prefix="e">Compare the computer-produced certificate of title for consistency with the owner's application and supporting documents. </section></section><section prefix="5">When the title application has been completed, and the application examiner at each significant stage has indicated, by placing his unique symbol upon the application in the space provided thereon, that an application has passed the required examinations, the application shall be examined by a title examination certifier. </section><section prefix="6">The title application certifier shall ensure that each application has received the required examinations as indicated by the presence of each required examiner's symbol. Upon satisfying himself that an application has passed the required examinations, the title examination certifier shall place his unique symbol together with the date upon the application. </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall withhold issuance of a title, until its questions are resolved to its satisfaction, when it finds material discrepancies or has information giving probable cause to believe: <section prefix="a">That an applicant is not the lawful owner of a vehicle for which he seeks a title; </section><section prefix="b">His application is not in order; </section><section prefix="c">The documentation supporting an application is insufficient or fraudulent; </section><section prefix="d">The vehicle has an illegitimate vehicle identification number; </section><section prefix="e">The vehicle is stolen; or </section><section prefix="f">That the computer-produced certificate of title is not consistent with the owner's application. </section></section><section prefix="8">In the case of multiple owners, the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall require only two (2) primary owners' names to be printed on the certificate of title. Upon submission of the title application, if more than two (2) owners are listed, the primary owners shall be determined by the title applicants. In such instances, the certificate of the title shall note that there are more than two (2) owners. The names of all title applicants shall be documented in AVIS. </section><section prefix="9">When the Department of Vehicle Regulation finds that a certificate of title should be issued for a vehicle, the endorsement of the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall be engrossed upon the certificate of title following a preprinted statement which shall read: I certify that the Department of Vehicle Regulation has exercised due diligence in examining an application for a certificate of title for the above-described vehicle, and to the best of our knowledge and belief, the applicant whose name appears above is the lawful owner of the apparently legitimate vehicle described herein. --------------- (signature), commissioner, Department of Vehicle Regulation, Kentucky Transportation Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41136</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>