<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.820</section_number><catch_line>Functions, powers, and duties of Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </catch_line><order_by>820</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall have the following functions, powers, and duties: <section prefix="a">To conduct a survey of all of the existing facilities within the state having to do with the diagnosis, evaluation, and treatment of patients with kidney disease and to prepare and submit its findings and a specific program of action; </section><section prefix="b">To evaluate the need for the creation of local or regional facilities and for the establishing of a major kidney research center; </section><section prefix="c">To develop and administer scientific investigations into the cause, prevention, methods of treatment, and cure of renal disease, including research into transplantation of kidneys; </section><section prefix="d">To develop techniques for an effective method of mass testing for the detection of kidney diseases and urinary tract infections; </section><section prefix="e">To develop more efficient methods of medical care for kidney disease and to develop more effective and economical kidney dialysis equipment; </section><section prefix="f">To survey and evaluate the need for a program of professional education and training for medical students, physicians, and nurses in the care and treatment of kidney diseases; </section><section prefix="g">To report to the Governor and to a committee of the legislature annually on or before February 1 its findings, a progress report, its activities and the state's total needs in this area; and </section><section prefix="h">To enter into such contracts and agreements with individuals, colleges, universities, associations, corporations, municipalities, and other units of government as may be deemed necessary and advisable to carry out the general intent and purposes of this section. Such contracts may provide for payment by the state, within the limit of funds available, for materials, equipment, or services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary may adopt rules and regulations necessary to effect the purposes of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 372, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 313, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 63, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21) and (25). -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8483</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>