<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.310</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 234.310 to 234.440. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text>As used in KRS 234.310 to 234.440, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="2">"Person" includes every natural person, fiduciary, association, state, or political subdivision, or corporation. Whenever used in any clause prescribing and imposing imprisonment the term "person" as applied to an association means and includes the partners or members thereof, and as applied to corporations, the officers thereof; </section><section prefix="3">"Liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel" means and includes all combustible gases and liquids as described in KRS 234.100 used for the generation of power in an internal combustion engine to propel vehicles of any kind upon the public highways; </section><section prefix="4">"Motor vehicle" means any vehicle, machine or mechanical contrivance propelled by an internal combustion engine and licensed for operation and operated upon the public highways and any trailer or semitrailer attached to or having its front end supported by such motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="5">"Public highways" means every way or place generally open to the use of the public as a matter of right for the purpose of vehicular travel, notwithstanding that they may be temporarily closed or travel thereon restricted for the purpose of construction, maintenance, repair or reconstruction; </section><section prefix="6">"Liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel dealer" means any person who imports or causes to be imported into this state for resale or use, or any person making sales in this state, of liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel for resale or use in this state by a licensed liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel user-seller; </section><section prefix="7">"Liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel user-seller" means any person, not licensed as a liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel dealer, who dispenses liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel into the fuel tanks of, or attached to, motor vehicles for the propulsion of such motor vehicles on the public highways, and shall include any such person who so dispenses liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel for consumption in such motor vehicles owned, leased, or operated by him. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 634, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>