<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-160</section_number><catch_line>Examination for license -- Application for examination. </catch_line><order_by>9-160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual applying for any license under this subtitle requiring an examination shall pass a written examination unless exempt under KRS 304.9-170. Examinations required by this section shall be developed and conducted in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may make arrangements, including contracting with an outside testing service, for administering examinations and collecting the nonrefundable fee set forth in KRS 304.4-010. </section><section prefix="3">Each individual applying for an examination shall remit a nonrefundable fee as prescribed by the commissioner as set forth in KRS 304.4-010. </section><section prefix="4">An individual who fails to appear for the examination as scheduled or fails to pass the examination, shall reapply for an examination and remit all required fees and forms before being rescheduled for another examination. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1055, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 322, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 16, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16909</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>