<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.750</section_number><catch_line>Public health taxing district created in counties not electing to create same -- Officers. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of this section and KRS 212.755, inter alia, to create a public health taxing district via operation of law in every county of the Commonwealth that has not heretofore created same except in counties containing cities of the first class or a consolidated local government. </section><section prefix="2">In all counties where a county or city-county health department or urban-county department of health has been established, except in counties containing a city of the first class or a consolidated local government, and a public health taxing district has not been established pursuant to the provisions of KRS 212.720 to 212.740, a public health taxing district is hereby declared to be created upon June 13, 1968, or upon the creation of an urban-county department of health. The members of the county or city-county board of health or urban-county department of health shall, by virtue of their office, constitute and be the governing body of the public health taxing district and shall perform the duties attendant thereto in addition to their duties as members of the county or city-county board of health or urban-county department of health. The officers of the county or city-county board of health or urban-county department of health shall be the officers of the public health taxing district. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section and KRS 212.755 shall in any way abridge the rights of two (2) or more counties from establishing a district health department. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002; and ch.346, sec.209, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 202, secs. 1, 2 and 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2002).  This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs.214 and 346, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8674</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>