<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.662</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Milk Commission established. </catch_line><order_by>662</order_by><text>The Kentucky Milk Commission is hereby established and shall consist of the following thirteen (13) members: <section prefix="1">The Commissioner or the Commissioner's designee, who shall serve as chair; </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) nonvoting members as follows: <section prefix="a">President of the Kentucky Farm Bureau or the president's designee; </section><section prefix="b">Director of the Division of Public Health Protection and Safety, Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or the director's designee; </section><section prefix="c">Director of the University of Kentucky Agriculture Experiment Station or the director's designee; and </section><section prefix="d">A representative of the Kentucky Dairy Development Council (KDDC) designated by the KDDC; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Eight (8) members appointed by the Governor, who shall be residents of the state. The members shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) milk producers who are actively and principally engaged in dairy farming in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) milk processor or a designee of the processor; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) retailer; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) consumers; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) employee representative of a milk marketing agency or dairy cooperative; and </section><section prefix="f">One (1) representative of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services who has experience in the administration of the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>