<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.610</section_number><catch_line>Tax for maintenance of band or orchestra in cities of the home rule class -- Procedure -- Submission to vote.   </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Cities of the home rule class may levy an annual tax of not more than ten (10) mills on the assessed valuation of the city, for the purpose of providing a fund for the maintenance or employment of a band or orchestra. </section><section prefix="2">Before such tax may be levied a petition signed by five percent (5%) of the legal voters of the city, as shown by the last regular municipal election, must be filed with the city legislative body, requesting that the following question be submitted to the voters: "Shall a tax of not exceeding ten (10) mills be levied each year for the purpose of furnishing a fund for the maintenance or employment of a municipal band or orchestra?" </section><section prefix="3">The petition shall be filed with the county clerk and the county clerk shall certify whether the petition is sufficient not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding a general election, and the legislative body shall cause the question to be submitted to the voters at the first following general municipal election. </section><section prefix="4">The levy shall be authorized if a majority of the electors voting at the election cast votes in favor of the proposition, and the legislative body may then enact an ordinance carrying the plan into effect. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 181, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 49, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2741j-7, 2741j-8, 2741j-9, 2741j-10, 2741j-12. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43766</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>