<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.725</section_number><catch_line>Petition for order of protection -- Venue -- Verified contents --Concurrent jurisdiction -- Protocols for access and supplementaljurisdiction -- Referral.  </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text>(1)A petition for an order of protection may be filed by:(a)A victim of domestic violence and abuse; or(b)An adult on behalf of a victim who is a minor otherwise qualifying for reliefunder this subsection.(2)The petition may be filed in the victim's county of residence or a county wherethe victim has fled to escape domestic violence and abuse.(3)The petition shall be verified and contain:(a)The name, age, address, occupation, residence, and school orpostsecondary institution of the petitioner;(b)The name, age, address, occupation, residence, and school orpostsecondary institution of the person or persons who have engaged inthe alleged act or acts complained of in the petition;(c)The facts and circumstances which constitute the basis for the petition;(d)The date and place of the marriage of the parties, if applicable; and(e)The names, ages, and addresses of the petitioner's minor children, ifapplicable.(4)The petition shall be filed on forms prescribed by the Administrative Office ofthe Courts and provided to the person seeking relief by the circuit clerk or byanother individual authorized by the court to provide and verify petitions inemergency situations, such as law enforcement officers and Commonwealth'sor county attorneys.(5)All petitions requested, completed, and signed by persons seeking protectionunder this chapter shall be accepted and filed with the court.(6)(a)Jurisdiction over petitions filed under this chapter shall be concurrentbetween the District Court and Circuit Court and a petition may be filed bya petitioner in either court, except that a petition shall be filed in a familycourt if one has been established in the county where the petition is filed.(b)The Court of Justice shall provide a protocol for twenty-four (24) houraccess to orders of protection in each county with any protocol, whetherstatewide or local, being subject to Supreme Court review and approval ofthe initial protocol and any subsequent amendments. This protocol mayallow for petitions to be filed in or transferred to a court other than thosespecified in paragraph (a) of this subsection.(c)The Court of Justice may authorize by rule that petitions in a specificcounty be filed in accordance with a supplemental jurisdictional protocoladopted for that county. This protocol may provide for petitions to be filedin or transferred to a court other than those specified in paragraph (a) ofthis subsection.(7)Any judge to whom a petition is referred under subsection (6) of this sectionshall have full authority to review and hear a petition and subsequently grantand enforce an order of protection.(8)If the judge of a court in which there is a pending request for modification orenforcement of an existing order of protection is unavailable or unable to actwithin a reasonable time, the proceedings may be conducted by any judge ofthe county in accordance with court rules.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 3, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. --Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 414,sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 3,effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>