<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="413" order_by="413">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>413.130When</section_number><catch_line>certain actions in KRS 413.120 accrue.   </catch_line><order_by>130When</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In every action upon a merchants' account as described in subsection (9) of KRS 413.120, the limitation shall be computed from January 1 next succeeding the respective dates of the delivery of the several articles charged in the account. Judgment shall be rendered for no more than the amount of articles actually charged or delivered within five (5) years preceding that in which the action was brought. If any merchant willfully postdates any article charged in such account, or the receipt for the delivery of it, he shall forfeit ten (10) times the amount of the article postdated, to be credited against the account. This credit shall be allowed in an action on the account, without any written pleadings setting it up. </section><section prefix="2">In an action to recover a balance due upon a mutual open and current account concerning the trade of merchandise between merchant and merchant or their agents, as described in subsection (10) of KRS 413.120, where there have been reciprocal demands between the parties, the cause of action is deemed to have accrued from the time of the last item proved in the account claimed, or proved to be chargeable on the adverse side. </section><section prefix="3">In an action for relief or damages for fraud or mistake, referred to in subsection (11) of KRS 413.120, the cause of action shall not be deemed to have accrued until the discovery of the fraud or mistake. However, the action shall be commenced within ten (10) years after the time of making the contract or the perpetration of the fraud. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1998. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2518, 2519, 2520. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>