<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="269" order_by="269">MISCELLANEOUS PROVISIONS AS TO DITCHES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION </unit></structure><section_number>269.270</section_number><catch_line>County surface water drainage districts. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county judge/executive in each county of this Commonwealth, wherein the fiscal court has requested it, is hereby authorized to establish a countywide surface water drainage district for the entire county including all municipalities. The cost of procuring the necessary rights-of-way and the construction and maintenance of such countywide drainage district shall be paid by the fiscal court out of the annual levy for county taxes. When the fiscal court undertakes such a project it may acquire for the county by contract or condemnation any land necessary to carry out the project. If condemnation proceedings are necessary they shall be conducted in the manner provided in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The administration of this district shall be exclusively by or within the fiscal court of said county, and the fiscal court is hereby authorized and empowered to employ such assistants, including commissioners or superintendent, and other employees as may be necessary for the construction, maintenance and continued operation of said system, and shall fix the salaries of all employees to be paid as other county employees are paid. </section><section prefix="3">In the construction and maintenance of such drainage system the fiscal court is authorized and empowered, as a part of the cost of construction and maintenance of said system, to build or construct such bridges and culverts over and across the ditches or canals of this system as in the opinion of the fiscal court are necessary. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing herein contained shall authorize or empower the construction or maintenance of a sanitary sewer system or sanitary sewers. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 430, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 108. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 45, secs. 1, 2, 3, and 4, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13017</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>