<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.265</section_number><catch_line>Care and control of dog -- Destruction of dog running at large at night -- Exemption for hunting dogs. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An owner shall exercise proper care and control of his dog to prevent the dog from violating any local government nuisance ordinance. </section><section prefix="2">Any peace officer or animal control officer may seize or destroy any dog found running at large between the hours of sunset and sunrise and unaccompanied and not under the control of its owner or handler. A peace officer or animal control officer shall be under a duty to make a fair and reasonable effort to determine whether any dog found at large between sunset and sunrise is a hound or other hunting dog which has become lost temporarily from a pack or wandered from immediate control of its owner, or handler, and if he is reasonably sure that the dog is a hunting dog, then he shall not destroy the dog, unless it is found in the act of pursuing or wounding livestock, or wounding or killing poultry, or attacking human beings. </section><section prefix="3">A hound or hunting dog may be unrestrained when engaged in lawful hunting activities while on private or public property designated or authorized for that purpose. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 21, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 29, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12467</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>