<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.111</section_number><catch_line>Actions for violations of KRS 250.021 to 250.111 -- Informal hearing -- Injunctions. </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the director has probable cause to believe that any of the provisions of KRS 250.021 to 250.111 have been violated, he shall give notice to the person who is in apparent violation designating a time and place for an informal hearing. If, after the informal hearing, or without the hearing if the person fails to appear, the director determines that a violation has occurred, he may issue a letter of reprimand, levy a fine pursuant to KRS 250.990, or impose any other penalties or sanctions authorized under KRS 250.021 to 250.111.  Any penalty or sanction imposed as a result of an informal hearing may be appealed, and upon appeal an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="2">The director may petition a court of competent jurisdiction for a temporary or permanent injunction restraining any person from violating or continuing to violate any provision of KRS 250.021 to 250.111 or any administrative regulation promulgated thereunder, notwithstanding the existence of other remedies of law. The injunction shall be issued without bond. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 165, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 10, effective April 8, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (4/8/94).  Although the section of 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370 creating this statute directed its placement in KRS Chapter 350, it is clear from the subject matter of this statute and the structure of ch. 370 that placement in KRS Chapter 250 was intended, and this has been done in codification pursuant to KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12095</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>