<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.207</section_number><catch_line>Local corrections assistance fund. </catch_line><order_by>207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local corrections assistance fund is created as a separate revolving fund to be administered by the department. The fund shall consist of amounts transferred to the fund pursuant to KRS 196.288, along with any other proceeds from grants, contributions, appropriations, or other moneys made available for purposes of the fund. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, amounts not expended at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year. </section><section prefix="3">Any interest earnings from the fund shall become a part of the fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="4">Moneys in the fund shall accrue to the fund and shall be retained in the fund until the General Assembly establishes a statutory process and method for distributing the funds to local correctional facilities and programs. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.69, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 69, directed that a new section of KRS Chapter 196 be created for this statute. However, during codification, the Reviser of Statutes determined that it was more appropriately placed within KRS Chapter 441, relating to jails and county prisoners, and created the new section as KRS 441.207 under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39584</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>