<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">A PLANNING AND OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENTAL FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>7A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Capital project" means: <section prefix="a">Any undertaking which is to be financed or funded through an appropriation by the General Assembly of general fund, road fund, bond fund, trust and agency fund, or federal fund moneys, where the expenditure is a capital expenditure pursuant to statute or under standards prescribed by the Legislative Research Commission under the authority of KRS Chapter 48; </section><section prefix="b">Any undertaking which is to be financed by a capital expenditure for use by the state government or one of its departments or agencies, as defined in KRS 12.010 or enumerated in KRS 12.020, including projects related to the construction or maintenance of roads, and including projects of institutions of higher education as defined in KRS 164A.550(2); </section><section prefix="c">Any capital construction item, or any combination of capital construction items necessary to make a building or utility installation complete, estimated to cost six hundred thousand dollars ($600,000) or more, or any item of movable equipment, estimated to cost two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000) or more, regardless of the source of funds; </section><section prefix="d">Any lease of real property whose value is two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000) or more; </section><section prefix="e">Any lease of an item of movable equipment if the total cost of the lease, lease-purchase, or lease with an option to purchase is two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000) or more; or </section><section prefix="f">Any new acquisition, upgrade, or replacement of an information technology system estimated to cost six hundred thousand dollars ($600,000) or more. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the Capital Planning Advisory Board of the Kentucky General Assembly created by KRS 7A.110. </section><section prefix="3">"Plan" means the state capital improvement plan provided for by KRS 7A.120. </section><section prefix="4">"State agency" means any department, commission, council, board, bureau, committee, institution, legislative body, agency, government corporation, or other entity of the executive, judicial, or legislative branch of the state government. </section><section prefix="5">"Information technology system" means any related computer or telecommunications components that provide a functional system for a specific business purpose and contain one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">Hardware; </section><section prefix="b">Software, including application software, systems management software, utility software, or communications software; </section><section prefix="c">Professional services for requirements analysis, system integration, installation, implementation, or data conversion services; or </section><section prefix="d">Digital data products, including acquisition and quality control. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 503, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=496</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>