<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-974</section_number><catch_line>Effect on limited partnerships formed prior to July 15, 1988. </catch_line><order_by>2-974</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited partnership formed under any statute of this Commonwealth prior to July 15, 1988, until or unless it becomes a limited partnership under this subchapter, shall continue to be governed by the provisions of the statute under which it was formed. </section><section prefix="2">A limited partnership formed under any statute of this Commonwealth prior to July 15, 1988, may elect to become subject to this subchapter upon the filing of an amended and restated certificate of limited partnership which complies with the provisions of KRS 362.2-201. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the occurrence of any event which would require the filing of a certificate of amendment by a limited partnership under the Kentucky Revised Uniform Limited Partnership Act, KRS 362.401 to 362.525, as it exists on July 12, 2006, or under the statute under which the limited partnership was formed, the limited partnership shall file an amended and restated certificate of limited partnership which complies with the provisions of KRS 362.2-201. </section><section prefix="4">A limited partnership formed under any statute of this Commonwealth prior to July 15, 1988, shall not be required to change its name to include the word "Limited" or the abbreviation "Ltd." until such time as it becomes subject to this subchapter. </section><section prefix="5">The enactment of this subchapter shall not impair, or otherwise affect, the organization or the continued existence of a limited partnership existing on July 15, 1988, nor does any repeal of any statutory provision by 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 65, impair any contract or affect any right accrued before July 15, 1988. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 192, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification>KRS 362.2-1204. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41540</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>