<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.517</section_number><catch_line>Sales tax incentive for alternative fuel, gasification, and renewable energy facilities. </catch_line><order_by>517</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Approved company" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; </section><section prefix="b">"Authority" means the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority established under KRS 154.20-010; </section><section prefix="c">"Eligible project" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010; and </section><section prefix="d">"Tax incentive agreement" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other provision of KRS 134.580 or this chapter, an approved company constructing, retrofitting, or upgrading an eligible project may be eligible for a sales tax incentive of up to one hundred percent (100%) of the Kentucky sales or use tax paid on tangible personal property purchased during the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the eligible project as provided in KRS 154.27-070. The tangible personal property shall be incorporated into the eligible project to qualify for the sales tax incentive. </section><section prefix="3">The authority shall notify the department upon approval of an eligible project. The notification shall include the name of the eligible project, the name of the approved company, and the date on which the approved company is eligible to receive incentives under this section. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">An approved company seeking an incentive under this section shall file a request for incentives within sixty (60) days following the end of the calendar year in which the activation date occurs. The request shall include all documentation relating to the payment of the sales and use tax. </section><section prefix="b">In subsequent years, the approved company shall file a request for incentives within sixty (60) days following the end of each calendar year. </section><section prefix="c">The approved company shall file a final request for incentives within sixty (60) days from the earlier of the completion of the construction, retrofit, or upgrade of the eligible project, or the five (5) year anniversary of the activation date. </section><section prefix="d">The request for incentives shall be in the form prescribed by the department through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="5">Interest shall not be allowed or paid on any sales tax incentive payment made under the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The sales tax incentive shall be reduced by the amount of vendor compensation allowed under KRS 139.570. </section><section prefix="7">The approved company seeking the sales tax incentive payment shall execute information-sharing agreements prescribed by the department with contractors, vendors, and other related parties to verify the costs of tangible personal property eligible for the sales tax incentive payment under this section. </section><section prefix="8">The department shall notify the authority of the incentive distributed to each approved company upon request. </section></text><history> Created 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 10, effective August 30, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> August 30, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>