<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.415</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 441.420 to 441.450. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text>As used in KRS 441.420 to 441.450: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">"Local correctional facility" means a jail as defined in KRS 441.005, and any other facility by whatever name known that is operated by a unit of local government, combination of units of local governments, or regional jail authority for the involuntary confinement of persons arrested for or charged with the commission of a crime and of persons convicted of a crime. </section><section prefix="b">The definition in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall not include a hospital licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 216B unless the hospital is operated solely for the purpose of incarcerating persons specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection; and </section></section><section prefix="2">"Construction authority" means the Local Correctional Facilities Construction Authority established under KRS 441.615. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.77, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).2011 Ky. Acts ch.2 sec.77, directed that a new section of KRS 441.420 to 441.450 be created for this statute. However, during codification, the Reviser of Statutes determined that this statute, which contains definitions for KRS 441.420 to 441.450, was more appropriately numbered preceding that range of statutes, and created the new section as KRS 441.415 under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39592</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>