<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.290</section_number><catch_line>Lien on watches and jewelry for repairs -- Sale for charges. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person performing work upon any watch, clock or jewelry for a price shall have a lien upon that article for the amount due for the work. The lien shall include the value or agreed price of all materials furnished in connection with the work, whether added to the article or not. The lien may be enforced by legal action or as hereafter provided. </section><section prefix="2">If the account remains unpaid six (6) months after completing the work, the person holding the lien may, upon thirty (30) days' notice in writing to the owner specifying the amount due and informing the owner that the payment of the amount due within thirty (30) days will entitle him to redeem the property, sell the article at public or bona fide private sale to satisfy the account. The notice may be served by mail directed to the owner's last known address, or, if the owner or his address is unknown, it may be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. </section><section prefix="3">The proceeds of the sale, after paying the expenses thereof, shall be applied in liquidation of the indebtedness secured by the lien, and the balance, if any, shall be held for a period of twelve (12) months for the owner, and if it is not called for in that time it shall be paid into the district school fund. </section></text><history>Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 215, effective June 16, 1966. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2504a-1. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1966</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>