<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="413" order_by="413">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>413.248</section_number><catch_line>Liability of donor for damages resulting from condition of donated food. </catch_line><order_by>248</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person, including an individual, corporation, partnership, organization, association, or retail food establishment, who donates apparently wholesome food to a nonprofit organization for distribution to the needy is not subject to civil or criminal liability that arises from the condition of the food, unless an injury or death results from an act or omission of the donor which constitutes gross negligence, recklessness, or intentional misconduct. </section><section prefix="2">A nonprofit organization that distributes apparently wholesome food to the needy at no charge and that substantially complies with applicable local, county, state, and federal laws and regulations regarding the storage and handling of food for distribution to the public is not subject to civil or criminal liability that arises from the condition of the food, unless an injury or death results from an act or omission of the organization that constitutes gross negligence, recklessness, or intentional misconduct. </section><section prefix="3">This section does not create any liability. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 2, effective April 2, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17887</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>