<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.125</section_number><catch_line>Separate vote to determine wet, moist, or dry status in cities with populations of 3,000 or more -- Right of city precincts to vote for separate dry status.   </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "city" or "cities" means a city or cities containing a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census. </section><section prefix="2">A city shall not be deemed to be the "same territory" as that of a county within the meaning of KRS 242.030(5). A city shall have the right to determine its wet or dry status separate from a county's wet or dry status. </section><section prefix="3">A dry or moist city may hold a local option election to take the sense of the city residents for establishing the city as a wet territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of establishing the city as a wet territory, the whole city shall become wet territory by application of KRS 242.200. </section><section prefix="4">Once a city votes under this section to become wet territory separate from the county, a countywide local option election establishing the county as dry or moist territory shall not cause the city to become dry or moist territory. </section><section prefix="5">A wet city may hold a local option election to take the sense of the city residents for establishing the city as a dry or moist territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of establishing the city as a dry or moist territory, the whole city shall become dry or moist territory by application of KRS 242.190. </section><section prefix="6">If a city votes to become wet territory, a precinct of the city may hold a later election in conformity with this chapter to take the sense of the city precinct residents for establishing the city precinct as a dry or moist territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of establishing the city precinct as a dry or moist territory, the city precinct shall become dry or moist territory by application of KRS 242.190. </section><section prefix="7">If a city precinct becomes dry or moist territory separate from a wet city, the city precinct may hold a later election in conformity with this chapter, to take the sense of the city precinct residents for reestablishing the city precinct as a wet territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of reestablishing the city precinct as a wet territory, the city precinct shall become wet territory by application of KRS 242.200. </section><section prefix="8">A dry or moist county containing a wet city may hold a local option election to take the sense of the county residents for establishing the county as a wet territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of establishing the county as a wet territory, the whole county shall become wet territory by application of KRS 242.200. </section><section prefix="9">A wet county containing a wet city by separate city election under this section may hold a local option election to take the sense of the county residents for establishing the county as a dry or moist territory. If the majority of the votes are in favor of establishing the county as a dry or moist territory, the county territory outside the wet city limits shall become dry or moist territory by application of KRS 242.190. </section><section prefix="10">Residents of any city, including a separately wet city, are residents of the county, and shall therefore be permitted to sign any petitions for, and vote in, county local option elections under this section. </section><section prefix="11">A petition seeking a local option election under this section shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages in (name of county, city, or precinct)?'". </section><section prefix="12">In any local option election under this section, the proposition to be voted upon shall state "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages in (name of county, city, or city precinct)?". </section><section prefix="13">The status of any moist territory approving limited alcoholic beverage sales through a previous election held under KRS 242.123, 242.124, 242.1242, and 242.1244, or any other limited local option election, shall not be affected by any outcome of any election held under this section. A territory's moist status may only be changed by a local option election on the original same moist election proposition. </section><section prefix="14">Any city that does not meet the population requirements of subsection (1) of this section that held a separate city-wide election pursuant to subsections (1) to (4) of this section prior to January 1, 2015, shall maintain its wet status and shall be treated as a city as defined in this section for the purposes of subsections (5) to (13) of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 291, effective January 1, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 66, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 213. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 213. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>