<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="327" order_by="327">PHYSICAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>327.075</section_number><catch_line>Reinstatement of license or certificate -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may reinstate within three (3) years a license or certificate which has lapsed, upon payment of the prescribed renewal fee and, in addition, the payment of a reinstatement fee to be promulgated by the board by administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="2">The board may reinstate a license or certificate which has been lapsed for more than three (3) years, upon showing that the applicant is able to practice with reasonable competency. In determining competency, the board may require the applicant to successfully complete all or any part of the required examination. </section><section prefix="3">The board may reinstate a license which has been suspended or revoked under provisions of this chapter if, after a hearing conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, the board determines the applicant is able to practice the profession with reasonable competency and is able to maintain the ethical code and standards of practice promulgated by administrative regulation. As a condition of reinstatement, the board may impose reasonable restrictions under which the licensee or certificate holder shall practice. </section><section prefix="4">Any person aggrieved by a final order of the board denying, suspending, or revoking his license or certificate may appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 301, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>