<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.687</section_number><catch_line>Vehicle license cost recovery fee charged by motor vehicle renting company.   </catch_line><order_by>687</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Motor vehicle renting company" means a holder of a certificate as required under KRS 281.630 to operate as a U-Drive-It, which regularly engages in renting or leasing motor vehicles to customers for less than a sixty (60) day term as part of an established business; </section><section prefix="b">"Vehicle license costs" means the costs incurred by a motor vehicle renting company for licensing, titling, registration, property tax, plating, and inspecting rental motor vehicles; and </section><section prefix="c">"Vehicle license cost recovery fee" means a charge on a vehicle rental transaction originating within the Commonwealth that is separately stated on the rental agreement to recover vehicle license costs. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If a motor vehicle renting company includes a vehicle license cost recovery fee as a separately stated charge in a rental transaction, the amount of the fee shall represent the company's good-faith estimate of the motor vehicle rental company's daily charge to recover its actual total annual vehicle license costs. </section><section prefix="b">If the total amount of the vehicle license cost recovery fees collected by a motor vehicle renting company under this section in any calendar year exceeds the company's actual vehicle license costs, the motor vehicle renting company shall: <section prefix="1">Retain the excess amount; and </section><section prefix="2">Adjust the vehicle cost recovery fee for the following calendar year by a corresponding amount. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall prevent a motor vehicle renting company from including, or making adjustments during the calendar year to, separately stated surcharges, fees, or charges in the rental agreement, which may include but are not limited to vehicle license cost recovery fees, airport access fees, airport concession fees, consolidated facility charges, and all applicable taxes. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44166</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>