<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.080</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations governing officers and department -- Bonds of employees -- Oaths -- Acquisition of real estate.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations for the enlistment, training, discipline, and conduct of officers of the department and individuals employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, and the commissioner may promulgate administrative regulations for the governing and operation of the department as appear to him or her reasonably necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 16.010 to 16.170. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may require any officer, individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, or civilian who receives or disburses public funds in the course of his or her duties to file a bond, conditioned that he or she will honestly, correctly, and according to law, receive, disburse, and account for all public moneys coming into his or her hands. The commissioner, each officer, and each individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, shall execute a bond to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of not less than two thousand dollars ($2,000), conditioned upon the faithful discharge of his or her duties. The premium on the bonds shall be paid by the department. The commissioner, each officer of the department, and each individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class shall, before entering upon the discharge of their official duties, take the constitutional oath of office. </section><section prefix="3">Subject to the provisions of KRS 56.440 to 56.550, the commissioner, with the approval of the Governor and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, may acquire real estate or interests therein, by purchase, lease, or otherwise, necessary for the purposes of the department, and, with like approval, provide for the acquisition or construction of necessary buildings and other permanent structures and facilities. Title to any real estate acquired shall be taken in the name of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 62, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 2. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 14. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 3. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42244</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>