<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159">COMPULSORY ATTENDANCE </unit></structure><section_number>159.140</section_number><catch_line>Duties of director of pupil personnel or assistant. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director of pupil personnel, or an assistant appointed under KRS 159.080, shall: <section prefix="a">Devote his or her entire time to the duties of the office except as provided in subsection (2) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Enforce the compulsory attendance and census laws in the attendance district he or she serves; </section><section prefix="c">Acquaint the school with the home conditions of a habitual truant as described in KRS 159.150(3), and the home with the work and advantages of the school; </section><section prefix="d">Ascertain the causes of irregular attendance and truancy, through documented contact with the custodian of the student, and seek the elimination of these causes; </section><section prefix="e">Secure the enrollment in school of all students who should be enrolled and keep all enrolled students in reasonably regular attendance; </section><section prefix="f">Attempt to visit the homes of students who are reported to be in need of books, clothing, or parental care; </section><section prefix="g">Provide for the interviewing of students and the parents of those students who quit school to determine the reasons for the decision. The interviews shall be conducted in a location that is nonthreatening for the students and parents and according to procedures and interview questions established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education. The questions shall be designed to provide data that can be used for local district and statewide research and decision-making. Data shall be reported annually to the local board of education and the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="h">Report to the superintendent of schools in the district in which the student resides the number and cost of books and school supplies needed by any student whose parent, guardian, or custodian does not have sufficient income to furnish the student with the necessary books and school supplies; and </section><section prefix="i">Keep the records and make the reports that are required by law, by regulation of the Kentucky Board of Education, and by the superintendent and board of education. </section></section><section prefix="2">A local school district superintendent may waive the requirement that a director of pupil personnel devote his or her entire time to his or her duties. The superintendent shall report the decision to the commissioner of education. </section><section prefix="3">In any action brought to enforce compulsory attendance laws, the director of pupil personnel or an assistant shall document the home conditions of the student and the intervention strategies attempted and may, after consultation with the court-designated worker, refer the case to the family accountability, intervention, and response team. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 1, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 220, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4434-6, 4434-8, 4434-9, 4434-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43491</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>