<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">B LONG-TERM POLICY RESEARCH </unit></structure><section_number>7B.070</section_number><catch_line>Coordination by center of long-term planning -- Relationships with state agencies -- Use of center's findings and recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The center shall serve as a mechanism for coordinating resources and groups to focus on long-term planning; </section><section prefix="2">The center shall solicit input from the Legislative Research Commission, the Governor's Office for Policy and Management, universities, the private sector and the public, including local governments and area development districts; </section><section prefix="3">The Governor's Office for Policy and Management and the Legislative Research Commission shall biennially submit to the center a list of issues solicited from the program cabinets of the executive branch and co-chairs of interim legislative committees, respectively. The center shall include these issues in its broad-based efforts to determine priority study areas; </section><section prefix="4">A representative from the Governor's Office for Policy and Management and a legislator appointed by the Legislative Research Commission shall be invited to serve on each advisory committee; </section><section prefix="5">The board may enter into agreements with state agencies and institutions of higher education to provide staff on a time-limited basis for specific research projects; </section><section prefix="6">The center shall: <section prefix="a">Ensure that if departments or agencies of state government have responsibilities in an area of policy under study, they are encouraged to comment on the potential effects of government policies on critical trends and alternative futures; </section><section prefix="b">Consider the comments of the departments and agencies in performing its duties under this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">Include the official comments of the departments and agencies in any report provided to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></section><section prefix="7">Findings and recommendations in the studies of the center shall be delivered to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission for referral to the appropriate agency and interim committee. The head of the state agency or program to which the report pertains and the co-chairs of the interim legislative committees with jurisdiction shall give affirmative consideration to the report by a written response to the center within sixty (60) days, stating the action that shall be taken in response to the report. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">As the branches propose drafts of uniform forms to be used by all budget units pursuant to KRS 48.040(1), they shall provide for the affirmative consideration of the trends set forth by the biennial trends report of the center; </section><section prefix="b">As the Legislative Research Commission prescribes the uniform forms, records, and instructions to be used by branch budget units, it shall incorporate a requirement that agencies explain how their budget priorities address the trends and long-term policy implications set forth in the biennial trends report of the center. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (3) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=511</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>