<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.18-715</section_number><catch_line>Powers of commissions -- Duties of state agencies. </catch_line><order_by>18-715</order_by><text>The interstate water sanitation control commissions created by compacts to which Kentucky is a party, which compacts are composed of states forming a river basin, shall have all the powers provided for in the respective compacts, and all the powers necessary or incidental to the carrying out of the compacts in every particular. All officers of this state shall do all things falling within their respective provinces and jurisdictions necessary or incidental to the carrying out of the compacts in every particular, it being the policy of this state to perform and carry out the compacts and to accomplish the purposes thereof. All officers, departments, cabinets and persons of and in the state government or administration of this state shall at convenient times and upon request of the respective commissions furnish the commissions with information and data possessed by them and aid the commissions by loan of personnel or other means lying within their legal powers respectively. The courts of general jurisdiction of this state shall have the jurisdiction specified in the enforcement articles of the compacts, and the Attorney General or any other law-enforcing officer of this state shall have the power to institute any action for the enforcement of the orders of the commissions. Any powers granted to the commissions by this section shall be regarded as in aid of and supplemental to and not as a limitation upon any of the powers vested in the commissions by other laws of this state or by the laws of any of the states party to any of the compacts, or by Congress, or by the terms of the compacts. </text><history>Amended by implication 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1958. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4286b-3, 4286b-4. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1958</effective><former-codification> KRS 224.210, and also previously codified as 220.570. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10344</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>