<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="24" order_by="24">A DISTRICT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>24A.230</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction -- Authority. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The small claims division shall have jurisdiction, concurrent with that of the District Court, in all civil actions, other than libel, slander, alienation of affections, malicious prosecution and abuse of process actions, when the amount of money or damages or the value of the personal property claimed does not exceed two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500) exclusive of interest and costs. </section><section prefix="2">The division may also be used in civil matters when the plaintiff seeks to disaffirm, avoid, or rescind a contract or agreement for the purchase of goods or services not in excess of two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500) exclusive of interest and costs. </section><section prefix="3">The division shall have authority to grant appropriate relief, except no prejudgment actions for attachment, garnishment, replevin or other provisional remedy may be filed in the division. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  2011 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 4, provides that "any case which has been filed in a Circuit Court or District Court prior to the effective date of this Act (June 8, 2011) and the change in jurisdictional amounts (made by 2011 Ky. Acts ch.  91) shall remain in the court in which the case was originally filed, until the disposition of the case." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39856</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>