<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.435</section_number><catch_line>Designation of community action agency. </catch_line><order_by>435</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A community action agency may be designated by the following political subdivisions: <section prefix="a">One (1) or more counties; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) or more municipal corporations; or </section><section prefix="c">One (1) or more counties and one (1) or more municipal corporations. </section></section><section prefix="2">The chief elected official of the designating political subdivision may designate: <section prefix="a">The political subdivision as the community action agency, with the concurrence of the legislative authority of the political subdivision; or </section><section prefix="b">An eligible private nonprofit corporation as a community action agency if such corporation's board of directors is established pursuant to KRS 273.437. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the event a political subdivision elects not to designate a community action agency as provided under this section, the Governor may designate an eligible private nonprofit corporation as the community action agency for the political subdivision; provided, however, that the board of directors for the community action agency shall be established pursuant to KRS 273.437. </section><section prefix="4">The designating political subdivision shall: <section prefix="a">Publish, pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, a notice containing the designation of a community action agency, a summary of the plan for such agency, a location at which the plan can be reviewed, and the time, date, and location of a hearing on the plan; and </section><section prefix="b">Not less than thirty (30) nor more than sixty (60) days from the publication of the notice in subsection (1), convene a public hearing specifically for the purpose of receiving public comment on the designation plan. </section></section><section prefix="5">All community action agencies which were organized and operating subject to the provisions of KRS 273.410 to 273.455 as of September 30, 1981, shall be recognized as the community action agencies for each applicable political subdivision unless and until each political subdivision exercises the authority granted under this section. </section><section prefix="6">No community action agency shall be created after July 15, 1982, unless the: <section prefix="a">Population of the political subdivision equals or exceeds fifty thousand (50,000); or </section><section prefix="b">Political subdivisions designating a new community action agency are geographically contiguous and include a combined population equal to or exceeding fifty thousand (50,000). </section></section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13739</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>