<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.546</section_number><catch_line>Registrant prohibited from using social networking Web site or instant messaging or chat room program accessible by minors -- Registrant prohibited from photographing, filming, or making a video of a minor without consent of minor's parent or guardian.   </catch_line><order_by>546</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Instant messaging or chat room program" means a software program that allows two (2) or more persons to communicate over the Internet in real time using typed text; and </section><section prefix="b">"Social networking Web site" means an Internet Web site that: <section prefix="1">Facilitates the social introduction between two (2) or more persons; </section><section prefix="2">Allows a person to create a Web page or a personal profile; and </section><section prefix="3">Provides a person who visits the Web site the opportunity to communicate with another person. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">No registrant shall knowingly or intentionally use a social networking Web site or an instant messaging or chat room program if that Web site or program allows a person who is less than eighteen (18) years of age to access or use the Web site or program. </section><section prefix="3">No registrant shall intentionally photograph, film, or video a minor through traditional or electronic means without the written consent of the minor's parent, legal custodian, or guardian unless the registrant is the minor's parent, legal custodian, or guardian. The written consent required under this subsection shall state that the person seeking the consent is required to register as a sex offender under Kentucky law. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates subsection (2) or (3) of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42073</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>