<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.019</section_number><catch_line>Division of Historic Properties -- State curator. </catch_line><order_by>019</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Historic Properties established by KRS 42.425 shall be responsible for overseeing the management and preservation of state-owned historic properties including, but not limited to, the Executive Mansion, Old Governor's Mansion, Vest Lindsey House, Berry Hill, and the State Capitol. In addition, the division shall be responsible for maintaining state-owned furniture, china, silver, and art works and the care, display, inventory, conservation, restoration, and storage of any state-owned item of historical significance. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Parks and the Kentucky Horse Park may advise and consult the Division of Historic Properties in the operation, maintenance, restoration, conservation, and inventory of the state's shrines and museums. </section><section prefix="3">The director of the Division of Historic Properties shall serve as state curator pursuant to KRS 11.026. The director may employ the personnel and assemble the records and files necessary to perform the duties, responsibilities, and functions of the office. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 699, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21956</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>