<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.300</section_number><catch_line>Findings and goals of General Assembly regarding provision of water services in the Commonwealth -- Transfer of responsibility -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that it is necessary to encourage regionalization, consolidation, and partnerships among governmental agencies, and private parties when appropriate, with the goal of making potable water and wastewater treatment available to all Kentuckians through the maximization of financial resources and the conservation of natural resources of the Commonwealth. Based on these findings, the General Assembly declares that the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority shall implement a program for the provision of water services as authorized in the budget and directed by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall be responsible for the management and operation of the Water Resource Information System. The authority shall maintain and, at least annually, update the information contained in this system to ensure its accuracy. </section><section prefix="3">The authority may request all branches of state and local government, including special districts and water districts, to provide information relating to the status of existing plants, the financial condition of existing systems, and the existing regulatory authority held by agencies of government regarding the issue of water resource development and management. All branches of state and local government shall, to the extent reasonable and appropriate, comply with such requests for information. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall promulgate administrative regulations that require a water supply and distribution system receiving or seeking funding to provide current information regarding the financial, managerial, and technical aspects of its system and, thereafter, to furnish updates to the information so provided. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 90, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10591</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>