<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.27-100</section_number><catch_line>Construction of carbon dioxide transmission pipeline -- Proceedings for condemnation under Eminent Domain Act -- Legislative determination of essential public use. </catch_line><order_by>27-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section, "carbon dioxide transmission pipeline" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.27-010. </section><section prefix="2">If a carbon dioxide transmission pipeline company has received a construction certificate from the Kentucky State Board on Electric Generation and Siting under KRS 278.714 and is unable to contract or agree with the owner after a good-faith effort to do so, the company may condemn the lands and material for the use and occupation of the lands that are necessary for: <section prefix="a">Constructing, maintaining, utilizing, operating, and gaining access to a carbon dioxide transmission pipeline and all necessary machinery, equipment, pumping stations, appliances, and fixtures for use in connection with a carbon dioxide transmission pipeline; and </section><section prefix="b">Obtaining all necessary rights of ingress and egress to construct, examine, alter, repair, maintain, operate, or remove a carbon dioxide transmission pipeline and all of its component parts. </section></section><section prefix="3">The proceedings for condemnation shall be as provided in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">Carbon dioxide transmission pipelines, and the routing, construction, maintenance, and operation of them are, as a matter of legislative determination, declared to be a public use essential to the fulfillment of the purposes of this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.82, sec.1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>