<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5705Direct</section_number><catch_line>request.   </catch_line><order_by>5705Direct</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petitioner may file a direct request seeking establishment or modification of a support order or determination of parentage of a child. In the proceeding, the law of this state applies. </section><section prefix="2">A petitioner may file a direct request seeking recognition and enforcement of a support order or support agreement. In the proceeding, KRS 407.5706, 407.5707, 407.5708, 407.5709, 407.5710, 407.5711, 407.5712, and 407.5713 apply. </section><section prefix="3">In a direct request for recognition and enforcement of a Convention support order or foreign support agreement: <section prefix="a">A security, bond, or deposit is not required to guarantee the payment of costs and expenses; and </section><section prefix="b">An obligee or obligor that in the issuing country has benefited from free legal assistance is entitled to benefit, at least to the same extent, from any free legal assistance provided for by the law of this state under the same circumstances. </section></section><section prefix="4">A petitioner filing a direct request is not entitled to assistance from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="5">This Article does not prevent the application of laws of this state that provide simplified, more expeditious rules regarding a direct request for recognition and enforcement of a foreign support order or foreign support agreement. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 59, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>