<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.647</section_number><catch_line>Immunity from civil liability for rendering emergency care or treatment with epinephrine auto-injector.   </catch_line><order_by>647</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any individual or entity who, in good faith and without compensation, renders emergency care or treatment by the use of an epinephrine auto-injector shall be immune from civil liability for any personal injury as a result of the care or treatment, or as a result of any act or failure to act in providing or arranging further medical treatment, if the person acts as an ordinary, reasonable prudent person would have acted under the same or similar circumstances. </section><section prefix="2">The immunity from civil liability for any personal injury under subsection (1) of this section includes: <section prefix="a">A health-care practitioner who prescribes or authorizes the emergency use of the epinephrine auto-injector; </section><section prefix="b">A pharmacist who fills a prescription for the epinephrine auto-injector; </section><section prefix="c">A certified individual who provides or administers the epinephrine auto-injector; </section><section prefix="d">An authorized entity who stores or provides the epinephrine auto-injector to a certified individual or authorized noncertified individual; and </section><section prefix="e">An individual trainer or training entity providing the certified individual. </section></section><section prefix="3">The immunity from civil liability under subsection (1) of this section shall not apply if the personal injury results from the gross negligence or willful or wanton misconduct of the person rendering the emergency care. </section><section prefix="4">The requirements of KRS 311.646(6) shall not apply to any individual who provides or administers an epinephrine auto-injector if that individual is acting as a Good Samaritan under KRS 313.035 and 411.148. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 31, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 32 provides that this statute and KRS 311.645 and 311.646 created in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, secs. 29, 30, and 31 may be cited as the "Emergency Allergy Treatment Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44634</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>