<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.348</section_number><catch_line>Advanced placement, International Baccalaureate, dual enrollment, and dual credit courses. </catch_line><order_by>348</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Department of Education shall make available to middle and high schools information concerning the prerequisite content necessary for success in secondary courses, Advanced Placement or AP courses, and International Baccalaureate or IB courses. The department shall provide sample syllabi, instructional resources, and instructional supports for teachers that will assist in preparing students for more rigorous coursework. Instructional supports shall include professional development for assisting students enrolled in the Kentucky Virtual High School or other virtual learning settings. </section><section prefix="b">Each secondary school-based decision making council shall offer a core curriculum of AP, IB, dual enrollment, or dual credit courses, using either or both on-site instruction or electronic instruction through the Kentucky Virtual High School or other on-line alternatives. In addition, each school-based decision making council shall comply with any additional requirements for AP, IB, dual enrollment, and dual credit courses that may be established cooperatively by the Kentucky Department of Education, the Education Professional Standards Board, and the Council on Postsecondary Education in accordance with the definitions in KRS 158.007. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each secondary school-based decision making council shall establish a policy on the recruitment and assignment of students to AP, IB, dual enrollment, and dual credit courses that recognizes that all students have the right to participate in a rigorous and academically challenging curriculum. All students who are willing to accept the challenge of a rigorous academic curriculum shall be admitted to AP courses, including AP courses offered through the Kentucky Virtual High School and accepted for credit toward graduation under KRS 158.622(3)(a), IB courses, dual enrollment courses, and dual credit courses, if they have successfully completed the prerequisite coursework or have otherwise demonstrated mastery of the prerequisite content knowledge and skills as determined by measurable standards. If a school does not offer an AP course in a particular subject area, the school shall permit a qualified student to enroll in the AP course offered by the Kentucky Virtual High School and receive credit toward graduation under KRS 158.622(3)(a). </section><section prefix="3">Effective with the 2008-2009 school year and thereafter, students enrolled in AP or IB courses in the public schools shall have the cost of the examinations paid by the Kentucky Department of Education. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3719</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>