<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who operates a hotel without a permit as provided in KRS 219.011 to 219.081 or who fails to comply with any other provisions of KRS 219.011 to 219.081 or any administrative regulation promulgated pursuant thereto shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall on conviction thereof be subject to a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than five hundred dollars ($500), or by imprisonment for not more than thirty (30) days, or both; but if the violation is committed after a conviction of the person under this section has become final, the person shall be subject to a fine of not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000), or by imprisonment for not more than ninety (90) days, or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who operates, constructs, or alters a community without a permit as provided for in KRS 219.310 to 219.410 or who violates any other provision of KRS 219.310 to 219.410 or any administrative regulation promulgated by the secretary or order issued pursuant thereto shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). Each day of violation shall constitute a separate offense. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(22). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 9. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9766</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>