<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.257</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for distribution of explanatory materials -- Open Records and Open Meetings laws -- Retention and management of public records. </catch_line><order_by>257</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of the Attorney General shall, within ninety (90) days of June 20, 2005, and thereafter, within ninety (90) days of the effective date of any legislation amending the provisions of the Open Meetings Act or the Open Records Act, distribute to all county judge/executives, mayors, county attorneys, city attorneys, superintendents of public school districts, presidents of each of the state public postsecondary education institutions identified in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or 164.001(13) or (17), and attorneys of public school districts and public postsecondary education institutions throughout Kentucky written information prepared by the Office of the Attorney General that explains the procedural and substantive provisions of the Open Meetings Act, KRS 61.805 to 61.850, and the Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884, together with the information required by KRS 171.223 to be prepared by the Department for Libraries and Archives concerning proper retention and management of public records. This distribution may be by electronic means. </section><section prefix="2">All superintendents of public school districts and the presidents of each of the state public postsecondary education institutions identified in KRS 161.220(4)(b) or 164.001(13) or (17) shall be responsible for designating and submitting the names and addresses of the attorneys to whom this information shall be disseminated to the Office of the Attorney General. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=915</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>