<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.205</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Printing requirements for personal checks. </catch_line><order_by>205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section the following terms shall have the following respective meanings: <section prefix="a">"Check" means any check, draft, or similar order for the withdrawal or payment of money, but such term does not include any counter check or similar draft or order, nor does it include any check, draft or order provided upon the opening of any account for use by the customer until printed checks for such account have been prepared; </section><section prefix="b">"Federal or state financial institution" means any financial institution and any bank, savings and loan association, or credit union organized under the laws of the United States and operated in this state; </section><section prefix="c">"Personal checking account" means any demand or similar deposit account that is opened or established in the name of one (1) or more natural persons with a federal or state financial institution subsequent to July 15, 1986, and from which signatories on the account can withdraw or order the payment of funds by using a check. </section></section><section prefix="2">All checks provided directly or indirectly by a federal or state financial institution for use in connection with a particular personal checking account shall have the numerical month and year in which the account was opened legibly printed on the faces of the checks. </section><section prefix="3">In the case of a personal checking account that is closed and a new account opened simultaneously upon the advice of the bank, the checks in the new account shall have the numerical month and year in which the closed account was opened legibly printed on the faces of the checks. If the closed account was opened prior to July 15, 1986, no date shall be required to be imprinted on the checks. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>