<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.420</section_number><catch_line>Duties of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall:  <section prefix="a">Fix and announce dates for the examinations;  </section><section prefix="b">Prepare and make available forms for application for a water well driller certificate;  </section><section prefix="c">See that all examinations for certificates are graded;  </section><section prefix="d">Prepare and issue certificates to those entitled thereto;  </section><section prefix="e">Upon recommendation of the board, promulgate rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 223.405 to 223.460, including the conducting of examinations and the suspension and revocation of certificates;  </section><section prefix="f">Inspect and investigate water wells to ensure compliance with the provisions of KRS 223.405 to 223.460;  </section><section prefix="g">Maintain and publish annually a register showing the names and addresses of certified water well drillers and distribute a copy of same to each certified individual free of charge;  </section><section prefix="h">Maintain under the control of the executive secretary and treasurer a record showing:  <section prefix="1">The names and addresses of all certified individuals under KRS 223.425;  </section><section prefix="2">The dates of issuance and renewal of all certificates;  </section><section prefix="3">The date and substance of the charges set forth in any complaint for suspension or revocation of any certificate;  </section><section prefix="4">The date and substance of all petitions for reinstatement of certificates; and  </section><section prefix="5">The final order on such complaints and petitions.  </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Upon written request the cabinet shall make the information set forth in paragraph (h) of subsection (1) of this section available to any person so requesting.  </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may conduct training to further the provisions of KRS 223.405 to 223.460.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9977</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>