<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.977</section_number><catch_line>Directory of coal road system. </catch_line><order_by>977</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall publish a directory, including supporting maps and other documents, designating the official coal road system in coal impact and coal producing counties which shall include all public highways, roads, bridges, and streets over which quantities of coal sufficient to significantly affect the condition and state of repair of such highways, roads, bridges, and streets have been transported in the immediately preceding year. The cabinet shall further publish the total county mileage of the official coal road system and the total ton-miles within each coal impact and coal producing county for said preceding year. </section><section prefix="2">Every person, producer or processor shipping or transporting coal over the public highways, roads, bridges, and streets, shall file with the Transportation Cabinet information at intervals as the cabinet shall designate by administrative regulation promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, for the purpose of identifying those highways, roads, and streets comprising the coal road system and the quantities of coal transported thereon, in order that the cabinet can accurately calculate total ton-miles within each coal impact and coal producing county. A copy of the information furnished to the Energy and Environment Cabinet pursuant to the provisions of KRS 350.0285 and a copy of the information furnished to the Department for Natural Resources pursuant to the provisions of KRS 351.070 and 352.420 shall be submitted to the Transportation Cabinet to satisfy the reporting requirements of this subsection and the transportation plan shall be annually updated to reflect in route changes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 231, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 20, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 177.977, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 177.972. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5407</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>