<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.481</section_number><catch_line>Rights of judgment creditor. </catch_line><order_by>481</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section provides the exclusive remedy by which the judgment creditor of a partner or the transferee of a partner may satisfy a judgment out of the judgment debtor's transferable interest. </section><section prefix="2">On application to a court of competent jurisdiction by any judgment creditor of a partner or a partner's transferee, the court may charge the transferable interest of the judgment debtor with payment of the unsatisfied amount of the judgment. To the extent so charged, the judgment creditor has only the rights of a transferee, and shall have no right to participate in the management of or to cause the dissolution of the partnership. The court may appoint a receiver of the share of the distributions due or to become due to the judgment debtor in respect of the partnership and make all other orders, directions, accounts, and inquiries the judgment debtor might have made or which the circumstances of the case may require to give effect to the charging order. </section><section prefix="3">A charging order constitutes a lien on and the right to receive distributions made with respect to the judgment debtor's transferable interest. A charging order does not of itself constitute an assignment of the transferable interest. </section><section prefix="4">The court may order a foreclosure upon the transferable interest subject to the charging order at any time. The purchaser at the foreclosure sale has the rights of a transferee. </section><section prefix="5">At any time before foreclosure, an interest charged may be redeemed: <section prefix="a">By the judgment debtor; </section><section prefix="b">With property other than limited partnership property, by one (1) or more of the other partners; or </section><section prefix="c">With limited partnership property, by the limited partnership with the consent of all partners whose interests are not so charged. </section></section><section prefix="6">This section does not deprive any partner or a partner's transferee of the benefit of any exemption laws applicable to the partner's or transferee's transferable interest. </section><section prefix="7">The partnership is not a necessary party to an application for a charging order. Service of the charging order on a partnership may be made by the court granting the charging order or as the court may otherwise direct. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 50, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 53, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>