<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.780</section_number><catch_line>Petition for annexation of lands -- Requirements -- Parties -- Hearing -- Determination -- Referendum. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any one (1) or more owners of land may petition the board of supervisors to have their lands added to a watershed conservancy district. Such petition shall define the boundaries of the land desired to be annexed, the number of acres of land involved, and other information pertinent to such proposal. When the boundary described embraces lands of others than the petitioners, the petition shall so state and shall be signed by twenty-five (25) or more of the landowners in the territory described, if fifty (50) or more such owners are involved, or by a majority if less than fifty (50) landowners are involved. </section><section prefix="2">Within thirty (30) days after such petition is filed, the board shall cause due notice to be given, as provided in KRS 262.010(4), of a hearing on such petition. All interested parties shall have a right to attend such hearing and be heard. The board shall determine whether the lands described in the petition or any portion thereof shall be included in the district. If all the landowners in the territory involved are not petitioners, a referendum shall be held within such territory as provided in KRS 262.725, 262.730 and 262.735, before making a final determination. If it is determined that such land should be added, this fact shall be certified by the board of supervisors to the county clerk in the county or counties involved. After recording, the certification shall be filed with the State Soil Conservation Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 389, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 17, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><lrc-note>.This section was amended by 1984 Acts Chapter 100, sec. 24, and 1984 Acts Chapter 218, sec. 7, which conflict and cannot be compiled together. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the amendment in Chapter 218, sec. 7 prevails as the later enactment. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>