<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.340</section_number><catch_line>Incorporation, powers, directors of federation -- Existing federation. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The said federation of farm bureaus organized pursuant to KRS 247.330 shall be a body corporate upon the filing with the county clerk of the county in which the principal office of said federation is located, articles of incorporation signed by the requisite number of authorized representatives of said county farm bureaus, and upon the filing of a copy of said articles of incorporation certified to by said county clerk, in the office of the Secretary of State of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">Said articles of incorporation shall state: <section prefix="a">The names of the county farm bureaus organizing said state federation; </section><section prefix="b">The corporate name of said state federation; </section><section prefix="c">The location of the principal office; </section><section prefix="d">The nature of its business and its general powers, and may set out any other provision, which the incorporators may deem desirable and which are not in conflict with the law. </section></section><section prefix="3">The incorporators signing the articles of incorporation shall constitute the first board of directors until the first annual election date to be fixed by the bylaws of the corporation. </section><section prefix="4">Any state federation of county farm bureaus heretofore organized pursuant to the provisions of KRS 247.330, or, Chapter 76 of the Acts of 1920 of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and having heretofore filed its articles of incorporation as provided in this section, shall not be required to reincorporate, but may continue its corporate existence as if done pursuant hereto, and said corporation or any corporation organized pursuant to this section and KRS 247.330, may amend its articles of incorporation by a majority vote of its voting delegates assembled in annual state convention. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 382, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 5, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42d-17. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11626</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>