<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.068</section_number><catch_line>Fees for fingerprint impressions or photograph requested for professional, trade, or commercial purposes or personal use. </catch_line><order_by>068</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city, county, charter county, urban-county government, consolidated local government, unified local government, or special district, or any agency or instrumentality thereof, may charge a fee of ten dollars ($10) per set of fingerprint impressions taken and five dollars ($5) per photograph taken or copied when those services are requested by a person for professional, trade, or commercial purposes or for personal use. </section><section prefix="2">If the Department of Kentucky State Police sets new fingerprinting and photograph fees under the provisions of KRS 16.068, any city, county, charter county, urban-county government, consolidated local government, unified local government, or special district, or any agency or instrumentality thereof, may increase fingerprinting and photograph fees to equal those fees established by the Department of Kentucky State Police through administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall change any other fee allocation allowed by statute. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has inserted "unified local government," after "consolidated local government," in subsection (2) of this statute to match the way the types of government are listed in subsection (1) of this statute. "Unified local government" was inadvertently omitted from subsection (2) in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 4, and the Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error under the authority of KRS 7.136(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43526</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>