<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.0813</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board -- Administrative regulations -- Fees.   </catch_line><order_by>0813</order_by><text>The board shall: <section prefix="1">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A for the administration and enforcement of KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="2">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A establishing a code of ethics, standards of practice, and continuing education for licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselors, licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associates, certified alcohol and drug counselors, and registered alcohol and drug peer support specialists; </section><section prefix="3">Approve and disapprove, at least twice a year, those persons who shall be licensed, certified, or registered under KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="4">Approve the examination required of applicants for licensure or certification as alcohol and drug counselors and applicants for registration as alcohol and drug peer support specialists, and promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A for the administration and grading of the examination; </section><section prefix="5">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to define the process to register with the board as a registered alcohol and drug peer support specialist, certified alcohol and drug counselor, licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associate, or licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor; </section><section prefix="6">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A establishing grounds and procedures for denying, suspending, failing to reissue, or revoking a license, certificate, or registration, and issuing reprimands and admonishments pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="7">Hold a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B upon the request of an aggrieved licensee, licensee associate, certificate holder, or registrant, or an applicant for a license, certificate, or registration; </section><section prefix="8">Employ needed personnel and establish their duties and compensation; </section><section prefix="9">Maintain a register of licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselors, licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associates, certified alcohol and drug counselors, and registered alcohol and drug peer support specialists; </section><section prefix="10">Keep a complete record of the board's proceedings; </section><section prefix="11">Investigate suspected or alleged violations of KRS 309.080 to 309.089 and the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="12">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A establishing an initial licensure fee, certification fee, registration fee, and annual renewal fees not to exceed three hundred dollars ($300) each; </section><section prefix="13">Take legal action as necessary to restrain or enjoin violations of KRS 309.080 to 309.089 and the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089; </section><section prefix="14">Submit an annual report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission by January 1 of each year, which lists all hearings conducted by the board and the decisions rendered; and </section><section prefix="15">Collect and deposit all fees, fines, and other moneys owed to the board into the State Treasury to the credit of the revolving fund established in KRS 309.082. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h), during codification of 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 4 (this statute), the Reviser of Statutes has corrected a reference in subsection (15) to "Section 15 of this Act" to read instead "Section 16 of this Act" since the text of subsection (15) is referring to a revolving fund established in Section 16 of that Act, not Section 15. As codified, Section 16 became KRS 309.082. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44292</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>