<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.570</section_number><catch_line>Hearing -- Burden of proof. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At a hearing convened pursuant to KRS 387.500 to 387.770 for the purpose of determining the disability of a respondent, the respondent shall have a jury trial and shall have the right to present evidence and to confront and cross-examine all witnesses.  </section><section prefix="2">The hearing may be closed to the public on request of the respondent or his counsel.  </section><section prefix="3">The respondent shall be present at the hearing, and his presence may be waived only upon a determination of the court that his attendance would subject him to serious risk of harm. Such determination shall be evidence only of the respondent's inability to attend the hearing and shall not be considered in determining the need for guardianship or conservatorship.  </section><section prefix="4">The court may remove itself to the place of residence of the respondent to conduct the hearing in the presence of the respondent.  </section><section prefix="5">The burden of proof shall be on the Commonwealth to prove the disability or partial disability of the respondent by clear and convincing evidence.  </section><section prefix="6">The respondent will not be determined partially disabled or disabled unless at least one (1) of the persons who participated in the interdisciplinary evaluation required by KRS 387.540 testifies in person at the hearing. This section shall not be interpreted to preclude the respondent from requiring the testimony of more than one (1) person participating in the preparation of the evaluation report. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>