<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.090</section_number><catch_line>Law enforcement to assist protective order petitioner and victim ofdating violence and abuse, sexual assault, or stalking -- Statewideenforcement -- Civil and criminal immunity.  </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text>(1)A court issuing an interpersonal protective order shall direct the appropriatelaw enforcement agency to assist the petitioner in having the provisions of theorder complied with.(2)When a law enforcement officer has reason to suspect that a person has beenthe victim of dating violence and abuse, sexual assault, or stalking, the officershall use all reasonable means to provide assistance to the victim, includingbut not limited to:(a)Remaining at the location of the call for assistance so long as the officerreasonably suspects there is danger to the physical safety of individualsthere without the presence of a law enforcement officer;(b)Assisting the victim in obtaining medical treatment, including transportingthe victim to the nearest medical facility capable of providing thenecessary treatment; and(c)Advising the victim immediately of the rights available to them, includingthe provisions of this chapter.(3)Orders of protection shall be enforced in any county of the Commonwealth.(4)Officers acting in good faith under this chapter shall be immune from criminaland civil liability.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 27, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44775</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>