<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.180</section_number><catch_line>Prosecution of adult abuse, neglect, and exploitation. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If adequate personnel are available, each Commonwealth's attorney's office and each county attorney's office shall have an attorney trained in adult abuse, neglect, and exploitation. </section><section prefix="2">Commonwealth's attorneys and county attorneys, or their assistants, shall take an active part in interviewing the adult alleged to have been abused, neglected, or exploited, and shall inform the adult about the proceedings throughout the case. </section><section prefix="3">If adequate personnel are available, Commonwealth's attorneys and county attorneys shall provide for an arrangement that allows one (1) lead prosecutor to handle the case from inception to completion to reduce the number of persons involved with the adult victim. </section><section prefix="4">Commonwealth's attorneys, county attorneys, cabinet representatives, and other members of multidisciplinary teams shall minimize the involvement of the adult in legal proceedings, avoiding appearances at preliminary hearings, grand jury hearings, and other proceedings when possible. </section><section prefix="5">Commonwealth's attorneys, county attorneys, and victim advocates employed by Commonwealth's attorneys or county attorneys shall make appropriate referrals for counseling, private legal services, and other appropriate services to ensure the future protection of the adult when a decision is made not to prosecute the case. The Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney shall explain the decision not to prosecute to the family or guardian, as appropriate, and to the adult victim. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8198</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>