<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.765</section_number><catch_line>Administration of fund -- Transfer of reimbursement funds -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>765</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS Chapter 342 to the contrary, the office of the Attorney General shall be responsible for the administration of the uninsured employers' fund and shall be charged with the conservation of the assets of the fund. Funds to reimburse the Attorney General's office for expenses incurred in litigation and administration in defense of the uninsured employers' fund shall be transferred upon request of the Attorney General's office and approval by the secretary of the Labor Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The office of the Attorney General shall report monthly to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, the Interim Joint Committee on Labor and Industry, and the commissioner the amount of the agency fund expenditures in each month for the uninsured employers' fund and the nature of these expenditures. In addition, the Office of the Attorney General shall report quarterly to the commissioner on the amount of funds recouped from uninsured employers. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1848, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 14, sec. 74, effective April 4, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 437, Pt. II, J, sec. 44(3), (4), effective April 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32552</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>