<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.125</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Bicycle and Bikeway Commission -- Membership -- Duties -- Authority to adopt administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Kentucky Bicycle and Bikeway Commission within the Transportation Cabinet. The commission shall consist of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor. Members of the commission shall receive necessary travel expenses. The members of the commission shall elect a chairman who shall serve a two (2) year term. Initially, three (3) members shall be appointed for two (2) years, and four (4) members for four (4) years. Each appointment thereafter shall be for four (4) years. Upon the resignation of a member in midterm, the Governor shall appoint a replacement for the remainder of the unexpired term. The Governor shall make appointments to the commission with a view to represent each of the state's geographical regions and to various types of bicycle users and interests. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall meet in various sections of the state on a quarterly basis, and at other times as may be necessary to fulfill its duties. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The commission shall be provided with adequate staff as determined by the secretary, and this staff shall be responsible for maintaining the minutes of the meetings, researching bicycle and bikeway related topics, and other activities for the commission as may be consistent with the commission's role within the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall have the following duties: <section prefix="a">To represent the interests of bicyclists in advising the secretary on all matters pertaining to bicycles, bikeways, and their use, extent, and location; </section><section prefix="b">Assist the bicycle and bikeway program in the exercise of its duties within the cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Promote the best interests of the bicycling public, within the context of the total transportation system, to governing officials and the public at large. </section></section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall study bicycle and bikeway needs and potentials and shall report the findings to the legislature on an annual basis. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall adopt administrative regulations to implement the purposes of KRS 174.120 and this section. </section><section prefix="6">Initial appointments to the commission shall be made no later than August 1, 1994. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>