<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-512</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of financing statement. </catch_line><order_by>9-512</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to KRS 355.9-509, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or, subject to subsection (5) of this section, otherwise amend the information provided in, a financing statement by filing an amendment that: <section prefix="a">Identifies, by its file number, the initial financing statement to which the amendment relates; and </section><section prefix="b">If the amendment relates to an initial financing statement filed in a filing office described in KRS 355.9-501(1)(a), provides the information specified in KRS 355.9-502(2). </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 355.9-515, the filing of an amendment does not extend the period of effectiveness of the financing statement. </section><section prefix="3">A financing statement that is amended by an amendment that adds collateral is effective as to the added collateral only from the date of the filing of the amendment. </section><section prefix="4">A financing statement that is amended by an amendment that adds a debtor is effective as to the added debtor only from the date of the filing of the amendment. </section><section prefix="5">An amendment is ineffective to the extent it: <section prefix="a">Purports to delete all debtors and fails to provide the name of a debtor to be covered by the financing statement; or </section><section prefix="b">Purports to delete all secured parties of record and fails to provide the name of a new secured party of record. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 103, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>