<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">ORGANIZATION AND GOVERNMENT OF CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>83.580</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of mayor -- Information on city and officials to Department for Local Government -- Representation of county districts on boards and commissions. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The mayor shall: <section prefix="a">Cause the ordinances of the city and the laws of the state to be executed and enforced; </section><section prefix="b">Communicate to the board of aldermen at least once a year a statement of the finances and general condition of the affairs of the city and information in relation thereto as the board of aldermen requires; </section><section prefix="c">Recommend, by written message to the board of aldermen, the measures he deems expedient; </section><section prefix="d">Fill, with the consent of the board of aldermen, all vacancies in executive and ministerial offices and the filling of which is not otherwise provided for; </section><section prefix="e">Exercise a general supervision over all the executive and ministerial officers of the city and see that their official duties are honestly performed; and </section><section prefix="f">No later than January 31 of each year, mail to the Department for Local Government a list containing current city information including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="1">The correct name of the mayor, members of the board of aldermen, and the following appointed officials who are serving as of January 1 of each year: <section prefix="a">Clerk of the board of aldermen; </section><section prefix="b">City treasurer; </section><section prefix="c">City attorney; </section><section prefix="d">Finance director; </section><section prefix="e">Police chief; </section><section prefix="f">Fire chief; and </section><section prefix="g">Public works director; </section></section><section prefix="2">The correct name of the city, mailing address for city hall, and the telephone number of city hall; and </section><section prefix="3">The name and telephone number of either an elected or appointed official to serve as a contact person that may be reached during normal business hours of 8:00 a.m. to 4:30 p.m. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The mayor shall appoint to those seats which are not subject to prior qualification on a board or commission an equal number of members from each county commissioner's district, as created in accordance with KRS 67.045, into which the authority of the board or commission extends. If there are more districts than members of a particular board or commission, the mayor shall not appoint more than one (1) member from any district. If there are more members of a particular board or commission than there are districts, the mayor shall equalize appointments from among districts to the extent possible. The mayor shall not be required, but shall use his best efforts, to balance appointments from among districts on a board or commission if the appointments are to be made from nominees submitted by other groups or individuals, or if nominees shall have a professional or technical background, expertise, or membership. The mayor shall attempt to balance appointments from among districts on all boards and commissions to equalize representation of all districts over the entire range of boards and commissions. </section><section prefix="3">The mayor may: <section prefix="a">Remove from office, by a written order, any officer appointed by him, unless otherwise provided by law; </section><section prefix="b">Appoint his own staff, and remove them at pleasure; </section><section prefix="c">Require from any executive or ministerial officer of the city or joint agency of the city a statement in writing concerning the discharge of his duties; and </section><section prefix="d">Exercise the same power to administer oaths that justices of the peace and other judicial officers of the state have. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Department for Local Government shall immediately forward one (1) copy of the information received from the mayor to the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 65, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 59, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 43, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25150</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>