<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.111</section_number><catch_line>Superintendents Training Program and Assessment Center -- Local board not responsible for training costs -- Assessment of superintendents required – Contracts for training providers permitted. </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Education shall establish a Superintendents Training Program and Assessment Center. The department shall provide for assessor training and shall ensure that an assessment center includes but is not limited to training and participation in the following components: <section prefix="a">Core concepts of leadership and quality practices; </section><section prefix="b">Effective implementation of school-based decision making; </section><section prefix="c">Kentucky school law; </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky school finance and budgeting; </section><section prefix="e">School curriculum and assessment; </section><section prefix="f">Instructional leadership; </section><section prefix="g">School improvement; </section><section prefix="h">Community and board relations; </section><section prefix="i">Effective communication; and </section><section prefix="j">An executive coaching and mentoring program with an emphasis on demonstrated professional growth. </section></section> The department may provide assessment centers regionally. <section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, an employing local board of education shall not be responsible for any training costs associated with a superintendent's participation in the training and assessment center process. </section><section prefix="3">At the conclusion of the training, each participant shall deliver to the employing board of education and the Kentucky Department of Education a comprehensive collection of work products and assessments that demonstrate proficiency in each area of training. </section><section prefix="4">In addition to any applicable certification and experience requirements, any person hired for the first time as superintendent in Kentucky shall successfully complete the assessment center process within two (2) years of taking office as superintendent. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Board of Education shall adopt administrative regulations to govern the training content, number of hours, assessments, and work products for successful completion of the training and assessment center process. The board shall also establish the continuing professional development requirements for school superintendents to include, at a minimum, three (3) hours of annual training in school finance and three (3) hours of annual training in ethics. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Education may contract with qualified agencies, organizations, or institutions or may approve programs offered by training providers to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1, effective April 10, 2014; and ch. 136, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective February 17, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt.  II, sec. 46, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 77 and 136, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43529</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>