<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.14-650</section_number><catch_line>Definition for KRS 304.14-650 to 304.14-675. </catch_line><order_by>14-650</order_by><text>As used in KRS 304.14-650 to 304.14-675, "short-term nursing home insurance policies" means any insurance policy or rider advertised, marketed, offered, or designed to provide coverage for less than twelve (12) consecutive months for each covered person on an expense-incurred, indemnity, prepaid, or other basis for one (1) or more necessary or medically necessary diagnostic, preventative, therapeutic, rehabilitative, maintenance, or personal care services, provided in a setting other than an acute care unit of a hospital unless the hospital or unit is licensed or certified to provide services in a skilled nursing facility, extended care facility, intermediate care facility, convalescent nursing home, personal care facility, home health care agency, adult day care facility, and assisted living facility. This term shall also include a policy or rider that provides for payment of benefits based upon cognitive impairment or loss of functional capacity. Short-term nursing home insurance policies may be issued by insurers, fraternal benefit societies, nonprofit hospitals, medical-surgical, dental, and health services corporations, health maintenance organizations, or any similar organization to the extent they are otherwise authorized to issued life or health insurance. Short-term nursing home insurance policies shall not include any insurance policy which is offered primarily to provide basic Medicare supplement coverage, basic hospital expense coverage, basic medical-surgical expense coverage, hospital confinement indemnity, major medical expense coverage, disability income or related-asset protection coverage, accident only coverage, specified disease or specified accident coverage. </text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17188</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>