<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.843</section_number><catch_line>Monitoring of operations of authority by Attorney General and Auditor of Public Accounts -- Report to General Assembly. </catch_line><order_by>843</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General and the Auditor of Public Accounts shall monitor the operations of the authority. </section><section prefix="2">Either the Attorney General or the Auditor of Public Accounts, or both, may make at any time any examinations or investigations, jointly or severally, of the operations, practices, management, or other matters relating to the authority as they deem necessary. Either of them shall have the power to subpoena witnesses and records for these purposes, and otherwise to compel the giving of evidence for any matter under study. The Attorney General, the Auditor of Public Accounts, or any employee authorized by either of them may require the giving of this evidence under oath and may administer the oath. Any person voluntarily providing information or evidence may be required to do so under oath administered by the Attorney General, the Auditor of Public Accounts, or any employee authorized by either of them. If any person fails or refuses to testify or furnish documentary evidence concerning any matter requested, the Franklin Circuit Court, on application of either the Attorney General or the Auditor of Public Accounts or both, may compel obedience by proceedings for contempt as in the case of disobedience of a subpoena issued from the Circuit Court or of a refusal to testify in the Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="3">The Attorney General and the Auditor of Public Accounts shall have without restriction: <section prefix="a">Full access to all records of the authority, except that confidential medical records of employees of insureds are available only by subpoena; </section><section prefix="b">Full access to all financial transactions and investigations of the authority; and </section><section prefix="c">The right to attend all meetings of the board and its committees. </section></section><section prefix="4">If fraud, mismanagement, illegal activity, imprudent practices, or other deficiencies are found in the operations or other practices of the authority, the Attorney General or Auditor of Public Accounts, or both shall: <section prefix="a">Recommend internal corrective action; </section><section prefix="b">Institute a civil action or action for injunctive relief to compel corrective action; </section><section prefix="c">Institute criminal proceedings against any officer or employee of the authority or any other person, as defined in KRS 446.010, as may be necessary; or </section><section prefix="d">Any combination of the above listed actions or any other form of action reasonably calculated to assure efficient and honest operations of the authority and those involved with it. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Attorney General and the Auditor of Public Accounts shall report jointly to the General Assembly in January of each year in which the General Assembly convenes in an even-numbered-year regular session the results of the monitoring activities required by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 24, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 12, sec. 61, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>