<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.930</section_number><catch_line>Purposes of KRS 381.935 to 381.945. </catch_line><order_by>930</order_by><text>The purposes of KRS 381.935 to 381.945 are as follows:  <section prefix="1">To facilitate and require the demonstration of a clear understanding between the owners of surface and mineral estates in land concerning their respective rights to use and occupy or injure the surface of the land;  </section><section prefix="2">To protect the security of titles to land and improvements thereto;  </section><section prefix="3">To promote the free alienability of land;  </section><section prefix="4">To prevent hardship and injustice to surface or mineral owners arising from uncertainty of the law;  </section><section prefix="5">To promote the conservation and the full and efficient use of all natural resources of the state, including the land, the making of improvements to the land, the growth of agriculture, the development of new industry and the general economic well-being of the state and its people;  </section><section prefix="6">To codify a rule of construction for mineral deeds relating to coal extraction so as to implement the intention of the parties at the time the instrument was created; and  </section><section prefix="7">To foster certainty and uniformity in the operation of the law.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35575</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>