<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.310</section_number><catch_line>License for participants in horse racing. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person not required to be licensed under KRS 230.300 who desires to participate in horse racing in the Commonwealth as a horse owner, trainer, jockey, apprentice jockey, agent, stable employee, racing official, association employee, or employee of a person or concern contracting with the association to provide a service or commodity and which requires their presence on association grounds during a race meeting, or veterinarian, farrier, horse dentist, or supplier of food, tack, medication, or horse feed, or in any other capacity as the racing commission shall from time to time establish by administrative regulation, shall first apply to the racing commission for a license to participate in the activity on association grounds during a race meeting. No person required to be licensed by this section may participate in any activity required to be licensed on association grounds during a race meeting without a valid license therefor. An applicant for a license shall submit to the racing commission fingerprints as may be required and other information necessary and reasonable for processing a license application. The racing commission is authorized to exchange fingerprint data with the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Federal Bureau of Investigation in order to conduct a criminal history background check of an applicant. The racing commission may issue a license if it finds that the financial responsibility, age, experience, reputation, competence, and general fitness of the applicant to perform the activity permitted by a license are consistent with the best interest of racing and the maintenance of the honesty, integrity, and high quality thereof. </section><section prefix="2">A license may be issued for the calendar year for which an applicant applies or, if authorized by administrative regulation, a license may be issued that expires on the last day of the birth month of the licensee. A license may be renewed by the racing commission. The license shall be valid at all horse race meetings in the Commonwealth during the period for which it is issued unless suspended or revoked under the administrative regulations promulgated by the racing commission under this chapter. With respect to horse owners and trainers, the racing commission may promulgate administrative regulations to facilitate and promote uniform, reciprocal licensing with other states. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 456, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 262, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 21, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 5. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 11, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10843</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>