<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.190</section_number><catch_line>Identification of contributors and advertisers. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All newspaper or magazine advertising, posters, circulars, billboards, handbills, sample ballots, and paid-for television or radio announcements which expressly advocate the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate, slate of candidates, or group of candidates for nomination or election to any public office shall be identified by the words "paid for by" followed by the name and address of the individual or committee which paid for the communication; except that if paid for by a candidate, slate of candidates, or campaign committee, it shall be identified only by the words "paid for by" followed by the name of the candidate, slate of candidates, or campaign committee, whichever is applicable. For television and radio broadcasts, compliance with Federal Communications Commission regulations regarding sponsored programs and broadcasts by candidates for public office shall be considered compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="2">The management of newspapers and magazines shall keep a one (1) year record of all statements, articles, or advertisements referred to in subsection (1) of this section, that appear in their publications, however, nothing in subsection (1) of this section shall be construed to require editors or editorial writers of newspapers and magazines to identify themselves in the manner therein required with any article or editorial written by them as part of their duties as an employee or employer. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 191. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27870</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>