<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.948</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 164.9481, 164.9483, and 164.9485. </catch_line><order_by>948</order_by><text>As used in KRS 164.9481, 164.9483, and 164.9485, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Campus" means all property owned, managed, or controlled by an institution of postsecondary education including but not limited to academic buildings; student housing and recreational facilities; residential facilities operated by any officially recognized student organization; all sections of public property such as streets, sidewalks, and parking facilities immediately contiguous to campus buildings; and remote facilities leased for use as classroom space or student living. </section><section prefix="2">"Campus security authority" means campus police, security officers, and any official at a postsecondary education institution who has significant responsibility for student and campus activities, including student discipline, student housing, student judicial affairs, and student life administration. Professional mental health, pastoral, and other licensed counselors when functioning in that capacity are not considered campus security authorities. </section><section prefix="3">"Crime" means murder, manslaughter, reckless homicide, assault, menacing, wanton endangerment, terroristic threatening, stalking, forcible or nonforcible sex offenses, burglary, criminal damage to property, arson, theft, motor vehicle theft, robbery, weapons possession, and criminal attempt for any of the aforementioned crimes, and arrests for drug-related violations and liquor law violations. </section><section prefix="4">"Immediately" means before the last fire unit has left the scene in order for the state fire marshal to have the opportunity to speak with fire unit personnel before they leave the scene, but no later than two (2) hours following the time the fire or threat of fire is discovered. In the event of a minor fire to which the local fire officials are not called or do not respond, "immediately" means no later than one (1) hour following the discovery of the fire. </section><section prefix="5">"Postsecondary education institution" means any Kentucky public four (4) year institution or two (2) year community college or technical college that grants a postsecondary education credential, and any private college or university that is licensed by the Council on Postsecondary Education under KRS 164.945 to 164.947. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 223, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4503</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>