<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.540</section_number><catch_line>Scope of section -- Disposition of stock upon revocation, surrender, court disposition, or nonrenewal of license -- Disposition upon bankruptcy.   </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this section shall apply to any licensee who is unable to continue in business at the licensed premises because of an act of God; a casualty; an acquisition by a federal, state, city, or other governmental agency under the power of eminent domain granted to the government or agency; a voluntary or involuntary acquisition by any private corporation through the corporation's power of eminent domain; a loss of lease because the landlord fails to renew an existing lease; court action; or other verifiable business reason. </section><section prefix="2">If a license issued by the department has been revoked, the former licensee may, under the supervision of the state director, dispose of and transfer his or her stock to another licensee if the disposition is completed within ninety (90) days and the licensee is a distiller, rectifier, winery, or brewer. The disposition shall be completed within thirty (30) days if the licensee is a wholesaler or distributor or within twenty (20) days if the licensee is a retailer. </section><section prefix="3">A retail licensee in good standing with the department who voluntarily ceases to operate his or her business for any reason other than revocation by the board or a court order shall dispose of all alcoholic beverage inventory within thirty (30) days of the event. The following requirements shall apply to the disposition of the licensee's inventory: <section prefix="a">If the premises is still open to the public and the licensee has not yet surrendered the license, the licensee shall sell alcoholic beverages only to the public and shall not sell below costs; </section><section prefix="b">If a licensee has terminated his or her business and has surrendered his or her license to the department, he or she shall submit a written request for approval from the state director within ten (10) days in advance of the sale to dispose of the licensee's remaining inventory. The request shall identify the retailer who is purchasing the inventory, the proposed date of the sale, and the quantity, types, and brands of alcohol to be sold; and </section><section prefix="c">If a licensee has more than one (1) licensed retail premises and closes one (1) or more retail premises and seeks to transfer his or her inventory to another licensed retail premises he or she owns, he or she shall submit a request in writing to the state director at least ten (10) days before the inventory is transferred. The request shall identify the premises to which the alcohol is being transferred, the proposed date of the transfer, and the quantity, types, and brands of alcohol to be sold. </section></section><section prefix="4">If a retail licensee files for bankruptcy or is directed by a court to dispose of inventory to satisfy a lien or judgment, the inventory may be sold only to a retail alcoholic beverage licensee. The bankrupt licensee or the licensee subject to the court order shall notify the department of the sale and shall attach a copy of the court order or the judgment directing the sale and a list of the quantity, types, and brands of alcohol to be sold. Any licensee who purchases the inventory shall notify the department within five (5) days after the transfer of the specific inventory sold. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 77, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 581, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-144. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>