<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.147</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Department of Kentucky State Police. </catch_line><order_by>147</order_by><text>The Department of Kentucky State Police shall: <section prefix="1">Collect data necessary for the operation of the centralized criminal history record information system from all persons and agencies mentioned in KRS 17.150; </section><section prefix="2">Prepare and distribute to all such persons and agencies forms to be used in reporting data to the centralized criminal history record information system. The forms shall provide for items of information needed by federal bureaus or departments engaged in the administration of criminal justice programs; </section><section prefix="3">Prescribe the forms and content of records to be kept by such persons and agencies to insure reporting of data to the centralized criminal history record information system; </section><section prefix="4">Instruct such persons and agencies in the installation, maintenance, and use of such records and in the manner of reporting to the centralized criminal history record information system; </section><section prefix="5">Tabulate, analyze, and interpret the data collected; </section><section prefix="6">Supply data, at their request, to participating federal bureaus, departments, or criminal justice agencies engaged in the administration of criminal justice programs; and </section><section prefix="7">Annually present to the Governor, on or before July 1, concerning the criminal statistics of the preceding calendar year, and present at such other times as the commissioner may deem wise, or the Governor may request, reports on special aspects of criminal statistics. A sufficient number of copies of all reports shall be printed for general distribution in the interest of public enlightenment. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 81, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 4. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(9). -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 4. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1207</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>