<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.074</section_number><catch_line>Naming of state road or bridge. </catch_line><order_by>074</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every road which is part of the state primary system shall be identified by a specific route number or name which shall be designated on the official state road map. In addition to a route number, the secretary: <section prefix="a">Shall name a road or road segment to comply with the provisions of subsections (2) and (3) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">May, at the secretary's discretion, or subject to the provisions of subsection (4) of this section, name a road or bridge on the state highway system after an individual, historic event, or any other name which may be of significance to the history of this Commonwealth or any of its counties or communities. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall, within thirty (30) days of receipt of a written request by the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, name a state road or segment of a state road in memory and honor of one (1) or more Kentucky state troopers killed in the line of duty. The written request shall comply with the provisions of subsection (4) of this section and shall include: <section prefix="a">The trooper's name; </section><section prefix="b">The name and address of any living relatives of the trooper, if known; </section><section prefix="c">Date and circumstances of the trooper's death; and </section><section prefix="d">The route number and current name of the state road where the trooper was killed, if applicable, or the route number and current name of the state road closest to the deceased trooper's home. </section></section><section prefix="3">The written request required under subsection (2) of this section shall identify the route number, current name of the state road, or milepoints of the specific segment of state road the Department of Kentucky State Police are requesting be named in honor and memory of a state trooper killed in the line of duty. The road or road segment identified in the request shall be either the state road where the trooper was killed, or the state road closest to the deceased trooper's home. The cabinet shall consult with the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police on the design of the road signs naming the state road or road segment in honor and memory of each trooper, and the cabinet shall erect the appropriate highway signs within thirty (30) days of receipt of the written request required under subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">If the road segment identified in the request under subsection (2) of this section has already been named for another individual or organization, either by action of the General Assembly or by order of the secretary, the Department of Kentucky State Police and the cabinet shall consult on and determine an alternate location that is acceptable to both agencies. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall be petitioned by a unit of local government, civic organization, or other interested party before naming a road or bridge on the state primary road system. In addition, the secretary shall be convinced by the petitioner that the person or event that the road or bridge is being named for is of civic or historical significance. </section><section prefix="6">Except as provided in subsections (9) and (10) of this section, the secretary shall name a road or bridge upon direction by joint resolution of the General Assembly. Upon introduction of a resolution, the secretary shall inform the chairman of the committee to which the resolution is assigned as to whether he or she has been petitioned to name a road or bridge presented in the resolution and if so petitioned, his or her reasons for not taking action on the request. </section><section prefix="7">If the secretary grants the request to name a road or bridge through petition, the signs to be placed on the roads shall become the responsibility of the petitioner with the design and placement of the signs approved by the department. If the signs are to be placed as a result of a resolution passed by the General Assembly, the responsibility for placement of the signs shall be upon the Department of Highways. </section><section prefix="8">The Transportation Cabinet may adopt administrative regulations to implement the road and bridge naming program. The administrative regulations shall at a minimum establish basic standards for design and placement of signs or allow the local entity to reimburse the Transportation Cabinet for the cost of manufacturing and installing the signs for which a petition has been granted. </section><section prefix="9">The new proposed truck bypass around Mayfield, Kentucky, shall be named the "Dick Castleman Bypass," after former State Representative Dick Castleman. </section><section prefix="10">The bridge on United States Highway 27 over the Kentucky River near Camp Nelson, between Jessamine and Garrard Counties, shall be named the "Loyd Murphy Memorial Bridge." </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 185, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5260</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>