<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.295</section_number><catch_line>Urban-county government may set liquor sale hours -- Local option on Sunday sales in urban-county -- Licensing -- Sunday sales extension. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any county containing an urban-county government, a premises that has been granted a license for the sale of distilled spirits or wine at retail shall not be permitted to remain open for any purpose between midnight and 6 a.m., or at any time during the twenty-four (24) hours of a Sunday, unless the licensee provides a separate department within his or her licensed premises capable of being locked and closed off, within which is kept all stocks of distilled spirits and wine, and all fixtures and apparatus connected with his or her business as a licensee, and the department is kept locked during the time mentioned above. The licensee shall be deemed to have complied with this section; except that the legislative body of an urban-county government in which traffic in distilled spirits and wine is permitted under KRS Chapter 242 shall have the exclusive right and power, by ordinance, to establish the hours and times in which distilled spirits and wine may be sold within its jurisdictional boundaries. Provided, however, distilled spirits or wine may not be sold in any portion of a county containing an urban-county government during the twenty-four (24) hours between 6 a.m. Sunday and 6 a.m. Monday, except as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section; and provided, also, that all stocks of distilled spirits and wine shall be kept locked during the hours in which the licensee is prohibited from selling distilled spirits and wine. </section><section prefix="2">In any county containing an urban-county government in which the sale of distilled spirits and wine is permitted under KRS Chapter 242, an election on the question of permitting the sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink on Sunday may be held as provided in KRS 242.020 to 242.040 and 242.060 to 242.120. In any election, the form of the proposition shall be, "Are you in favor of the sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink between the hours of one p.m. and midnight on Sunday in (name of county)?". </section><section prefix="3">In any county containing an urban-county government in which the sale of distilled spirits and wine is permitted under KRS Chapter 242, the legislative body of the urban-county government may by resolution or ordinance submit to the electorate a proposal to permit the sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink on Sunday from 1 p.m. until a closing hour specified in the proposal by hotels, motels, convention centers, convention hotel complexes, restaurants, racetracks, and commercial airports which are licensed for the retail sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink and which have dining facilities with a minimum seating capacity of one hundred (100) people at tables and which receive less than fifty percent (50%) of their annual food and beverage receipts from dining facilities by the sale of alcohol. The proposal to be submitted to the electorate shall be framed so that any voter who wishes to vote in favor of the limited Sunday sales of distilled spirits and wine by the drink may signify his or her approval by voting "yes" and any voter who wishes to vote against the limited Sunday sales of distilled spirits and wine by the drink may do so by voting "no." The election shall be held on a date stipulated by the legislative body, and the cost of the election shall be borne by the urban-county government. The proposal shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424 and shall also be advertised by written or printed handbills posted at not less than five (5) conspicuous places in each precinct of the county for two (2) weeks before the election. The general election laws, including penalties for violations, shall apply to the election, except where those laws are inconsistent with the provisions of this section. The proposal submitted to the electorate shall be effective immediately if a majority of those voting on the proposal vote "yes." </section><section prefix="4">In any county containing an urban-county government in which the sale of distilled spirits and wine by the drink is permitted on Sunday as provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section, licensed retailers selling distilled spirits and wine by the drink may apply to the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits for a special Sunday retail drink license. Upon receipt of an application and payment of the prescribed fee, the director shall issue a license. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes to the contrary, in any county containing an urban-county government where Sunday sales of distilled spirits and wine by the drink have been previously approved, the legislative body of the urban-county government may by ordinance extend Sunday sales to any premises licensed to sell distilled spirits and wine by the drink located within the territorial boundaries of the urban-county government and may by ordinance establish the hours such distilled spirits and wine by the drink may be sold. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 92, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 11, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>