<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.123</section_number><catch_line>Effect of revisory act on other acts adopted at same session. </catch_line><order_by>123</order_by><text>If any act to revise and correct the Kentucky Revised Statutes adopted during a session of the General Assembly: <section prefix="1">Amends or repeals and reenacts a statute section also amended or repealed and reenacted by another act adopted at the same session, then effect shall be given to both acts insofar as there is no conflict in substance. In the event of a conflict in substance between the acts, the nonrevisory act prevails to the extent of the conflict; </section><section prefix="2">Repeals an act amended by another act adopted at the same session, then such repeal has no effect; </section><section prefix="3">Amends or repeals and reenacts a statute section repealed by another act adopted at the same session, the repeal of the section by the nonrevisory act prevails. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in any act to revise and correct the Kentucky Revised Statutes adopted by the General Assembly shall be construed to effect any substantive change in the statute law of Kentucky and if any substantive change appears to be effected it shall be disregarded and the law as it existed prior to the effective date of the revisory act shall be given full force and effect. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, secs. 284 and 285, effective June 16, 1966. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1966</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=468</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>