<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.210</section_number><catch_line>Tiering of administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When promulgating administrative regulations and reviewing existing ones, administrative bodies shall, whenever possible, tier their administrative regulations to reduce disproportionate impacts on certain classes of regulated entities, including government or small business, or both, and to avoid regulating entities that do not contribute significantly to the problem the administrative regulation was designed to address. The tiers, however, shall be based upon reasonable criteria and uniformly applied to an entire class. Administrative bodies shall use any number of tiers that will solve most efficiently and effectively the problem the administrative regulation addresses. A written statement shall be submitted to the Legislative Research Commission explaining why tiering was or was not used. </section><section prefix="2">Administrative bodies may use, but shall not be limited to, the following methods of tiering administrative regulations: <section prefix="a">Reduce or modify substantive regulatory requirements; </section><section prefix="b">Eliminate some requirements entirely; </section><section prefix="c">Simplify and reduce reporting and recordkeeping requirements; </section><section prefix="d">Provide exemptions from reporting and recordkeeping requirements; </section><section prefix="e">Reduce the frequency of inspections; </section><section prefix="f">Provide exemptions from inspections and other compliance activities; </section><section prefix="g">Delay compliance timetables; </section><section prefix="h">Reduce, modify, or waive fines or other penalties for noncompliance; and </section><section prefix="i">Address and alleviate special problems of individuals and small businesses in complying with an administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="3">When tiering regulatory requirements, administrative bodies may use, but shall not be limited to, size and nonsize variables. Size variables include number of citizens, number of employees, level of operating revenues, level of assets, and market shares. Nonsize variables include degree of risk posed to humans, technological and economic ability to comply, geographic locations, and level of federal funding. </section><section prefix="4">When modifying tiers, administrative bodies shall monitor, but shall not be limited to, the following variables: <section prefix="a">Changing demographic characteristics; </section><section prefix="b">Changes in the composition of the workforce; </section><section prefix="c">Changes in the inflation rate requiring revisions of dollar-denominated tiers; </section><section prefix="d">Changes in market concentration and segmentation; </section><section prefix="e">Advances in technology; and </section><section prefix="f">Changes in legislation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 21, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 21, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=748</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>