<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.345</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of information. </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text> Except as otherwise provided in this section, the department shall not disclose the identity of any individual filing a complaint or request for inspection under any section of this chapter, except as necessary to enforce, and then only with the specific written permission of the complainant.  Except as otherwise provided in this section, information secured from inspection of the records, or from the transcriptions thereof, or from inspection of the employer's premises by the commissioner or the commissioner's authorized representatives, shall be held confidential and shall not be disclosed or be open to any person except such information may be made available to: <section prefix="1">Officials concerned with, and for the purposes of administration of the laws relating to matters under the jurisdiction of the commissioner; </section><section prefix="2">Any agency of this or any other state, or any federal agency for the purpose of enforcing KRS 337.275 to 337.325, 337.345, and 337.385 to 337.405; and </section><section prefix="3">To the Wage and Hour and Public Contracts Division of the United States, Department of Labor. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1734, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32075</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>