<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2">CITIZENSHIP, EMBLEMS, HOLIDAYS, AND TIME </unit></structure><section_number>2.108</section_number><catch_line>Hurricane Creek coal mine site designated as state historic site.   </catch_line><order_by>108</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Hurricane Creek coal mine site in Leslie County, at which thirty-eight (38) miners lost their lives on December 30, 1970, is designated as a state historic site. </section><section prefix="2">As funds are available, Leslie County shall construct a memorial to those who perished, which shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">A monument to the miners, to be built at the mine site with the names of the thirty-eight (38) miners who lost their lives and the one (1) survivor; </section><section prefix="b">Informational materials about the mining disaster; </section><section prefix="c">Signage, off-street parking, and other features to encourage visitors; and </section><section prefix="d">A plan for construction and periodic maintenance of the monument site. </section></section><section prefix="3">Leslie County's fiscal court is authorized to establish a restricted account for the site, and to raise funds from federal, state, and local entities and from private sources for this account. Funds in the account shall be expended only for the mining disaster memorial. Moneys received and expended shall be reported separately in the county's budget. </section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall, prior to December 30, 2010, issue a proclamation recognizing the fortieth anniversary of the Hurricane Creek mine disaster, memorializing the deceased miners and their families, and honoring the courage of all Kentucky's miners. The Governor shall call upon all citizens to observe the occasion honoring miners in communities across the Commonwealth. The Governor is authorized to recognize the mine disaster anniversary in future years, on or before December 30, through a proclamation. </section><section prefix="5">Working with Leslie County officials, state agencies shall provide assistance in informing the public about the site. The Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, with assistance from the Kentucky Heritage Council, the Kentucky Historical Society, the Division of Mine Safety, and the Kentucky Mining Board, and within the limits of funds available, shall prepare and distribute information about the Hurricane Creek mining disaster, the risks which miners faced historically, and the advances in mining safety since the 1970 disaster. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44518</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>