<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.1-220</section_number><catch_line>Fees for filing documents and issuing certificates --Miscellaneous charges.  </catch_line><order_by>1-220</order_by><text>The Secretary of State shall collect the following fees when the documentsdescribed in this subsection are delivered to him for filing:(1)Articles of incorporation  $   40(2)Amendment of articles of incorporation $   40(3)Restatement of articles of incorporation $   40(4)Amended and restated articles $  80(5)Articles of merger or share exchange $  50(6)Articles of dissolution $  40(7)Articles of revocation of dissolution 15(8)Any other document required or permitted tobe filed by this chapter $  15</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 48, effective July 15,2010; and repealed, reenacted, and amended ch. 151, sec. 51, effectiveJanuary 1, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 48, effective June 26,2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. --Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1989; and ch. 85, sec.3, effective July 15, 1988.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2011</effective><former-codification> KRS 271A.631.</former-codification><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  This section was repealed,reenacted, and amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, and repealed and reenactedby 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intentof the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment not serve to void theamendment, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict, therefore, they havebeen codified together. (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec.183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Actwhich reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are herebymade expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of thosesections being unaffected by the provisions of this section.".Similar versions of this section werecreated by 1988 Acts Chapter 85, Section 3, and 1988 Acts Chapter 23, Section3, which conflict in regard to the amount of fees to be charged by Secretary ofState. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the fees set forth in Chapter 85 prevail as thelater enactment. The remaining provisions do not appear to be in conflict andhave been compiled together.</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36638</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>