<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.280</section_number><catch_line>Effect of civil service laws and regulations upon transferred employees. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event that a public agency or agencies determine to transfer any of its employees to the joint or cooperative action, which employees are subject to any civil service laws or regulations, such employees shall not lose any rights or benefits which have accrued prior to such transfer. Such employees, when transferred, to the joint or cooperative action from a public agency or agencies that are subject to any civil service laws or regulations, and who have completed probationary appointments with the public agency or agencies prior to the date of transfer, shall be considered as having satisfied all of the qualifications of the joint or cooperative action and shall be given full and regular appointments as defined in such laws or regulations as of the date they are transferred to the joint or cooperative action. </section><section prefix="2">In the event that the joint or cooperative action is such that its employees would be afforded civil service rights or benefits if they were employees of a county or city, such employees shall be afforded the protection of civil service laws or regulations; provided, however, that such protection is available under the laws of this state. </section><section prefix="3">In the event the joint or cooperative action employs a person employed immediately prior thereto by a component city or county, or by a special district, such employee shall be deemed to remain an employee of such city, county or special district for the purposes of any pension plan of such city, county, or special district, and shall continue to be entitled to all rights and benefits thereunder as if he had remained as an employee of the city, county, or special district, until the joint or cooperative action has provided a pension plan to which such employee is eligible and such employee has elected, in writing, to participate therein. Until such election, the joint or cooperative action shall deduct from the remuneration of such employee the amount which such employee is or may be required to pay in accordance with the provisions of the plan of such city, county, or special district and the joint or cooperative action shall pay to the city, county, or special district any amounts required to be paid under the provisions of such plan by employer and employee, unless an agreement, not adversely affecting the employee's interest, or expectancy, has been made pursuant to KRS 65.250 (1)(d) for the payment of the employer's pension obligation. </section></text><history>Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 79. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 5. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 216, secs. 6 and 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23382</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>