<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">C APPLIED BEHAVIOR ANALYSTS </unit></structure><section_number>319C.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Applied behavior analysis" means the design, implementation, and evaluation of environmental modifications, using behavioral stimuli and consequences, to produce socially significant improvement in human behavior, including the use of direct observation, measurement, and functional analysis of the relationship between environment and behavior; </section><section prefix="2">"Applied behavior analysis interventions" means interventions that are based on scientific research and the direct observation and measurement of behavior and environment which utilize contextual factors, establishing operations, antecedent stimuli, positive reinforcement, and other consequences to help people develop new behaviors, increase or decrease existing behaviors, and elicit behaviors under specific environmental conditions; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Kentucky Applied Behavior Analysis Licensing Board; </section><section prefix="4">"Certification board" means the Behavior Analyst Certification Board® or its successor; </section><section prefix="5">"Certified" means a practitioner who has met the certification criteria of the certification board; </section><section prefix="6">"Licensed behavior analyst" means an individual who is licensed by the board and meets the requirements of KRS 319C.080; </section><section prefix="7">"Licensed assistant behavior analyst" means an individual who: <section prefix="a">Is licensed by the board as an assistant behavior analyst and meets the requirements of KRS 319C.080; and </section><section prefix="b">Works under the supervision of a certified behavior analyst; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Practice of applied behavior analysis" means the application of the principles, methods, and procedures of the experimental analysis of behavior and applied behavior analysis, including but not limited to applications of those principles, methods, and procedures to: <section prefix="a">Design, implement, evaluate, and modify treatment programs to change the behavior of individuals diagnosed with an autism spectrum disorder; </section><section prefix="b">Design, implement, evaluate, and modify treatment programs to change the behavior of individuals; </section><section prefix="c">Design, implement, evaluate, and modify treatment programs to change the behavior of groups; and </section><section prefix="d">Consult with individuals and organizations. </section></section> The practice of applied behavior analysis shall not include diagnosis, counseling, psychological testing, neuropsychology, psychotherapy, cognitive therapy, sex therapy, psychoanalysis, or hypnotherapy as treatment modalities; <section prefix="9">"Supervised experience" means services rendered as a part of the certification requirements of a behavior analyst or assistant behavior analyst under the supervision of a licensed behavior analyst; </section><section prefix="10">"Supervisee" means a person who is not licensed but acts under the extended authority and direction of a licensed behavior analyst or a licensed assistant behavior analyst to provide applied behavior analysis services; and </section><section prefix="11">"Temporary licensee" means a person who is obtaining supervised experience and has obtained a temporary license. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31292</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>