<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="168" order_by="168">EDUCATIONAL TELEVISION </unit></structure><section_number>168.050</section_number><catch_line>Terms of members -- Vacancies -- Reelection or reappointment. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Effective July 1, 1994, the terms of the members other than the chief state school officer and the member appointed from the staff or personnel of the department shall be originally, two (2) members for a term of four (4) years; two (2) members for a term of three (3) years; two (2) members for a term of two (2) years; and one (1) member for a term of one (1) year, to be determined by the Governor. Thereafter the terms shall be for four (4) years. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to vacancies from death or resignation, vacancies shall occur upon removal of permanent residence from the Commonwealth; in the case of the elected member representing the department and the board, by change of assignment or by severance from relationship with the department or the board for any reason; and, in the cases of the members representing the University of Kentucky and the state colleges, by termination of the member's membership on the council for any reason. Vacancies during the term of any member shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term only; and vacancies of elected or appointed members by reason of the expiration of the term shall be for terms of four (4) years each, in the same manner as the initial election or appointment, as the case may be. </section><section prefix="3">Elected or appointed members shall be eligible for reelection or reappointment for any number of terms, as long as the prescribed qualifications prevail. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 3, effective March 22, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 280, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 5. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4 (second and third paragraphs). </history><metadata><effective> March 22, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4730</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>