<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.160</section_number><catch_line>Utilities to file and display general schedules of rates and conditions for service -- Adherence to schedules -- Exclusion from disclosure of confidential or proprietary provisions in special contracts. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Under rules prescribed by the commission, each utility shall file with the commission, within such time and in such form as the commission designates, schedules showing all rates and conditions for service established by it and collected or enforced. The utility shall keep copies of its schedules open to public inspection under such rules as the commission prescribes. </section><section prefix="2">No utility shall charge, demand, collect, or receive from any person a greater or less compensation for any service rendered or to be rendered than that prescribed in its filed schedules, and no person shall receive any service from any utility for a compensation greater or less than that prescribed in such schedules. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section do not require disclosure or publication of a provision of a special contract that contains rates and conditions of service not filed in a utility's general schedule if such provision would otherwise be entitled to be excluded from the application of KRS 61.870 to 61.884 under the provisions of KRS 61.878(1)(c)1. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 22, effective April 1, 1979. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3952-30, 3952-31. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>