<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-258</section_number><catch_line>Investor entitled to credit -- Amount -- Carry-forward -- Liabilities -- Transferability -- Notification of Department of Revenue -- Additional credits -- Maximum credits. </catch_line><order_by>20-258</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An investor shall be entitled to a nonrefundable credit equal to forty percent (40%) of the investor's proportional ownership share of all qualified investments made by its investment fund and verified by the authority. The aggregate tax credit available to any investor shall not exceed forty percent (40%) of the cash contribution made by the investor to its investment fund. The credit may be applied against: <section prefix="a">Both the income tax imposed by KRS 141.020 or 141.040, and the limited liability entity tax imposed by KRS 141.0401, with the ordering of the credits as provided in KRS 141.0205; </section><section prefix="b">The corporation license tax imposed by KRS 136.070; </section><section prefix="c">The insurance taxes imposed by KRS 136.320, 136.330, and 304.3-270; and </section><section prefix="d">The taxes on financial institutions imposed by KRS 136.300, 136.310, and 136.505. </section></section><section prefix="2">The tax credit amount that may be claimed by an investor in any tax year shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of the initial aggregate credit amount approved by the authority for the investment fund which would be proportionally available to the investor. An investor may first claim the credit granted in subsection (1) of this section in the year following the year in which the credit is granted. </section><section prefix="3">If the credit amount that may be claimed in any tax year, as determined under subsections (1) and (2) of this section, exceeds the investor's combined tax liabilities against which the credit may be claimed for that year, the investor may carry the excess tax credit forward until the tax credit is used, but the carry-forward of any excess tax credit shall not increase the fifty percent (50%) limitation established by subsection (2) of this section. Any tax credits not used within fifteen (15) years of the approval by the authority of the aggregate tax credit amount available to the investor shall be lost. </section><section prefix="4">The tax credits allowed by this section shall not apply to any liability an investor may have for interest, penalties, past due taxes, or any other additions to the investor's tax liability. The holder of the tax credit shall assume any and all liabilities and responsibilities of the credit. </section><section prefix="5">The tax credits allowed by this section are not transferable, except that: <section prefix="a">A nonprofit entity may transfer, for some or no consideration, any or all of the credits it receives under this section and any related benefits, rights, responsibilities, and liabilities. Within thirty (30) days of the date of any transfer of credits pursuant to this subsection, the nonprofit entity shall notify the authority and the Department of Revenue of: <section prefix="1">The name, address, and Social Security number or employer identification number, as may be applicable, of the party to which the nonprofit entity transferred its credits; </section><section prefix="2">The amount of credits transferred; and </section><section prefix="3">Any additional information the authority or the Department of Revenue deems necessary. </section></section><section prefix="b">If an investor is an entity and is a party to a merger, acquisition, consolidation, dissolution, liquidation, or similar corporate reorganization, the tax credits shall pass through to the investor's successor. </section><section prefix="c">If an individual investor dies, the tax credits shall pass to the investor's estate or beneficiaries in a manner consistent with the transfer of ownership of the investor's interest in the investment fund. </section></section><section prefix="6">The tax credit amount that may be claimed by an investor shall reflect only the investor's participation in qualified investments properly reported to the authority by the investment fund manager. No tax credit authorized by this section shall become effective until the Department of Revenue receives notification from the authority that includes: <section prefix="a">A statement that a qualified investment has been made that is in compliance with KRS 154.20-250 to 154.20-284 and all applicable regulations; and </section><section prefix="b">A list of each investor in the investment fund that owns a portion of the small business in which a qualified investment has been made by virtue of an investment in the investment fund, and each investor's amount of credit granted to the investor for each qualified investment. </section></section> The authority shall, within sixty (60) days of approval of credits, notify the Department of Revenue of the information required pursuant to this subsection and notify each investor of the amount of credits granted to that investor, and the year the credits may first be claimed. <section prefix="7">After the date on which investors in an investment fund have cumulatively received an amount of credits equal to the amount of credits allocated to the investment fund by the authority, no investor shall receive additional credits by virtue of its investment in that investment fund unless the investment fund's allocation of credits is increased by the authority pursuant to an amended application. </section><section prefix="8">The maximum amount of credits to be authorized by the authority shall be three million dollars ($3,000,000) for each of fiscal years 2002-03 and 2003-04. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 42, effective June 28, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 571, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 28, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>(6/28/2006).  2006 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 73, provides that "unless a provision of this Act specifically applies to an earlier tax year, the provisions of this Act shall apply to taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2007." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2701</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>