<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.35-050</section_number><catch_line>Functions of basic research centers and applied research centers -- Advisory committees -- Goal of infrastructure -- Centers to retain a contact with experts. </catch_line><order_by>35-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The function of the basic research centers shall be to perform basic research of significant benefit to one (1) or more key industries that have been identified in and targeted by the state's economic development strategic plan as having major importance to the sustained economic growth of the Commonwealth. The areas of research to be performed by each basic research center shall be set forth in the contract between the council and the contracting university and shall be approved only for those projects for which the center has a commitment from a private sector partner to make use of the results of the research. </section><section prefix="2">The functions of the applied research centers shall be: <section prefix="a">To perform applied research, development, and technology transfer on a fee for service basis, to businesses and groups of businesses. For performing this function the center shall give preference to businesses in key industries and networks of businesses; </section><section prefix="b">To provide advice to businesses regarding other areas of business operations necessary for improved performance, including workforce training, total quality assurance, inventory control, and reorganization of the business and workplace; and </section><section prefix="c">To perform applied research and technology development of significant benefit to one (1) or more key industries in areas set forth in the contract between the council and the contracting university. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall appoint advisory committees of persons knowledgeable in each key industry to advise the council and the centers with regard to research needs of the industry and to evaluate research plans and research results. </section><section prefix="4">It shall be the goal of the infrastructure that eighty percent (80%) of the total revenues of each center shall be generated by payments under contracts from private businesses. </section><section prefix="5">To perform the functions set out in this section each center shall retain or contract with scientists, engineers, and other persons having high levels of expertise in appropriate fields of research, including but not limited to, faculty, staff and students of the contracting universities; provided, however, that all contracts with persons employed by the contracting university shall be subject to approval by the council. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>