<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.080</section_number><catch_line>Drilling through coal bed. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A well penetrating one (1) or more workable coal beds shall be drilled in such manner as will, if practicable, exclude all oil, gas or gas pressure from the coal bed, except such as is found in the coal bed itself. Each string of casing that is run through a workable coal bed shall be seated at least thirty (30) feet below the coal bed in twenty (20) feet of cement, mud, clay or other nonporous material that will make an effective seal. If a second workable coal bed is found less than thirty (30) feet below the first workable coal bed, the casing shall be seated and mudded off as above provided at least thirty (30) feet below the second bed. If gas is found between the two (2) beds, it shall be treated as prescribed by KRS 353.090. After any such string of casing has been properly seated, drilling may proceed immediately. </section><section prefix="2">When a well is drilled through the horizon of a coal bed where the coal has been removed, the hole shall be drilled at least thirty (30) feet below the coal bed, and shall be of a size sufficient to permit the placing of a liner, which shall start not less than twenty (20) feet beneath the horizon of the coal bed and extend not less than twenty (20) feet above it. Within this liner, which may be welded to the casing to be used, shall be centrally placed the largest size casing to be used in the well, and the space between the liner and the casing shall be filled with cement as the liner and casing are lowered into the hole. Cement shall be placed in the bottom of the hole to a depth of twenty (20) feet to form a sealed seat for both liner and casing. Following the setting of the liner, drilling may proceed. If it is necessary to drill through the horizon of two (2) or more coal beds where the coal has been removed, the liner shall be started not less than twenty (20) feet below the lowest horizon penetrated and shall extend to a point not less than twenty (20) feet above the highest horizon penetrated. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766b-8, 3766b-11. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>