<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.260</section_number><catch_line>Transportation and delivery in dry or moist territory prohibited -- Exception for any moist territory where sale of alcoholic beverages specifically authorized under limited local option election.   </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person or public or private carrier to bring into, transfer to another, deliver, or distribute in any dry or moist territory, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, any alcoholic beverage, regardless of its name. Each package of such beverage so brought, transferred, or delivered in such territory shall constitute a separate offense. Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any distiller or manufacturer or any authorized agent of a distiller, manufacturer, or wholesale dealer from transporting or causing to be transported by a licensed carrier any alcoholic beverage to their distilleries, breweries, wineries, or warehouses where the sale of such beverage may be lawful, either in or out of the state. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall also apply to any moist territory unless the sale of the alcoholic beverage in question has been specifically authorized in that moist territory under a limited local option election. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 25, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 186, secs. 1 and 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554c-20. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>"Alcoholic beverage" has been substituted for "intoxicating liquor" in order to fit the definitions contained in KRS 242.010. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>