<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.5395</section_number><catch_line>Public hearing required for city-owned or city-controlled electric generating facility considering acquiring property for wind-based electric generating facility. </catch_line><order_by>5395</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city-owned or city-controlled electric generating entity shall hold a public meeting in any county where acquisition of real estate or any interest in real estate is being considered for construction of a wind-based electric generating facility. A request for a public meeting may be made by any city or county governmental entity with jurisdiction. The meeting shall be held not more than thirty (30) days from the date of the request. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the meeting is to fully inform the public, landowners, and other interested parties of the full extent of the project being considered, including the project time line. One (1) or more representatives of the city-owned or city-controlled electric generating entity with full knowledge of all aspects of the project shall be present and shall answer questions from the public. </section><section prefix="3">Notice of the time, subject, and location of the meeting shall be posted in both a local newspaper, if any, and a newspaper of general circulation in the county. Notice shall also be placed on the Web site of the city-owned or city-controlled electric generating entity. </section><section prefix="4">A person that, on or before April 10, 2014, has started acquiring interests in real estate for a project as described in subsection (1) of this section shall hold a meeting that complies with this section within thirty (30) days of April 10, 2014. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 8, effective April 10, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> April 10, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42959</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>