<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.067</section_number><catch_line>Requirement for registration with Department of Revenue to collect and remit sales and use tax -- Exemption -- Applicability to foreign persons -- Administrative regulation. </catch_line><order_by>067</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Affiliate" means a person who directly or indirectly owns or controls, is owned or controlled by, or is under common ownership or control with another person or group of persons; and </section><section prefix="b">"Person" includes any individual, firm, copartnership, pass-through entity as defined in KRS 141.010(26), joint venture, association, social club, fraternal organization, corporation, estate, trust, business trust, receiver, trustee, syndicate, cooperative, assignee, governmental unit or agency, or any other group or combination acting as a unit. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Commonwealth shall not contract to acquire goods or services, and a person shall not contract to supply goods or services to the Commonwealth, unless, prior to or contemporaneous with entering into the contract, the person contracting to supply goods or services and its affiliates register with the Department of Revenue to collect and remit the sales and use tax imposed by KRS Chapter 139. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall require a person or affiliate to register if the person or affiliate does not make sales to customers in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of subsection (2) of this section are specifically applicable to foreign persons, notwithstanding the fact that the foreign person or the affiliate may not otherwise be legally obligated to collect and remit the sales and use tax. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall promulgate an administrative regulation to establish the procedure ensuring compliance with the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22339</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>