<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="316" order_by="316">EMBALMERS AND FUNERAL DIRECTORS </unit></structure><section_number>316.127</section_number><catch_line>Licensing for establishments existing before July 12, 2006. </catch_line><order_by>127</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A funeral establishment licensed on July 12, 2006, that meets the definition of a full-service funeral establishment shall be issued a license as a full-service funeral establishment. This license shall be effective until the date that the funeral establishment's former license would have expired. The funeral establishment shall be required to make an application for renewal under this chapter as a full-service funeral establishment. </section><section prefix="2">A funeral establishment licensed on July 12, 2006, that meets the definition of an embalming service establishment shall be issued a license for an embalming service establishment. This license shall be effective until the date that the funeral establishment's former license would have expired. The funeral establishment shall be required to make an application for renewal under this chapter as an embalming service establishment. </section><section prefix="3">A funeral establishment licensed on July 12, 2006, that does not meet the definition of a full-service funeral establishment or embalming service establishment shall be issued a license for a visitation and ceremonial funeral service establishment. This license shall be renewable as a visitation and ceremonial funeral service establishment license for the entire time of the establishment's existence, subject to the restrictions of subsection (4) of this section, or until the board approves the establishment's application for another type of establishment license. </section><section prefix="4">A visitation and ceremonial funeral service establishment that is licensed as a funeral establishment prior to July 12, 2006, shall be exempt from the requirement of ownership in whole or in part by an affiliated full-service funeral establishment. This exemption shall lapse if the visitation and ceremonial funeral service establishment is sold, ceases to exist, or engages in any activity that changes its license. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31067</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>