<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.110</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 90.110 to 90.230. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>The following terms, as used in KRS 90.110 to 90.230, shall have the following meanings, unless the context clearly requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Emergency appointment" means any appointment to any position subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, which may be made only in the absence of an appropriate eligible list for the position and which may be made without competitive examination pending the establishment of an eligible list and which appointment shall not exceed the duration of the emergency and in no case to exceed ninety (90) days in any one (1) fiscal year. </section><section prefix="2">"Probationary appointment" means an appointment to any position subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, which shall be made in accordance with the provisions of KRS 90.180 and which shall not be less than six (6) months nor more than one (1) year in duration. </section><section prefix="3">"Regular appointment" means an appointment to a position subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 made after an employee has served a probationary period in a manner deemed satisfactory to the appointing authority. </section><section prefix="4">"Director" means the personnel director, as provided for in KRS 90.140. </section><section prefix="5">"Position" means every place of employment in the classified service hereunder including office. </section><section prefix="6">"Employee" means any person in the classified service hereunder. </section><section prefix="7">"Classified service" means all positions in cities of the first class within the jurisdiction of the board, and within the purview of KRS 90.110 to 90.230. </section><section prefix="8">"Board" means the civil service board created hereunder. </section><section prefix="9">"Appointing authority" means the officer, board, commission, department, agency, person or group of persons, having the power of appointment to and removal from positions in the classified service as provided for in KRS 90.110 to 90.230. </section><section prefix="10">"Competitive examination" shall include consideration and rating of any or all of the following qualifications of applicants: Education, training, experience, general adaptability, special aptitude, physical fitness, knowledge, skill, personality, character, and such other qualifications as may be deemed necessary for the satisfactory performance of the duties of the respective positions. </section><section prefix="11">"Eligible list" means a list of names of persons who have been found qualified through suitable competitive examinations for positions or classes of positions as provided for in KRS 90.110 to 90.230. </section><section prefix="12">"Service ratings" means the evaluation of the efficiency and general worth of employees in positions subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 as determined by the appointing authority. </section><section prefix="13">"Dismissal" means the discharge of an employee by the appointing authority. </section><section prefix="14">"Lay-off" means the separation of an employee from the classified service because of a reduction of force owing to decreased work or decreased funds in the department, commission, board or agency in which the employee has been employed. </section><section prefix="15">"Class" or "class of positions" means a position or group of positions subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230 sufficiently similar in duties, responsibilities and qualification requirements to be designated by the same title and placed within the same salary range. </section><section prefix="16">"Reinstatement" means the reappointment of a person who formerly held a position, subject to the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, to such former position or to any other position in the same class. </section><section prefix="17">"Transfer" means a change by an employee from one (1) position to another position within the same class. </section><section prefix="18">"Promotion" means a change from a position in a lower class to a position in a higher class involving an increase in responsibility or a change in title. </section><section prefix="19">"Demotion" means a change from a position in a higher class to a position in a lower class involving a decrease in responsibility or a change in title. </section><section prefix="20">"Suspension" means the separation of an employee from the service for a temporary or fixed period of time, which separation is inflicted upon the employee by his appointing authority, as a disciplinary measure under the rules established by the board. </section><section prefix="21">"Public hearing" means such as may be given after public notice of at least five (5) days, so that any person or persons may have an opportunity to appear before the board and be heard on the matter involved. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>