<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.360</section_number><catch_line>Court costs. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Court costs commensurate with those in District or Circuit Court, as appropriate, shall be charged by the juvenile session of District Court against juveniles who are informally adjusted or found delinquent because of status offenses or public offenses and by the Circuit Court against juveniles who are found to be youthful offenders. </section><section prefix="2">Where possible, court costs shall be assessed against the child, but they may be assessed against the child's parent or legal guardian. </section><section prefix="3">Court costs shall not be assessed against a parent or guardian who is the complainant against the child or who has been the victim of the child's acts. </section><section prefix="4">In the case of children who have been committed, court costs shall not be assessed against the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet. </section><section prefix="5">The court may require juveniles to pay court costs on the installment plan or in any other manner provided for fines by KRS Chapter 534 or to engage in community labor at state minimum wage rates to pay off their court costs. Labor to pay court costs shall be in addition to community labor ordered for other purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 35, effective July 15, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20175</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>