<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.905</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 177.910 to 177.950. </catch_line><order_by>905</order_by><text>As used in KRS 177.910 to 177.950, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Road" means any county, state, federal or limited access highway or turnpike, including bridges and bridge approaches. </section><section prefix="2">"Automobile, vehicle or machinery recyclers" means any place where five (5) or more junked, wrecked or nonoperative automobiles, vehicles, machines and other similar scrap or salvage materials, excluding inoperative farm equipment, are deposited, parked, placed or otherwise located, or any business as defined in subsection (3) where ten (10) or more junked, wrecked or nonoperative automobiles, vehicles, machines and other similar scrap or salvage materials are deposited, parked, placed or otherwise located. </section><section prefix="3">"Business" means any person engaged as an automobile dealer, body shop operator, wrecker service operator, service station operator or other activity which may buy, sell or repair nonoperative vehicles, automobiles or machinery as a service. </section><section prefix="4">"Material recyclers" shall mean any establishment or place of business, including garbage dumps and sanitary fills, maintained, operated, or used for storing, keeping, buying or selling of old or scrap copper, brass, rope, rags, batteries, paper, trash, rubber debris, waste, or motor vehicle parts, iron, steel, and other old or scrap ferrous or nonferrous material. </section><section prefix="5">"Operator or operators" means a person, firm or corporation operating an automobile, vehicle, machinery or material recycling establishment or place of business or the allowing of such automobile, vehicle, machinery or material recycling establishment or place of business to be placed or deposited, or to remain on premises owned or controlled by such person, firm or corporation. </section><section prefix="6">"Person" means any individual, firm, agency, company, association, partnership, business trust, joint stock company, body politic or corporation. </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Highways. </section><section prefix="8">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Highways. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 146, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><lrc-note>This section was amended by two 1980 acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5386</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>