<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who willfully violates any of the provisions of KRS 353.050 to 353.130 or KRS 353.200 relating to the manner of drilling and casing or plugging and filling any well, or fixing the distance from wells within which mining operations may not be conducted, or any person who willfully violates any of the terms of an order of the department allowing mining operations within a lesser distance of any well than that prescribed by this chapter shall be fined not more than two hundred dollars ($200) or imprisoned in jail for not more than twelve (12) months, or both. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (1) of KRS 353.150 shall be fined one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense and in addition thereto one hundred dollars ($100) for each thirty (30) days the violation continues. The penalty shall be recovered in a civil action in the name of the Commonwealth for the use of the county in which the well is located. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 353.160 shall be fined not more than two hundred dollars ($200) and, if the offender is a natural person, imprisoned not less than ten (10) days nor more than six (6) months. Each day that the violation continues shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (1) of KRS 353.180 shall be fined not less than one hundred ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="5">If any person violates any of the provisions of KRS 353.190 he shall be fined five dollars ($5) for every twenty-four (24) hours that the violation continues. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766b-18, 3766b-21, 3912, 3914a, 4358, 4359. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33164</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>