<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.140</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of commuter air carrier services -- Financial aid, benefits or services by airport boards. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet is authorized to establish in cooperation with airport boards, established pursuant to KRS 183.132 through 183.138, a pilot demonstration air service project for the purpose of developing air services on a regularly scheduled basis for the movement of passengers, mail and cargo by a commuter air carrier between five (5) or more airport termini in the Commonwealth of Kentucky at least one of which does not receive service from a carrier certificated by the civil aeronautics board, in the public interest of convenience and necessity for air transportation. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet may reimburse any airport board for direct financial aid, or benefits and services in lieu thereof, which the airport board has expended for the development of commuter air carrier services that provide regularly scheduled passenger, mail and cargo service or any combination thereof to the airport terminus operated by the airport board. </section><section prefix="3">Any airport board established pursuant to KRS 183.132 through 183.138 is authorized to provide direct financial aid, or benefits and services in lieu thereof, to commuter air carriers that provide regularly scheduled passenger, mail, and cargo service or any combination thereof to their community. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 3.</history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 17, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 938j-1. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 183.140:</former-history-former-name><catchline-at-repeal>  Air boards in counties having first-class cities. </catchline-at-repeal><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5743</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>