<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.222</section_number><catch_line>Drafting rules.   </catch_line><order_by>222</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a new administrative regulation, there shall be no underlining or bracketing. </section><section prefix="2">In an amendment to an administrative regulation, the new words shall precede the deleted words. The administrative body shall: <section prefix="a">Underline all new words; and </section><section prefix="b">Place the deleted words in brackets and strike through these words. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">An administrative regulation shall not be amended by reference to a section only. An amendment shall contain the full text of the existing administrative regulation being amended. </section><section prefix="b">A section of an administrative regulation shall not be reserved for future use. </section></section><section prefix="4">In drafting administrative regulations, the administrative body shall comply with the requirements established in this subsection. <section prefix="a">The administrative body shall use plain and unambiguous words that are easily understood by laymen. The administrative body shall avoid ambiguous, indefinite, or superfluous words and phrases. </section><section prefix="b">A duty, obligation, or prohibition shall be expressed by "shall" or "shall not." "Should," "could," or "must" shall not be used. The future tense shall not be expressed by the word "shall." A discretionary power shall be expressed by "may." </section><section prefix="c">The words "said," "aforesaid," "hereinabove," "hereinafter," "beforementioned," "whatsoever," or similar words of reference or emphasis shall not be used. Where an article may be used, the administrative body shall not use the word "such." It shall not use the expression "and/or" and shall not separate alternatives with a slash. It shall not use contractions. When a number of items are all mandatory, the word "and" shall be used. When all of a number of items are not mandatory, the word "or" shall be used. </section><section prefix="d">Certain words are defined in the Kentucky Revised Statutes. Where applicable, these definitions shall be used. Definitions appearing in the Kentucky Revised Statutes shall not be duplicated in a proposed administrative regulation. A reference shall be made to the chapters and sections of the Kentucky Revised Statutes in which the definitions appear. </section><section prefix="e">If definitions are used, they shall be placed in alphabetical order in the first section of an administrative regulation or in a separate administrative regulation. The section or administrative regulation shall be titled "Definitions." If definitions are placed in the first section of an administrative regulation, the definitions shall govern only the terms in that administrative regulation. If definitions are placed in a separate administrative regulation, that administrative regulation shall be the first administrative regulation of the specific chapter of the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service to which the definitions apply. The title of the administrative regulation shall also contain the number of the chapter of the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service to which the definitions apply. In the text of an administrative regulation, the word defined in the definitions section, rather than the definition, shall be used. Definitions shall be used only: <section prefix="1">When a word is used in a sense other than its dictionary meaning, or is used in the sense of one of several dictionary meanings; </section><section prefix="2">To avoid repetition of a phrase; or </section><section prefix="3">To limit or extend the provisions of an administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="f">If a word has the same meaning as a phrase, the word shall be used. </section><section prefix="g">The present tense and the indicative mood shall be used. Conditions precedent shall be stated in the perfect tense if their happening is required to be completed. </section><section prefix="h">The same arrangement and form of expression shall be used throughout an administrative regulation, unless the meaning requires variations. </section><section prefix="i">"If" or "except" shall be used rather than "provided that" or "provided, however." "If" shall be used to express conditions, rather than the words "when" or "where." </section><section prefix="j">A word importing the masculine gender may extend to females. A word importing the singular number may extend to several persons or things. </section><section prefix="k">Any reference in an administrative regulation to "medical doctor," "M.D.," or "physician" shall be deemed to include a doctor of osteopathy or D.O., unless either of those terms is specifically excluded. </section><section prefix="l">An administrative body shall use the phrases specified in this subsection: Do Not Use:     Use: And/or      "and" for a conjunctive        "or" for a disjunctive Any and all     either word As provided in this  administrative regulation  ---- At the time     when And the same hereby is   is Either directly or indirectly   ---- Except where otherwise   State specific  provided     exemption. Final and conclusive    final Full force and effect    force or effect In the event that; In case   if Including but not    State the specific items  limited to      to be included. Is authorized; Is empowered   may Is defined and shall be  construed to mean   means Is hereby required to    shall It shall be lawful     may Latin words     Do not use unless medical or        scientific terminology. Null and void and of no effect  void Order and direct     either word Provision of law     law Until such time as    until Whenever      if </section><section prefix="m"><section prefix="1">Unless the authority for an administrative regulation is an appropriation provision that is not codified in the Kentucky Revised Statutes, the specific chapter and section number of the Kentucky Revised Statutes authorizing the promulgation of an administrative regulation shall be cited. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If an act has not been codified in the Kentucky Revised Statutes at the time an administrative regulation is promulgated, or if the authority is any branch budget bill, the citation shall be as follows: "(year) Ky. Acts ch. (chapter number), sec. (section number)." When an act has been codified, the administrative body shall notify the regulations compiler of the proper citation in writing. Upon receipt of the written notice, the regulations compiler shall correct the citation. </section><section prefix="b">For acts of extraordinary sessions, the citation shall be as follows: "(year) (Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. (chapter number), sec. (section number)." If there is more than one (1) extraordinary session of the General Assembly in the year, the citation shall specify the specific extraordinary session, as follows: "(year) (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. (chapter number), sec. (section number)." </section></section><section prefix="3">When an act has been codified, the administrative body shall notify the regulations compiler of the proper citation of the Kentucky Revised Statutes in writing. Upon receipt of the written notice, the regulations compiler shall correct the citation. </section><section prefix="4">If the statutory authority is an appropriation act, the citation shall be as follows: "(year) Ky. Acts ch. (chapter number), Part (part and subpart numbers)." </section><section prefix="5">If the authority is an executive order, the citation shall be as follows: "EO (year executive order issued)-(number of executive order)." </section></section><section prefix="n">If the statutory authority is a federal statute, the citation shall be the: <section prefix="1">United States Code (U.S.C.), if it has been codified; or </section><section prefix="2">Public Law (Pub. L.) and official session laws, if it has not been codified. </section></section><section prefix="o"><section prefix="1">If the statutory authority is a federal regulation codified in the Code of Federal Regulations, the citation shall include the title, part, and section number, as follows: "(title number) C.F.R. (part and section number)." </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If the statutory authority is a federal regulation that has not been codified in the Code of Federal Regulations, the citation shall be to the Federal Register, as follows: "(volume number) Fed. Reg. (page number) (effective date of the federal regulation) (section of Code of Federal Regulations in which it will be codified)." </section><section prefix="b">When the federal regulation is codified, the citation shall be amended to read as provided by subparagraph 1. of this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">If the statutory authority is a federal regulation that has been amended, and the amendment is not reflected in the current issue date of the volume of the Code of Federal Regulations in which the federal regulation is codified, the citation shall be to the Federal Register as follows: "(federal regulation that has been amended), (volume number) Fed. Reg. (page number) (effective date of the amendment)." </section><section prefix="b">When the amendment is codified in the appropriate volume of the Code of Federal Regulations, the citation shall be amended to read as provided by subparagraph 1. of this paragraph. </section></section></section><section prefix="p">Citations of items in the "RELATES TO" paragraph of an administrative regulation shall comply with paragraphs (m), (n), and (o) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="q">An administrative regulation may cite the popular name of a federal or state law if the popular name is accompanied by the citation required by this paragraph. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 410, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 23, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 425, secs. 1 and 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40711</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>