<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.4015Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 247.401 to 247.4029.   </catch_line><order_by>4015Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.401 to 247.4029, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Engages in a farm animal activity" means leading, showing, exhibiting, riding, training, providing, or assisting in providing medical treatment of, grooming, driving, or being a passenger upon a farm animal, whether mounted or unmounted; visiting, touring, or utilizing a farm animal facility as part of an organized event or activity; or assisting a participant or show management in farm animal activities. The term does not include being a spectator at a farm animal activity, except in cases where the spectator voluntarily places himself or herself in immediate proximity to the activity; </section><section prefix="2">"Farm animal" means one (1) or more of the following domesticated animals: cattle, oxen, sheep, swine, goats, horses, ponies, mules, donkeys, hinnies, ratites (ostrich, rhea, emu), camelids (alpaca, camel, llama), and poultry; </section><section prefix="3">"Farm animal activity" means: <section prefix="a">Shows, fairs, exhibits, competitions, performances, or parades that involve farm animals; </section><section prefix="b">Training or teaching activities, or both, involving farm animals; </section><section prefix="c">Boarding farm animals, including normal daily care; </section><section prefix="d">Rides, trips, shows, clinics, demonstrations, sales, hunts, parades, games, exhibitions, or other activities of any type, however informal or impromptu, that are sponsored by a farm animal activity sponsor or other person; </section><section prefix="e">Testing, riding, inspecting, or evaluating a farm animal belonging to another, whether or not the owner has received some monetary consideration or other thing of value for the use of the farm animal or is permitting a prospective purchaser of the farm animal to ride, inspect, or evaluate the farm animal; </section><section prefix="f">Placing or repairing horseshoes, trimming the hooves on a farm animal, or otherwise providing farrier services; or </section><section prefix="g">Examining or administering medical treatment to a farm animal by a veterinarian; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Farm animal activity sponsor" means an individual, group, club, partnership, corporation, or other legally constituted entity, whether the sponsor is operating for profit or nonprofit, which sponsors, organizes, allows, or provides the facilities for a farm animal activity, including, but not limited to: pony clubs, 4-H clubs, hunt clubs, riding clubs, polo clubs, school and college sponsored classes, programs, activities, and therapeutic riding programs, and operators, instructors, and promoters of farm animal facilities, including, but not limited to, stables, clubhouses, ponyride strings, fairs, exhibitions, farmstays, and arenas at which the activity is held; </section><section prefix="5">"Farm animal facility" means any areas used for any farm animal activity, including, but not limited to, farms, ranches, riding arenas, training stables or barns, pastures, riding trails, show rings, polo fields, tents and other semipermanent structures, and other areas or facilities used or provided by farm animal activity sponsors or where participants engage in farm animal activities; </section><section prefix="6">"Farm animal professional" means a person engaged for compensation in any of the following: <section prefix="a">Instructing a participant or renting to a participant a farm animal for the purpose of riding, driving, or being a passenger upon the farm animal; </section><section prefix="b">Providing daily care of farm animals boarded at a farm animal facility; </section><section prefix="c">Renting equipment or tack to a participant in a farm animal activity; </section><section prefix="d">Training a farm animal; </section><section prefix="e">Examining or administering medical treatment to a farm animal as a veterinarian; </section><section prefix="f">Providing farrier services to a farm animal; or </section><section prefix="g">Providing shearing services to a farm animal; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Farmstay" has the same meaning as in KRS 219.011; </section><section prefix="8">"Horse racing activities" means the conduct of horse racing activities within the confines of any horse racing facility licensed and regulated by KRS 230.070 to 230.990, but shall not include harness racing at county fairs; </section><section prefix="9">"Inherent risks of farm animal activities" means dangers or conditions which are an integral part of farm animal activities, including, but not limited to; <section prefix="a">The propensity of a farm animal to behave in ways that may result in injury, harm, or death to persons around them; </section><section prefix="b">The unpredictability of the reaction of a farm animal to sounds, sudden movement, and unfamiliar objects, persons, or other animals; </section><section prefix="c">Certain hazards such as surface and subsurface conditions; </section><section prefix="d">Collisions with other farm animals or objects; and </section><section prefix="e">The potential of a participant to act in a negligent manner that may contribute to injury to the participant or others, such as failing to maintain control over a farm animal or not acting within his or her ability; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Participant" means any individual, whether amateur or professional, who engages in a farm animal activity, whether or not a fee is paid to participate in the farm animal activity; and </section><section prefix="11">"Person" means any individual, corporation, association, or other legally constituted entity that owns or controls one or more farm animals. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44511</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>