<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-230</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240. </catch_line><order_by>20-230</order_by><text>As used in KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240: <section prefix="1">"Application" means a document submitted by small businesses and investors, on a form supplied by the authority, for the purpose of requesting certification to participate in the program and to apply for a credit; </section><section prefix="2">"Authority" means the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority; </section><section prefix="3">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">"Credit" means the nonrefundable angel investor tax credit established by KRS 141.396 and awarded by the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-236; </section><section prefix="5">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="6">"Enhanced incentive counties" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.32-010; </section><section prefix="7">"Entity" means any corporation, limited liability company, business development corporation, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, association, joint stock company, receivership, trust, professional service organization, or other legal entity through which business is conducted; </section><section prefix="8">"Fee" means a nonrefundable application fee in an amount set by the authority, to be collected by the authority to offset the cost of administering KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240; </section><section prefix="9">"Full-time employee" means a person that is required to work a minimum of thirty-five (35) hours per week and is subject to the tax imposed by KRS 141.020; </section><section prefix="10">"Knowledge-based" has the same meaning as in KRS 164.6011; </section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">"Qualified activity" means any knowledge-based activity related to the new economy focus areas of the Department of Commercialization and Innovation, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Bioscience; </section><section prefix="2">Environmental and energy technology; </section><section prefix="3">Health and human development; </section><section prefix="4">Information technology and communications; and </section><section prefix="5">Materials science and advanced manufacturing. </section></section><section prefix="b">A "qualified activity" does not include any activity principally engaged in by financial institutions, commercial development companies, credit companies, financial or investment advisors, brokerage or financial firms, other investment funds or investment fund managers, charitable and religious institutions, oil and gas exploration companies, insurance companies, residential housing developers, retail establishments, or any activity that the authority determines in its discretion to be against the public interest, against the purposes of KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240, or in violation of any law; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Qualified investment" means an investment meeting the requirements of KRS 154.20-234 for qualified investments, and certified pursuant to KRS 154.20-236; </section><section prefix="13">"Qualified investor" means an individual investor meeting the requirements of KRS 154.20-234 for qualified investors, and certified pursuant to KRS 154.20-236; and </section><section prefix="14">"Qualified small business" means an entity meeting the requirements of KRS 154.20-234 for qualified small businesses, and certified pursuant to KRS 154.20-236. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014).  In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering within subsection (11) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 21, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>