<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.210</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In KRS 67A.210 to 67A.350, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Administrative or directorial position" means the head of a department or other executive unit other than those excluded under KRS 67A.220. </section><section prefix="b">"Appointing authority" means the officer, commission, board or body having the power of appointment or removal in any office, department, commission, board or institution, under law, ordinance or comprehensive plan, and does not include any ratifying authority entitled to approve or disapprove an appointment. </section><section prefix="c">"Civil service" means the offices and positions of trust or employment in the service of the urban-county government not specifically excluded by KRS 67A.220 to 67A.340. </section><section prefix="d">"Commission" means the civil service commission as established under KRS 67A.230. </section><section prefix="e">"Comprehensive plan" means the plan for merger of local governments provided in this chapter. </section><section prefix="f">"Competitive examination" means the examination or evaluation described in KRS 67A.230 and 67A.240. </section><section prefix="g">"Dismissal" means the discharge of an employee. </section><section prefix="h">"Employee" means any person employed in the conduct of municipal affairs including an administrative or directorial position, but the term shall not include: <section prefix="1">Officers elected by the voters, and persons appointed to fill vacancies in elective offices; </section><section prefix="2">Members of all boards, commission and authorities established under the provisions of the comprehensive plan or by ordinance pursuant thereto; </section><section prefix="3">The chief administrative officer as denominated in the comprehensive plan; </section><section prefix="4">Department commissioners of all executive departments created by the comprehensive plan or by ordinance pursuant thereto; </section><section prefix="5">All administrative assistants appointed by the mayor or highest elective executive officer under the provisions of the comprehensive plan and all secretaries excluded by the provisions of the comprehensive plan; </section><section prefix="6">Temporary or part-time employees and all persons employed to conduct special inquiries, investigations or studies for the urban-county government; </section><section prefix="7">Constitutional officers and their appointees. </section></section><section prefix="i">"Pension fund" means the moneys derived from the employees or the levy of a special tax, or any other sum derived from any other source, to be used for the retirement of employees after the prescribed years of service and for the benefit of disabled employees, and widows and dependent children in the case of death of an employee within the scope of his employment according to the terms of KRS 67A.320 through 67A.340, the comprehensive plan, or the ordinances of the urban-county government, including retirement systems adopted pursuant to law. </section><section prefix="j">"Seniority" for purposes of KRS 67A.240, 67A.250, and 67A.270 refers to length of service as defined in the comprehensive plan or ordinance, but shall in each case include such service under cities, counties or other municipalities which have been merged into the urban-county government. Seniority and length of service for purposes of KRS 67A.320 and 67A.330 shall be in accordance with rules established by the comprehensive plan or ordinance, but shall in each case include service or seniority obtained under pension plans described in such sections existing in municipalities prior to the adoption of urban-county government, and shall in no case give credit to any service or seniority except in respect to such prior service in municipalities having such pension plans, or under urban-county governments, except that the urban-county government may purchase credits in lieu of seniority, the cost thereof being determined by the trustees of the pension fund, in accordance with sound actuarial principles, for employees whose seniority or length of service was under municipalities other than those described herein. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 67A.230 to 67A.340 are independent of and do not affect the laws governing the police and fire departments, nor their pension funds. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 1, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>