<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="517" order_by="517">BUSINESS AND COMMERCIAL FRAUDS </unit></structure><section_number>517.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Adulterated" means varying from the standard of composition or quality prescribed by statute or lawfully promulgated administrative regulation or, if none, as set by established commercial usage. </section><section prefix="2">"Business record" means any writing or article kept or maintained by an enterprise for the purpose of evidencing or reflecting its condition or activity. </section><section prefix="3">"Enterprise" means any entity of one (1) or more persons, corporate or otherwise, public or private, engaged in business, commercial, professional, industrial, eleemosynary, social, political, or governmental activity. </section><section prefix="4">"Fiduciary" means a trustee, guardian, executor, administrator, receiver, and any person carrying on fiduciary functions on behalf of a corporation or other organization which is a fiduciary. </section><section prefix="5">"Mislabeled" means: <section prefix="a">Varying from the standard of truth or disclosure in labeling prescribed by statute or lawfully promulgated administrative regulation or, if none, as set by established commercial usage; or </section><section prefix="b">Represented as being another person's product, though otherwise labeled accurately as to quality or quantity. </section></section><section prefix="6">"Sham or front company" means any business established or in existence which falsely represents that business to be a minority business enterprise, or disadvantaged business enterprise, as defined in 79 C.F.R. 23.5 or 15 C.F.R. 1400.2, operated or operating for the purpose of obtaining funds, contracts, subcontracts, services, or other benefits from any local government, local government agency, or special district of this Commonwealth from the Commonwealth, or any state government agency or public corporation of this Commonwealth, or from the United States government or any federal government agency. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 145, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19837</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>