<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-100</section_number><catch_line>Environmental Quality Commission:  Membership, terms, compensation, officers, meetings. </catch_line><order_by>1-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Environmental Quality Commission which shall consist of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">All members of the commission shall be citizens eligible to vote in elections in this Commonwealth. At all times a majority of the commission shall meet the requirements of KRS 224.1-105, and "person" as used in KRS 224.1-105, shall relate to a majority of the members of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Of the seven (7) members of the commission first to be appointed, one (1) shall be appointed for a term of one (1) year; two (2) for a term of two (2) years; two (2) for a term of three (3) years; and two (2) for a term of four (4) years, beginning on January 1, 1973. Thereafter, all appointments shall be made for terms of four (4) years beginning on the first day of January of the year in which the appointment is made. Each of the appointed members of the commission shall hold office for the term for which he was appointed and until his successor shall have been appointed and taken office in his stead or until he shall resign or be removed in a manner provided by law. </section><section prefix="4">Any vacancy in an unexpired term shall be filled for the unexpired portion of the term in the same manner as the original appointment to that term. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the commission shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for each meeting attended and may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of official duties. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall select one (1) of its members as chairman, another as vice chairman, and another as secretary at its first regular meeting in the calendar year. </section><section prefix="7">Staff services for the commission shall be performed, insofar as practicable, by personnel of the cabinet. </section><section prefix="8">The commission may request and receive the assistance of any state or municipal educational institution, experiment station, laboratory, or other agency when it is deemed necessary or beneficial by the commission in the performance of its duties. </section><section prefix="9">The commission shall hold regular meetings at least once in every three (3) months, the time and place of which shall be determined by the commission. Special meetings may be called by the chairman or by three (3) members of the commission by delivery to each member of the commission of a written notice thereof at least five (5) days in advance of the date of any such meeting. Four (4) members of the commission shall constitute a quorum at any meeting. The commission shall establish bylaws for the conduct of its meeting and shall keep an accurate record of all its proceedings. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 20, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.041. KRS 224.01-100. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-100</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>