<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.020</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of property from one district to another -- Title not affected -- District may own school in another district.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The title to school property in territory transferred from one (1) school district to another shall not be affected by the transfer. In case of the sale of such property the board of education to which the property belongs may allow a credit on the sale price of the property in proportion to the ratio which the school population of the transferred territory is to the total school population of the district from which the territory was transferred before the transfer was made. </section><section prefix="2">A board of education owning and operating a school plant in another district on June 14, 1934, may continue to own and operate the plant, and a county board of education may establish and maintain a school in an independent school district. Any independent school district may purchase school sites and establish and maintain schools outside the limits of the independent district, but independent districts containing cities of the first class or designated cities shall not purchase school sites or establish or maintain schools outside the county in which the independent district is located. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section, "designated city" means a city classified as a city of the second class as of January 1, 2014, under the city classification system in effect prior to January 1, 2015. The Department of Education shall, on or before January 1, 2015, create an official registry listing the cities that qualify as a "designated city" under this section and shall publish that registry on its Web site. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 227, effective January 1, 2015. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 549, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-5. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43812</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>