<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.595</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 99.595 to 99.605 and 132.452. </catch_line><order_by>595</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Administering agency" means the agency delegated responsibility by the legislative body to implement the provisions of KRS 99.595 to 99.605 and 132.452. </section><section prefix="2">"Commercial facility" means any structure the primary purpose and use of which is the operation of a commercial business enterprise and which is twenty-five (25) years old or older. </section><section prefix="3">"Existing residential building" means a residential building which has been in existence for at least twenty-five (25) years and use of which is to provide independent living facilities for one (1) or more persons. </section><section prefix="4">"Legislative body" means the board of aldermen in a city of the first class operating under KRS Chapter 83, the city council in a city operating pursuant to KRS 83A.130, the city commission in a city operating pursuant to KRS 83A.140, the board of commissioners in a city operating pursuant to KRS 83A.150, the fiscal court in a county, the legislative council in a consolidated local government operating pursuant to KRS Chapter 67C, and the legislative body in an urban-county government operating pursuant to KRS Chapter 67A. </section><section prefix="5">"Local government" means a county, municipal, consolidated local government, or urban-county government. </section><section prefix="6">"Rehabilitation" means the process of returning an existing structure to a state of utility through repair or alteration which makes possible an efficient contemporary use. </section><section prefix="7">"Repair" means the reconstruction or renewal of any part of an existing structure for the purpose of maintenance. </section><section prefix="8">"Restoration" means the process of accurately recovering the form and details of a structure and its setting as it appeared at a particular period of time by removal of later work or by the replacement of missing earlier work. </section><section prefix="9">"Stabilization" means the process of applying measures designed to reestablish a weather-resistant enclosure and the structural stability of an unsafe or deteriorated property while maintaining the essential form as it exists. </section><section prefix="10">"Assessment or reassessment moratorium" means the act of deferring the value of the improvements from the taxable assessment of qualifying units of real property for a maximum period of five (5) years. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 123, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26562</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>