<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.10-200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 286.10-200 to 286.10-285 and KRS 286.10-991. </catch_line><order_by>10-200</order_by><text>As used in KRS 286.10-200 to 286.10-285 and KRS 286.10-991, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Capital" means the assets of a business entity less the liabilities of that business entity. Assets and liabilities shall be measured according to generally accepted accounting principles or relevant pronouncements of the financial accounting standards board; </section><section prefix="2">"Department" means the Department of Financial Institutions; </section><section prefix="3">"Person" means any sole proprietorship, general partnership, corporation, limited liability company, or limited liability partnership duly qualified to do business in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="4">"Pledgor" means any individual who executes a title pledge agreement as defined in subsection (5) of this section; </section><section prefix="5">"Title pledge agreement" means a thirty (30) day written agreement whereby a title pledge lender agrees to make a loan of money to a pledgor, and the pledgor agrees to give the title pledge lender a security interest in unencumbered titled personal property owned by the pledgor, subject to the terms and conditions of KRS 286.10-200 to 286.10-285 and KRS 286.10-991. A pledgor shall have no personal liability on a title pledge agreement and a title pledge agreement shall not be considered a debt transaction for any purpose of law; </section><section prefix="6">"Title pledge lender" means any person engaged in the business of making title pledge agreements; </section><section prefix="7">"Title pledge office" means the location at which, or premises in which, a title pledge lender regularly conducts business; and </section><section prefix="8">"Titled personal property" means any personal property the ownership of which is evidenced and delineated by a state issued certificate of title but shall not include mobile homes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 822, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.200. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14925</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>