<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.925</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>925</order_by><text>In addition to all other powers and duties vested in it by law, the cabinet shall have the authority, power, and duty to: <section prefix="1">Adopt, modify, and repeal regulations and standards relating to the public health or health aspects of the operation of state confinement facilities, and exercise general supervision over the administration of KRS 211.920 to 211.945 and assist in the enforcement of all regulations and standards promulgated pursuant to it; </section><section prefix="2">Collect, evaluate, and disseminate information from state confinement facilities as it relates to the public health of the people of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="3">Develop comprehensive plans for the elimination of conditions in state confinement facilities which adversely affect the public health or the health of those persons confined or likely to be confined in any state confinement facility; </section><section prefix="4">Enter upon the premises and inspect any state confinement facility for the purpose of determining the extent of compliance with KRS 211.920 to 211.945 and investigating the effect of the operation of state confinement facilities upon the public health or the health of those persons confined or likely to be confined in any state confinement facility; </section><section prefix="5">Advise, consult, and cooperate with other agencies of the Commonwealth, including the Department of Corrections, other jurisdictions, the federal government, interstate and interlocal agencies, and local governments regarding the effects of the operation of confinement facilities upon the public health; </section><section prefix="6">Accept, receive, and administer grants or other funds or gifts from public and private agencies for the purpose of implementing KRS 211.920 to 211.945. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 76, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 31, effective January 1, 1983. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8528</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>