<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.782</section_number><catch_line>Report on use of energy-efficiency measures in state government -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>782</order_by><text>The cabinet shall report on or before October 15, 2008, and on or before every October 15 thereafter to the Legislative Research Commission on progress made to maximize the use of energy-efficiency measures in state government. The Legislative Research Commission shall transmit the report to the appropriate interim joint committees and to the General Assembly when it convenes. The report shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">A summary of initiatives undertaken by the cabinet during the reporting period to promote adoption of low cost/no cost energy-efficiency measures, including employee training efforts; </section><section prefix="2">A summary of energy-efficiency measures installed and energy improvements made during the reporting period; </section><section prefix="3">Energy consumption and expenditure data for facilities owned or leased by state government and any documented savings made as a result of energy-efficiency measures and improvements; </section><section prefix="4">Status report on the number of buildings newly constructed, renovated, or leased in accordance with the high-performance building standards required under KRS 56.777 and the amount of savings realized based upon a life-cycle cost analysis; </section><section prefix="5">Any efforts made during the reporting period to promote acquisition of energy-efficient products pursuant to KRS 45A.045(12) and the amount of savings expected to be realized in the first year of operation from the purchase of ENERGY STAR-qualified products pursuant to KRS 56.775; </section><section prefix="6">Any recommendations for future funding of energy improvements or other measures needed to assure energy efficiency in state government; and </section><section prefix="7">Any improvements in energy efficiency planned or realized through the use of the LEED rating system, the Green Globes rating system, ENERGY STAR-qualified products, and guaranteed energy savings performance contracts. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 8, effective February 25, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 33, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, secs. 34 and 43, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> February 25, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts. ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22692</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>