<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.509</section_number><catch_line>Regional interagency councils for services to children with a behavioral health need in each area development district.   </catch_line><order_by>509</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There are hereby created regional interagency councils for services to children with a behavioral health need. These councils shall be formed in each area development district within the Commonwealth of Kentucky, except that those area development districts that contain a county with a population greater than one hundred thousand (100,000) may form up to three (3) such councils. The regional interagency councils for services to children with a behavioral health need shall be chaired by the service region administrator of the Department for Community Based Services or a program specialist with expertise in this service area as the district supervisor's designee. Each council shall be composed of the following members: <section prefix="a">The children's services coordinator from each regional community mental health center or their designee in the case of a multicouncil district; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) court-designated worker chosen by the Chief Regional District Judge within the region; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) specialist in special education chosen by the school district superintendents in the area served by the regional council; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) parent of a child with a behavioral health need, who is a consumer of state-funded services for children with a behavioral health need, and one (1) parent who meets the same criteria to serve as the parent member's alternate, who may attend and participate in all council meetings, but shall vote only in the absence of the parent member. For each appointment to be made, the regional interagency council for which the appointment is to be made shall submit to the Governor a list of two (2) names of parents who are qualified for appointment from which list the Governor shall make the appointment. Appointees shall serve a term of four (4) years. If the child of the parent member or alternate parent member ceases to be a consumer of state-funded services for children with an emotional disability during the term of appointment, the member shall be eligible to serve out the remainder of the term of appointment; </section><section prefix="e">Any other local public or private agency that provides services to children with a behavioral health need which the regional interagency council may invite to have a representative become a permanent or temporary member of the council; and </section><section prefix="f">Representatives from the Department of Juvenile Justice and local health departments. </section></section><section prefix="2">No member of a regional interagency council for services to children with a behavioral health need shall be given compensation in addition to that which they already receive as service providers or state employees, except that the parent members and alternate parent members of regional interagency councils shall be reimbursed for all expenses incurred through the performance of their duties as council members. </section><section prefix="3">Each regional interagency council for services to children with a behavioral health need shall perform the following functions: <section prefix="a">Review case histories of children referred to it by its members or any other entity within its geographical area to coordinate service provision; </section><section prefix="b">Coordinate the development of interagency service plans for children with a behavioral health need in the least restrictive alternative mode of treatment; </section><section prefix="c">Identify the time frames necessary and the parties responsible for the timely development of the interagency service plans for children with a behavioral health need; </section><section prefix="d">Verify that services identified in interagency service plans are developed, accessed, and delivered in a coordinated and timely manner; </section><section prefix="e">Initiate and adopt interagency agreements as necessary for providing services to children with a behavioral health need by the agencies represented in the regional council; </section><section prefix="f">Advise the state interagency council regarding service delivery to children with a behavioral health need within the region; </section><section prefix="g">Refer those children for whom the regional councils cannot provide adequate services to the state interagency council; </section><section prefix="h">Implement the uniform grievance procedure established by the state interagency council; </section><section prefix="i">Make periodic reports to the state interagency council regarding the number of children referred to the regional council and the progress made in meeting the needs of each child; </section><section prefix="j">Recognize local interagency councils for services to children with a behavioral health need when it determines the council would be beneficial to service delivery; </section><section prefix="k">Participate in family accountability, intervention, and response teams established pursuant to KRS 605.035; and </section><section prefix="l">Promote services to meet the behavioral health need of a child. </section></section><section prefix="4">The secretary for health and family services and the designee of the State Department of Education shall ensure that regional councils for services to children with a behavioral health need are formed. </section><section prefix="5">Local interagency councils for services to children with a behavioral health need may be formed as necessary to enhance service provision, better coordinate services, or initiate special projects and fundraising activities for children with a behavioral health need within a city, county, or other local community. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 19, effective July 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 204, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 28, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 168, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43960</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>