<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.527</section_number><catch_line>Extension of system to include police court judges and their present and future survivors covered as of December 31, 1977, under retirement plans established by cities of second or third class -- Procedure for transfer of coverage to state system. </catch_line><order_by>527</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The system shall extend to and embrace police court judges and present and future survivors who are covered as of December 31, 1977, by pension plans established under KRS 26.650 or 26.652 and which existed as of July 31, 1976. </section><section prefix="2">Within thirty (30) days after January 1, 1978, the city legislative body of each city with a pension plan established under KRS 26.650 or 26.652 shall furnish the system a record of the period of service and contributions of each person covered by the plan, and, for any survivor who is benefiting from the plan, the monthly pension amount being received and any other information requested by the system. </section><section prefix="3">Upon receiving the information required by subsection (2) of this section, the system shall credit each person with service sufficient to guarantee that he or his survivors shall receive at a minimum the benefits to which he would be entitled under KRS 26.660, except that the service required for vesting shall be that required by the system rather than that required by KRS 26.650 or 26.652.  In addition, each individual's contributions to the plan under which he was covered as of December 31, 1977, shall be credited to his account in the system. </section><section prefix="4">Each person covered by the system under this section shall have the same rights and responsibilities as any other member or retiree of the system but at no additional cost to the person. </section><section prefix="5">Each city with a pension plan established under KRS 26.650 or 26.652 as of July 31, 1976, shall pay to the system an amount equal to that which would have existed in the police judge pension fund as of December 31, 1977, if the fund contained: <section prefix="a">The actual amount paid by each police judge making contributions to the fund, and </section><section prefix="b">Contributions by the city equal to the amount which would have been paid if the city had contributed to the fund at the rate provided for under KRS 61.565. </section></section><section prefix="6">Within five (5) years after the system makes its determination, each city shall pay to the system the amount computed by the system under subsection (5) of this section.  Any additional cost of funding benefits provided under subsection (3) of this section shall be paid by the state. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>