<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.450</section_number><catch_line>Map of mine to be filed initially and annually -- Additional maps. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The operator or superintendent of each underground mine shall annually make or cause to be made a map of the workings of the mine which is accurate and of professional quality, on a scale of not less than one hundred (100) and not more than five hundred (500) feet to the inch, showing the area mined and the forms of the excavations up to January 1, together with the location and connection of the property and mineral lease lines of all adjoining lands within one thousand (1,000) feet of the excavations and, marked on each tract, the name of each owner or lessee of adjoining lands and of mine property for which the map is being filed. Such map shall also show: <section prefix="a">The proposed general plan of mining for the next twelve (12) months; </section><section prefix="b">All pillared, worked-out, and abandoned areas; </section><section prefix="c">Entries and aircourses with the direction of airflow indicated by arrows; </section><section prefix="d">Dip of the coal bed; </section><section prefix="e">Escapeways; </section><section prefix="f">Major roof falls; </section><section prefix="g">Any worked-out areas within one thousand (1,000) feet of the projections proposed for the next twelve (12) months, designating whether active, abandoned, or pillared, and showing precautions to be taken if mines are projected towards old workings which cannot be examined; </section><section prefix="h">Mines above or below; </section><section prefix="i">Water pools above; </section><section prefix="j">Location of all known oil and gas wells, both producing and abandoned, within the area required to be mapped, as well as owners and well numbers when possible; </section><section prefix="k">Such map shall identify those areas of the mine which are inaccessible or cannot be entered safely and on which no information is available; </section><section prefix="l">The name and address of the mine, the mine number, seam, and seam thickness; </section><section prefix="m">The scale and orientation of the map, longitude and latitude, and corresponding USGS 7.5 minute quadrangle map; </section><section prefix="n">The property or boundary lines of the mine, indicating the twenty-five (25) foot barrier required by KRS 352.490 between projections and property lines; </section><section prefix="o">All known drill holes that penetrate the coal bed being mined; </section><section prefix="p">All shaft, slope, drift, and tunnel openings and auger and strip-mined areas of the coal bed being mined; </section><section prefix="q">The location of all surface mine ventilation fans; the location may be designated on the mine map by symbols; </section><section prefix="r">The location of railroad tracks and public highways leading to the mine, and mine buildings of a permanent nature with identifying names shown, and watersheds near openings of the mine; </section><section prefix="s">The location and description of at least two (2) permanent base line points coordinated with the underground and surface mine traverses, and the location and description of at least two (2) permanent elevation bench marks used in connection with establishing or referencing mine elevation surveys, and any other identifying permanent landmarks; </section><section prefix="t">The location and elevation of any body of water dammed in the mine or held back in any portion of the mine; provided, however, such bodies of water may be shown on overlays or tracings attached to the mine maps used to show contour lines; </section><section prefix="u">The elevations of tops and bottoms of shafts and slopes, and the floor at the entrance to drift and tunnel openings; </section><section prefix="v">The elevation of the floor at intervals of not more than two hundred (200) feet in: <section prefix="1">At least one (1) entry of each working section, main entry, and cross entries; </section><section prefix="2">The last line of open crosscuts of each working section, and main and cross entries before such sections and main and cross entries are abandoned; and </section><section prefix="3">Rooms advancing toward or adjacent to property or boundary lines or adjacent mines; and </section></section><section prefix="w">Contour lines passing through whole number elevations of the coal bed being mined. The spacing of such lines shall not exceed ten (10) foot elevation levels, except that a broader spacing of contour lines may be approved by the commissioner or his authorized representative for steeply pitching coal beds. Contour lines may be placed on overlays or tracings attached to mine maps. </section></section> The operator, superintendent, or mine manager shall deposit a true copy of the map with his license application to the commissioner within forty-five (45) days after January 1, and another copy of the map shall be kept at the office of the mine. A copy shall also be furnished the district office of the department. <section prefix="2">After making and filing the map with the commissioner, the operator, superintendent, or mine manager thereafter is only required to file annually with the commissioner, within the time specified, such additional map and statement as is necessary to show the progress of the workings, the amount and forms of excavations, and the property lines within one thousand (1,000) feet of the excavations extended since the date of the preceding map. The commissioner shall annually, before January 1, give notice that the map is required. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner may require any operator, superintendent, or mine manager to furnish a map other than those required in subsections (1) and (2) of this section or of a surface mine, and the operator or superintendent shall immediately comply with the requirement. </section><section prefix="4">The mine inspector shall have the authority to stop production at the mine of any operator who does not furnish within thirty (30) days of notification of specific deficiencies a map which fully complies with the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 27, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 28. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 40. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-43. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33026</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>