<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.550</section_number><catch_line>Suspension or revocation of race track license. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>In addition to all other penalties provided in KRS 138.510 to 138.540: <section prefix="1">When the pari-mutuel system of betting is operated at a track licensed under KRS Chapter 230, the license may be suspended, revoked or renewal refused by the commission upon the failure of the operator to comply with KRS 138.510 to 138.540 or the rules and regulations promulgated by the department pursuant thereto, even though the pari-mutuel system of betting and the track are operated by different persons, corporations, or associations; and </section><section prefix="2">Any advance deposit account wagering licensee that fails to remit the tax imposed by KRS 138.513, to remit returns required by KRS 138.530, or to maintain the records required by KRS 138.530 or administrative regulations promulgated by the department, may have the license granted under KRS 230.260 suspended, revoked, or not renewed by the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 109, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 109, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 392, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 50, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43404</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>