<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.900</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.900 to 211.905 and KRS 211.994. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.900 to 211.905 and KRS 211.994, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" shall mean the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" shall mean the secretary for health and family services or his authorized representative; </section><section prefix="3">"Lead-based hazard" shall mean levels contained in the federal Residential Lead-based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992; </section><section prefix="4">"Dwelling" shall mean any structure or child-occupied facility, all or a part of which is designed for human habitation; </section><section prefix="5">"Dwelling unit" shall mean any room or group of rooms or other interior areas of a dwelling or child-occupied facility designed or used for human habitation; </section><section prefix="6">"Owner" shall mean any person who, alone, jointly, or severally with others, has legal title to, charge, care, or control of any dwelling or dwelling unit as owner, agent of the owner, or as executor, administrator, trustee, conservator, or guardian of the estate of the owner; </section><section prefix="7">"At-risk persons" shall mean all children seventy-two (72) months of age and younger and pregnant women who reside in dwellings or dwelling units which were constructed and painted prior to 1978, or reside in geographic areas defined by the cabinet as high risk, or possess one (1) or more risk factors identified in a lead poisoning verbal risk assessment approved by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="8">"Outreach programs" shall mean those efforts to locate, screen, and diagnose for elevated lead blood levels, those at-risk persons who are not utilizing existing screening and diagnostic programs or those programs which may be established after June 21, 1974; </section><section prefix="9">"Elevated blood lead level" means any blood lead level greater than or equal to ten </section><section prefix="10">micrograms per deciliter of whole blood or a level consistent with </section>recommendations by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the American Academy of Pediatrics; and (10) "Confirmed elevated blood lead level" means a first venous blood lead test or a second capillary blood lead test taken within the time frames specified by the cabinet where the blood lead test result is greater than or equal to fifteen (15) micrograms per deciliter of whole blood. </text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 390, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 330, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 72, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 76 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8513</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>