<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.065</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary actions -- Civil penalty -- Permanent file -- Assurance of voluntary compliance -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue a license, or suspend, revoke, impose probationary conditions, impose an administrative fine, issue a written reprimand, or any combination thereof regarding any licensee upon proof that the licensee or applicant has: <section prefix="a">Violated any provision of KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090 or any administrative regulation promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Knowingly and willfully made a material misstatement in connection with an application for license or renewal; </section><section prefix="c">Been convicted of a felony; </section><section prefix="d">Practiced fraud, deceit, or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="e">Committed any act that would have been cause for refusal to issue the license had it existed and been known to the board at the time of issuance; </section><section prefix="f">Been incompetent or negligent in the practice of private investigating; or </section><section prefix="g">Violated the code of ethics promulgated by administrative regulation by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to or in lieu of any other lawful disciplinary action under this section, the board may assess a civil penalty not exceeding two thousand dollars ($2,000). </section><section prefix="3">When the board issues a written reprimand to the licensee a copy of the reprimand shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to submit a response within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have that response filed in the permanent file. </section><section prefix="4">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may accept an assurance of voluntary compliance from the licensee if the assurance effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="5">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its probation, suspension, or other disciplinary action. </section><section prefix="6">Any party aggrieved by a disciplinary action of the board may bring an action in Franklin Circuit Court pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="7">A license shall be subject to expiration and renewal during any period in which the license is suspended. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>