<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="516" order_by="516">FORGERY AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>516.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Coin machine" means a coin box, turnstile, vending machine, or other mechanical or electronic device or receptacle designed: <section prefix="a">To receive a coin or bill or token made for the purpose; and </section><section prefix="b">In return for the insertion or deposit thereof, automatically to offer, provide, assist in providing, or permit the acquisition of property or service; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Complete written instrument" means a written instrument which purports to be a genuine written instrument fully drawn with respect to every essential feature thereof; </section><section prefix="3">"Controlled substance" has the same meaning as it does in KRS 218A.010; </section><section prefix="4">"Incomplete written instrument" means a written instrument which contains some matter by way of content or authentication but which requires additional matter in order to render it a complete written instrument; </section><section prefix="5">To "falsely alter" a written instrument means to change, without the authority of anyone entitled to grant it, a written instrument, whether it be in complete or incomplete form, by means of erasure, obliteration, deletion, insertion of new matter, transposition of matter, or in any other manner, so that such instrument in its thus altered form appears or purports to be in all respects an authentic creation of or fully authorized by its ostensible maker or drawer; </section><section prefix="6">To "falsely complete" a written instrument means to transform, by adding, inserting or changing matter, an incomplete written instrument into a complete one, without the authority of anyone entitled to grant it, so that the complete instrument appears or purports to be in all respects an authentic creation of or fully authorized by its ostensible maker or drawer; </section><section prefix="7">To "falsely make" a written instrument means to make or draw a complete written instrument in its entirety or an incomplete written instrument, which purports to be an authentic creation of its ostensible maker or drawer, but which is not either because the ostensible maker or drawer is fictitious or because, if real, he did not authorize the making or drawing thereof; </section><section prefix="8">"Forged instrument" means a written instrument which has been falsely made, completed, or altered; </section><section prefix="9">"Slug" means an object or article which by virtue of its size, shape, or any other quality is capable of being inserted, deposited, or otherwise used in a coin machine as an improper substitute for a genuine coin, bill, or token; </section><section prefix="10">"Value of the slug" means the value of the coin, bill, or token for which it is capable of being substituted; and </section><section prefix="11">"Written instrument" means any instrument or article containing written or printed matter or its equivalent used for the purpose of reciting, embodying, conveying, or recording information, or constituting a symbol or evidence of value, right, privilege, or identification, which is capable of being used to the advantage or disadvantage of some person. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 132, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19823</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>