<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.810</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions to open meetings. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All meetings of a quorum of the members of any public agency at which any public business is discussed or at which any action is taken by the agency, shall be public meetings, open to the public at all times, except for the following: <section prefix="a">Deliberations for decisions of the Kentucky Parole Board; </section><section prefix="b">Deliberations on the future acquisition or sale of real property by a public agency, but only when publicity would be likely to affect the value of a specific piece of property to be acquired for public use or sold by a public agency; </section><section prefix="c">Discussions of proposed or pending litigation against or on behalf of the public agency; </section><section prefix="d">Grand and petit jury sessions; </section><section prefix="e">Collective bargaining negotiations between public employers and their employees or their representatives; </section><section prefix="f">Discussions or hearings which might lead to the appointment, discipline, or dismissal of an individual employee, member, or student without restricting that employee's, member's, or student's right to a public hearing if requested. This exception shall not be interpreted to permit discussion of general personnel matters in secret; </section><section prefix="g">Discussions between a public agency and a representative of a business entity and discussions concerning a specific proposal, if open discussions would jeopardize the siting, retention, expansion, or upgrading of the business; </section><section prefix="h">State and local cabinet meetings and executive cabinet meetings; </section><section prefix="i">Committees of the General Assembly other than standing committees; </section><section prefix="j">Deliberations of judicial or quasi-judicial bodies regarding individual adjudications or appointments, at which neither the person involved, his representatives, nor any other individual not a member of the agency's governing body or staff is present, but not including any meetings of planning commissions, zoning commissions, or boards of adjustment; </section><section prefix="k">Meetings which federal or state law specifically require to be conducted in privacy; </section><section prefix="l">Meetings which the Constitution provides shall be held in secret; and </section><section prefix="m">That portion of a meeting devoted to a discussion of a specific public record exempted from disclosure under KRS 61.878(1)(m). However, that portion of any public agency meeting shall not be closed to a member of the Kentucky General Assembly. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any series of less than quorum meetings, where the members attending one (1) or more of the meetings collectively constitute at least a quorum of the members of the public agency and where the meetings are held for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of subsection (1) of this section, shall be subject to the requirements of subsection (1) of this section. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit discussions between individual members where the purpose of the discussions is to educate the members on specific issues. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (3/16/2005).  The Office of the Kentucky Attorney General requested that amendments in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, to the arrangement of the paragraphs of subsection (1) of this section be changed. The change was requested "in the interest of preventing confusion  to the public and public agencies" and was made by the Statute Reviser under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>