<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.381</section_number><catch_line>Inspection fee -- Quarterly statements. </catch_line><order_by>381</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be paid to the Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station for all fertilizers distributed in this state to nonregistrants or nonlicensees an inspection fee at the rate of fifty cents ($0.50) per ton; except sales or exchanges between importers, manufacturers, distributors, licensees, or registrants are exempted. </section><section prefix="2">Every registrant or licensee who distributes fertilizer in the state shall file on forms approved by the director a quarterly statement setting forth the number of net tons of each grade of fertilizer distributed in this state, the county of the consignee, the form in which the fertilizer was distributed, e.g., bags, bulk, or liquid, and whether the fertilizer was for farm or nonfarm use. The report shall be due on or before the last day of January, April, July, and October of each year, and upon the filing of the statement the registrant or licensee shall pay the inspection fee at the rate stated in subsection (1) of this section. If the tonnage report is not filed and the payment of inspection fees is not made within fifteen (15) days after the due date, a collection fee, amounting to ten percent (10%), with a minimum of fifty dollars ($50), of the amount due shall be assessed against the registrant or licensee and added to the amount due. </section><section prefix="3">If more than one (1) person is involved in the distribution of a fertilizer, the last person who has the fertilizer registered or is licensed and who distributed to a nonregistrant dealer or consumer shall be responsible for reporting the tonnage and paying the inspection fee, unless the report and payment are made by a prior distributor of the fertilizer. </section><section prefix="4">On individual packages of fertilizer containing ten (10) pounds or less, there shall be paid, in lieu of the inspection fee of fifty cents ($0.50) per ton required by subsection (1) of this section, an annual inspection fee of fifty dollars ($50) for each grade of each brand sold or distributed. If a person distributes fertilizer in packages of ten (10) pounds or less and in packages over ten (10) pounds, the annual fee shall apply only to that portion distributed in packages of ten (10) pounds or less. </section><section prefix="5">Fees collected shall be used for the payment of the costs of inspecting, sampling, analyzing, and other expenses necessary for the administration of KRS 250.361 to 250.451. </section><section prefix="6">No information furnished to the director under this section shall be disclosed in a way to divulge the operation of any person. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12129</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>