<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.035</section_number><catch_line>Advisory committee on housing policy. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Housing Corporation shall oversee the development and implementation of the Kentucky housing policy. The corporation shall create an advisory committee on housing policy consisting of the following: <section prefix="a">The following nine (9) state government members, or their duly appointed designees: the commissioner of education; commissioner of the Department for Local Government; commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction; secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet; secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; executive director of the Human Rights Commission; state historic preservation officer; secretary of the Transportation Cabinet; and executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation; </section><section prefix="b">At-large members shall be appointed by the chairman of the board of directors of the Kentucky Housing Corporation. There shall be one (1) at-large representative for each of the following: <section prefix="1">Public housing authorities; </section><section prefix="2">Mortgage banking industry; </section><section prefix="3">Manufactured housing industry; </section><section prefix="4">Realtors; </section><section prefix="5">Homebuilders; </section><section prefix="6">Urban nonprofit housing organizations; </section><section prefix="7">Rural nonprofit housing organizations; </section><section prefix="8">Urban advocates for the homeless; </section><section prefix="9">Rural advocates for the homeless; </section><section prefix="10">Residents of economically diverse urban neighborhoods; </section><section prefix="11">Residents of economically diverse rural neighborhoods; </section><section prefix="12">Rental property providers; </section><section prefix="13">Advocates for persons with physical disabilities; </section><section prefix="14">Advocates for persons with mental disabilities; </section><section prefix="15">The Kentucky State Building Trades Council; </section><section prefix="16">The Kentucky League of Cities; and </section><section prefix="17">The Kentucky Association of Counties; and </section></section><section prefix="c">One (1) member of the Senate and one (1) member of the House of Representatives. </section></section><section prefix="2">State government members and General Assembly members shall serve on the advisory committee during the term of their elected or appointed state government positions. Members appointed as provided by subsection (1)(b) of this section shall be appointed for four (4) year terms, except that initially five (5) shall be appointed for two (2) year terms, six (6) shall be appointed for three (3) year terms, and six (6) shall be appointed for four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="3">The advisory committee shall meet at least quarterly and hold additional meetings as necessary. Eleven (11) members of the committee shall constitute a quorum for the purposes of conducting business and exercising its powers for all purposes. </section><section prefix="4">Any vacancy shall be filled as provided by the requirements and procedures for the initial appointment and only for the remainder of the term of the initial appointment. </section><section prefix="5">Any at-large member may be removed at any time, with or without cause, by resolution of a majority of the board of directors of the corporation. </section><section prefix="6">The advisory committee shall consult with and advise the officers and directors of the corporation concerning matters relating to the Kentucky housing policy. </section><section prefix="7">The corporation shall annually report its findings and recommendations regarding the Kentucky housing policy to the Governor and the Interim Joint Committee on Local Government of the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="8">The advisory committee shall elect a presiding officer from among its members and may establish its own rules of procedure which shall not be inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="9">Members of the advisory committee shall serve without compensation. Members who are not employees of the Commonwealth shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual expenses incurred in carrying out their duties on the committee. </section><section prefix="10">The Kentucky Housing Corporation shall provide the staff and funding for the administrative activities of the advisory committee. The Kentucky Housing Corporation shall perform all budgeting, procurement, and other administrative activities necessary to the functioning of the advisory committee. The advisory committee may authorize studies as it deems necessary and utilize Kentucky Housing Corporation funds and other available resources from the public or private sector to provide housing needs data. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 243, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 83, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 87, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 43, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 19, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 70, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 132, effective July 15, 1998.. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6928</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>