<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="528" order_by="528">GAMBLING </unit></structure><section_number>528.050</section_number><catch_line>Possession of gambling records in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of possession of gambling records in the first degree when, with knowledge of the contents thereof, he possesses any writing, paper, instrument or article of a kind commonly used: <section prefix="a">In the operation or promotion of a bookmaking scheme or enterprise and constituting, reflecting or representing bets totaling more than $500; or </section><section prefix="b">In the operation, promotion or playing of a lottery or mutuel scheme or enterprise and constituting, reflecting or representing more than 500 plays or chances therein. </section></section><section prefix="2">It shall be a defense to any prosecution under this section that: <section prefix="a">The writing, paper, instrument or article possessed by the defendant constituted, reflected or represented bets of the defendant himself in a number not exceeding ten (10); or </section><section prefix="b">The writing, paper, instrument or article possessed by the defendant was neither used nor intended to be used in the operation or promotion of a bookmaking scheme or enterprise, or in the operation, promotion, or playing of a lottery or mutuel scheme or enterprise. </section></section><section prefix="3">Possession of gambling records in the first degree is a Class D felony. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 244, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>