<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.300</section_number><catch_line>Adoption of branch budget bills -- Separate branch budget bill required for Transportation Cabinet -- Enactment of biennial highway construction plan. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The financial plan for each fiscal year as presented in the branch budget recommendation shall be adopted, with any modifications made by the General Assembly, by the passage of a branch budget bill for each branch of government, and any revenue and other acts as necessary. </section><section prefix="2">With regard to the Transportation Cabinet, the General Assembly shall: <section prefix="a">Enact, as a separate bill, a branch budget for the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Enact, as a separate bill, the biennial highway construction plan, as amended by the General Assembly, including identification of projects from the last four (4) years of the six (6) year road plan that may be moved forward, and the conditions and requirements under which the identified projects may be moved forward; and </section><section prefix="c">Adopt the last four (4) years of the six (6) year road plan, as amended by the General Assembly, as a joint resolution. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 10, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 5, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 21, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39790</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>