<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-010</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Economic Development Partnership -- Membership -- Vacancies -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>10-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Economic Development Partnership, a board governing the Cabinet for Economic Development, is created and established, performing essential governmental and public functions and purposes essential to improving and promoting the health and general welfare of the people of the Commonwealth through sustainable economic development, as prescribed in KRS 154.1-020. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall have reorganization powers and authority as prescribed in KRS 12.028 and shall constitute an administrative body as defined in KRS 12.010, but it and the cabinet shall not be subject to the reorganization by the Governor, KRS Chapter 12 notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="c">The board shall serve as the governing body of the cabinet and shall exercise all powers and authorities conferred upon it by statute, including, but not limited to, the following functions: <section prefix="1">Strategic planning; </section><section prefix="2">Finance; </section><section prefix="3">Business assistance; </section><section prefix="4">Marketing and promotion; </section><section prefix="5">Community development; </section><section prefix="6">Workforce development; </section><section prefix="7">Innovation; and </section><section prefix="8">All economic development powers and authorities not specifically conferred by statute to another agency or authority of state government. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of thirteen (13) voting members and two (2) nonvoting members. The thirteen (13) voting members shall consist of the Governor, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet, the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the secretary of the Labor Cabinet, and eight (8) private sector members who shall be appointed by the Governor. The secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet shall serve as a voting member upon the absence of the Governor. The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development and the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall serve as nonvoting members. </section><section prefix="3">By no later than thirty (30) days after July 14, 1992, the governing bodies of each of the following organizations shall meet and nominate two (2) persons from each of the six (6) Congressional districts of the Commonwealth and two (2) persons from the state at large, as candidates for the initial appointment as private sector members to the board: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Industrial Development Council; </section><section prefix="b">The Associated Industries of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky State AFL-CIO; </section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation; </section><section prefix="e">The Kentucky Chamber of Commerce; and </section><section prefix="f">The Kentucky Economic Development Corporation. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall select the original eight (8) private sector members from the aggregation of the lists provided pursuant to subsection (3) with at least one (1) appointment being chosen from each organization's list and at least one (1) appointment being chosen from each Congressional district. After the initial appointments, appointments to vacancies shall be made in the same manner as prescribed in subsection (3) of this section, except that there is no requirement that the vacancy be filled from the same organization's list as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="5">The terms of office of the initial appointments of the private sector members to the board shall be staggered so that one-fourth (1/4) of all appointments shall expire one (1), two (2), three (3), and four (4) years, respectively, from the date of their appointment. All succeeding appointments shall be for four (4) years. </section><section prefix="6">In making appointments to the board, the Governor shall assure broad geographical representation, as well as representation from the major sectors of Kentucky's economy by leading executives with a knowledge of the problems of large and small businesses, local economic development, and the transfer of research and development from the laboratory to the marketplace. In filling vacancies, the Governor shall attempt to assure the continuing representation on the board of broad constituencies of Kentucky's economy, including manufacturing and agriculture. </section><section prefix="7">Vacancies on the board which may occur from time to time shall be filled as follows: <section prefix="a">Any vacancy which occurs shall be filled for the unexpired term in accordance with the procedures established for the original appointment. </section><section prefix="b">If any private sector member misses more than two (2) consecutive meetings of the board, then that position shall be declared vacant and filled in accordance with this section. </section></section><section prefix="8">The board shall meet quarterly and at other times upon call of the chairman or a majority of the board. </section><section prefix="9">A quorum shall be a majority of the voting membership of the board. </section><section prefix="10">A quorum shall be required to organize and conduct the business of the board, except that an affirmative vote of seven (7) or more members of the entire board shall be required to fire the cabinet's secretary, and to adopt or amend the strategic plan. </section><section prefix="11">Private sector members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for all reasonable, necessary, and actual expenses. </section><section prefix="12">All existing duties, responsibilities, functions, personnel, programs, funds, obligations, records, and real and personal property of the Cabinet for Economic Development, as of July 14, 1992, shall be under the authority and control of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 192, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch.16,sec. 38, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 32, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2598</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>