<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.550</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Cervid CWD Surveillance and Identification Program. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a ban on the importation of live members of the animal family Cervidae into the Commonwealth that have not been subject to a program of surveillance and identification for cervid chronic wasting disease (CWD) that meets or exceeds: <section prefix="a">The requirements of the Kentucky Cervid CWD Surveillance and Identification (CCWDSI) Program set forth in this section and in administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture; and </section><section prefix="b">Any other health requirements as regulated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture or the United States Department of Agriculture for cervids. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Department of Agriculture shall be responsible for authorizing importation of the members of the animal family Cervidae into the Commonwealth that have been subject to a program of surveillance and identification for cervid CWD that meets or exceeds: <section prefix="a">The requirements of the Kentucky CCWDSI Program set forth in this section and in administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture; and </section><section prefix="b">Any other health requirements as regulated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture or the United States Department of Agriculture for cervids. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the animal family Cervidae shall not be eligible for importation into the Commonwealth unless the program of surveillance and identification for cervid CWD to which they have been subject: <section prefix="a">Has been certified by the exporting state's state veterinarian or agency having jurisdiction over that state's surveillance and identification program; </section><section prefix="b">Has been approved by the Kentucky state veterinarian as meeting or exceeding the standards imposed under the Kentucky CCWDSI Program; and </section><section prefix="c">Meets, at a minimum, the following requirements: <section prefix="1">The program shall require cervid owners to obtain identification and laboratory diagnosis from brain tissue as directed by the exporting state's state veterinarian or agency with jurisdiction for cervids twelve (12) months of age or greater that: <section prefix="a">Display clinical signs of CWD; </section><section prefix="b">Die, including deaths by slaughter or by hunting, including hunting on hunting preserves; or </section><section prefix="c">Are ill or injured, regardless of whether the illness or injury results in death; and </section></section><section prefix="2">The program shall require cervid owners to obtain cervids from herds that have been monitored for at least five (5) years and that have complied with the standards contained in the Kentucky CCWDSI Program. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Cervids originating from a state that has reported a confirmed case of CWD in wild or captive cervids shall not be imported into Kentucky until the United States Department of Agriculture approves: <section prefix="a">Regulations that allow importation from states with confirmed cases of CWD; and </section><section prefix="b">A live test for CWD that is available for live testing of cervids. </section></section><section prefix="5">Importation of members of the animal family Cervidae into the Commonwealth shall be consistent with this section and with administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Department of Agriculture in cooperation with the Kentucky Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12405</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>