<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.48-240</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited activities. </catch_line><order_by>48-240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall make any deceptive statement or omit material facts in connection with solicitation for membership in a liability self-insurance group. </section><section prefix="2">Liability self-insurance groups shall not engage in unfair claims settlement practices and shall: <section prefix="a">Respond to claimant inquiries within fifteen (15) working days. </section><section prefix="b">Respond to Department of Insurance inquiries concerning claims within fifteen (15) working days. </section><section prefix="c">Complete the investigation of losses within thirty (30) days from the date the group has notice of a loss. An additional thirty (30) day period may be taken if reasonably necessary and upon written notice to the claimant. </section><section prefix="d">Not continue negotiations for settlement of a claim directly with a claimant who is neither an attorney nor represented by an attorney until the claimant's rights may be affected by a statute of limitations, a policy, or contract time limit without giving the claimant written notice at least sixty (60) days before the date on which the time limit shall expire and affect the claimant's rights. </section><section prefix="e">Not commit any other unfair or deceptive act or practice, as described in Subtitle 12 of this chapter, relating to claim settlement. </section></section><section prefix="3">Liability self-insurance groups shall not commit unfair or deceptive acts or practices, as described in Subtitle 12 of this chapter, under its certificate of filing from the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1603, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 48, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 48, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>