<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.040</section_number><catch_line>Qualification of board members. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "relative" means father, mother, brother, sister, husband, wife, son, daughter, aunt, uncle, son-in-law, and daughter-in-law. </section><section prefix="2">A member of the Kentucky Board of Education shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least thirty (30) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Have at least an associate degree or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="c">Have been a resident of Kentucky for at least three (3) years preceding the member's appointment; </section><section prefix="d">Not hold a state office requiring the constitutional oath; </section><section prefix="e">Not be a member of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="f">Not hold or discharge the duties of any civil or political office, deputyship, or agency under the city or county of his or her residence; </section><section prefix="g">Not be directly or indirectly interested in the sale to the Kentucky Board of Education or the Department of Education of books, stationery, or any other property, materials, supplies, equipment, or services for which board or department funds are expended; </section><section prefix="h">Not have a relative as defined in subsection (1) of this section who is employed by the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="i">Not have been removed from the board for cause; and </section><section prefix="j">Not be engaged as an elementary or secondary education professional educator. </section></section><section prefix="3">Appointments to the board shall be made without reference to occupation, political affiliation, or similar considerations. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 48, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 38, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 87, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. III, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4377-5. </history><metadata><effective> March 10, 2003 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails pursuant to KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3105</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>