<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.590</section_number><catch_line>Types of guardians and conservators to be appointed -- Order of appointment -- Filing of judgment and order -- Legal disabilities. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the respondent is found partially disabled in managing his personal affairs, but not partially disabled or disabled in managing his financial resources, a limited guardian shall be appointed. </section><section prefix="2">If the respondent is found partially disabled in managing his financial resources, but not partially disabled or disabled in managing his personal affairs, a limited conservator shall be appointed. </section><section prefix="3">If the respondent is found partially disabled in managing both his personal affairs and financial resources, a limited guardian shall be appointed, unless the court considers it in the best interest of the ward to appoint both a limited guardian and a limited conservator. </section><section prefix="4">If the respondent is found disabled in managing his financial resources, but not partially disabled or disabled in managing his personal affairs, a conservator shall be appointed. </section><section prefix="5">If the respondent is found disabled in managing both his personal affairs and financial resources, a guardian shall be appointed, unless the court considers it in the best interest of the ward to appoint both a limited guardian and a conservator. </section><section prefix="6">The order of appointment of a limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator shall specify: <section prefix="a">The type of guardianship or conservatorship to which the ward is subject; </section><section prefix="b">The name and address of the limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator; </section><section prefix="c">The name and address of the standby guardian or conservator, if a standby guardian or conservator is designated; </section><section prefix="d">The specific legal disabilities to which the respondent is subject, if the respondent has been determined to be partially disabled; </section><section prefix="e">The corresponding powers and duties of the limited guardian or limited conservator, if the respondent has been determined to be partially disabled; and </section><section prefix="f">The duration of the term of guardianship or conservatorship. </section></section><section prefix="7">A limited guardian or limited conservator shall not be appointed for a term greater than five (5) years and may be appointed for a lesser period. A guardian or conservator may be appointed for a period of unlimited duration. </section><section prefix="8">The judgment of partial disability or disability and the order of appointment shall be filed in the District Court. The judgment shall be indexed by the county clerk in the book in which notices of actions and encumbrances are indexed. Unless such judgment is filed and indexed, it shall not constitute notice to any subsequent bona fide purchaser for value, mortgagee, or encumbrancer. </section><section prefix="9">If the respondent is determined to be disabled or partially disabled but no limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator is appointed at the hearing, the determination shall have no legal effect. </section><section prefix="10">The rights of which a ward is legally deprived upon a determination of disability in managing his personal affairs and financial resources include but are not limited to the right to dispose of property, execute instruments, enter into contractual relationships, determine his living arrangements, consent to medical procedures, and obtain a motor vehicle operator's license. A ward shall only be deprived of the right to vote if the court separately and specifically makes a finding on the record as established in KRS 387.580(3)(c). </section><section prefix="11">A partially disabled or disabled person for whom a limited guardian, limited conservator, or conservator has been appointed retains all legal and civil rights except those which have by court order been designated as legal disabilities or which have been specifically granted to the limited guardian, limited conservator, or conservator. A person who is partially disabled may be subject to some but not all of the disabilities specified in subsection (10) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 10, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36048</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>