<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.180</section_number><catch_line>Supervision of pupils' conduct. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each teacher and administrator in the public schools shall in accordance with the rules, regulations, and bylaws of the board of education made and adopted pursuant to KRS 160.290 for the conduct of pupils, hold pupils to a strict account for their conduct on school premises, on the way to and from school, and on school sponsored trips and activities. </section><section prefix="2">The various boards of education of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and the principals of the public schools, may use teacher's aides in supervisory capacities, such as playground supervision, hallway supervision, lunchroom and cafeteria supervision, and other like duties, including, but not limited to, recreational activities and athletic events, relating to the supervision and control of the conduct of the pupils; and while so engaged, such teacher's aides shall have the same authority and responsibility as is granted to and imposed by law upon teachers in the performance of the same or similar duties. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 481, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4503-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3889</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>