<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.34-110</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of subchapter -- Expenditure and employment retention requirements for recovery of costs and tax incentives -- Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>34-110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of this subchapter is to provide a means for the Commonwealth to promote job retention by providing incentives for existing businesses to reinvest in existing manufacturing operations in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">To qualify for the incentives provided in this subchapter, an approved company shall: <section prefix="1">Incur eligible equipment and related costs of at least two million five hundred thousand dollars ($2,500,000); </section><section prefix="2">Agree to maintain a full-time employment base of at least eighty-five percent (85%) at the facility on the date of preliminary approval; and </section><section prefix="3">Not have been awarded incentives under Subchapter 26 of this chapter for a period of at least five (5) years prior to applying for incentives under this subchapter. </section></section><section prefix="b">An approved company meeting the expenditure and employment retention requirements established by this subsection shall be eligible to recover up to fifty percent (50%) of the amount expended for eligible equipment and related costs, and up to one hundred percent (100%) of job skills upgrade training costs. The actual amount that an approved company may recover shall be negotiated with the authority, and may be less than the maximum amount for which the approved company is eligible. </section></section><section prefix="3">An approved company shall be eligible for tax incentives of up to one hundred percent (100%) of the Kentucky income tax imposed under KRS 141.020 or 141.040 and the limited liability entity tax imposed under KRS 141.0401 on the income, Kentucky gross profits, or Kentucky gross receipts of the approved company generated by or arising from the eligible project, as set forth in KRS 154.34-120. </section><section prefix="4">The General Assembly finds and declares that: <section prefix="a">The general welfare and material well-being of the citizens of the Commonwealth depend in large measure upon the reinvestment and development of existing industry in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">It is in the best interest of the Commonwealth to induce reinvestment in existing manufacturing facilities within the Commonwealth in order to advance the public purposes of relieving unemployment by preserving jobs that may be lost if not for the incentives to be offered by the authority to approved companies, and by preserving and creating sources of tax revenues for the support of public services provided by the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="c">The authority prescribed by this subchapter and the purposes to be accomplished under this subchapter are proper governmental and public purposes for which public moneys may be expended. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2009).  2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, provides that, notwithstanding the amendments contained in Sections 1 to 6 of that Act (which includes this statute), "all reinvestment projects preliminarily approved on or after the effective date of this Act shall not be eligible for final approval until July 1, 2010"; and 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 8, provides that, notwithstanding the amendments in Sections 1 to 6 of that Act or the repeals in Section 114 of that Act, "all reinvestment projects preliminarily or finally approved prior to the effective date of this Act shall be governed by Subchapter 34 of KRS Chapter 154 as it existed prior to the effective date of this Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2902</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>