<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.225</section_number><catch_line>Determination of order of names on ballot. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of determining the order in which the names of candidates or slates of candidates to be voted for by the electors of the entire state shall be certified and printed on the ballots with the designation of the respective offices, the Secretary of State shall prepare lists of the counties of each congressional district of the state. He shall arrange the surnames of all candidates or slates of candidates for each office in alphabetical order for the First Congressional District, and the names shall be certified in this order to the county clerks of all the counties comprising that district. For each succeeding congressional district, taken in numerical order, the name appearing first for each office in the last preceding district shall be placed last, and the name appearing second in the last preceding district shall be placed first, and each other name shall be moved up one (1) place. The lists shall be certified accordingly. </section><section prefix="2">For all other offices for which nomination papers and petitions are filed with the Secretary of State, the order of names of candidates for each office shall be determined by lot at a public drawing to be held in the office of the Secretary of State at 2 p.m., standard time, on the Thursday following the last Tuesday in January preceding the primary or the Thursday following the second Tuesday in August preceding the general election. </section><section prefix="3">For all offices for which nomination papers and petitions are filed in the office of the county clerk, the order in which the names of candidates for each office are to be printed on the ballot shall be determined by lot at a public drawing in the office of the county clerk at 2 p.m., standard time, on the Thursday following the last Tuesday in January before the primary or the Thursday following the second Tuesday in August preceding the general election. </section><section prefix="4">If the number of certified candidates or slates of candidates cannot be placed on a ballot which can be accommodated on voting machines currently in use in the county, the county clerk shall notify the State Board of Elections, as provided in KRS 118.215. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 40, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 296, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 43, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 10, effective March 19, 1977. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 112, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>