<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.275</section_number><catch_line>Arson investigators. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner, Department of Kentucky State Police, may designate officers and employees of the Department of Kentucky State Police to investigate and enforce the provisions against arson and arson related offenses occurring within the state and such officers when duly authorized by the commissioner, Department of Kentucky State Police, shall have the general powers of a peace officer for the prevention of other offenses against the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">Each arson investigator so appointed shall, before entering upon the discharge of his or her various duties, take an oath before a person authorized to administer oaths to faithfully discharge his or her duties, and the oath shall be subscribed by the person taking it and filed in the records of the department. </section><section prefix="3">Each of said persons shall give such bond as the commissioner, Department of Kentucky State Police, may designate and with such surety as required by the commissioner, Department of Kentucky State Police, conditioned upon faithful performance of his or her duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 260, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 90, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(8). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>.  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10641</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>