<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.050</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of chief probation officers and volunteer probation officers -- Training.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In counties containing a city of the first class or a city with a population equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) as of the most recent federal decennial census, the county judge/executive may appoint a chief probation officer of the juvenile court and such number of assistant probation officers, professional and clerical personnel as may be authorized by the fiscal court. Such officers shall receive reasonable salaries to be fixed by the fiscal court, and shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. The salaries and expenses shall be paid out of the county treasury. The officers shall serve at the pleasure of the county judge/executive but shall be subject to the direction and control of the judges of the District Court in the performance of their duties. The officers shall be peace officers who shall possess all the powers of peace officers in carrying out the purposes of KRS Chapters 600 to 645. A probation officer may take into custody any child that he has reasonable grounds to believe is in violation of conditions of his probation. </section><section prefix="2">In counties containing an urban-county government, the mayor shall appoint a chief probation officer of the juvenile session of the District Court and such number of assistant probation officers, professional and clerical personnel as are reasonably necessary for the operation of the juvenile session of the District Court. Such officers shall receive reasonable salaries to be fixed by the urban-county council, and shall be allowed their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. The salaries and expenses shall be paid out of the urban-county treasury. The officers shall serve at the pleasure of the mayor but shall be subject to the direction and control of the judges of the District Court in the performance of their duties. The officers shall be peace officers who shall possess all the powers of peace officers in carrying out the purposes of KRS Chapters 600 to 645. A probation officer may take into custody any child that he has reasonable grounds to believe is in violation of conditions of his probation. </section><section prefix="3">In any county, the Chief District Judge may appoint or designate one (1) or more discreet persons of good moral character to serve as volunteer probation officers of the juvenile session. Such volunteer probation officers shall serve during the pleasure of the judge and without compensation, except that the fiscal court or the urban-county council, as appropriate, may authorize the payment of compensation and reasonable expenses out of the county or urban-county treasury of any such officers. </section><section prefix="4">Officers appointed pursuant to this section shall be trained in the administration of a validated risk and needs assessment. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 310, effective January 1, 2015; and ch. 132, sec. 29, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 4, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 92 and 132, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43895</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>