<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.340</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by special agent's or solicitor's license -- Issuance to nonresident -- Form.   </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A special agent's or solicitor's license may be issued to a duly authorized representative, employee, or agent of, or solicitor for a distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler licensed in Kentucky or by the state of his or her residence and by the United States if a resident therein. The license shall authorize the licensee to offer for sale and to solicit orders for the sale of any alcoholic beverage sold by a distiller, rectifier, winery, or wholesaler who is licensed in Kentucky or who is a nonresident. The license shall set forth the name, address, and, unless the vendor is a nonresident, the license numbers of the vendors the agent or solicitor represents, as well as the name, address, and license number of the agent or solicitor. An agent or solicitor shall not represent any vendor or licensee whose name does not appear upon the license or the application for the license. </section><section prefix="2">A special agent's or solicitor's license may be issued to a nonresident of this state. The license shall authorize the nonresident to represent a manufacturer, winery, or wholesaler who is licensed by another state and by the federal government, if the nonresident has been issued a license by another state conferring privileges similar to a special agent's or solicitor's license authorized by subsection (1) of this section. If the state of residence of the applicant does not issue a similar license, the application filed with the department shall not be accepted without the approval of the alcoholic beverage control agency of the state of the applicant's residence. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 73, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-127. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42508</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>