<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.220</section_number><catch_line>Firefighters Foundation Program fund -- Funds accruing under KRS 42.190 and 136.392 -- Lapsing of certain funds -- Moneys appropriated. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the "Firefighters Foundation Program Fund" consisting of appropriations from the general fund of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and insurance premium surcharge proceeds and earnings on the investments of those proceeds which accrue to this fund pursuant to KRS 42.190 and 136.392. The fund may also receive any other funds, gifts or grants made available to the state for distribution to local governments and volunteer fire departments in accordance with the provisions of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300 and KRS 95A.262. </section><section prefix="2">All moneys remaining in this fund on July 1, 1982, and deposited thereafter, including earnings from their investment, shall be deemed a trust and agency account. Beginning with the fiscal year 1994-95, through June 30, 1999, moneys remaining in the account at the end of the fiscal year in excess of three million dollars ($3,000,000) shall lapse, but moneys in the revolving loan fund established in KRS 95A.262 shall not lapse. On and after July 1, 1999, moneys in this account shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the fund are hereby appropriated by the General Assembly for the purposes provided in KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 510, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 5, effective April 1, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>