<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.450</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>To effectuate the purposes of KRS 146.410 to 146.530, the cabinet has the powers and duties enumerated as follows: <section prefix="1">To provide administrative services, office facilities, and such other assistance as may be agreed upon by the cabinet and the commission; </section><section prefix="2">To enforce rules established by the commission pertaining to public use of and activities on nature preserves, and on any real property held by the commission; </section><section prefix="3">To acquire, subject to the prior written approval of the commission, by gift, devise, purchase, grant, agreement, dedication, and transfer the fee simple title, or any lesser right or interest in real property, including but not limited to, leasehold estates, easements, and licenses granting to the commission specified rights of use or licenses denying to the grantor specified rights of use, or both, and to dedicate the same to the system of nature preserves as provided in KRS 146.410 to 146.530; </section><section prefix="4">To dedicate in the manner provided for in KRS 146.410 to 146.530 real property held by it as nature preserves; </section><section prefix="5">To transfer from or to the commission real property or any interests or rights therein. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 9. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1519</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>