<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.150</section_number><catch_line>Expenditure of funds for liability or property insurance. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county or city or urban-county government and any board, commission, agency or authority of a county, city or urban-county government may expend funds necessary to insure any of its employees, officials and property against any liability or property damage arising out of an act or omission committed in the scope and course of performing legal duties. </section><section prefix="2">A county fee officer and his deputies and assistants may be insured pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, or the officer may expend excess fees to insure himself and his deputies and assistants against any liability arising out of an act or omission committed in the scope and course of performing legal duties. </section><section prefix="3">Any parties eligible to expend funds for insurance pursuant to this section may associate, pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300, for the purpose of insuring themselves against any liability or property damage. </section><section prefix="4">An association of governmental units formed for the purpose of providing insurance to the participating members may act on behalf of and with the approval of the participating governmental units to borrow money and issue revenue bonds to fund the costs of providing the insurance. Revenue bonds issued pursuant to the authority granted in this subsection shall be issued in accordance with KRS 65.270. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 309, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3, effective May 12, 1979.</history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988</effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by two 1988 acts which were identical and which have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>