<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.930</section_number><catch_line>Right-of-way to emergency vehicles -- Blocking or following emergency vehicles -- Driving over unprotected hoses of fire department. </catch_line><order_by>930</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the approach of an emergency vehicle equipped with, and operating, one (1) or more flashing, rotating, or oscillating red or blue lights, visible under normal conditions from a distance of five hundred (500) feet to the front of such vehicle; or the driver is given audible signal by siren, exhaust whistle, or bell, the driver of every other vehicle shall yield the right-of-way, immediately drive to a position parallel to, and as close as possible to, the edge or curb of the highway clear of any intersection, and stop and remain in such position until the emergency vehicle has passed, except when otherwise directed by a police officer or firefighter. </section><section prefix="2">Upon the approach of any emergency vehicle, operated in conformity with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, the operator of every vehicle shall immediately stop clear of any intersection and shall keep such position until the emergency vehicle has passed, unless directed otherwise by a police officer or firefighter. </section><section prefix="3">No operator of any vehicle, unless he is on official business, shall follow any emergency vehicle being operated in conformity with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section closer than five hundred (500) feet, nor shall he drive into, or park the vehicle into, or park the vehicle within, the block where the vehicle has stopped in answer to an emergency call or alarm unless he is directed otherwise by a police officer or firefighter. </section><section prefix="4">No vehicle, train, or other equipment shall be driven over any unprotected hose of a fire department when the hose is laid down on any street, private driveway, or track for use at any fire or fire alarm unless the fire department official in command consents that the hose be driven over. </section><section prefix="5">Upon approaching a stationary emergency vehicle or public safety vehicle, when the emergency vehicle or public safety vehicle is giving a signal by displaying alternately flashing yellow, red, red and white, red and blue, or blue lights, a person who drives an approaching vehicle shall, while proceeding with due caution: <section prefix="a">Yield the right-of-way by moving to a lane not adjacent to that of the authorized emergency vehicle, if: <section prefix="1">The person is driving on a highway having at least four (4) lanes with not fewer than two (2) lanes proceeding in the same direction as the approaching vehicle; and </section><section prefix="2">If it is possible to make the lane change with due regard to safety and traffic conditions; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Reduce the speed of the vehicle, maintaining a safe speed to road conditions, if changing lanes would be impossible or unsafe. </section></section><section prefix="6">This section does not operate to relieve the person who drives an emergency vehicle from the duty to operate the vehicle with due regard for the safety of all persons using the highway. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6470</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>