<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.271</section_number><catch_line>State hospital patients to be discharged to registered boarding homes only -- Quarterly follow-up visits by cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>271</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No patient in an institution for the mentally ill or the intellectually disabled operated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall be discharged to a boarding home as defined in KRS 216B.300 unless the boarding home is registered pursuant to KRS 216B.305. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall conduct a quarterly follow-up visit, using cabinet personnel or through contract with the Regional Community Mental Health Centers, of all patients of state facilities for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability that are discharged to boarding homes. Any resident found to have needs that cannot be met by the boarding home shall be referred to the Department for Community Based Services for appropriate placement. Any boarding home suspected of operating as an unlicensed personal care facility or housing residents with needs that cannot be met by the boarding home shall be reported to the Division of Community Health Services for investigation. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 74, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 321, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 42, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 266, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40802</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>