<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>In this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Person" includes one (1) or more individuals, labor organizations, joint apprenticeship committees, partnerships, associations, corporations, legal representatives, mutual companies, joint-stock companies, trusts, unincorporated organizations, trustees, trustees in bankruptcy, fiduciaries, receivers, or other legal or commercial entity; the state, any of its political or civil subdivisions or agencies. </section><section prefix="2">"Commission" means the Kentucky Commission on Human Rights. </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means a member of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">"Disability" means, with respect to an individual: <section prefix="a">A physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one (1) or more of the major life activities of the individual; </section><section prefix="b">A record of such an impairment; or </section><section prefix="c">Being regarded as having such an impairment. </section></section> Persons with current or past controlled substances abuse or alcohol abuse problems and persons excluded from coverage by the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (P.L. 101-336) shall be excluded from this section. <section prefix="5">"Discrimination" means any direct or indirect act or practice of exclusion, distinction, restriction, segregation, limitation, refusal, denial, or any other act or practice of differentiation or preference in the treatment of a person or persons, or the aiding, abetting, inciting, coercing, or compelling thereof made unlawful under this chapter. </section><section prefix="6">"Real property" includes buildings, structures, real estate, lands, tenements, leaseholds, cooperatives, condominiums, and hereditaments, corporeal and incorporeal, or any interest in the above. </section><section prefix="7">"Housing accommodations" includes improved and unimproved property and means any building, structure, lot or portion thereof, which is used or occupied, or is intended, arranged, or designed to be used or occupied as the home or residence of one (1) or more families, and any vacant land which is offered for sale or lease for the construction or location thereon of any such building or structure. </section><section prefix="8">"Real estate operator" means any individual or combination of individuals, labor organizations, joint apprenticeship committees, partnerships, associations, corporations, legal representatives, mutual companies, joint-stock companies, trusts, unincorporated organizations, trustees in bankruptcy, receivers, or other legal or commercial entity, the county, or any of its agencies, that is engaged in the business of selling, purchasing, exchanging, renting, or leasing real estate, or the improvements thereon, including options, or that derives income, in whole or in part, from the sale, purchase, exchange, rental, or lease of real estate; or an individual employed by or acting on behalf of any of these. </section><section prefix="9">"Real estate broker" or "real estate salesman" means any individual, whether licensed or not, who, on behalf of others, for a fee, commission, salary, or other valuable consideration, or who with the intention or expectation of receiving or collecting the same, lists, sells, purchases, exchanges, rents, or leases real estate, or the improvements thereon, including options, or who negotiates or attempts to negotiate on behalf of others such an activity; or who advertises or holds himself out as engaged in these activities; or who negotiates or attempts to negotiate on behalf of others a loan secured by mortgage or other encumbrance upon a transfer of real estate, or who is engaged in the business of charging an advance fee or contracting for collection of a fee in connection with a contract whereby he undertakes to promote the sale, purchase, exchange, rental, or lease of real estate through its listing in a publication issued primarily for this purpose; or any person employed by or acting on behalf of any of these. </section><section prefix="10">"Financial institution" means bank, banking organization, mortgage company, insurance company, or other lender to whom application is made for financial assistance for the purchase, lease, acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, repair, maintenance, or improvement of real property, or an individual employed by or acting on behalf of any of these. </section><section prefix="11">"Licensing agency" means any public or private organization which has as one (1) of its duties the issuing of licenses or the setting of standards which an individual must hold or must meet as a condition to practicing a particular trade or profession or to obtaining certain employment within the state or as a condition to competing effectively with an individual who does hold a license or meet the standards. </section><section prefix="12">"Credit transaction" shall mean any open or closed end credit transaction whether in the nature of a loan, retail installment transaction, credit card issue or charge, or otherwise, and whether for personal or for business purposes, in which a service, finance, or interest charge is imposed, or which provides for repayment in scheduled payments, when such credit is extended in the course of the regular course of any trade or commerce, including but not limited to transactions by banks, savings and loan associations, or other financial lending institutions of whatever nature, stock brokers, or by a merchant or mercantile establishment which as part of its ordinary business permits or provides that payment for purchases of property or services therefrom may be deferred. </section><section prefix="13">"To rent" means to lease, to sublease, to let, or otherwise to grant for a consideration the right to occupy premises not owned by the occupant. </section><section prefix="14">"Family" includes a single individual. </section><section prefix="15"><section prefix="a">"Familial status" means one (1) or more individuals who have not attained the age of eighteen (18) years and are domiciled with: <section prefix="1">A parent or another person having legal custody of the individual or individuals; or </section><section prefix="2">The designee of a parent or other person having custody, with the written permission of the parent or other person. </section></section><section prefix="b">The protection afforded against discrimination on the basis of familial status shall apply to any person who is pregnant or is in the process of securing legal custody of any individual who has not attained the age of eighteen (18) years. </section></section><section prefix="16">"Discriminatory housing practice" means an act that is unlawful under KRS 344.360, 344.367, 344.370, 344.380, or 344.680. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 1. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 2, sec. 201. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32600</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>