<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280">PRIVATE TOLL BRIDGES AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>280.250</section_number><catch_line>Rates of toll. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At the time of granting any ferry privilege, the county judge/executive shall fix the rates of toll to be charged at the ferry, which shall be in the following proportions: For every heavy four (4) wheeled wagon, carriage or coach and driver, the same as for six (6) horses; for every light or open four (4) wheeled carriage or light wagon and driver, the same as for four (4) horses; for every two (2) wheeled carriage or cart and driver, the same as for two (2) horses; for every hogshead of tobacco, not in a wagon or cart, the same as for one (1) horse; for every head of neat-cattle, the same as for one (1) horse; for every sheep, goat, hog or lamb, one-fifth (1/5) as much as for a horse. </section><section prefix="2">The rates may be changed by order from time to time, but before an increase may be made reasonable notice of the application must be given to the county attorney, or posted for at least one (1) month on the courthouse door, and before a reduction may be made the county attorney must have written notice served on the owner of the ferry. </section><section prefix="3">No owner or keeper of a ferry, or agent or servant thereof, shall demand or take from any person a greater toll than that allowed by the order of the county judge/executive fixing the rates of toll at his ferry. A violation of this provision by a keeper, agent or servant shall be deemed a violation by the owner. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 461, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 264, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1813, 1814. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14262</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>