<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.480</section_number><catch_line>Duties of probation and parole officers. </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text>Probation and parole officers shall: <section prefix="1">Investigate all cases referred to them for investigation by the commissioner or by any court in which they are authorized to serve; </section><section prefix="2">Furnish to each person released under their supervision a written statement of the conditions of probation or parole and instruct him regarding the conditions; </section><section prefix="3">Keep informed concerning the conduct and conditions of each person under their supervision and use all suitable methods to aid and encourage them to bring about improvement in their conduct and condition; </section><section prefix="4">Keep detailed records of their work; </section><section prefix="5">Collect and disburse all moneys in accordance with the orders of the commissioner, board, or court; </section><section prefix="6">Keep accurate and complete accounts of all moneys received and disbursed in accordance with orders of the commissioner, board, or court, and give receipts therefor; </section><section prefix="7">Make the reports in writing the court or commissioner may require; </section><section prefix="8">Coordinate their work with that of other social agencies and file identifying information regarding their cases with any social service index or exchange operation in the area to which they are assigned. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 112, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(16). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 24, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19196</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>