<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7063</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for local participation agreements -- Pledge of incremental revenues superior to other pledges of revenues. </catch_line><order_by>7063</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local participation agreement shall be executed among the agencies and taxing districts involved in administering or providing financing or pledging incremental revenues to support the implementation of a development plan in a development area. The local participation agreement shall be adopted by a city or county by ordinance and by any other taxing authority or agency by resolution, and shall include but not be limited to the following provisions: <section prefix="a">Identification of the parties to the local participation agreement and the duties and responsibilities of each entity under the agreement; </section><section prefix="b">Specific identification of the incremental revenues released or pledged, or wage assessments pledged by type of tax by each taxing district; </section><section prefix="c">The anticipated benefit to be received by each taxing district for the release or pledge, including: <section prefix="1">A detailed summary of old revenues collected and projected new revenues for each taxing district on an annual basis for the term of the local participation agreement; and </section><section prefix="2">The maximum amount of incremental revenue to be paid by each taxing district and the maximum number of years the payment will be effective; </section></section><section prefix="d">A detailed description of the development area, including a legal description of the parcels included in the development area; </section><section prefix="e">A description of each proposed project that is the subject of a local participation agreement, including an estimate of the costs of construction, acquisition, and development; </section><section prefix="f">A requirement that pledged incremental revenues will be deposited in a special fund established pursuant to KRS 65.7061, including the timing and procedure for depositing incremental revenues and other pledged amounts into the special fund; </section><section prefix="g">Terms of default and remedies, provided that no remedy shall permit the withholding by any party to the local participation agreement of any incremental revenues pledged to the special fund if increment bonds are outstanding that are secured by a pledge of those incremental revenues; </section><section prefix="h">The commencement date, activation date, and termination date; and </section><section prefix="i">Any other provisions not inconsistent with KRS 65.7041 to 65.7083 deemed necessary or appropriate by the parties to the agreement. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any pledge of incremental revenues in a local participation agreement shall be superior to any other pledge of revenues for any other purpose and shall, from the activation date to the termination date set forth in the local participation agreement, supersede any statute, ordinance, or resolution regarding the application or use of incremental revenues. An ordinance in conflict with a local participation agreement shall not be adopted while any increment bonds secured by that pledge remain outstanding. Ordinances or resolutions pledging incremental revenues on a subordinate basis to any existing pledges may be adopted. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 12, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23481</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>