<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.210</section_number><catch_line>Conduct in mine -- Intoxication, alcoholic beverage or controlled substance prohibited -- Notification to director of violations of substance- or alcohol-abuse policies.   </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall knowingly injure any shaft, lamp, instrument, air course, or brattice; obstruct or throw open airways; disturb any part of the machinery or appliances; open a door used for directing ventilation without closing it afterwards; enter any part of a mine against caution; disobey any order given in carrying out any of the provisions of KRS Chapter 351 or 352; or do any act endangering the life or health of any person employed in the mine or endangering the security of the mine. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall enter or be on any licensed facility while intoxicated or under the influence of alcohol or a controlled substance or be in possession of any alcoholic beverage or controlled substance at any licensed facility; provided, however, this shall not apply to private vehicles driven to and from the mine. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee shall notify the director, by the close of the next business day, of any certified persons who have been discharged for violation of the company's substance-abuse or alcohol-abuse policies or who tested positive and failed to complete an employee assistance program. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 33, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 23. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-37. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44550</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>