<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.080</section_number><catch_line>Retail sales to certain persons prohibited -- Affirmative defense in prosecution for selling to a minor. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>A retail licensee, or the licensee's agent, servant, or employee, shall not sell, give away, or deliver any alcoholic beverages, or procure or permit any alcoholic beverages to be sold, given away, possessed by, or delivered to: <section prefix="1">A minor, except that in any prosecution for selling alcoholic beverages to a minor it shall be an affirmative defense that the sale was induced by the use of false, fraudulent, or altered identification papers or other documents and that the appearance and character of the purchaser were such that his or her age could not have been ascertained by any other means and that the purchaser's appearance and character indicated strongly that he or she was of legal age to purchase alcoholic beverages. This evidence may be introduced either in mitigation of the charge or as a defense to the charge itself. </section><section prefix="2">A person actually or apparently under the influence of alcoholic beverages. </section><section prefix="3">Anyone known to the seller or server to be an habitual drunkard or any person known to the seller or server to have been convicted of drunkenness as many as three (3) times within the most recent twelve (12) month period. </section><section prefix="4">Anyone known to the seller or server to have been convicted of any misdemeanor attributable directly or indirectly to the use of alcoholic beverages or anyone known to the seller or server to have been convicted of a felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-181. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>