<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.60-130</section_number><catch_line>Petroleum storage tank environmental assurance fund -- Duties of Division of Waste Management.   </catch_line><order_by>60-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Energy and Environment Cabinet, Department for Environmental Protection, Division of Waste Management, shall: <section prefix="a">Establish by administrative regulation the policy, guidelines, and procedures to administer the financial responsibility and petroleum storage tank accounts of the petroleum storage tank environmental assurance fund. In adopting administrative regulations to carry out this section, the division may distinguish between types, classes, and ages of petroleum storage tanks. The division may establish a range of amounts to be paid from the fund, or may base payments on methods such as pay for performance, task order, or firm fixed pricing, which are designed to provide incentives for contractors to more tightly control corrective action costs, and shall establish criteria to be met by persons who contract to perform corrective action to be eligible for reimbursement from the fund. The criteria may include the certification of individuals, partnerships, and companies. Criteria shall be established to certify laboratories that contract to perform analytical testing related to the underground storage tank program. Owners and operators shall have all required analytical testing performed by a certified laboratory to be eligible for fund participation. Persons who contract with petroleum storage tank owners or operators shall not be paid more than the amount authorized by the division for reimbursement from the fund for the performance of corrective action. At a minimum, the division shall promulgate administrative regulations that will insure an unobligated balance in the fund adequate to meet financial assurance requirements and corrective action requirements of KRS 224.60-135(2) and (4). If the unobligated balance in the fund is not adequate to meet the requirements of this paragraph, the division shall obligate funds necessary to meet these requirements; </section><section prefix="b">Establish by administrative regulation the criteria to be met to be eligible to participate in the financial responsibility and petroleum storage tank accounts and to receive reimbursement from these accounts. The division may establish eligibility criteria for the petroleum storage tank account based upon the financial ability of the petroleum storage tank owner or operator. Owners or operators seeking coverage under the petroleum storage tank account shall file for eligibility and for financial assistance with the division. To ensure cost effectiveness, the division shall promulgate administrative regulations specifying the circumstances under which prior approval of corrective action costs shall be required for those costs to be eligible for reimbursement from the fund. In promulgating administrative regulations to carry out this section, the division may distinguish between types, classes, and ages of petroleum storage tanks and the degree of compliance of the facility with any administrative regulations of the cabinet promulgated pursuant to KRS 224.60-105 or applicable federal regulations; </section><section prefix="c">Establish a financial responsibility account within the fund which may be used by petroleum storage tank owners and operators to demonstrate financial responsibility as required by administrative regulations of the cabinet or the federal regulations applicable to petroleum storage tanks, consistent with the intent of the General Assembly as set forth in KRS 224.60-120(5). The account shall receive four-tenths of one cent ($0.004) from the one and four-tenths cent ($0.014) paid on each gallon of gasoline and special fuels received in this state pursuant to KRS 224.60-145. To be eligible to use this account to demonstrate compliance with financial responsibility requirements of the cabinet or federal regulations, or to receive reimbursement from this account for taking corrective action and for compensating third parties for bodily injury and property damage, the petroleum storage tank owner or operator shall meet the eligibility requirements established by administrative regulation promulgated by the division; </section><section prefix="d">Establish a small operator assistance account within the fund which may be used by the division to make or participate in the making of loans, to purchase or participate in the purchase of the loans, which purchase may be from eligible lenders, or to insure loans made by eligible lenders; </section><section prefix="e">Establish a petroleum storage tank account within the fund to be used to pay the costs of corrective action due to a release from a petroleum storage tank not eligible for reimbursement from the financial responsibility account. Reimbursements of corrective action projects performed under the petroleum storage tank account shall be carried out on or before July 15, 2019. Any corrective action costs incurred after this date shall not be eligible for reimbursement under the petroleum storage tank account. The account shall receive one cent ($0.01) from the one and four-tenths cent ($0.014) paid on each gallon of gasoline and special fuels received in this state pursuant to KRS 224.60-145. This account shall not be used to compensate third parties for bodily injury and property damage. Within three (3) months after July 15, 2004, the division shall develop a plan to address the payment of claims and completion of corrective action at facilities eligible for reimbursement from this account. The division shall establish a ranking system to be used for the distribution of amounts from this account for the purpose of corrective action. In promulgating administrative regulations to carry out this section, the division shall consider the financial ability of the petroleum storage tank owner or operator to perform corrective action and the extent of damage caused by a release into the environment from a petroleum storage tank; </section><section prefix="f">Hear complaints brought before the division regarding the payment of claims from the fund in accordance with KRS 224.10-410 to 224.10-470; </section><section prefix="g">Establish and maintain necessary offices within this state, appoint employees and agents as necessary, and prescribe their duties and compensation; </section><section prefix="h">Employ, in accordance with the procedures found in KRS 45A.690 to 45A.725 for awarding personal service contracts, a qualified actuary to perform actuarial studies, as directed by the division, for determining an appropriate reserve in the financial responsibility account and the petroleum storage tank account sufficient to satisfy the obligations in each account for all eligible facilities and to satisfy future liabilities and expenses necessary to operate each account. The division shall, by administrative regulation, set the entry level for participation in the fund; </section><section prefix="i">Authorize expenditures from the fund to carry out the purpose of KRS 224.60-105 to 224.60-160, including reasonable costs of administering the fund, the procurement of legal services, and the procurement of analytical testing services when necessary to confirm the accuracy of analytical testing results obtained by a petroleum storage tank owner or operator. The expenditures shall be paid from the appropriate account; </section><section prefix="j">Establish a small operators' tank removal account within the fund to reimburse the reasonable cost of tank system removal for small owners and operators. The account shall not be used when an owner or operator is removing the tank with the intention of replacing or upgrading the tank. In promulgating administrative regulations to carry out this paragraph, the division may distinguish among owners and operators based on income and types and classes of tanks. The division shall not place a limit on the number of tanks that an owner or operator has in order to be eligible to participate in the program and receive reimbursement under this paragraph; </section><section prefix="k">Establish by administrative regulation the policy, guidelines, and procedures to perform financial audits of any petroleum storage tank owner or operator receiving reimbursement from the fund or any entity contracting or subcontracting to provide corrective action services for facilities eligible for fund reimbursement. Financial audits shall be limited to those files, records, computer records, receipts, and other documents related to corrective action performed at a facility where the costs of corrective action have been reimbursed by the fund. Files, records, computer records, receipts, and other documents related to corrective action reimbursed by the fund shall be subject to a financial audit for a period of three (3) years after the date of final reimbursement from the fund. Results of the audits shall be protected from disclosure as allowed by KRS 61.878(1)(c). Financial auditing services may be contracted for or personnel may be employed as needed to implement the requirements of this paragraph; </section><section prefix="l">Be authorized to enter and inspect any facility intending to seek reimbursement for the cost of corrective action to determine the reasonableness and necessity of the cost of corrective action. The division may collect soil or water samples or require storage tank owners or operators to split samples with the division for analytical testing. Refusal to allow entry and inspection of a facility or refusal to allow the division to collect or split samples shall make the facility ineligible for fund participation; </section><section prefix="m">Have inspectors on site at all tank system removals. Failure to comply with this provision shall make the facility ineligible for fund participation. A petroleum storage tank owner or operator may request through certified mail that the division schedule an inspector to be present at an upcoming tank removal. If the request is made at least two (2) weeks before the time for the removal and an inspector fails to be present at the time scheduled, the tank removal may proceed without making the facility ineligible for fund participation unless the owner is notified by the division no later than ten (10) days prior to the proposed date that an inspector is not available on the proposed date, in which event a representative of the division shall contact the operator and schedule a new date. If no inspector is present at the rescheduled date, the removal may then proceed without penalty; and </section><section prefix="n">Establish that the deadline for submission of final reimbursement requests under the petroleum storage tank account is two (2) years after receipt of a no further action letter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The division may advise the cabinet on the promulgation of administrative regulations concerning petroleum storage tanks. </section><section prefix="3">The division may sue and be sued in its own name. </section><section prefix="4">The division may transfer funds from the petroleum storage tank account to the small operator tank removal account as needed to satisfy the obligations, future liabilities, and expenses necessary to operate that account. The division may transfer funds to the financial responsibility account as needed to maintain within that account sufficient funds to demonstrate financial responsibility and to ensure payment of claims as provided in subsection (1)(c) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 378, effective July 15, 2010; ch. 47, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 59, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 2, effective March 23, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 26, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 498, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 318, sec. 137, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 3, effective April 13, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 6, effective April 9, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.819. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42105</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>