<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.452</section_number><catch_line>Legend Drug Repository Program to be established -- Purpose -- Permitted donations -- Voluntary participation -- Handling fee -- Distribution. </catch_line><order_by>452</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish and maintain a legend drug repository program to support the donation of a legend drug or supplies needed to administer a legend drug for use by an individual who meets the eligibility criteria specified by an administrative regulation promulgated by the cabinet. The repository program shall not accept any controlled substance. </section><section prefix="2">Donations may be made on the premises of a health facility or pharmacy that elects to participate in the program and meets requirements specified by the cabinet by an administrative regulation promulgated by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">The health facility may charge a handling fee to an individual who received a legend drug or supplies under the program established under this section, except that the fee shall not exceed the amount established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">A health facility or pharmacy that receives a donated legend drug under this section may distribute the legend drug or supplies to another eligible health facility or pharmacy for use under the program created under this section. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section or KRS 194A.454 shall require a health facility, pharmacy, pharmacist, or practitioner to participate in the program established in this section. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>