<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.140</section_number><catch_line>Advancement to sheriffs for expenses. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any sheriff may be entitled to receive an advancement to defray necessary official expenses and to apply to the payment of the salaries of the sheriff or the sheriff's deputies and assistants. The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall, on the first day of each calendar month, determine the necessary amount that may be advanced to the sheriff, which amount shall not exceed one-twelfth (1/12) of the total fees collected by the sheriff for the preceding year and may be for a less amount, and in no event shall it exceed sixty thousand ($60,000) dollars per month. When approved by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, a warrant shall be drawn on the State Treasury in favor of the sheriff for such advancement. At the end of each calendar year the sum of such advancements shall be deducted from the part of the total of fees and commissions paid into the State Treasury by the sheriff, pursuant to Section 106 of the Constitution of Kentucky, that is available for use for the payment of the salaries of the sheriff, the sheriff's deputies and assistants, and necessary office expenses. </section><section prefix="2">If the office of sheriff becomes vacant, the sums advanced under this section shall be charged against that part of the fees and the commissions of the office of the sheriff that have been, or shall be, paid into the State Treasury during the calendar year in which the advancements were made, and that is available for payment of the salaries of the sheriff, the sheriff's deputies and assistants, and necessary expenses of the office. </section><section prefix="3">If the total of fees and commissions paid into the State Treasury by the sheriff for any calendar year is insufficient to match the amount of advancements made to the sheriff, his or her sureties and the sheriff in his or her official capacity shall be liable to the state for any excess of advancements over the total of fees and commissions paid into the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="4">If a sheriff makes a request for funds from the State Treasury to defray necessary official expenses, the sheriff shall not be required to submit a detailed statement of his or her personal assets and liabilities as a condition of the application process. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4587-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23202</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>