<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-139</section_number><catch_line>Family or dependents coverage to apply to newly born child from moment of birth and to include inherited metabolic diseases -- Requirement for notification and payment of premium -- Coverage for milk fortifiers to prevent enterocolitis.   </catch_line><order_by>17A-139</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A health benefit plan that provides coverage for a family or dependent shall provide coverage of a newly born child of the insured from the moment of birth. </section><section prefix="2">Coverage for a newly born child shall consist of coverage of injury or sickness, including the necessary care and treatment of medically diagnosed congenital defects and birth abnormalities. </section><section prefix="3">If payment of a specific premium or fee is required to provide coverage for a child, the policy or contract may require that notification of birth of a newly born child and payment of the required premium or fees must be furnished to the insurer within thirty-one (31) days after the date of birth in order to have the coverage continue beyond that thirty-one (31) day period. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">For the purposes of this subsection: <section prefix="1">"Milk fortifier" means a commercially prepared human milk fortifier made from concentrated one hundred percent (100%) human milk; and </section><section prefix="2">"One hundred percent (100%) human diet" means the supplementation of a mother's expressed breast milk or donor milk with a milk fortifier. </section></section><section prefix="b">A health benefit plan that provides prescription drug coverage shall provide that coverage for a one hundred percent (100%) human diet, if the one hundred percent (100%) human diet and supplemented milk fortifier products are prescribed for the prevention of necrotizing enterocolitis and associated comorbidities, and are administered under the direction of a physician. Coverage under this subsection may be subject to a cap of fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000) per infant, for each plan year, subject to annual inflation adjustments. </section></section><section prefix="5">The requirements of this section shall apply to all health benefit plans delivered or issued for delivery on or after June 25, 2013. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 457, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42421</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>