<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.1662</section_number><catch_line>Duties of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>1662</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain a roster of qualified arbitrators from which arbitrators provided pursuant to this section shall be selected; </section><section prefix="b">Refer or provide without charge, upon request of the party or parties to an agreement to arbitrate, a qualified arbitrator or a panel of qualified arbitrators; </section><section prefix="c">Assure that the needs of the parties requesting his or her services are served. To accomplish this purpose he or she may establish through administrative regulations procedures for the preparation of panels or the appointment of arbitrators, including consideration of such factors as background, experience, qualifications, availability, geographical location and the expressed preference of the parties; and </section><section prefix="d">Prescribe through administrative regulations a fee schedule and reporting requirements to which arbitrators listed on the roster shall subscribe. </section></section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall not have the power or authority to: <section prefix="a">Compel parties to arbitrate or agree to arbitration; </section><section prefix="b">Enforce an agreement to arbitrate; </section><section prefix="c">Compel parties to agree to a particular arbitrator; </section><section prefix="d">Influence, alter or set aside decisions of arbitrators provided pursuant to this section, KRS 336.1663 and 336.1664; or </section><section prefix="e">Compel, deny or modify payment of compensation to an arbitrator. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1721, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32014</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>