<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.660</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 217.650 to 217.710. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>As used in KRS 217.650 to 217.710 unless the context indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary for health and family services; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Person" includes any individual, partnership, corporation, firm, or association; </section><section prefix="4">"Hazardous substance" means any substance or mixture of substances which is: <section prefix="a">"Toxic" and has the inherent capacity to produce bodily injury to man through ingestion, inhalation, or absorption through any body surface, including toxic substances which are poisonous; </section><section prefix="b">"Corrosive" on contact with living tissue causing substantial destruction of tissue by chemical action, but does not refer to action on inanimate surfaces; </section><section prefix="c">"Irritant" and not corrosive within the meaning of paragraph (b), which on immediate, prolonged, or repeated contact with normal living tissue will induce a local inflammatory reaction; </section><section prefix="d">"Strong sensitizer" and will cause on normal living tissue through an allergic or photodynamic process a hypersensitivity which becomes evident on reapplication of the same substance and which is designated as such by the secretary; </section><section prefix="e">"Flammable" with a flashpoint of eighty (80) degrees Fahrenheit or below; </section><section prefix="f">"Radioactive" as a result of disintegration of unstable atomic nuclei and emits energy; </section><section prefix="g">Capable of generating pressure through decomposition, heat, or other means; </section><section prefix="h">Capable of causing substantial personal injury or illness during any customary or reasonably anticipated handling or use; and </section></section><section prefix="5">"Label" means a display of written, printed, or graphic matter upon the immediate container of any substance, or that is easily legible through the outside container or wrapper. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 518, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 462, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art VI, sec. 107(1), (10) and (11). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9400</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>