<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-804</section_number><catch_line>Power of general partner and person dissociated as general partner to bind partnership after dissolution. </catch_line><order_by>2-804</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited partnership is bound by a general partner's act after dissolution which: <section prefix="a">Is appropriate for winding up the limited partnership's activities; or </section><section prefix="b">Would have bound the limited partnership under KRS 362.2-402 before dissolution if, at the time the other party enters into the transaction, the other party does not have notice of the dissolution. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person dissociated as a general partner binds a limited partnership through an act occurring after dissolution if: <section prefix="a">At the time the other party enters into the transaction: <section prefix="1">Less than two (2) years has passed since the dissociation; and </section><section prefix="2">The other party does not have notice of the dissociation and reasonably believes that the person is a general partner; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The act: <section prefix="1">Is appropriate for winding up the limited partnership's activities; or </section><section prefix="2">Would have bound the limited partnership under KRS 362.2-402 before dissolution and, at the time the other party enters into the transaction, the other party does not have notice of the dissolution. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 152, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34614</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>