<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.555</section_number><catch_line>Methods by which to determine a political party's delegate votes for presidential candidates. </catch_line><order_by>555</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state executive committee of each political party shall, pursuant to its party's rules, determine whether to distribute its party's authorized delegate votes for presidential candidates at its party's national convention based on the results of a party caucus, a presidential preference primary, or a combination of the two (2) methods. Each state executive committee shall notify the State Board of Elections of its decision not later than the December 31 preceding the day for conducting a presidential preference primary as set by KRS 118.561. </section><section prefix="2">If a state executive committee determines that its party's authorized delegate votes for presidential candidates at its party's national convention shall be distributed based on the results of a party caucus, a presidential preference primary shall not be conducted for that political party, and the provisions of KRS 118.561 to 118.651 shall not apply. The distribution of delegates among the presidential candidates shall be determined by party rule. </section><section prefix="3">If a state executive committee determines that its party's authorized delegate votes for presidential candidates at its party's national convention shall be distributed based on the results of both a party caucus and a presidential preference primary, the formula for distribution of authorized delegate votes based on the results of a party caucus shall be determined by party rule. The distribution of delegates based on the results of a presidential preference primary shall be in accordance with the provisions of KRS 118.641(1). Regardless of the method by which the authorized delegate votes are distributed, the casting of votes on the first ballot at each party's national convention shall be in accordance with the provisions of KRS 118.641(2). </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>