<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.232</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Safety requirements governing use of electrical face equipment -- Examination for methane gas. </catch_line><order_by>232</order_by><text>For purposes of this section, "approved" means that a device, apparatus, equipment, machinery, or practice employed in the mining of coal has been approved by the commissioner of the Department for Natural Resources or accepted by a nationally or federally recognized testing laboratory or the United States Department of Labor Mine Safety and Health Administration; "suitable" means a design, material, or installation that meets the requirements of its intended use or that is accepted by a nationally or federally recognized testing laboratory or the United States Department of Labor Mine Safety and Health Administration. <section prefix="1">No person shall be placed in charge of electrical face equipment in any mine unless he is a qualified person capable of determining the safety of the roof, face, and ribs of the working places and detecting the presence of explosive gas. Operators of electrical face equipment shall undergo an examination to determine their fitness to detect explosive gas and shall have a minimum of forty-five (45) days of actual mining experience before they are permitted to have charge of electric face equipment. Safety committeemen, shotfirers, and others whose duty may require them to make inspections for gas shall undergo and pass an examination or possess a mine foreman's certificate before using an approved multi-gas detection device underground. The examination shall be given by the mine inspector. Blank forms for the examination shall be furnished by the department. A copy shall be retained on file at the mine office and the original shall be sent to the department fully made out and signed by the applicant and approved by the mine inspector. </section><section prefix="2">No electric face equipment shall be brought inby the last breakthrough next to the working face until the equipment operator has made an inspection for explosive gas using an approved gas detection device or instrument in the place where the equipment is to work unless the inspection is then made by some other competent person authorized and appointed for that purpose by the mine foreman. If any explosive gas in excess of one percent (1%) is found in the place, the electrical equipment shall not be taken in until the gas is removed. </section><section prefix="3">While the electric equipment is operating at the face, an examination for gas shall be made at not more than twenty (20) minute intervals. If methane gas is found in excess of one percent (1%) at any time, the power shall be de-energized from the equipment and left de-energized until the gas is reduced to less than one percent (1%) and the place determined safe by a foreman. </section></text><history>Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33001</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>