<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="378" order_by="378">A KENTUCKY UNIFORM VOIDABLE TRANSACTIONS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>378A.040</section_number><catch_line>Transfer or obligation voidable as to present or future creditor.  </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text>(1)A transfer made or obligation incurred by a debtor is voidable as to a creditor,whether the creditor's claim arose before or after the transfer was made or theobligation was incurred, if the debtor made the transfer or incurred theobligation:(a)With actual intent to hinder, delay, or defraud any creditor of the debtor;or(b)Without receiving a reasonably equivalent value in exchange for thetransfer or obligation, and the debtor:1.Was engaged or was about to engage in a business or a transactionfor which the remaining assets of the debtor were unreasonablysmall in relation to the business or transaction; or2.Intended to incur, or believed or reasonably should have believedthat the debtor would incur, debts beyond the debtor's ability to payas they became due.(2)In determining actual intent under subsection (1)(a) of this section,consideration may be given, among other factors, to whether:(a)The transfer or obligation was to an insider;(b)The debtor retained possession or control of the property transferred afterthe transfer;(c)The transfer or obligation was disclosed or concealed;(d)Before the transfer was made or obligation was incurred, the debtor hadbeen sued or threatened with suit;(e)The transfer was of substantially all the debtor's assets;(f)The debtor absconded;(g)The debtor removed or concealed assets;(h)The value of the consideration received by the debtor was reasonablyequivalent to the value of the asset transferred or the amount of theobligation incurred;(i)The debtor was insolvent or became insolvent shortly after the transferwas made or the obligation was incurred;(j)The transfer occurred shortly before or shortly after a substantial debtwas incurred; and(k)The debtor transferred the essential assets of the business to a lienor thattransferred the assets to an insider of the debtor.(3)A creditor making a claim for relief under subsection (1) of this section has theburden of proving the elements of the claim for relief by a preponderance of theevidence.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 4, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44724</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>