<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="402" order_by="402">MARRIAGE </unit></structure><section_number>402.050</section_number><catch_line>Who may solemnize marriage -- Persons present. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Marriage shall be solemnized only by: <section prefix="a">Ministers of the gospel or priests of any denomination in regular communion with any religious society; </section><section prefix="b">Justices and judges of the Court of Justice, retired justices and judges of the Court of Justice except those removed for cause or convicted of a felony, county judges/executive, and such justices of the peace and fiscal court commissioners as the Governor or the county judge/executive authorizes; or </section><section prefix="c">A religious society that has no officiating minister or priest and whose usage is to solemnize marriage at the usual place of worship and by consent given in the presence of the society, if either party belongs to the society. </section></section><section prefix="2">At least two (2) persons, in addition to the parties and the person solemnizing the marriage, shall be present at every marriage. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 516, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 401, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec.  1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2103, 2107. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36470</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>