<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.340</section_number><catch_line>Order of county judge/executive assessing omitted property -- Certifying of assessment -- Penalties -- Collection. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within ten (10) days after the summons has been served, or within thirty (30) days after the warning order against the defendant whose name and place of residence are unknown has been made, if it appears to the county judge/executive that the property is liable for taxation and has not been assessed, the county judge/executive shall enter an order fixing the value at the fair cash value estimated as required by law. The county judge/executive shall certify the assessment of the property and its value, together with such other facts as may be required by law or directed by the county judge/executive to appear in the order, to the Department of Revenue and to the sheriff of the county, together with the amount of penalty and cost of assessment, in order that the taxes due the state, county, school or any other taxing district may be collected, with the penalty and costs. If the property is not liable for taxes, the county judge/executive shall make an order to that effect. Either party may appeal from the decision of the county judge/executive to the Circuit Court, and then to the Court of Appeals as in other civil cases, except that no appeal bond shall be required where the appeal is by the commissioner of revenue acting as the relator. </section><section prefix="2">If the owner of the property fails to pay the tax assessed, interest, penalties and costs, the lien under the attachment may be enforced and a sufficiency of the property sold to pay the obligation to the state, county, school or other taxing district. All persons owning property that is assessed as herein provided shall, in addition to the taxes and interest from the time the taxes should have been paid, pay the costs of the proceedings and a penalty of twenty percent (20%) on the amount of the taxes due, except where the property was duly listed and the taxes paid thereon within the time prescribed by law, and except where some different penalty is expressly provided by law. </section><section prefix="3">The taxes, costs and penalties shall be collected and accounted for as other taxes and penalties are required to be collected, and by the same officers. The county clerk shall enter all such assessments in a book to be kept for that purpose, showing the date of the assessment, the name of the person against whom the assessment is made, the location and description of the property assessed, and the value thereof. The officer collecting the taxes shall, when they are paid, notify the clerk of the payment, and the payment shall be noted by the clerk opposite the entry of the assessment. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 190, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 260, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 145, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4260-1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28260</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>