<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.505</section_number><catch_line>State Interagency Council for Services to Children. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text>There is hereby created a State Interagency Council for Services to Children. The chairperson of the council shall be designated by the Governor and shall establish procedures for the council's internal procedures. <section prefix="1">This council shall be composed of the following: <section prefix="a">Members who shall serve by virtue of their positions: the commissioner of the Department of Education, the commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, the commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services, the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, the commissioner of the Department for Medicaid Services, the commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice, the director of the Division of Family Resource and Youth Services Centers, the executive director of the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs, and the general manager of the Division of Juvenile Services of the Administrative Offices of the Courts, or their designees; </section><section prefix="b">The Governor shall appoint one (1) parent of a child with a behavioral health need, who is a consumer of state-funded services for children with a behavioral health need to serve as a member of the council, and one (1) parent who meets the same criteria to serve as the parent member's alternate to serve in the absence of the parent member. For each appointment to be made, the State Family Advisory Council shall submit to the Governor a list of two (2) names of parents who are qualified for appointment from which list the Governor shall make the appointment. Appointees shall serve a term of four (4) years. If the child of the parent member or alternate parent member ceases to be a consumer of state-funded services for children with a behavioral health need during the term of appointment, the member shall be eligible to serve out the remainder of the term of appointment. The alternate parent member may attend and participate in all council meetings but shall vote only in the absence of the parent member. The parent member and alternate parent member shall receive no compensation in addition to that which they may already receive as service providers or state employees, but the parent member and alternate parent member shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred through the performance of their duties as council members; </section><section prefix="c">The chairperson of the council shall appoint one (1) youth between the ages of fourteen (14) and twenty-five (25), who has a mental health disorder or co-occurring disorder and is or has been a consumer of state-funded services for children with a behavioral health need, to serve as a member of the council, and one (1) youth who meets the same criteria to serve as the youth member's alternate in the absence of the youth member. For each appointment to be made, the Statewide Youth Council of the Kentucky Partnership for Families and Children shall submit to the chairperson a list of four (4) names of youth who are qualified for appointment, from which list the chairperson shall make the appointment. Appointees shall serve a term of two (2) years, and the youth member and the youth member's alternate shall be eligible to serve out the remainder of their term of appointment regardless of age. The alternate youth member may attend and participate in all council meetings but shall vote only in the absence of the youth member. The youth member and alternate youth member shall receive no compensation in addition to that which they may already receive as service providers or state employees, but the youth member and alternate youth member shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred through the performance of their duties as council members; and </section><section prefix="d">At the end of a term, a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed. </section></section><section prefix="2">The State Interagency Council for Services to Children shall: <section prefix="a">Consider issues and make recommendations annually to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission regarding the provision of services for children with an emotional disability; </section><section prefix="b">Direct each regional interagency council to: <section prefix="1">Coordinate services to children with an emotional disability and identify factors contributing to a lack of coordination; and </section><section prefix="2">Participate in family accountability, intervention, and response teams established pursuant to KRS 605.035; </section></section><section prefix="c">Develop a form to be signed by the parent or other legal guardian of a child referred for services to any interagency council for children with a behavioral health need. The form shall enable the agencies involved with the child to share information about the child as necessary to identify and provide services for the child; </section><section prefix="d">Review service and treatment plans for children for whom reviews are requested, and provide any advice and assistance that the state council determines to be necessary to meet the needs of children with a behavioral health need referred by regional councils; </section><section prefix="e">Assess the effectiveness of regional councils in meeting the service needs of children with a behavioral health need; </section><section prefix="f">Establish a uniform grievance procedure for the state, to be implemented by each regional interagency council. Appeals may be initiated by the child, parent, guardian, person exercising custodial control or supervision, or other authorized representative about matters relating to the interagency service plan for the child or the denial of services by the regional interagency council. Upon appeal, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B; </section><section prefix="g">Meet at least monthly and maintain records of meetings, except that records that identify individual children shall only be disclosed as provided by law; </section><section prefix="h">Adopt interagency agreements as necessary for coordinating services to children with a behavioral health need by the agencies represented in the state council; </section><section prefix="i">Develop services to meet the needs of children with a behavioral health need; and </section><section prefix="j">Promote services to prevent the behavioral health need of a child. </section></section><section prefix="3">The State Interagency Council for Services to Children may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to comply with the requirements of KRS 200.501 to 200.509. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 29, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 22, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 202, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 166, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 318, sec. 94, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. --Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43494</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>