<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">ORGANIZATION AND GOVERNMENT OF CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>83.410</section_number><catch_line>Legislative finding and expression of legislative intent. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This chapter is intended by the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to grant to citizens living within a city of the first class the authority to govern themselves to the full extent required by local government and not in conflict with the Constitution or laws of this state or by the United States. </section><section prefix="2">The powers herein granted shall be in addition to all other powers granted to cities by other provisions of law. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this chapter shall be broadly construed and considered in the light of the express legislative purpose set forth in subsections (1) and (2) hereof. </section><section prefix="4">The powers herein granted are based upon a legislative finding that the urban crisis cannot be solved by actions of the General Assembly alone, and that the most effective agency for the solution of these problems is the government of a city of the first class. This legislative finding is based upon hearings held by the General Assembly and the conclusion of its members that conditions found in cities of the first class are sufficiently different from those found in other cities to necessitate this grant of authority and complete home rule. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>