<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6405</section_number><catch_line>Initial annual certification -- Renewal, expiration, termination, and reinstatement of certification.  </catch_line><order_by>6405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The initial annual certification for a fire sprinkler inspector shall be for not less than seven (7) months nor more than eighteen (18) months. </section><section prefix="2">Any certification for a fire sprinkler inspector issued in accordance with this chapter shall expire on the last day of the inspector's birth month in the year following certification. </section><section prefix="3">Renewal notices shall be sent to each certified inspector at least sixty (60) days prior to the expiration of his or her certification. The notice shall: <section prefix="a">Inform the certified inspector of the need to renew the certification; and </section><section prefix="b">Describe the materials to be submitted with a request for renewal. </section></section><section prefix="4">An individual who applies to renew a certification as a certified fire sprinkler inspector shall: <section prefix="a">Complete and submit the fire sprinkler inspector's written or electronic renewal form as provided by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Show proof of general liability insurance in the amount required by this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Provide proof of completion of six (6) hours of continuing education prior to certification renewal. The required continuing education shall be received within the twelve (12) months prior to renewal; or </section><section prefix="2">Submit proof that the inspector is a current and valid holder of NICET certification in the testing of water-based systems. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">A thirty (30) day grace period shall be allowed after the renewal deadline of the certification during which time a fire sprinkler inspector may continue to practice and may renew his or her certification upon meeting the requirements promulgated through administrative regulation by the department. </section><section prefix="6">Any certification not renewed on or before the last day of the thirty (30) day grace period shall terminate based upon failure to timely renew certification. Upon termination, the individual shall no longer be eligible to inspect within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="7">After expiration of the thirty (30) day grace period, a formerly certified fire sprinkler inspector with a terminated certification shall have the certification reinstated upon meeting the requirements promulgated through administrative regulation by the department. An applicant for reinstatement after termination of his or her certification shall not be required to submit to any examination as condition for reinstatement, if the reinstatement application is made within two (2) years from the date of certification termination. </section><section prefix="8">After termination and two (2) years, the applicant shall retest and comply with application requirements set forth in KRS 198B.6401. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 32, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 32, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>