<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.383</section_number><catch_line>Marksmanship qualification for certified peace officers. </catch_line><order_by>383</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to maintain his or her certification as a peace officer, each certified peace officer shall annually meet the marksmanship qualification requirement for a retired peace officer as specified in KRS 237.140. Each law enforcement agency whose officers are required to meet the requirements of this subsection shall retain a record of each of its officers having met the annual marksmanship qualification. These records shall be made available upon request to the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council and to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet in order to carry out its responsibilities under KRS 15.330 and 15.450. </section><section prefix="2">Any law enforcement agency employing a certified peace officer may require the certified peace officer to meet a marksmanship qualification requirement which is in excess of that specified in KRS 237.140. Failure of a certified peace officer to meet the increased marksmanship qualification requirement specified by his or her employing or appointing agency shall not affect the certification of the officer, but may subject the officer to discipline by the agency, including suspension or dismissal of the officer from the agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 14, effective March 31, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=935</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>