<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-610</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner's power to issue regulations and examine licensees. </catch_line><order_by>4-610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of this subtitle shall be enforced by the commissioner, who may, after notice to licensees and a hearing, promulgate regulations, referenced to the section or sections which set forth the legislative standards they interpret or apply, for the proper conduct of the business licensed under this subtitle. All regulations of general application shall state the date of promulgation and the effective date. A copy of every such regulation shall be sent to all licensees before the effective date thereof and a copy shall be kept in an indexed permanent book in the office of the commissioner as a public record. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall make an annual examination of the affairs, business, office, and records of every licensee, and such further examinations or investigations as the commissioner deems necessary for the purpose of discovering violations of this subtitle or of securing information necessary for its proper enforcement. Every licensee shall pay a fee sufficient to cover the cost of each examination based upon fair compensation for time and actual expenses. </section><section prefix="3">For the purpose of making such examinations or investigations the commissioner and his or her representatives may require the attendance of and examine under oath all persons whose testimony he or she may require, relative to the loans or business of any such licensee, and shall have free access to the accounts, papers, records, files, safes, vaults, offices, and places of business used in connection with any business conducted under any license issued in accordance with this subtitle. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 668, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 21, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.610. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code.  (7/15/98).  In codifying the 1998 amendment to this statute, the phrase "of the business licensed under this chapter. All regulations of general" has been restored to subsection (1) of this statute under KRS 446.280. This text was in 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 21, creating this statute, and has never been deleted from it by legislative action. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>