<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.260</section_number><catch_line>Special temporary license for qualifying event -- Activities permitted and prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A special temporary license may be issued in wet territory to any regularly organized fair, exposition, racing association, or other party, when in the opinion of the board a necessity therefor exists. This license shall authorize the licensee to exercise the privileges of a quota retail drink licensee and an NQ4 retail malt beverage drink licensee at designated premises for a specified and limited time, not to exceed thirty (30) days, and shall expire when the qualifying event ends. All restrictions and prohibitions applying to a distilled spirits and wine quota retail drink licensee or an NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license shall apply also to a special temporary licensee. </section><section prefix="2">A nonprofit organization holding an NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license may be issued a special temporary license to sell distilled spirits and wine by the drink on the licensed premises for a specified and limited time, not to exceed ten (10) days. The temporary license may be issued in conjunction with any public or private event, including but not limited to weddings, reception, reunions, or similar occasions. </section><section prefix="3">The holder of a special temporary license may sell, serve, and deliver distilled spirits, wine, or malt beverages by the drink, for consumption at the event only in: <section prefix="a">Those cities and counties where quota retail drink licenses are authorized to be issued under KRS 243.230; </section><section prefix="b">A city approving retail distilled spirits and wine sales under KRS 242.127 and 242.129; or </section><section prefix="c">A city or county that has enacted an economic hardship ordinance under KRS 243.072. </section></section><section prefix="4">The holder of a special temporary license may only sell, serve, and deliver wine or malt beverages by the drink, for consumption at an event located in all other cities and counties not identified in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">A special temporary license shall not be issued for an event held in moist territory where only limited alcoholic beverages drink sales have been approved through a moist local option election. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 299, effective January 1, 2015; and ch. 115, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 70, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-127. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2015). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 92 and 115. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 92, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43884</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>