<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.020</section_number><catch_line>Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Kentucky Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction within the Kentucky Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction comprised of twenty-one (21) members to include: the commissioner of the department, one (1) local government fire chief selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Firemen's Association; the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation; the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, Cabinet for Health and Family Services; the Attorney General or any assistant attorney general he or she may designate to represent the interests of consumers; one (1) professional homebuilder selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Home Builders Association of Kentucky; one (1) registered architect selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Society of Architects; one (1) registered structural engineer selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers; one (1) registered mechanical engineer selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers; one (1) registered electrical engineer selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Society of Professional Engineers; one (1) citizen member selected by the Governor to represent the interests of low and moderate-income housing consumers within the Commonwealth of Kentucky; one (1) citizen member at large; one (1) practicing general contractor selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Association of General Contractors; one (1) practicing code administrator selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Codes Administrators Association of Kentucky; one (1) realtor selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Association of Realtors; one (1) member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky State Building Trades Council; one (1) member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Association of Plumbing, Heating and Cooling Contractors; one (1) member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Mechanical Contractors Association; one (1) electrical contractor member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the National Electrical Contractors Association; one (1) retailer member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Retail Federation; and one (1) member selected by the Governor from a list of three (3) submitted by the Kentucky Building Materials Association. </section><section prefix="2">Except for the commissioner of the department, the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation, and the Attorney General or his or her designee, who shall serve on the board during the term of their existing office and shall be voting members, board members shall be appointed for four (4) year terms, except that initially four (4) shall be appointed for two (2) year terms, four (4) shall be appointed for three (3) year terms, and six (6) shall be appointed for four (4) year terms. No board member shall be appointed for more than one (1) successive term except as provided in subsection (3) of this section. The Governor shall, within the limitations of this subsection, set the length of term of each of the initial appointees to the board. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies occurring on the board among those members appointed by the Governor shall be filled by seeking nominations as in subsection (1) of this section from the organization which originally nominated the member who is to be replaced. A replacement for a board member shall be appointed immediately upon the expiration of the departing board member's term of service. Should a board member vacate his or her position on the board prior to the expiration of the member's term, a replacement member shall be appointed for the period of the unexpired term. Should the unexpired term be less than two (2) years, the person selected to fill the unexpired term may subsequently be appointed to one (1) successive four (4) year term. </section><section prefix="4">Members may be removed from the board by the Governor for unethical conduct or for failure to attend three (3) or more successive meetings of the board without reasonable cause. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall meet at least quarterly. Before assuming their duties, members of the board shall take an oath as specified in Section 228 of the Constitution of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the department shall serve as chairman of the board. The board may elect from its members other officers as are required to conduct its business, except that neither the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation, nor the Attorney General or his or her designee shall be elected to office on the board. </section><section prefix="7">The board may adopt such rules, regulations, and bylaws as are necessary to conduct its internal business. Any administrative regulations promulgated by the board for any purpose other than internal business shall be subject to the requirements of KRS 198B.040(11). </section><section prefix="8">No member of the board may vote on any matter which will result in his or her direct or indirect financial gain. </section><section prefix="9">Those members of the board who are not salaried governmental employees shall be compensated for their time when attending board meetings or attending to official duties as directed by the board at the rate of fifty dollars ($50) per day. All board members shall be compensated for expenses incurred in the conduct of board business. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 246, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 172, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 133, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 270, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6964</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>