<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.300</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 309.300 to 309.319. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text>As used in KRS 309.300 to 309.319, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means Kentucky Board of Interpreters for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing. </section><section prefix="2">"Committee" means Kentucky Board of Interpreters for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing Policy Committee. </section><section prefix="3">"Consumer" means a person who is deaf, hard of hearing, or who requires special communication techniques in order to communicate. </section><section prefix="4">"Interpreter" means a person who engages in the practice of interpreting. </section><section prefix="5">"Interpreting" means the translating or transliterating of English concepts to any necessary specialized vocabulary used by a consumer or the translating of a consumer's specialized vocabulary to English concepts. Necessary specialized vocabularies include, but are not limited to, American Sign Language, English-based sign language, cued speech, and oral interpreting. </section><section prefix="6">"Nationally recognized certification" means certification granted by a national organization that is based on a skills assessment of the applicant. These organizations include, but are not limited to, the Registry of Interpreters for the Deaf, the National Association of the Deaf, and the National Training, Evaluation, and Certification Unit. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>