<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="423" order_by="423">NOTARIES PUBLIC AND COMMISSIONERS OF FOREIGN DEEDS </unit></structure><section_number>423.020</section_number><catch_line>Notary may act in any county -- Certification of notary's authority. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A notary public may exercise all the functions of his office in any county of the state, by filing in the county clerk's office in such county his written signature and a certificate of the county clerk of the county for which he was appointed, setting forth the fact of his appointment and qualification as a notary public, and paying a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 to the county clerk. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk of a county in whose office any notary public has so filed his signature and certificate shall, when requested, subjoin to any certificate of proof or acknowledgment signed by the notary a certificate under his hand and seal, stating that such notary public has filed a certificate of his appointment and qualifications with his written signature in his office, and was at the time of taking such proof or acknowledgment duly authorized to take the same; that he is well acquainted with the handwriting of the notary public and believes that the signature to such proof or acknowledgment is genuine. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 34, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 85 and 93, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3721a. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><note>  Amendment of this section by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 85 and 93 became effective July 1, 1992, in compliance with 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 30. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>