<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.040</section_number><catch_line>Organization of department -- Qualifications of officers -- Investigation of applicants.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall consist of the commissioner and the number of officers, individuals employed as a Trooper R Class, CVE R Class, and civilians, and shall be organized in the manner as the commissioner from time to time determines. </section><section prefix="2">All persons appointed as officers shall at the time of their appointment: <section prefix="a">Be not less than twenty-one (21) nor more than thirty-one (31) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Be of good moral character, and in good health; </section><section prefix="c">Be citizens of the United States and residents of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="d">Possess a minimum of sixty (60) hours of credit, or an associate degree, from an accredited college or university, or be a high school graduate with at least two (2) years' experience in the military or in law enforcement. </section></section><section prefix="3">The commissioner shall prescribe minimum physical requirements for appointment as an officer of the department and for individuals employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, and shall conduct such tests and require such physical examinations as deemed necessary to determine the fitness and qualification of each applicant. All other qualifications being equal, preference shall be given to veterans of the Armed Forces of the United States in time of war, who were honorably discharged. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner shall direct an investigation to be conducted in order to determine an applicant's suitability for employment as an officer. The contents of the investigation shall be subject to the Open Records Act, KRS 61.870 to 61.884 and KRS 61.991, except that the identity of any witness or informant involving information relative to this investigation shall remain confidential. The identity of any witness or informant shall be subject to the subpoena power of a court of competent jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(3) and (6). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 11. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42241</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>