<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.30-080</section_number><catch_line>Requirement that minimal capital investment be made prior to the release of incremental revenues -- Escrow account -- Duties of authority to monitor agreements and track revenues. </catch_line><order_by>30-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Prior to any incremental revenues being released by the Commonwealth for any project, the authority shall certify that the minimum capital investment has been made as required by the tax incentive agreement. </section><section prefix="b">Incremental revenues received after the activation date but prior to certification of the minimum capital investment shall be retained by the Commonwealth until the minimum capital investment is certified by the authority. The incremental revenues shall be released to the agency upon certification. If the minimum capital investment is not certified within the time period established by the authority, the incremental revenues shall be forfeited to the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">The authority shall monitor all tax incentive agreements and shall verify for each project expenditure identified as approved public infrastructure costs and where applicable, financing costs, approved signature project costs and expenses for land preparation, demolition and clearance. </section><section prefix="3">The authority shall track the amount of incremental revenues released to each agency under each tax incentive agreement. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 21, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><former-codification> KRS 65.7081. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2851</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>