<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.340</section_number><catch_line>Reports by boards to Kentucky Board of Education -- Filing of policies on specified matters. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each board of education shall, on the forms prepared by the chief state school officer and approved by the Kentucky Board of Education, prepare and submit to the Kentucky Board of Education reports on all phases of its school service. Each board may prepare and publish for the information of the public a report on the progress of its schools. </section><section prefix="2">Each board of education shall file in the board's office its policies relating to the following matters: <section prefix="a">Transportation of pupils; </section><section prefix="b">Discipline and conduct of pupils; </section><section prefix="c">Limitations or restrictions on use of school facilities; </section><section prefix="d">Conduct of meetings of the board of education, including policies on the calling of executive sessions; </section><section prefix="e">Personnel policies that apply to certified employees, including fringe benefits, salary schedules, nonclassroom duties, in-service training, teacher-student ratio, hiring, assignment, transfer, dismissal, suspension, reinstatement, promotion, and demotion; </section><section prefix="f">Evaluation of certified employees; </section><section prefix="g">Selection of textbooks and instructional materials; </section><section prefix="h">Expenditure and accounting for school funds, including all special funds; and </section><section prefix="i">Policies dealing with school-based decision making. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The local board of education may adopt a policy requiring that each school council, or if none exists, the principal, make an annual report at a public meeting of the board describing the school's progress in meeting the educational goals set forth in KRS 158.6451 and district goals established by the board. </section><section prefix="b">Biennially, the local board shall review in a public meeting the portion of each school's consolidated plan that sets forth the activities and schedule to reduce the achievement gaps among the various groups of students as required in KRS 158.649. If a district has more than twenty (20) schools, the district may review the achievement gap data of each school in a comprehensive district report at a regularly scheduled meeting of the board. The report shall include the schools' and district's plans to reduce any identified gaps in student achievement. </section></section><section prefix="4">It is intended that these policies shall cover matters within the authority and discretion of the district board of education and not matters otherwise required by law or regulation. Such policies shall be filed in the board's office by August 15, 1974, shall be kept up to date by filing annual amendments thereto each August 15 and shall be public records. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 231, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-54. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>