<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.110</section_number><catch_line>Report of offense under penal code to department. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All city and county law enforcement agencies shall cause a photograph, a set of fingerprints, and a general description report of all persons arrested on a felony charge to be made and two (2) copies of each item forwarded within thirty (30) days after the arrest to the Department of Kentucky State Police of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, in accordance with administrative regulations of the cabinet. Unless the charges are dismissed or withdrawn at that appearance, the judge shall require any adult person appearing before any Circuit Court in the Commonwealth on a felony charge, who has not been arrested, to, if this has not already been done in the case before the court, be photographed and fingerprinted, and have a general description made following his arraignment. Agencies specified above shall furnish any other information involving offenses or in their possession relative to law enforcement upon request by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">Each city and county law enforcement agency shall advise the Department of Kentucky State Police of the disposition made of all cases wherein a person has been charged with an offense. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 75, effective June 26, 2007. --  Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 427, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 129, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1198</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>