<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.0651</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Division of State Risk and Insurance Services -- Assistance from other agencies -- Risk management program.   </catch_line><order_by>0651</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of State Risk and Insurance Services shall: <section prefix="a">Oversee and assist the management of the state fire and tornado insurance fund established in KRS Chapter 56; </section><section prefix="b">Develop and manage programs of risk assessment and insurance for the protection of state property not covered by the state fire and tornado insurance fund; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet on the fiscal management of programs relating to life insurance, workers' compensation, and health care benefits for state employees; </section><section prefix="d">Serve as the central clearinghouse for coordinating and evaluating existing and new risk management programs within all state agencies; </section><section prefix="e">Develop financing techniques for risk protection; </section><section prefix="f">Provide insurance for all state-owned and state-operated facilities and vehicles; and </section><section prefix="g">Develop and implement other risk management, insurance, and self-insurance programs or other functions and duties as the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet may direct the division to undertake and implement within the general statutory authority and control of the Finance and Administration Cabinet over state property and fiscal affairs of the executive branch of state government, including, but not limited to, those areas pertaining to tort and contractual liability, fidelity, and property risks. </section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall be construed or interpreted as affecting the operation of the employee benefit programs generally administered by the Office of Employee Relations and Department of Employee Insurance within the Personnel Cabinet. These agencies shall coordinate the operation of life insurance, workers' compensation, health care benefit programs, and other self-insured programs with the Division of State Risk and Insurance Services. </section><section prefix="3">All cabinets, departments, boards, commissions, and other state agencies shall provide to the Division of State Risk and Insurance Services the technical advice and other assistance the Division of State Risk and Insurance Services or the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall request in the performance of the functions of the division as described in this section. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall have the power and authority to promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A for purposes of implementing a risk management program for the executive branch of state government. Any administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary shall be administered by the Division of State Risk and Insurance Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012; and repealed, reenacted, and amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 32, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 14, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 154, sec. 62, effective July 15, 1998. -- Renumbered by Reviser of Statutes and amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 216, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification>KRS 42.0245.  KRS 42.0192. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10 and repealed, reenacted, and amended by 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/15/94).  This statute was formerly codified as KRS 42.0192 and was renumbered by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136(1)(a) because of changes made by 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 4. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40259</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>