<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.712</section_number><catch_line>License required -- Qualifications -- Application -- Insurance -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>712</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual shall not advertise or claim to be a home inspector and shall not conduct a home inspection for compensation without first obtaining a license as a home inspector. </section><section prefix="2">An individual shall not advertise as, claim to be, or engage in or work at the trade of home inspection unless an owner or employee of that business is a licensed home inspector. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall deny a license to any applicant who fails to: <section prefix="a">Furnish evidence satisfactory to the board, showing that the individual: <section prefix="1">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="2">Has graduated from high school or earned a Kentucky or other state's general educational development (GED) diploma; and </section><section prefix="3">Meets other criteria established by the board through promulgation of administrative regulations; </section></section><section prefix="b">Verify the information submitted on the application form; </section><section prefix="c">Complete a board-approved training program or course of study involving the performance of home inspections, and pass an examination prescribed or approved by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Submit to the board a certificate of insurance that is acceptable to the board and that: <section prefix="1">Is issued by an insurance company or other legal entity authorized to transact insurance business in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">Provides for general liability coverage of at least two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000); </section><section prefix="3">Lists the Kentucky Board of Home Inspectors as the certificate holder of any insurance policy satisfying the requirements of this paragraph; </section><section prefix="4">States that cancellation and nonrenewal of the underlying policy is not effective until the board receives at least ten (10) days' prior written notice of the cancellation or nonrenewal; and </section><section prefix="5">Contains any other terms and conditions established by the board; or </section></section><section prefix="e">Pay a licensing fee established in KRS 198B.706. </section></section><section prefix="4">An individual applying for a license as a home inspector shall apply on a written or electronic form prescribed and provided by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>