<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.220</section_number><catch_line>Cooperation with other agencies. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the administration of this chapter, the secretary shall: <section prefix="a">To the fullest extent consistent with the provisions of this chapter, cooperate with the federal Department of Labor; </section><section prefix="b">Make such reports in such form and containing such information as such agency may from time to time require; </section><section prefix="c">Comply with such provisions as such agency may from time to time find necessary to assure the correctness and verification of such reports; and </section><section prefix="d">Comply with the provisions of Title III of the Social Security Act relating to the expenditure of such funds as may be allotted and paid to this state for the purpose of assisting in the administration of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon request therefor the secretary shall furnish to any agency of this or any other state or the United States charged with the administration of public works or assistance, through public employment or otherwise, the name, address, ordinary occupation and employment status of each recipient of benefits and such recipient's rights to further benefits under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may make records relating to the administration of this chapter available to the Railroad Retirement Board and may furnish the Railroad Retirement Board, at the expense of that board, as many copies thereof as the board requests. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary may afford reasonable cooperation, including reciprocal collection of contributions by the enforcement of foreign judgments, with every agency of any state or of the United States charged with the responsibility of administering an unemployment insurance law. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall require employment offices in this state, upon request of a public agency administering or supervising the administration of a state plan approved under Part A of Title IV of the Social Security Act or of a public agency charged with any duty or responsibility under any program or activity authorized or required under Part D of Title IV of such act, shall, and, notwithstanding any other provision of law, is hereby authorized to furnish to such agency making the request, from any data contained in the files of any such employment office, information with respect to any individual specified in the request as to (a) whether such individual is receiving, has received, or has made application for unemployment compensation, and the amount of any such compensation being received by such individual; (b) the current (or most recent) home address of such individual; and (c) whether such individual has refused an offer of employment, and, if so, a description of the employment so offered and terms, conditions, and rate of pay therefor, provided that the secretary shall require employment offices in this state to furnish such other information as shall be required by the regulations of the Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 13, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(31). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 12. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32264</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>