<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.578</section_number><catch_line>Visual acuity requirements for certified driver training program -- Testing of knowledge of motor vehicle laws -- Out-of-state drivers establishing residence in Kentucky -- Restriction on taking of operator's license examination after three failings -- Consequence of failure to pass examination. </catch_line><order_by>578</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Applicants accepted to participate in a certified driver training program shall meet the following minimum vision requirements: <section prefix="a">A distance visual acuity of 20/200 or better, with corrective lenses, in the applicant's better eye; </section><section prefix="b">A visual field of at least one hundred twenty (120) degrees horizontally and eighty (80) degrees vertically in the same eye as used in paragraph (a) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="c">A distance visual acuity of 20/60 or better using a bioptic telescopic device; and </section><section prefix="d">No ocular diagnosis or prognosis that indicates a likelihood that significant deterioration of visual acuity or visual field to levels below the minimum standards outlined in this subsection will occur. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon acceptance into a certified driver training program, an applicant shall be given an examination to test his or her knowledge of the motor vehicle laws of the Commonwealth. This examination may be taken orally. Upon successful completion of this examination, the applicant shall be issued a temporary instruction permit, that shall be valid only when the applicant is accompanied by an employee of a certified driver training program. Temporary instruction permits issued under this section shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issue. </section><section prefix="3">An applicant who successfully completes a certified driver training program shall be reexamined by a vision specialist upon completion of the program. The examination shall certify that the applicant continues to meet the visual acuity and visual field standards set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">An applicant who successfully completes a certified driving training program and passes the visual reexamination required by subsection (3) of this section shall be eligible to take a comprehensive operator's license examination administered by the Department of Kentucky State Police. The operator's license examination shall include testing of the applicant's driving skills over a route specifically designed to test the applicant's competency using a bioptic telescopic device. </section><section prefix="5">An applicant who is a restricted out-of-state driver establishing residence in Kentucky shall be required to take and pass a temporary instruction permit examination before being eligible to take the operator's license examination. An applicant who is a restricted out-of-state driver establishing residence in Kentucky shall not be required to complete a certified driver training program but shall be required to take and pass the visual examination outlined in subsection (3) of this section before taking the operator's license examination. </section><section prefix="6">If an applicant or restricted out-of-state driver fails the operator's license examination three (3) times, he or she shall not be eligible to retake the examination until successfully completing additional training from a certified driver training program and obtaining an affidavit from the program director or bioptic driving instructor recommending that the applicant or restricted out-of-state driver be allowed to retake the examination. </section><section prefix="7">The Office for the Blind shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to set standards for a certified driver training program and to otherwise carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 199, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 117, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43242</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>