<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.650</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 186.650 to 186.700. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>As used in KRS 186.650 to 186.700: <section prefix="1">A "trailer" means any vehicle designed for carrying persons or property and being drawn by a motor vehicle being so constructed that no part of its weight rests upon the towing vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">"Semitrailer" means any vehicle designed for carrying persons or property and for being drawn by a motor vehicle and is so constructed that some part of its weight and some part of its load rests upon or is carried by another vehicle, except that: <section prefix="a">"Semitrailer" shall not include any vehicle designed for carrying persons or property and being drawn by a motor vehicle registered according to the provisions of KRS 186.050(4)(a) and used by a farmer only for transporting persons, food, provender, feed, machinery, livestock, material and supplies necessary for his farming operation, and the products grown on his farm. </section></section><section prefix="3">"Manufactured home" means a structure, transportable in one (1) or more sections, which: <section prefix="a">Is eight (8) body feet or more in width and forty (40) body feet or more in length when in the traveling mode; </section><section prefix="b">Has three hundred twenty (320) or more square feet when erected on site; </section><section prefix="c">Is built on a permanent chassis; </section><section prefix="d">Is designed to be used as a dwelling, with or without a permanent foundation, when connected to the required utilities; </section><section prefix="e">Includes plumbing, heating, air-conditioning, and electrical systems; and </section><section prefix="f">May be used as a place of residence, business, profession, or trade by the owner, lessee or their assigns, and may consist of one (1) or more units that can be attached or joined together to comprise an integral unit or condominium structure. </section></section><section prefix="4">"Recreational vehicle" means a vehicular type unit primarily designed as temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use, which either has its own motive power or is mounted on or drawn by another vehicle. The basic entities are: travel trailer, camping trailer, truck camper, and motor home; <section prefix="a">A travel trailer is a vehicular unit, mounted on wheels, designed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use. It shall be a size and weight which shall not require special highway movement permits when drawn by a motorized vehicle. It shall have a living area of less than two hundred twenty (220) square feet, excluding built-in equipment (such as wardrobes, closets, cabinets, kitchen units, or fixtures) and bath and toilet rooms. The exterior area of a travel trailer shall be less than three hundred twenty (320) square feet. </section><section prefix="b">A camping trailer is a vehicular portable unit mounted on wheels and constructed with collapsible partial side walls which fold for towing by another vehicle and unfold at the camp site to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use. </section><section prefix="c">A truck camper is a portable unit constructed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, travel, or camping use, consisting of a roof, floor, and sides, designed to be loaded onto and unloaded from the bed of a pick-up truck. </section><section prefix="d">A motor home is a vehicular unit designed to provide temporary living quarters for recreational, camping, or travel use built on or permanently attached to, a self-propelled motor vehicle chassis or on a chassis cab or van which is an integral part of the completed vehicle. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Cabinet" means the Transportation Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 3; and ch. 368, sec. 3. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 14, effective January 1, 1967; and ch. 255, sec. 172. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 18, effective January 1, 1963. -- Created 1956 (2nd Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6105</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>