<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.205</section_number><catch_line>Examination by election officers -- Correction of defects -- Reserve voting machine. </catch_line><order_by>205</order_by><text>Before permitting any person to vote on the day of the election, the election officers shall examine the machine to ascertain whether it has been operated since the counters referred to in subsections (10) and (11) of KRS 117.125 were set at zero, and to ascertain whether the ballot labels are arranged as specified on the printed instruction cards. If the machine indicates that it has been operated or if the ballot labels are not so arranged, the officers shall not unlock the operating device or mechanism, but shall immediately secure the attendance of the county clerk and one (1) member of the county board of elections other than the county clerk, who shall reset the counters at zero and relock the device covering the counters, or properly arrange the ballot labels, as the case may be, in the presence of the election officers. If the attendance of members of the board of elections cannot be obtained before the opening of the polls or within one (1) hour thereafter, the election officers shall notify the county clerk of the foregoing facts and obtain from the county clerk a reserve voting machine, and proceed to conduct the election. Any reserve machine shall have been certified for use at the election by the county board of elections and prepared for use at the election by the election officers in the precinct in the same manner as the original machine was prepared for the election. The machine found to have been so operated shall be returned immediately to the custody of the county clerk, whose duty it shall be to promptly repair same in order that it may be used as a reserve machine in the election if needed. </text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 25, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 34, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>