<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.540</section_number><catch_line>Regulations for school buses -- Operator required to have commercial driver's license with school bus endorsement. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to govern the design and operation of all Kentucky school buses and to govern the operation of district-owned passenger vehicles transporting students under KRS 156.153(2). The board shall, with the advice and aid of the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Transportation Cabinet, enforce the administrative regulations governing the operation of all school buses whether owned by a school district or privately contracted and all district-owned passenger vehicles transporting students under KRS 156.153(2). The regulations covering the operation shall by reference be made a part of any contract with a school district. Every school district and private contractor referred to under this subsection shall be subject to those regulations. </section><section prefix="2">Any employee of any school district who violates any of the administrative regulations in any contract executed on behalf of a school district shall be subject to removal from office. Any person operating a school bus under contract with a school district who fails to comply with any of the administrative regulations shall be guilty of breach of contract and the contract shall be canceled after proper notice and a hearing by the responsible officers of such school district. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who operates a school bus shall be required to possess a commercial driver's license issued pursuant to KRS 281A.170 with a school bus endorsement as described in KRS 281A.175. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 209, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, sec. 609, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 24. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-69m. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts Ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts Ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>