<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-203Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Commission on Military Affairs -- Purposes -- Powers -- Executive committee -- Executive director.   </catch_line><order_by>12-203Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs. The commission shall be a separate administrative body of state government within the meaning of KRS Chapter 12. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the purpose of the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs to: <section prefix="a">Address matters of military significance to Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Maintain a cooperative and constructive relationship between state agencies and the military entities in Kentucky, as necessary to ensure coordination and implementation of unified, comprehensive, statewide strategies involved with, or affected by, the military; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the Governor, the General Assembly, the Kentucky congressional delegation, and other appropriate government officials on all matters in which the military services and the Commonwealth have mutual interests, needs, and concerns; </section><section prefix="d">Take action to promote and optimize state and Department of Defense initiatives that will improve the military value of Kentucky's National Guard, active, and reserve military force structure and installations, and improve the quality of life for military personnel residing in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="e">Coordinate, as necessary, the state's interest in future Department of Defense base closure and restructuring activities; </section><section prefix="f">Recommend state, federal, and local economic development projects which would promote, foster, and support economic progress through military presence in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="g">Promote and assist the private sector in developing spin-off investments, employment, and educational opportunities associated with high-technology programs and activities at Kentucky's military installations; </section><section prefix="h">Recommend to the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership the long-range options and potential for the defense facilities located in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="i">Develop strategies to encourage military personnel to retire and relocate in Kentucky and promote those leaving the military as a viable quality workforce for economic development and industrial recruitment; and </section><section prefix="j">Allocate available grant money to qualified applicants to further the purposes of paragraphs (a) to (i) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The Governor or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="c">The adjutant general of the Commonwealth or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="d">The executive director of the Office of Homeland Security or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="e">The secretaries of the following cabinets or their designees: <section prefix="1">Finance and Administration; </section><section prefix="2">Justice and Public Safety; </section><section prefix="3">Energy and Environment; </section><section prefix="4">Transportation; </section><section prefix="5">Education and Workforce Development; </section><section prefix="6">Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="7">Personnel; </section><section prefix="8">Labor; </section><section prefix="9">Public Protection; and </section><section prefix="10">Tourism, Arts and Heritage; </section></section><section prefix="f">The Attorney General or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="h">The executive director of the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="i">The chairperson of the Kentucky Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve; </section><section prefix="j">Kentucky's Civilian Aides to the Secretary of the United States Army; </section><section prefix="k">The chairperson of the Senate Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection Committee and the chairperson of the House of Representatives Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Safety Committee; </section><section prefix="l">The Chief Justice or a designated representative; </section><section prefix="m">The commander or the designee of the commander of each of the following as nonvoting, ex officio members: <section prefix="1">U.S. Army Cadet Command; </section><section prefix="2">U.S. Army Human Resources Command; </section><section prefix="3">U.S. Army Recruiting Command; </section><section prefix="4">84th Training Command; </section><section prefix="5">One Hundredth Division (Institutional Training); </section><section prefix="6">101st Airborne Division; </section><section prefix="7">Blue Grass Army Depot; </section><section prefix="8">Fort Campbell Garrison; </section><section prefix="9">Fort Knox Garrison; </section><section prefix="10">11th Theatre Aviation Command, U.S. Army Reserve; </section><section prefix="11">U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Huntington District; </section><section prefix="12">U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Louisville District; </section><section prefix="13">Adjutant General of the U.S. Army; and </section></section><section prefix="n">Five (5) at-large members appointed by the Governor, who shall be residents of counties significantly impacted by military installations. </section></section><section prefix="4">The terms of the five (5) at-large members shall be staggered so that two (2) appointments shall expire at two (2) years, one (1) appointment shall expire at three (3) years, and two (2) appointments shall expire at four (4) years, from the dates of initial appointment. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The commission shall establish an executive committee consisting of the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development, the adjutant general of the Commonwealth, the commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs, the executive director of the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs, and the five (5) at-large members. The chair and vice chair of the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs shall be appointed by the Governor from among the members of the executive committee. </section><section prefix="b">The chair and vice chair of the commission shall also serve as chair and vice chair of the executive committee. </section><section prefix="c">The executive committee shall serve as the search committee for an executive director of the commission and shall have any other authority the commission delegates to it. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet one (1) time each year, and may meet at other times on call of the chair, to establish the commission's goals and to review issues identified and recommendations made by the executive committee. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the commission's business. Members' designees shall have voting privileges at commission meetings. </section><section prefix="7">Members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for their necessary travel expenses actually incurred in the discharge of their duties on the commission, subject to Finance and Administration Cabinet administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="8">The commission may establish committees or work groups composed of commission members and citizens as necessary to advise the commission in carrying out its responsibilities, duties, and powers. Citizen members of committees or work groups shall not have a vote. </section><section prefix="9">The commission may promulgate necessary administrative regulations as prescribed by KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="10">The commission may adopt bylaws and operating policies necessary for its efficient and effective operation. </section><section prefix="11">There shall be an executive director, who shall be the administrative head and chief executive officer of the commission, recommended by the executive committee, approved by the commission, and appointed by the Governor. The executive director shall have authority to hire staff, contract for services, expend funds, and operate the normal business activities of the commission. </section><section prefix="12">The Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs and its executive committee shall be an independent agency attached to the Office of the Governor. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 24, sec. 194, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 63, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005; and ch.99, sec. 22, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective March 27, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 108, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44560</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>