<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.650</section_number><catch_line>Required participation in funds -- Computation of amounts -- Designated monthly hold harmless amount. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Every political subdivision, school district, and special district shall participate in the gross revenues and excise tax fund and the state baseline and local growth fund. </section><section prefix="b">On or before December 1, 2005, each political subdivision shall certify to the department on a prescribed form the amount of collections it received from the local franchise fees collected from communications service and multichannel video programming service providers and other fees collected to fund public educational and government access programming during the period between July 1, 2004, and June 30, 2005. By certifying its participation under this subsection, each political subdivision: <section prefix="1">Consents to the hearing process provided in KRS 136.658; and </section><section prefix="2">Agrees to relinquish its right to enforce the portion of any contract or agreement that requires the payment of a franchise fee or tax on communications services and multichannel video programming services, regardless of whether the tax or fee is imposed on the provider or its customers. </section></section><section prefix="c">The amount of collections received by each political subdivision, school district, special district, and sheriff's department between July 1, 2004, and June 30, 2005, from the tax imposed by KRS 136.120 attributable to the franchise portion of the operating property, as noted in KRS 136.115, shall be calculated by the department from assessment data for calendar year 2004. </section></section><section prefix="2">The monthly portion of the gross revenues and excise tax fund that shall be distributed to political subdivisions, school districts and special districts under KRS 136.652 shall be computed as follows: <section prefix="a">Each political subdivision, school district and special district shall be assigned a percentage based on the amount of its collections certified under subsection (1) of this section as a ratio of the total certified amount of collections of all parties participating in the fund. This percentage shall be known as the "local historical percentage." The portion of the sheriff departments' certified collections identified in subsection (1) of this section from the tax imposed under KRS 136.120 attributable to the franchise portion of the operating property, as noted in KRS 136.115, that was imposed by county governments shall be added to each county's reported collections to determine its local historical percentage; </section><section prefix="b">The sheriff departments’ collections certified under subsection (1) of this section that are retained by the sheriff departments as their fee for collecting the taxes shall be the sheriff departments’ fixed hold-harmless amount; </section><section prefix="c">Three million thirty-four thousand dollars ($3,034,000), which represents one-twelfth (1/12) of the total potential collections, shall be designated as the "monthly hold-harmless amount"; and </section><section prefix="d">Each political subdivision's, school district's, and special district's local historical percentage shall be multiplied by the monthly hold-harmless amount to determine its monthly distribution from the fund. </section></section><section prefix="3">If during the period between June 30, 2005, and December 31, 2005, any political subdivision had a substantial change in its base revenue by enacting or modifying the rate of a local franchise fee prior to June 30, 2005, the political subdivision may request the department to determine its certified collection amount. </section><section prefix="4">If any political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff's department believes that the data used to determine its certified amount of collections are inaccurate, the political subdivision, school district, special district, or sheriff's department may request a redetermination by the oversight committee established by KRS 136.658. A redetermination shall be effective prospectively beginning with the next distribution cycle occurring ninety (90) days after the matter is finally settled. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 5, effective March 6, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 113, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> March 6, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (3/6/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 27, provides that this section applies retroactively to December 1, 2005. (1/1/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98. 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>