<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.167</section_number><catch_line>Program to encourage persons to enter Kentucky teaching profession -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>167</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By January 1, 2001, the Kentucky Department of Education, with help from representatives of the Education Professional Standards Board, the Council on Postsecondary Education, the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority, the Association of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities, public and private not-for-profit postsecondary institutions, and local educational agencies, shall develop a plan, including timelines for implementation, for a multidimensional recruitment and information program, to encourage persons to enter the teaching profession and to seek employment in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall not supplant or diminish current efforts required in KRS 161.165. </section><section prefix="3">The components of the program shall include: <section prefix="a">Early recruitment programs to inform middle and high school students about the potential of teaching as a career; </section><section prefix="b">Programs to encourage paraprofessionals in schools, as well as other nontraditional students, to pursue additional education to become teachers; </section><section prefix="c">Programs to enlist highly skilled career employees in specific content areas to pursue teaching as a second career; </section><section prefix="d">Options for recruiting persons with liberal arts and sciences majors and current students with nondeclared majors into nontraditional and accelerated teacher preparation programs; </section><section prefix="e">Marketing strategies for informing the public of the importance of high quality teaching to student achievement, the value of teachers to society as a whole, the benefits and rewards of teaching, and the options for entering teacher preparation, including scholarship information; and </section><section prefix="f">Expanding the Kentucky Department of Education's electronic bulletin board for certified vacancies in local school districts to include an option for potential teachers to voluntarily post their availability for education positions within the state. </section></section><section prefix="4">No later than March 15, 2001, the Department of Education shall present a status report of the recruitment and information program to the Interim Joint Committee on Education; and no later than October 15, 2001, the Department of Education shall present to the Interim Joint Committee on Education and the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue a summary report with recommendations. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3885</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>