<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.809</section_number><catch_line>Election of officers -- Quorum -- Compensation -- Ex officio members of board. </catch_line><order_by>809</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall elect a chair and other officers it deems necessary from its members. The Governor shall make the initial appointments to the board as follows: three (3) members shall be appointed to terms that expire December 31, 1995, and four (4) members shall be appointed to terms that expire December 31, 1997. Subsequent members shall serve terms of four (4) years and shall serve until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="2">Senate confirmation of the Governor's appointees is required in accordance with the provisions of KRS 11.160. If a member is not confirmed by the Senate, the Governor, within thirty (30) days of the rejection, shall make another appointment. That member shall serve the remainder of the term in question and shall also be subject to confirmation should the term extend until the next regular session, or a special session which includes this subject on the call, whichever occurs earlier. </section><section prefix="3">Six (6) members shall constitute a quorum. The board shall meet at least quarterly and at such other times as the chair may determine. The board shall also meet upon the call of four (4) or more of the members of the board. </section><section prefix="4">On July 15, 1998, each member, except the secretaries of the cabinets, shall be compensated eight thousand five hundred dollars ($8,500) annually, and beginning on July 15, 1999, twelve thousand dollars ($12,000) annually. In addition, the members of the board, except the secretaries of the cabinets, shall be reimbursed for necessary travel and lodging expenses in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Finance and Administration for state employees. </section><section prefix="5">A board member, except the secretaries of the cabinets, may be removed for cause by the board. Cause shall include, but not be limited to, incompetence or misconduct defined in policies or bylaws adopted by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 94, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 361, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 394, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 63, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 12, sec. 43, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 154, 361, and 394. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between Acts chs. 154 and 361, Acts ch. 361, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32564</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>