<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.745</section_number><catch_line>Duration of emergency protective order and domestic violence order-- Prohibited costs and conditions -- Mutual orders of protection --Amendment -- Expungement.  </catch_line><order_by>745</order_by><text>(1)An emergency protective order and a domestic violence order shall becomeeffective and binding on the respondent when the respondent is given notice ofthe existence and terms of the order by a peace officer or the court or uponpersonal service of the order, whichever is earlier. A peace officer or courtgiving notice of an unserved order shall make all reasonable efforts to arrangefor the order's personal service upon the respondent. Once effective, a peaceofficer or the court may enforce the order's terms and act immediately upontheir violation.(2)Costs, fees, or bond shall not be assessed against or required of a petitionerfor any filing, hearing, service, or order authorized by or required to implementKRS 403.715 to 403.785.(3)A court shall not require mediation, conciliation, or counseling prior to or as acondition of issuing an order of protection.(4)Mutual orders of protection may be issued only if:(a)Separate petitions have been filed by both parties; and(b)The orders are written with sufficient specificity to allow any peace officerto identify which party has violated the order.(5)Upon proper filing of a motion, either party may seek to amend an order ofprotection.(6)Testimony offered by an adverse party in a hearing ordered pursuant to KRS403.730 shall not be admissible in any criminal proceeding involving the sameparties, except for purposes of impeachment.(7)(a)The Court of Justice, county and Commonwealth's attorneys, lawenforcement agencies, and victim services organizations may jointlyoperate a domestic violence intake center to assist persons who apply forrelief under KRS 403.715 to 403.785.(b)In cases where criminal conduct is alleged, a court may suggest that apetitioner voluntarily contact the county attorney. A court may not withholdor delay relief if the petitioner elects to not contact the county attorney.(8)A person's right to apply for relief under this chapter shall not be affected bythat person leaving his or her residence to avoid domestic violence and abuse.(9)A court shall order the omission or deletion of the petitioner's address and theaddress of any minor children from any orders or documents to be madeavailable to the public or to any person who engaged in the acts complained ofin the petition.(10)(a)If a petition under KRS 403.715 to 403.785 did not result in the issuanceof a domestic violence order, the court in which the petition was heardmay for good cause shown order the expungement of the records of thecase if:1.Six (6) months have elapsed since the case was dismissed; and2.During the six (6) months preceding the expungement request, therespondent has not been bound by an order of protection issued forthe protection of any person, including an order of protection asdefined in KRS 456.010.(b)As used in this subsection, "expungement" has the same meaning as inKRS 431.079.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. --Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>