<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-280</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure of facts about injured person. </catch_line><order_by>39-280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon request of a basic or added reparation claimant or reparation obligor, information relevant to a claim for basic or added reparation benefits shall be disclosed as follows: <section prefix="a">An employer shall furnish a statement of the work record and earnings of an employee upon whose injury the claim is based. The statement shall cover the period specified by the claimant or reparation obligor making the request and may include a reasonable period before, and the entire period after, the injury. </section><section prefix="b">The claimant shall deliver to the reparation obligor a copy of every written report, previously or thereafter made, relevant to the claim, and available to him, concerning any medical treatment or examination of a person upon whose injury the claim is based and the names and addresses of physicians and medical care facilities rendering diagnoses or treatment in regard to the injury or to a relevant past injury, and the claimant shall authorize the reparation obligor to inspect and copy relevant records of physicians and of hospitals, clinics, and other medical facilities. </section><section prefix="c">A physician or hospital, clinic, or other medical facility furnishing examinations, services, or accommodations to an injured person in connection with a condition alleged to be connected with an injury upon which a claim is based, upon authorization of the claimant, shall furnish a written report of the history, condition, diagnoses, medical tests, treatment, and dates and cost of treatment of the injured person, and permit inspection and copying of all records and reports as to the history, condition, treatment, and dates and cost of treatment. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person other than the claimant providing information under this section may charge the person requesting the information for the reasonable cost of providing it. </section><section prefix="3">In case of dispute as to the right of a claimant or reparation obligor to discover information required to be disclosed, the claimant or reparation obligor may petition the Circuit Court in the county in which the claimant resides for an order for discovery including the right to take written or oral depositions. Upon notice to all persons having an interest, the order may be made for good cause shown. It shall specify the time, place, manner, conditions, and scope of the discovery. To protect against annoyance, embarrassment, or oppression, the court may enter an order refusing discovery or specifying conditions of discovery and directing payment of costs and expenses of the proceeding, including reasonable attorney's fees. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1975 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>