<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0206</section_number><catch_line>Public postsecondary education institution's program in speech-language pathology and teacher education. </catch_line><order_by>0206</order_by><text>A public postsecondary education institution with a degree program in speech-language pathology and a teacher education program, under the direction of the Council on Postsecondary Education, and in consultation with the Education Professional Standards Board and the Kentucky Board of Speech-Language Pathology and Audiology, shall: <section prefix="1">Align the programs of studies for speech-language pathology and teacher education to permit a student to successfully prepare for licensure as a speech-language pathology assistant and certification as a bachelor's level teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders; </section><section prefix="2">Increase the number of qualified students accepted into programs leading to licensure as a speech-language pathologist or speech-language pathology assistant and certification as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders, subject to: <section prefix="a">Requirements for program certification by national certifying bodies, including, but not limited to, student to faculty ratios; </section><section prefix="b">The strategic plans of the Council on Postsecondary Education and the postsecondary education institution; and </section><section prefix="c">The budgetary considerations of the postsecondary education institution. </section></section><section prefix="3">Provide expanded opportunities for speech-language pathology assistants working in public schools to pursue licensure as a speech-language pathologist and certification as a teacher of exceptional children/communication disorders, which may include: <section prefix="a">Expanded opportunities for admission to on-campus programs; </section><section prefix="b">The development and expansion of distance learning opportunities in collaboration with the Kentucky Commonwealth Virtual University; and </section><section prefix="c">Admissions requirements that take into account successful professional experience as a speech-language pathology assistant in lieu of other admissions requirements. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4171</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>