<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.955</section_number><catch_line>Police officers -- Powers and duties.   </catch_line><order_by>955</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Police officers so appointed shall be peace officers and conservators of the peace. They shall have general police powers including the power to arrest, without process, all persons who within their view commit any crime or misdemeanor. They shall possess all of the common law and statutory powers, privileges, and immunities of sheriffs, except that they shall be empowered to serve civil process to the extent authorized by the employing governing board of the respective public postsecondary education institution employing them. Without limiting the generality of the foregoing, such police officers are hereby specifically authorized and empowered, and it shall be their duty: <section prefix="a">To preserve the peace, maintain order and prevent unlawful use of force or violence or other unlawful conduct on the campuses of their respective institutions, and to protect all persons and property located thereon from injury, harm and damage; and </section><section prefix="b">To enforce, and to assist the officials of their respective institutions in the enforcement of, the lawful rules and regulations of said institution, and to assist and cooperate with other law enforcement agencies and officers. Provided, however, that such police officers shall exercise the powers herein granted upon any real property owned or occupied by their respective institutions, including the streets passing through and adjacent thereto. Said powers may be exercised in any county of the Commonwealth where the institution owns, uses, or occupies property. Additional jurisdiction may be established by agreement with the chief of police of the municipality or sheriff of the county or the appropriate law enforcement agency in which such property is located, dependent upon the jurisdiction involved. </section></section><section prefix="2">Police officers may exercise their powers away from the locations described in subsection (1) of this section only upon the following conditions: <section prefix="a">When in immediate pursuit of an actual or suspected violator of the law; </section><section prefix="b">When authorized to do so pursuant to the agreement authorized by subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">When requested to act by the chief of police of the city or county in which the institution's property is located; </section><section prefix="d">When requested to act by the sheriff of the county in which the institution's property is located; </section><section prefix="e">When requested to act by the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="f">When requested to act by the authorized delegates of those persons or agencies listed in paragraph (c), (d), or (e) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="g">When requested to assist a state, county or municipal police officer, sheriff, or other peace officer in the performance of his lawful duties; or </section><section prefix="h">When operating under an interlocal cooperation agreement pursuant to KRS Chapter 65. </section></section><section prefix="3">Police officers appointed pursuant to KRS 164.950 to 164.980 shall have, in addition to the other powers enumerated herein, the power to conduct investigations anywhere in this Commonwealth, provided the investigation relates to criminal offenses which occurred on property owned, leased, or controlled by the public postsecondary education institution. Where desirable and at the discretion of the public postsecondary education institution's police officials, the institution's police department may coordinate said investigations with any law enforcement agency of this Commonwealth or with agencies of the federal government. </section><section prefix="4">Police departments created and operated by the governing boards of public postsecondary education institutions shall, for all purposes, be deemed public police departments and the sworn police officers thereof are, for all purposes, deemed public police officers. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 164.950 to 164.980 shall be construed as a diminution or modification of the authority or responsibility of any city or county police department, the Department of Kentucky State Police, sheriff, constable, or other peace officer either on the property of an institution of postsecondary education or otherwise. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 174, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41824</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>