<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="165" order_by="165">A PROPRIETARY EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>165A.470</section_number><catch_line>License to operate CDL driver training school -- Persons who may not be connected with school -- Requirements for school and instructors.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not operate, conduct, maintain, or establish a CDL driver training school unless the person holds a valid current license issued by the commission. The following persons shall not be allowed to be connected in any capacity whatsoever with a CDL driver training school: <section prefix="a">Any person whose employment duties in any way relate to the issuance of a motor vehicle operator's license under KRS Chapter 186 or 281A; </section><section prefix="b">Any employee of the commission, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, or Department of Kentucky State Police; and </section><section prefix="c">Any member of the immediate family of persons identified in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person shall not operate, conduct, maintain, or establish a CDL driver training school unless the school has: <section prefix="a">At least one (1) licensed CDL driver training instructor in its employ; and </section><section prefix="b">At least one (1) commercial motor vehicle owned or leased in the name of the CDL driver training school that is properly registered in the Commonwealth and that has undergone a safety inspection within the past twelve (12) months. </section></section><section prefix="3">A person shall not continue to operate a CDL driver training school if the commission has suspended, revoked, canceled, or refused to renew the school's license. </section><section prefix="4">A person shall not act as an instructor for a CDL driver training school unless the person holds a valid current license as an instructor issued by the commission and unless the person is employed by a licensed CDL driver training school. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 177, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 5, effective April 9, 2002. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification>KRS 332.020. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40326</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>