<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">B ADMISSION OF AN INDIVIDUAL WITH AN INTELLECTUAL DISABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>202B.180</section_number><catch_line>Confidentiality of court records -- Expungement -- Disclosure by court order.   </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The court records of a respondent made in all proceedings pursuant to this chapter shall be confidential and shall not be open to the general public for inspection except when the disclosure is provided in KRS 202B.190. </section><section prefix="2">Following the discharge of a respondent from an ICF/ID or hospital or the issuance of a court order denying a petition for admission, a respondent may at any time move to have all court records pertaining to the proceedings expunged from the files of the court. The county attorney shall be given notice of any motion and shall have five (5) days in which to respond to same or request a hearing thereon. </section><section prefix="3">Any person seeking information contained in the court files or the court records of proceedings involving persons under this chapter may file a written motion in the appropriate court setting out why the information is needed. A District Judge may issue an order to disclose the information sought if the judge finds the order is appropriate under the circumstances and if the judge finds it is in the best interest of the person or of the public to have the information disclosed. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 52, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>