<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.125</section_number><catch_line>Secretary of Education and Workforce Development Cabinet -- Powers and duties -- Personnel. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet to administer this chapter; and he shall have power and authority to make such expenditures, require such reports, make such investigations, and take such other action not specifically assigned to the cabinet, as he or she deems necessary for the proper administration of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary is authorized, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapters 12, 42, 45, and 45A, to appoint, fix the compensation, and prescribe duties and powers of such officers and employees as may be necessary in the performance of his or her duties under this chapter. All positions shall be filled by persons selected and appointed on a nonpartisan merit basis. The secretary shall not employ or pay any person who is an officer or committee member of any political party organization. The secretary may delegate to any such person so appointed such power and authority as he or she deems reasonable and proper for the effective administration of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The salary and expenses of the secretary and his or her staff shall be considered a proper cost of the administration of this chapter, to be charged to the unemployment compensation administration fund in that proportion which the cost of such services rendered in the administration of this chapter bears to the overall cost of the services rendered in the administration of the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall submit to the Governor an annual report covering the administration and operation of this chapter and make such recommendations for amendments to this chapter as he or she deems proper. </section><section prefix="5">In the administration of this chapter the secretary shall cooperate to the fullest extent possible with any agency of this state or any other state or of the United States and shall take such action, through the adoption of appropriate rules, regulations, administrative methods, and standards, as may be necessary to secure for this state and its citizens all the advantages available under the provisions of the Social Security Act, as amended, that relate to unemployment compensation, the Federal Unemployment Tax Act, as amended, the Wagner-Peyser Act, as amended, and the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 72, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 135, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 61, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 98. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 10. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32252</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>