<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.070</section_number><catch_line>Harassment. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of harassment when, with intent to intimidate, harass, annoy, or alarm another person, he or she: <section prefix="a">Strikes, shoves, kicks, or otherwise subjects him to physical contact; </section><section prefix="b">Attempts or threatens to strike, shove, kick, or otherwise subject the person to physical contact; </section><section prefix="c">In a public place, makes an offensively coarse utterance, gesture, or display, or addresses abusive language to any person present; </section><section prefix="d">Follows a person in or about a public place or places; </section><section prefix="e">Engages in a course of conduct or repeatedly commits acts which alarm or seriously annoy such other person and which serve no legitimate purpose; or </section><section prefix="f">Being enrolled as a student in a local school district, and while on school premises, on school-sponsored transportation, or at a school-sponsored event: <section prefix="1">Damages or commits a theft of the property of another student; </section><section prefix="2">Substantially disrupts the operation of the school; or </section><section prefix="3">Creates a hostile environment by means of any gestures, written communications, oral statements, or physical acts that a reasonable person under the circumstances should know would cause another student to suffer fear of physical harm, intimidation, humiliation, or embarrassment. </section></section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, harassment is a violation. </section><section prefix="b">Harassment, as defined in paragraph (a) of subsection (1) of this section, is a Class B misdemeanor. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 217, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19926</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>