<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.7-105</section_number><catch_line>Reissuance in alternative medium.   </catch_line><order_by>7-105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon request of a person entitled under an electronic document of title, the issuer of the electronic document may issue a tangible document of title as a substitute for the electronic document if: <section prefix="a">The person entitled under the electronic document surrenders control of the document to the issuer; and </section><section prefix="b">The tangible document when issued contains a statement that it is issued in substitution for the electronic document. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon issuance of a tangible document of title in substitution for an electronic document of title in accordance with subsection (1) of this section: <section prefix="a">The electronic document ceases to have any effect or validity; and </section><section prefix="b">The person that procured issuance of the tangible document warrants to all subsequent persons entitled under the tangible document that the warrantor was a person entitled under the electronic document when the warrantor surrendered control of the electronic document to the issuer. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon request of a person entitled under a tangible document of title, the issuer of the tangible document may issue an electronic document of title as a substitute for the tangible document if: <section prefix="a">The person entitled under the tangible document surrenders possession of the document to the issuer; and </section><section prefix="b">The electronic document when issued contains a statement that it is issued in substitution for the tangible document. </section></section><section prefix="4">Upon issuance of the electronic document of title in substitution for a tangible document of title in accordance with subsection (1) of this section: <section prefix="a">The tangible document ceases to have any effect or validity; and </section><section prefix="b">The person that procured issuance of the electronic document warrants to all subsequent persons entitled under the electronic document that the warrantor was a person entitled under the tangible document when the warrantor surrendered possession of the tangible document to the issuer. </section></section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7-105, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>