<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-880</section_number><catch_line>Receiver to appoint successor to bank's rights, assets, obligations. </catch_line><order_by>3-880</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The receiver, with the approval of the receivership court, has the authority to appoint a successor to all rights, obligations, assets, deposits, agreements and trusts held by the closed bank as trustee, administrator, executor, guardian, agent and all other fiduciary or representative capacities.  The successor's duties and obligations commence upon appointment to the same extent binding upon the former bank and as though the successor had originally assumed such duties and obligations.  Specifically, the successor shall succeed to and be entitled to administer all trusteeships, administrations, executorships, guardianships, agencies and all other fiduciary or representative proceedings to which the closed bank is named or appointed in wills, whenever probated, or to which it is appointed by any other instrument, court order or by operation of law.  </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall be construed to impair any right of the grantor or beneficiaries of trust assets to secure the appointment of a substituted trustee or manager.  </section><section prefix="3">Within thirty (30) days after appointment, the successor shall give written notice, insofar as practicable, to all interested parties named in the books and records of the bank or in trust documents held by it that such successor has been appointed in accordance with state law.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 56, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.880. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14621</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>