<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-111</section_number><catch_line>Required information.   </catch_line><order_by>2-111</order_by><text>A limited partnership shall maintain at its designated office the following information: <section prefix="1">A current list showing the full name and last known street and mailing address of each partner, separately identifying the general partners, in alphabetical order, and the limited partners, in alphabetical order; </section><section prefix="2">A copy of the initial certificate of limited partnership and all amendments to and restatements of the certificate, together with signed copies of any powers of attorney under which any certificate, amendment, or restatement has been signed; </section><section prefix="3">A copy of any filed articles of conversion or merger; </section><section prefix="4">A copy of the limited partnership's federal, state, and local income tax returns and reports, if any, for the three (3) most recent years; </section><section prefix="5">A copy of any partnership agreement made in record form and any amendment made in record form to any partnership agreement; </section><section prefix="6">A copy of any financial statement of the limited partnership for the three (3) most recent years; </section><section prefix="7">A copy of the three (3) most recent annual reports delivered by the limited partnership to the Secretary of State pursuant to KRS 14A.6-010; </section><section prefix="8">A copy of any record made by the limited partnership during the past three (3) years of any consent given by or vote taken of any partner pursuant to this subchapter or the partnership agreement; and </section><section prefix="9">Unless contained in a partnership agreement in record form, a record stating: <section prefix="a">The amount of cash, and a description and statement of the agreed value of the other benefits, contributed and agreed to be contributed by each partner; </section><section prefix="b">The times at which, or events on the happening of which, any additional contributions agreed to be made by each partner are to be made; </section><section prefix="c">For any person that is both a general partner and a limited partner, a specification of what transferable interest the person owns in each capacity; and </section><section prefix="d">Any events upon the happening of which the limited partnership is to be dissolved and its activities wound up. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 131, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 90, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>