<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.901</section_number><catch_line>Statewide program for prevention, screening, diagnosis, and treatment of lead poisoning -- Duties of secretary -- Authorization of local regulations and programs. </catch_line><order_by>901</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall establish a statewide program for the prevention, screening, diagnosis, and treatment of lead poisoning, including identification of the sources of such poisoning through such research, educational, epidemiological, and clinical activities as may be necessary. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall also initiate activities which: <section prefix="a">Will either provide for or support the monitoring of all medical laboratories, private and public hospitals which perform lead determination tests on human blood or other tissues, so as to insure the accuracy of such tests; </section><section prefix="b">Will develop or encourage the development of appropriate programs and studies to identify sources of lead intoxication and assist other entities in the identification of lead in children's blood and the sources of that intoxication; and </section><section prefix="c">Will provide for or support the development of outreach programs to identify, screen, and diagnose for elevated lead blood levels, at-risk persons not otherwise utilizing existing screening and diagnostic programs. </section></section><section prefix="3">The secretary may contract with any agencies, individuals, or groups for the provision of services necessary to administer KRS 211.900 to 211.905 and KRS 211.994. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary may provide financial and technical assistance and consultation to local, county, or district governmental or private agencies for the promotion, establishment and maintenance of lead poisoning prevention, screening, diagnostic, and treatment programs. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall have the power to adopt, amend, or rescind such rules and regulations as deemed necessary or suitable for the proper administration of KRS 211.900 to 211.905 and KRS 211.994. The regulation shall include, but not be limited to, those which govern permissible limits of lead-based hazards in and about dwellings and dwelling units. </section><section prefix="6">Local boards of health may, by the adoption of local regulations, establish programs for the prevention, screening, diagnosis, and treatment of lead poisoning; provided that such regulations are the same as the provisions of KRS 211.900 to 211.905 and KRS 211.994 and the regulations promulgated by the secretary pursuant to subsection (5) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8514</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>