<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.445</section_number><catch_line>Use of savings attributed to agency's pilot personnel program -- Authority for administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>445</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall develop a plan to permit up to fifty percent (50%) of any actual savings attributed to the pilot personnel program to be retained by the agency. These savings shall not lapse and may be expended for the purchase of nonrecurring capital outlay, or the provision of salary incentives not added to base compensation for all participating employees in the pilot program on an equitable basis. However, at least fifty percent (50%) of savings retained by the agency shall be earmarked for salary incentives. Prior to the expenditure of any funds, the pilot agency shall prepare and submit a plan to the steering committee and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet for review and approval in order to expend any eligible funds. </section><section prefix="2">The provision set out in subsection (1) of this section shall conform to applicable federal regulations. </section><section prefix="3">Pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20439</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>