<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.132</section_number><catch_line>Failure to report insufficient firearms training when receiving certification without notice to specified law enforcement or prosecutorial personnel. </catch_line><order_by>132</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of failure to report insufficient firearms training when he or she receives certification that he or she has successfully completed a firearms instructor trainer, certified firearms instructor, or applicant training course and has not, in fact received lecture instruction, the showing of a required visual aid, hands-on firearm safety and cleaning training, range instruction and range firing, or has not successfully completed the marksmanship requirement during range firing and has not reported the matter in writing to the sheriff, Commonwealth's attorney, or county attorney serving the county in which the training was conducted or has not made a written report to the Department of Kentucky State Police and provided a copy of the certification documents to the agency reported to along with the report. The report shall be made not more than thirty (30) working days after receiving documentation of successful completion of training, unless additional time is requested and has been granted by an officer or agency to which a report shall be made. </section><section prefix="2">Failure to report insufficient firearms training is a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">A person who makes a report pursuant to this section within the time frame specified in subsection (1) of this section shall not be prosecuted for a violation of this section and shall be eligible to reenroll in the level of class for which the person was originally enrolled. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 268, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>