<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.020</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensure for Private Investigators -- Members -- Appointment -- Vacancies -- Reimbursement -- Meetings -- Removal of members -- Liability insurance. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Licensure for Private Investigators is hereby created. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor. <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be an attorney from the Office of the Attorney General to be designated by the Attorney General; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a municipal police officer of the rank of captain or above; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a county sheriff; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) members shall each have been private investigators for at least five (5) years prior to the date of their appointment and shall be of recognized business standing; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice of private investigating. </section></section><section prefix="3">All members shall be residents of this state and possess good moral character. </section><section prefix="4">The original members of the board shall be appointed by no later than January 1, 2003, as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) member to a one (1) year term; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members to a two (2) year term; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members to a three (3) year term; and </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) members to a four (4) year term. </section></section><section prefix="5">After the initial appointments to the board, all members shall serve a two (2) year term. </section><section prefix="6">Any vacancy occurring on the board shall be filled by the Governor. </section><section prefix="7">No member may serve more than two (2) full consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="8">No member shall continue to serve if the member no longer meets the qualifications required under subsections (2) and (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="9">The three (3) board members who are private investigators and the member at large shall receive the sum of one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day the board meets. All members shall receive reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. </section><section prefix="10">The board shall annually elect a chairman, a vice chairman, and a secretary-treasurer from the membership of the board. </section><section prefix="11">The board shall hold at least two (2) meetings annually and additional meetings as the board may deem necessary. Additional meetings may be held upon call of the chairman or upon written request of a quorum. Four (4) members of the board shall constitute a quorum to conduct business. </section><section prefix="12">Upon recommendation of the board, the Governor may remove any member of the board for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office. </section><section prefix="13">The board may purchase professional liability insurance for the board members and agents and staff of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 1, effective April 21, 2004. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 21, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>