<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.300</section_number><catch_line>Issuance or assumption of securities by utilities. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No utility shall issue any securities or evidences of indebtedness, or assume any obligation or liability in respect to the securities or evidences of indebtedness of any other person until it has been authorized so to do by order of the commission. </section><section prefix="2">Application for authority to issue or assume securities or evidences of indebtedness shall be made in such form as the commission prescribes. Every such application shall be made under oath, and shall be signed and filed on behalf of the utility by its president, or by a vice president, auditor, comptroller, or other executive officer having knowledge of the matters set forth and duly designated by the utility. Every such application shall be placed at the head of the docket of the commission and disposed of promptly within sixty (60) days after it is filed with the commission, unless it is necessary for good cause to continue the application for longer time than sixty (60) days, in which case the order making the continuance shall state fully the facts that make it necessary. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall not approve any issue or assumption unless, after investigation of the purposes and uses of the proposed issue and the proceeds thereof, or of the proposed assumption of obligation or liability, the commission finds that the issue or assumption is for some lawful object within the corporate purposes of the utility, is necessary or appropriate for or consistent with the proper performance by the utility of its service to the public and will not impair its ability to perform that service, and is reasonably necessary and appropriate for such purpose. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may grant or deny the application in whole or in part, or may grant it with such modifications and upon such terms and conditions as the commission deems necessary or appropriate. The order of the commission shall specify that the securities or evidences of indebtedness, or the proceeds thereof, shall be used only for the lawful purposes specified in the application, and both the application of the utility and the order of the commission shall state in general terms the purpose of the issuance or assumption. </section><section prefix="5">A copy of any order made and entered by the commission under this section, duly certified by the executive director of the commission, shall be sufficient evidence for all purposes of full and complete compliance by the utility with all procedural and other matters required precedent to the entry of the order. </section><section prefix="6">Securities and evidences of indebtedness issued and obligations and liabilities assumed by a utility, for which, under the provisions of this section, the authorization of the commission is required, shall comply with the terms and conditions of the order of authorization entered prior to the issue or assumption, and where the order has been fully complied with the validity of the issue or assumption shall not be affected by a failure to comply with any provision of this section or rule of the commission relating to procedure or other matters preceding the entry of the order of authorization or order supplemental thereto. </section><section prefix="7">The commission may require periodical or special reports from the utility issuing any security or evidence of indebtedness. The report shall show, in such detail as the commission requires, the disposition made of such securities or evidences of indebtedness, and the application of the proceeds thereof. </section><section prefix="8">This section does not apply to notes issued by a utility, for proper purposes and not in violation of law, that are payable at periods of not more than two (2) years from the date thereof, or to like notes, payable at a period of not more than two (2) years from date thereof, that are issued to pay or refund in whole or in part any such notes, or to renewals of such notes from time to time, not exceeding in the aggregate six (6) years from the date of the issue of the original notes so renewed or refunded. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in this section implies any guarantee of securities or evidences of indebtedness by the state, or any obligation on the part of the state with respect thereto, and nothing in this section limits the power of any court having jurisdiction to authorize or cause receiver's certificates or debentures to be issued according to the rules and practice obtaining in receivership proceedings in courts of equity. </section><section prefix="10">This section does not apply in any instance where the issuance of securities or evidences of indebtedness is subject to the supervision or control of the federal government or any agency thereof, but the commission may appear as a party to any proceeding filed or pending before any federal agency if the issuance of the securities or evidences of indebtedness will materially affect any utility over which the commission has jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="11">This section also does not apply to the issuance of securities or evidence of indebtedness by a utility principally engaged in transportation of gas by pipeline in interstate commerce and subject to the supervision, control or jurisdiction of the federal government or any agency, board or commission thereof. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 37, effective April 1, 1979. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3952-24. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14103</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>