<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-807</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of pre-effective-date financing statement.   </catch_line><order_by>9-807</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "pre-effective-date financing statement" means a financing statement filed before July 1, 2013. </section><section prefix="2">After July 1, 2013, a person may add or delete collateral covered by, continue or terminate the effectiveness of, or otherwise amend the information provided in, a pre-effective-date financing statement only in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in this article as amended by KRS 355.9-801 to 355.9-809. However, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement also may be terminated in accordance with the law of the jurisdiction in which the financing statement is filed. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, if the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the information in a pre-effective-date financing statement may be amended after July 1, 2013, only if: <section prefix="a">The pre-effective-date financing statement and an amendment are filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501; </section><section prefix="b">An amendment is filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501 concurrently with, or after the filing in that office of, an initial financing statement that satisfies KRS 355.9-806(3); or </section><section prefix="c">An initial financing statement that provides the information as amended and satisfies KRS 355.9-806(3) is filed in the office specified in KRS 355.9-501. </section></section><section prefix="4">If the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement may be continued only under KRS 355.9-805(3) and (5) or 355.9-806. </section><section prefix="5">Whether or not the law of this state governs perfection of a security interest, the effectiveness of a pre-effective-date financing statement filed in this state may be terminated after July 1, 2013, by filing a termination statement in the office in which the pre-effective-date financing statement is filed, unless an initial financing statement that satisfies KRS 355.9-806(3) has been filed in the office specified by the law of the jurisdiction governing perfection as provided in this article as amended by KRS 355.9-801 to 355.9-809 as the office in which to file a financing statement. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 97, effective July 1, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (3/14/2013). 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 10, secs. 2 and 3 provide that the statutes in Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code that were amended or created in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, secs. 60 to 99, are effective July 1, 2013. This statute was one of those sections. Since only the effective date of a prior Act was altered, and not the text of the affected statutes, reference to 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 10 does not appear in the history for this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41132</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>