<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23">A CIRCUIT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>23A.200</section_number><catch_line>Fees and costs for civil cases. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Supreme Court shall by rule set the filing fees and miscellaneous costs for civil cases filed in the Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="2">The following fee shall be paid directly to the sheriff or other officer serving the process by the party requesting the service, at the time of the request as follows:  Service of process (per process)  ............................................................. $20.00 </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 30, effective July 1, 1982; ch. 159, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 266, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 445, sec. 34, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 56, effective January 1, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note>This section was amended by four 1982 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. This section was amended in 1982 Acts Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. Although a reference to mental health proceedings under KRS Ch. 387 was added in (1) of this section by 1982 Acts ch. 445, sec. 34, the provisions of KRS Ch. 387 relating to such proceedings were repealed by 1982 Acts ch. 141, sec. 146. </lrc-note><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 30 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20629</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>