<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.1-080</section_number><catch_line>Others treated as qualified beneficiaries. </catch_line><order_by>1-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A charitable organization expressly designated to receive distributions under the terms of a charitable trust has the rights of a qualified beneficiary under this chapter if the charitable organization, on the date the charitable organization’s qualification is being determined: <section prefix="a">Is a distributee or permissible distributee of trust income or principal; </section><section prefix="b">Would be a distributee or permissible distributee of trust income or principal on the termination of the interests of other distributees or permissible distributes then receiving or eligible to receive distributions; or </section><section prefix="c">Would be a distributee or permissible distributee of trust income or principal if the trust ended on that date. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person appointed to enforce a trust established for the care of an animal or another noncharitable purpose under KRS 386B.4-080 or 386B.4-090, has the rights of a qualified beneficiary under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">Other than those listed in KRS 386B.7-060, the Attorney General has the rights of a qualified beneficiary with respect to a charitable trust governed by this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43071</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>