<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="512" order_by="512">CRIMINAL DAMAGE TO PROPERTY </unit></structure><section_number>512.070</section_number><catch_line>Criminal littering. -- Local governments may classify criminal littering as civil offenses.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of criminal littering when he: <section prefix="a">Drops or permits to drop on a highway any destructive or injurious material and does not immediately remove it; or </section><section prefix="b">Knowingly places or throws litter on any public or private property or in any public or private water without permission; or </section><section prefix="c">Negligently places or throws glass or other dangerous pointed or edged substances on or adjacent to water to which the public has access for swimming or wading or on or within fifty (50) feet of a public highway; or </section><section prefix="d">Discharges sewage, minerals, oil products, or litter into any public waters or lakes within the state. </section></section><section prefix="2">Criminal littering is a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">Violators may prepay to the Circuit Court clerk if prepayment is so noted on the citation and if the littering offense is not combined with an offense that is not prepayable. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any language or provision of this section or KRS 65.8808(3) to the contrary, the legislative body of a local government may, by ordinance, choose to classify the offenses proscribed in subsection (1) of this section as civil offenses in accordance with KRS 65.8808. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 111, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41122</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>