<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="440" order_by="440">ESCAPES, FUGITIVES FROM JUSTICE, AND EXTRADITION </unit></structure><section_number>440.010</section_number><catch_line>Warrant for escaped or inadvertently-released convict -- Reward. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a convict escapes from a penitentiary, or is inadvertently released prior to the expiration of the sentence, the warden of that penitentiary shall issue a warrant directed to all peace officers and other persons authorizing and requiring them to capture and convey the convict to the penitentiary. </section><section prefix="2">If a convict who is committed to the custody of the Department of Corrections, but is not actually confined in a facility operated by the Department of Corrections, escapes, or is inadvertently released prior to the expiration of the sentence, the commissioner of the Department of Corrections, or the commissioner's designee, shall issue a warrant directed to all peace officers and other persons authorizing and requiring them to capture and convey the convict to the penitentiary. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who captures and conveys an escaped convict back to the penitentiary shall be paid a reward of one hundred dollars ($100), and all reasonable expenses, by the state out of appropriations for that purpose. The warden may employ persons to go in pursuit of the convict, and they shall be paid a reasonable compensation for their services. </section><section prefix="4">Any officer who refuses or willfully neglects to obey the warrant of the warden shall be fined not less than ten dollars ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100). </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1936. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>