<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.050</section_number><catch_line>Hearing on petition for interpersonal protective order.  </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>(1)Prior to or at a hearing on a petition for an interpersonal protective order:(a)The court may obtain the respondent's Kentucky criminal and protectiveorder history and utilize that information to assess what relief and whichsanctions may protect against danger to the petitioner or other person forwhom protection is being sought, with the information so obtained beingprovided to the parties in accordance with the Rules of Civil Procedure;and(b)If the petitioner or respondent is a minor, the court shall inquire whetherthe parties attend school in the same school system to assist the court inimposing conditions in the order that have the least disruption in theadministration of education to the parties while providing appropriateprotection to the petitioner.(2)(a)If the adverse party is not present at the hearing ordered pursuant to KRS456.040 and has not been served, a previously issued temporaryinterpersonal protective order shall remain in place, and the court shalldirect the issuance of a new summons for a hearing set not more thanfourteen (14) days in the future. If service has not been made on theadverse party before that hearing or a subsequent hearing, the temporaryinterpersonal protective order shall remain in place, and the court shallcontinue the hearing and issue a new summons with a new date and timefor the hearing to occur, which shall be within fourteen (14) days of theoriginally scheduled date for the continued hearing. The court shall repeatthe process of continuing the hearing and reissuing a new summons untilthe adverse party is served in advance of the scheduled hearing. Ifservice has not been made on the respondent at least seventy-two (72)hours prior to the scheduled hearing, the court may continue the hearingno more than fourteen (14) days in the future. In issuing the summons,the court shall simultaneously transmit a copy of the summons or noticeof its issuance and provisions to the petitioner.(b)The provisions of this section permitting the continuance of aninterpersonal protective order shall be limited to six (6) months from theissuance of the temporary interpersonal protective order. If therespondent has not been served within that period, the order shall berescinded without prejudice. Prior to the expiration of the temporaryinterpersonal protective order, the court shall provide notice to thepetitioner stating that, if the petitioner does not file a new petition, theorder shall be rescinded without prejudice.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 23, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>