<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.300</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 198B.310 to 198B.330. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text>As used in KRS 198B.310 to 198B.330: <section prefix="1">"Safety glazing material" means any glazing material, such as tempered glass, laminated glass, wire glass or rigid plastic, which meets the test requirements of ANSI Standard Z-97.1-1966 and such further requirements as may be adopted by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction and which is so constructed, treated, or combined with other materials as to minimize the likelihood of cutting and piercing injuries resulting from human contact with the glazing material; </section><section prefix="2">"Hazardous locations" means those installations, glazed or to be glazed, in residential, commercial and public buildings known as sliding glass doors, framed or unframed glass doors and adjacent fixed glazed panels which may be mistaken for means of ingress or egress, storm doors, shower doors, and tub inclosures, whether or not the glazing in such doors, panels or inclosures is transparent, and in any other area wherein the use of other than safety glazing materials would constitute a hazard. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 259, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended and reenacted as KRS 198B.300, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(12). -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 17.410. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6987</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>