<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="507" order_by="507">A FETAL HOMICIDE </unit></structure><section_number>507A.020</section_number><catch_line>Fetal homicide in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of fetal homicide in the first degree when: <section prefix="a">With intent to cause the death of an unborn child or with the intent necessary to commit an offense under KRS 507.020(1)(a), he causes the death of an unborn child; except that in any prosecution, a person shall not be guilty under this subsection if he acted under the influence of extreme emotional disturbance for which there was a reasonable explanation or excuse, the reasonableness of which is to be determined from the viewpoint of a person in the defendant's situation under the circumstances as the defendant believed them to be. However, nothing contained in this section shall constitute a defense to a prosecution for or preclude a conviction of fetal homicide in the second degree or any other crime; or </section><section prefix="b">Including but not limited to the operation of a motor vehicle under circumstances manifesting extreme indifference to human life, he wantonly engages in conduct which creates a grave risk of death to an unborn child and thereby causes the death of an unborn child. </section></section><section prefix="2">Fetal homicide in the first degree is a capital offense. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective February 20, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> February 20, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19722</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>