<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.171</section_number><catch_line>General powers. </catch_line><order_by>171</order_by><text>Each corporation shall have power: <section prefix="1">To have perpetual succession by its corporate name unless a limited period of duration is stated in its articles of incorporation. </section><section prefix="2">To sue and be sued, complain and defend, in its corporate name. </section><section prefix="3">To have a corporate seal and alter it at pleasure, provided, however, that the presence or absence of a corporate seal on or from a writing shall neither add to nor detract from the legality thereof nor affect its validity in any manner or respect. </section><section prefix="4">To purchase, take, receive, lease, take by gift, devise or bequest, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, improve, use and otherwise deal in and with real or personal property, or any interest therein, wherever situated. </section><section prefix="5">To sell, convey, mortgage, pledge, lease, exchange, transfer and otherwise dispose of all or any part of its property and assets. </section><section prefix="6">To lend money to its employees, other than its officers and directors, and otherwise assist its employees, officers and directors. </section><section prefix="7">To purchase, take, receive, subscribe for, or otherwise acquire, own, hold, vote, use, employ, sell, mortgage, lend, pledge, or otherwise dispose of, and otherwise use and deal in and with, shares or other interests in, or obligations of, other domestic or foreign corporations, whether for profit or not for profit, associations, partnerships or individuals, or direct or indirect obligations of the United States, or of any other government, state, territory, governmental district or municipality or of any instrumentality thereof. </section><section prefix="8">To make contracts and incur liabilities, borrow money at such rates of interest as the corporation may determine, issue its notes, bonds, and other obligations, and secure any of its obligations by mortgage or pledge of all or any of its property, franchises and income. </section><section prefix="9">To lend money for its corporate purposes, invest and reinvest its funds, and take and hold real and personal property as security for the payment of funds so loaned or invested. </section><section prefix="10">To conduct its affairs, carry on its operations, and have offices and exercise the powers granted by KRS 273.161 to 273.390 in any state, territory, district, or possession of the United States, or in any foreign country. </section><section prefix="11">To elect or appoint officers and agents of the corporation, who may be directors or members, and define their duties and fix their compensation. </section><section prefix="12">To make and alter bylaws, not inconsistent with its articles of incorporation or with the laws of this state, for the administration and regulation of the affairs of the corporation. </section><section prefix="13">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation, to make donations for the public welfare or for charitable, scientific or educational purposes; and in time of war to make donations in aid of war activities. </section><section prefix="14">To indemnify any director or officer or former director or officer of the corporation, or any person who may have served at its request as a director or officer of another corporation in which it owns shares of capital stock or of which it is a creditor, against expenses actually and reasonably incurred by him in connection with the defense of any action, suit or proceeding, civil or criminal, in which he is made a party by reason of being or having been such director or officer, except in relation to matters as to which he shall be adjudged in such action, suit or proceeding to be liable for negligence or misconduct in the performance of duty to the corporation; and to make any other indemnification that shall be authorized by the articles of incorporation or bylaws, or resolution adopted after notice to the members entitled to vote. </section><section prefix="15">To pay pensions and establish pension plans or pension trusts for any or all of its directors, officers and employees. </section><section prefix="16">To cease its corporate activities and surrender its corporate franchise. </section><section prefix="17">To have and exercise all powers necessary or convenient to effect any or all of the purposes for which the corporation is organized. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 179, effective January 1, 1989. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13607</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>