<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.652Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Natural History Museum -- Board of directors -- Appointments, terms, and meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>652Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To achieve the purposes of KRS 146.650 to 146.666, the Kentucky Natural History Museum is created. The museum shall serve Kentuckians as a focal point of educational resources to: <section prefix="a">Support teaching the natural sciences and anthropology in Kentucky and to educate the public about the unique and diverse natural history of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Encourage the conservation of the state's natural resources; </section><section prefix="c">Create a stable repository for scientifically valuable and irreplaceable biological, geological, and archeological specimens; and </section><section prefix="d">Encourage the repatriation and preservation of Kentucky specimens that have been or may be sent outside the state because those specimens cannot be financially supported by their owners. </section></section><section prefix="2">The museum shall be developed and administered by a board of directors comprised of the following: <section prefix="a">The director of the Kentucky Geological Survey; </section><section prefix="b">The director of the Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission; </section><section prefix="c">The executive director of the Kentucky Heritage Council; </section><section prefix="d">The executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society; </section><section prefix="e">The commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources; and </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) members representing the Kentucky Academy of Science, one (1) each from the disciplines of biology and anthropology, who shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of four (4) nominees, two (2) from each discipline, submitted by the Kentucky Academy of Science. </section></section><section prefix="3">The director of the Kentucky Natural History Museum shall serve as an ex officio member of the board of directors, be counted for purposes of establishing a quorum for conducting business, and be entitled to participate in deliberations of the board, but shall not be entitled to vote when official actions are taken by the board. </section><section prefix="4">The first chair of the Kentucky Natural History Museum Board of Directors shall be the executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society, who shall call the first meeting of the board. At the first meeting, the board shall elect a chair. Each chair elected by the board shall serve a single term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Academy of Science's appointees shall serve three (3) year terms, and they may be reappointed for a second term. </section><section prefix="6">Nominees for appointment to the board shall have resided in Kentucky for at least one (1) year immediately prior to their consideration for appointment. </section><section prefix="7">The board may request the Governor to replace an appointed member who fails to attend three (3) consecutive board meetings. </section><section prefix="8">The appointed members of the board shall serve without pay but shall be paid for expenses directly related to attending board meetings and to performing board authorized activities. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall meet at least four (4) times a year. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44489</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>