<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.545</section_number><catch_line>Registrant prohibited from residing in certain areas and being present on school grounds -- Violations -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>545</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No registrant, as defined in KRS 17.500, shall reside within one thousand (1,000) feet of a high school, middle school, elementary school, preschool, publicly owned playground, or licensed day care facility. The measurement shall be taken in a straight line from the nearest property line of the school to the nearest property line of the registrant's place of residence. </section><section prefix="2">No registrant, as defined in KRS 17.500, nor any person residing outside of Kentucky who would be required to register under KRS 17.510 if the person resided in Kentucky, shall be on the clearly defined grounds of a high school, middle school, elementary school, preschool, or licensed day care facility, except with the advance written permission of the school principal, the school board, or the day care director that has been given after full disclosure of the person's status as a registrant or sex offender from another state and all registrant information as required in KRS 17.500. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">The registrant shall have the duty to ascertain whether any property listed in subsection (1) of this section is within one thousand (1,000) feet of the registrant's residence; and </section><section prefix="b">If a new facility opens, the registrant shall be presumed to know and, within ninety (90) days, shall comply with this section. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates subsection (1) of this section shall be guilty of: <section prefix="a">A Class A misdemeanor for a first offense; and </section><section prefix="b">A Class D felony for the second and each subsequent offense. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any registrant residing within one thousand (1,000) feet of a high school, middle school, elementary school, preschool, publicly owned playground, or licensed day care facility on July 12, 2006, shall move and comply with this section within ninety (90) days of July 12, 2006, and thereafter, shall be subject to the penalties set forth under subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to a youthful offender probated or paroled during his or her minority or while enrolled in an elementary or secondary education program. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 29, effective April 11, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification>KRS 17.495. </former-codification><lrc-note>(6/25/2009).  A reference in subsection (5) of this statute to "subsection (3) of this section" has been changed in codification to "subsection (4) of this section" to accurately reflect the renumbering of subsections of this statute in 2009 Ky. Acts ch.38, sec 2. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1256</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>