<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.020</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of state local debt officer and state local finance officer. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state local debt officer and the state local finance officer within the Department for Local Government shall exercise the following administrative functions of the state: <section prefix="a">The state local debt officer shall exercise all administrative functions as provided in the county debt act, KRS 66.280 to 66.390, and administrative functions relating to local government bonds as provided in KRS 66.045; and </section><section prefix="b">The state local finance officer shall exercise all administrative functions regarding county and local government budgets, as provided in KRS 68.210 to 68.360. </section></section><section prefix="2">The state local debt officer shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="a">To require reports from local governments to enable him to adequately provide the technical and advisory assistance authorized by this section. The reports shall provide the necessary information for a complete file on local government debt, which the state local debt officer shall keep open for public inspection at the Department for Local Government; </section><section prefix="b">To conduct studies in debt management, including ways and means of appraising the terms of alternative bids; </section><section prefix="c">To request assistance and information, which shall be provided by all departments, divisions, boards, bureaus, commissions, and other agencies of state government, to enable the state local debt officer to carry out his duties under this section; and </section><section prefix="d">To compile and publish annually a report which shall include detailed information on local government long-term debt issued and retired during the previous year and outstanding, and other available statistical data on local government finances. </section></section><section prefix="3">The state local finance officer shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="a">To coordinate for the Governor the state's responsibility for, and shall be responsible for liaison with the appropriate state and federal agencies with respect to, general revenue sharing for local government; </section><section prefix="b">To provide technical assistance and information to units of local government on matters including but not limited to fiscal management, purchases, and contracts; and </section><section prefix="c">To conduct training programs to instruct county and other local officials respecting their duties and responsibilities in the collection, expenditure, and management of public moneys subject to their control and jurisdiction. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 67, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 53, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 85, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 108, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 295, sec. 103, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 68, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 10. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>