<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.640</section_number><catch_line>City-county health department in county containing city with population of 15,000 or more -- Establishment -- Membership of board.   </catch_line><order_by>640</order_by><text>In any county containing a city, as defined in KRS 212.641, the fiscal court of the county and the legislative body of the city may, by joint action, establish a city-county health department. The department when established shall be governed by a city-county board of health composed of twelve (12) members, one (1) of whom shall be either the mayor, city manager, or the designee of the city manager of the city, whichever is appointed by the city legislative body, one (1) of whom shall be the county judge/executive, one (1) of whom shall be a dentist, one (1) of whom shall be a registered nurse, and three (3) of whom shall be physicians, one (1) of whom shall be a veterinarian, one (1) of whom shall be an engineer engaged in the practice of civil or sanitary engineering, one (1) of whom shall be an optometrist, one (1) licensed pharmacist, and one (1) lay person knowledgeable in consumer affairs residing in each county and appointed in the same manner as county board of health members and to hold office as provided in KRS 212.020. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 270, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 462, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43855</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>