<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.035</section_number><catch_line>Official repository for groundwater information. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Geological Survey shall be designated as the Commonwealth's official repository for all information relating to the occurrence and quality of groundwater as defined in KRS 151.100. </section><section prefix="2">The Energy and Environment Cabinet, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and any other cabinet, department, commission, board, or governmental agency, except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, that, by statute, administrative regulation, or as part of its routine activities, collects or generates information about groundwater, shall transmit or cause to be transmitted that information to the Kentucky Geological Survey within ninety (90) days of receipt or generation, or a time determined between the Geological Survey and the other party. </section><section prefix="3">The information to be transmitted may include: <section prefix="a">Drillers logs and completion reports of wells drilled or dug for the purpose of producing, testing, or monitoring groundwater; </section><section prefix="b">Geophysical logs of water wells; </section><section prefix="c">Water quality analyses of both organic and inorganic constituents; </section><section prefix="d">Results of all pump, extraction, and injection tests; </section><section prefix="e">Flow determinations of surface discharges of groundwater; and </section><section prefix="f">Any additional data as the Kentucky Geological Survey shall require. </section></section><section prefix="4">All institutions of higher learning shall be encouraged, but not required, to submit to the Kentucky Geological Survey copies of all research data, including theses and dissertations relating to the occurrence or quality of groundwater. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 176, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 121, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 105, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2074</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>