<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.7-419</section_number><catch_line>Derivative transactions -- Hedging -- Income generation -- Counterparty exposure amounts. </catch_line><order_by>7-419</order_by><text>An insurer may, directly or indirectly through an investment subsidiary, engage in derivative transactions under this section under the following conditions: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">An insurer may use derivative instruments under this section to engage in hedging transactions and certain income generation transactions, as these terms may be further defined in regulations promulgated by the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="b">An insurer shall be able to demonstrate to the commissioner the intended hedging characteristics and the ongoing effectiveness of the derivative transaction or combination of the transactions through cash flow testing or other appropriate analyses. </section></section><section prefix="2">An insurer may enter into hedging transactions under this section if, as a result of and after giving effect to the transaction: <section prefix="a">The aggregate statement value of options, caps, floors, and warrants not attached to another financial instrument purchased and used in hedging transactions does not exceed seven and one-half percent (7.5%) of its admitted assets; </section><section prefix="b">The aggregate statement value of options, caps, and floors written in hedging transactions does not exceed three percent (3%) of its admitted assets; and </section><section prefix="c">The aggregate potential exposure of collars, swaps, forwards, and futures used in hedging transactions does not exceed six and one-half percent (6.5%) of its admitted assets. </section></section><section prefix="3">An insurer may only enter into the following types of income generation transactions if, as a result of and after giving effect to the transactions, the aggregate statement value of the fixed income assets that are subject to call or that generate the cash flows for payments under the caps or floors, plus the face value of fixed income securities underlying a derivative instrument subject to call, plus the amount of the purchase obligations under the puts, does not exceed ten percent (10%) of its admitted assets: <section prefix="a">Sales of covered call options on noncallable fixed income securities, callable fixed income securities if the option expires by its terms prior to the end of the noncallable period, or derivative instruments based on fixed income securities; </section><section prefix="b">Sales of covered call options on equity securities, if the insurer holds in its portfolio, or can immediately acquire through the exercise of options, warrants, or conversion rights already owned, the equity securities subject to call during the complete term of the call options sold; </section><section prefix="c">Sales of covered puts on investments that the insurer is permitted to acquire under this subtitle, if the insurer has escrowed or entered into a custodian agreement segregating cash or cash equivalents with a market value equal to the amount of its purchase obligations under the put during the complete term of the put option sold; or </section><section prefix="d">Sales of covered caps or floors, if the insurer holds in its portfolio the investments generating the cash flow to make the required payments under the caps or floors during the complete term that the cap or floor is outstanding. </section></section><section prefix="4">An insurer shall include all counterparty exposure amounts in determining compliance with the limitations of KRS 304.7-403. </section><section prefix="5">In accordance with administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 304.7-367, the commissioner may approve additional transactions involving the use of derivative instruments in excess of the limits of subsection (2) of this section or for other risk management purposes under administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner, but replication transactions shall not be permitted for other than risk management purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1019, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 16, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16849</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>