<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.541</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 278.541 to 278.544. </catch_line><order_by>541</order_by><text>In addition to the definitions set forth in KRS 278.010 and 278.516(2), the following definitions shall apply to KRS 278.541 to 278.544: <section prefix="1">"Basic local exchange service" means a retail telecommunications service consisting of a primary, single, voice-grade line provided to the premises of residential or business customers with the following features and functions only: <section prefix="a">Unlimited calls within the telephone utility's local exchange area; </section><section prefix="b">Dual-tone multifrequency dialing; and </section><section prefix="c">Access to the following: <section prefix="1">Emergency 911 telephone service; </section><section prefix="2">All locally available interexchange companies; </section><section prefix="3">Directory assistance; </section><section prefix="4">Operator services; </section><section prefix="5">Relay services; and </section><section prefix="6">A standard alphabetical directory listing that includes names, addresses, and telephone numbers at no additional charge. </section></section></section> With respect to local exchange carriers, basic local exchange service also shall include any mandatory extended area service routes accessible as a local call within that exchange area on or before July 12, 2006. Basic local exchange service does not include any features or functions other than those listed in this subsection, nor any other communications service, even if such service should include features and functions listed herein; <section prefix="2">"Electing utility" means a telephone utility that elects to operate under KRS 278.543; </section><section prefix="3">"Local exchange carrier" or "LEC" has the same meaning as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 153(26); </section><section prefix="4">"Incumbent local exchange carrier" or "ILEC" has the same meaning as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 251(h); </section><section prefix="5">"Nonbasic service" means all retail telecommunications services provided to a residential or business customer, all arrangements with respect to those services, and all packages of products or services; provided, however, nonbasic service includes basic local exchange service only if the customer chooses to purchase a package that includes basic local exchange service as a component of the package; </section><section prefix="6">"Optional telephone feature" means any of those central office-based features that were tariffed by a local exchange carrier on or before February 1, 2006, that, where available: <section prefix="a">Are available to a line-side connection in a telephone switch: </section><section prefix="b">Are available on a stand-alone basis separate from a bundled offering; and </section><section prefix="c">Enhance the utility of basic local exchange service. </section></section> The term includes but is not limited to call forwarding, call waiting, and caller ID; <section prefix="7">"Package" means combinations of retail products or services offered, whether at a single price or with the availability of the price for one (1) product or service contingent on the purchase of others; and </section><section prefix="8">"Telephone utility" includes local exchange carriers and telecommunications carriers as those terms are defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 153 and any federal regulations implementing that section, except that the definition shall not include commercial mobile radio service providers as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 332 and the Federal Communications Commission's lawful regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14149</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>