<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.910</section_number><catch_line>Members of board -- Terms -- Chairman -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state board shall be composed of the following members: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the chief state school officer, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, and the Attorney General, or designees authorized to speak on their behalf; and </section><section prefix="b">Ten (10) public members appointed by the Governor. It is recommended that, as a group, the public members shall demonstrate knowledge in the area of child sexual abuse and exploitation prevention; shall be representative of the demographic composition of this state; and, to the extent practicable, shall be representative of all the following categories: parents, school administrators, law enforcement, the religious community, the legal community, the medical community, professional providers of child sexual abuse and exploitation prevention services, and volunteers in child sexual abuse and exploitation prevention services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The term of each public member shall be three (3) years, except that of the public members first appointed, three (3) shall serve for three (3) years, three (3) for two (2) years, and four (4) for one (1) year. A public member shall not serve more than two (2) consecutive terms, whether partial or full. A vacancy shall be filled for the balance of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="3">The Attorney General shall serve as chairman or designate a chairperson of the state board in which case the chairperson shall serve in that position at the pleasure of the Attorney General. The state board may elect other officers and committees as it considers appropriate. </section><section prefix="4">There shall be no per diem compensation; however, the schedule for reimbursement of expenses for the public members of the state board shall be the same as for state employees. The reimbursement, executive director and staff salaries, and all actual and necessary operating expenses of the state board shall be paid from the trust fund, pursuant to an authorization as provided in KRS 15.935. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 34, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 83, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 67, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective March 2, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1012</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>