<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.235</section_number><catch_line>Grants-in-aid to promote the arts -- Funds, how handled -- Property, how held. </catch_line><order_by>235</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The council may establish and carry out a program of grants-in-aid to groups or, in appropriate cases, to individuals engaged in or concerned with the arts for the purpose of enabling them to provide or support in Kentucky any of the following: <section prefix="a">Productions which have substantial artistic and cultural significance, giving emphasis to creativity and the maintenance and encouragement of professional excellence; </section><section prefix="b">Projects which will encourage and assist artists and enable them to achieve standards of professional excellence; </section><section prefix="c">Workshops which will encourage and develop the appreciation and enjoyment of the arts by residents of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="d">Other relevant projects, giving emphasis to creativity, including surveys, research, and planning in the arts. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any group or individual desirous of receiving a grant-in-aid must submit an application to the council that shall contain such data as the council may require. </section><section prefix="3">The receipt, control, and expenditure of funds shall be subject to the general provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes governing financial administration of all state agencies. Any real property acquired shall be held in the name of the Commonwealth for the use and benefit of the council; and the acquisition, control, or disposal of such property shall be subject to the applicable provisions of KRS Chapters 45, 45A and 56. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2(12). </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2463</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>