<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.040</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications -- Examinations -- Reciprocity. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for a master or journeyman plumber's license shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Be of good moral character; </section><section prefix="c">Be a citizen of the United States or be a resident alien who is authorized to work in the United States; and </section><section prefix="d">Possess all the other qualifications that may be prescribed by administrative regulations of the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, no master or journeyman plumber's license shall be issued except upon a successful passage of an examination as prescribed by the department. </section><section prefix="3">Examinations for a license as a master plumber or journeyman plumber shall be conducted at times and places fixed by the regulations of the commissioner. Applicants for an examination shall furnish the information required by the commissioner and shall receive from the department due notice of the time and place of the examination. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall prepare or cause to be prepared under its supervision examinations consisting of written and practical tests with such questions and tests by which the department will determine: <section prefix="a">With respect to master plumber's license applicants, that applicants are qualified in view of the definitions, provisions, and purposes of this chapter to carry on responsibly, reasonably, and competently, the activities which a licensed master plumber is authorized to engage in by this chapter; and </section><section prefix="b">With respect to journeyman plumber's license applicants, their knowledge and competency to carry on the activities which a licensed journeyman plumber is authorized to engage in by this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="5">The examination papers shall be preserved by the department for a period of one (1) year. </section><section prefix="6">The department may issue a license to any person who holds a valid license in another state if that state has a statewide plumbing code and, in the opinion of the Plumbing Code Committee, the other state's examination is at least equal to that of Kentucky and the other state agrees to reciprocate with Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1673, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 50, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(22). -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3909b-4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31187</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>