<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.789</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against employing certain felons at long-term care facilities, in nursing pools providing staff to nursing facilities, or in assisted-living communities -- Preemployment check with Justice and Public Safety Cabinet -- Temporary employment. </catch_line><order_by>789</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No long-term care facility as defined by KRS 216.535(1), nursing pool providing staff to a nursing facility, or assisted-living community shall knowingly employ a person in a position which involves providing direct services to a resident or client if that person has been convicted of a felony offense related to theft; abuse or sale of illegal drugs; abuse, neglect, or exploitation of an adult; or a sexual crime. </section><section prefix="2">A nursing facility, nursing pool providing staff to a nursing facility, or assisted-living community may employ persons convicted of or pleading guilty to an offense classified as a misdemeanor if the crime is not related to abuse, neglect, or exploitation of an adult. </section><section prefix="3">Each long-term care facility as defined by KRS 216.535(1), nursing pool providing staff to a nursing facility, or assisted-living community shall request all conviction information from the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet for any applicant for employment pursuant to KRS 216.793. </section><section prefix="4">The long-term care facility, nursing pool providing staff to a nursing facility, or assisted-living community may temporarily employ an applicant pending the receipt of the conviction information. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 248, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 17, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 380, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 427, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>