<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.681</section_number><catch_line>Advisory opinions. </catch_line><order_by>681</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission may render advisory opinions concerning matters under its jurisdiction, based upon real or hypothetical circumstances, when requested by: <section prefix="a">Any person covered by this code; </section><section prefix="b">Any person who is personally and directly involved in the matter; or </section><section prefix="c">The commission upon its own initiative. </section></section><section prefix="2">An advisory opinion shall be requested in writing and shall state relevant facts and ask specific questions. The request for the advisory opinion shall remain confidential unless confidentiality is waived, in writing, by the requestor. </section><section prefix="3">Advisory opinions shall be based on the Kentucky Revised Statutes as written and shall not be based on the personal opinions of commission members as to legislative intent or the spirit of the law. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish criteria under which it may issue confidential advisory opinions. All other advisory opinions shall be published except that before an advisory opinion is made public, it shall be modified so that the identity of any person associated with the opinion shall not be revealed. </section><section prefix="5">The confidentiality of an advisory opinion may be waived either: <section prefix="a">In writing by the person who requested the opinion; or </section><section prefix="b">By majority vote of the members of the commission, if a person makes or purports to make public the substance or any portion of an advisory opinion requested by or on behalf of the person. The commission may vote to make public the advisory opinion request and related materials. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A written advisory opinion issued by the commission shall be binding on the commission in any subsequent proceeding concerning the facts and circumstances of the particular case if no intervening facts or circumstances arise which would change the opinion of the commission if they had existed at the time the opinion was rendered. However, if any fact determined by the commission to be material was omitted or misstated in the request for an opinion, the commission shall not be bound by the opinion. </section><section prefix="b">A written advisory opinion shall be admissible in the defense of any criminal prosecution or civil proceeding for violations of this code for actions taken in reliance on that opinion. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 479, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 42, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>