<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.300</section_number><catch_line>Lien of dry cleaner, launderer, or tailor on article for work done -- Sale for charges -- Notification and criteria for sale. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who cleans, presses, glazes, launders, alters, or repairs any wearing apparel or household goods shall have a lien on the article remaining in his possession to secure the reasonable or agreed charge for the service. If the charge is not paid within ninety (90) days, the article may be sold to pay the charges and costs of notice, after notice has been given the customer of the time and place of sale. </section><section prefix="2">The notice of time and place of sale, when given, shall be by registered letter mailed to the last known address of the customer. The person sending the letter may do so anytime after an article has been held for at least sixty (60) days, and the notice by registered letter shall specify that the article may be sold unless it is redeemed within thirty (30) days from the date of the letter. </section><section prefix="3">Any article which is left with any person who cleans, presses, glazes, launders, alters, or repairs any wearing apparel or other household goods and which is not redeemed by the customer within one hundred eighty (180) days shall be considered abandoned. It may, without any liability or responsibility for the article on the part of the person holding it and without notification to the customer, be sold or otherwise disposed of. </section><section prefix="4">The foregoing provisions shall not apply to property that is to be placed in storage with the person rendering any service mentioned above, but such property shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 376.310. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2504b-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>