<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.650</section_number><catch_line>Veterans' Personal Loan Program. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Department" means the Department of Veterans' Affairs; and </section><section prefix="b">"Veteran" means a person who served in the active Armed Forces of the United States, including the Coast Guard of the United States, and was released, separated, discharged, or retired therefrom under honorable or general conditions. </section></section><section prefix="2">A veterans' personal loan program trust fund is established to oversee and administer funds under the Veterans' Personal Loan Program. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">To be eligible for a loan under the Veterans' Personal Loan Program, an applicant shall be a resident of, and living in, the Commonwealth on the date of the application. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">As used in this paragraph, "qualified" means having met loan conditions established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the department. However, the term of a loan shall not exceed ten (10) years. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall cause the veterans' personal loan program trust fund to lend a qualified veteran or deceased veteran's unremarried spouse not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), or a lesser amount established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the department, for: <section prefix="a">The purchase of a home, business, or business property; </section><section prefix="b">The education of the loan applicant or the loan applicant's spouse; </section><section prefix="c">The payment of family medical or funeral expenses; or </section><section prefix="d">The consolidation of debt. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department shall cause the veterans' personal loan trust fund to lend a qualified child of a veteran or parent or guardian of that child not more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), or a lesser amount established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the department, for the education of that child, who is under the age of twenty-seven (27), at a university, junior college, vocational training institute, or nonpublic school admitting children in preschool through grade twelve (12). </section></section><section prefix="c">No person shall receive a loan under this section in an amount that, when added to the balance of the person's existing loan or loans under this section, would result in a total indebtedness to the veterans' personal loan program trust fund of more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), or a lesser amount established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the department. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The veterans' personal loan program trust fund shall: <section prefix="1">Execute necessary instruments; and </section><section prefix="2">Collect principal and interest. </section></section><section prefix="b">The veterans' personal loan program trust fund may: <section prefix="1">Compromise indebtedness; </section><section prefix="2">Sue and be sued; </section><section prefix="3">Post bonds; </section><section prefix="4">Write off indebtedness that it considers uncollectible; </section><section prefix="5">Exercise the rights of an owner and mortgagee if a loan provided under this section is secured by a real estate mortgage; </section><section prefix="6">Charge to a loan applicant loan expenses incurred under this section; and </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, federal funds, and any other funds both public and private. </section><section prefix="b">Funds received, which are not necessary for the operation of the veterans' personal loan program trust fund, shall remain with the department to finance other department operations. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="5">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21880</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>