<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-335</section_number><catch_line>Requirement of creation of manifest system -- Contents of manifest -- Reporting -- Necessity of manifest for acceptance of waste. </catch_line><order_by>43-335</order_by><text>In order to assist in solid waste planning and management, to further the goals of waste reduction and recycling, and to assist in identification of parties in the event of environmental problems arising from the transport or disposal of the waste, the cabinet shall adopt administrative regulations creating a manifest system which shall require that each shipment of waste received at a municipal solid waste disposal facility or transfer facility be accompanied by written documentation in a form determined by the cabinet. The manifest shall identify the geographic source or sources of the waste, by county, city, and state; contain a description of the types of waste contained in the shipment; list the names and addresses of each transporter of the waste; and list the names and addresses of each solid waste management facility which handled the waste; and each broker who arranged or contracted for the transportation or disposal of the waste. Each municipal solid waste disposal facility shall indicate on the manifest the amount of waste by weight received from each transporter, and each transfer facility shall indicate on the manifest the amount of waste by weight received from each transporter and the amount of waste shipped from the facility for handling or disposal in Kentucky. The manifest shall provide a certification by each person named in the manifest that while the waste was in his custody or control no waste regulated by the cabinet as hazardous waste or infectious waste was knowingly introduced into the waste. A copy of each manifest shall be maintained at the municipal solid waste disposal facility and any transfer facility handling the waste, and shall be open to inspection by representatives of the cabinet, shall be transmitted to the cabinet on a quarterly basis, and shall be considered nonexempt records available for public inspection. Ninety (90) days after the effective date of the initial administrative regulations adopted by the cabinet to effectuate this section, no municipal solid waste disposal facility or transfer facility shall accept waste unless it is accompanied by a manifest. </text><history> Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 28, effective February 26, 1991. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> February 26, 1991 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.849. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>