<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.315</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of agency, special, and other funds to general fund in budget bill. </catch_line><order_by>315</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly may provide in a budget bill for the transfer to the general fund for the purpose of the general fund all or part of the agency funds, special funds, or other funds established under the provisions of KRS 15.430; 21.347; 21.540; 21.560; 42.500; 47.010; 48.010(15)(g); 56.100; 61.470; 64.345; 64.350; 64.355; 95A.220; 136.392; 138.510; 161.420; 161.430; 164A.020; 164A.110; 164A.800; 164A.810; 216A.110; 230.218; 230.400; 230.770; 248.540; 248.550; 278.130; 278.150; 286.1-485; 304.35-030; 311.450; 311.610; 312.019; 313.022; 314.161; 315.195; 316.210; 317.530; 317A.080; 319.131; 320.360; 321.320; 322.290; 322.330; 322.420; 323.080; 323.190; 323.210; 323A.060; 323A.190; 323A.210; 324.286; 324.410; 325.250; 326.120; 327.080; 330.050; 334.160; 334A.120; 335.140; 342.122; 342.480, etc. </section><section prefix="2">The transfer of moneys from the agency funds, special funds, or other funds to the general fund provided for in subsection (1) of this section shall be for the period of time specified in the budget bill. </section><section prefix="3">Any provisions of any statute in conflict with the provisions of subsections (1) and (2) of this section are hereby suspended or modified. Any suspension or modification shall not extend beyond the duration of the budget bill. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 4, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 39, effective March 30, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006). 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 instructs the Reviser of Statutes to adjust KRS references throughout the statutes to conform with the 2006 renumbering of the Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. Such an adjustment has been made in this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22565</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>