<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.345</section_number><catch_line>School superintendent or principal to be notified when child found guilty or when petition is filed -- Disclosure of records -- Provision of offense history to school superintendent. </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a child is adjudicated guilty of an offense which classifies him or her as a youthful offender, the judge in the court in which the matter was tried shall direct the clerk to notify the superintendent of the public school district in which the child is enrolled or the principal of any private elementary or secondary school which the child attends of the adjudication and the petition and disposition of the case. The name of the complainant shall be deleted. The court shall direct the appropriate prosecuting entity to give the school district or the school a statement of facts in the case. The superintendent shall notify the principal of the school in which the child is enrolled. </section><section prefix="2">When a child is adjudicated guilty of an offense which would classify him or her as a violent offender under KRS 439.3401, or be a felony under KRS Chapter 218A, 508, 510, or 527 if committed by an adult, but which would not classify him or her as a youthful offender, the judge in the court in which the matter was tried shall direct the clerk to notify within five (5) days of the order the superintendent of the public school district in which the child is enrolled or the principal of any private elementary or secondary school which the child attends of the charge, the adjudication, and the disposition of the case. The name of the complainant shall be deleted. The court shall authorize the county attorney to give the school district or the school a statement of facts in the case. The superintendent shall notify the principal of the school in which the child is enrolled. </section><section prefix="3">When a petition is filed against a child, or a child is adjudicated guilty of an offense that would be a felony or misdemeanor if committed by an adult, and the misdemeanor involves a controlled substance or the possession, carrying, or use of a deadly weapon, or physical injury to another person, the judge in the court in which the matter is considered shall direct the clerk to notify the superintendent of the public school district in which the child is enrolled or the principal of any private elementary or secondary school that the child attends of the charge, the adjudication, and the disposition of the case. The notification shall be made within twenty-four (24) hours of the time when the petition is filed. The name of the complainant shall be deleted. The court shall authorize the county attorney to give the school district or the school a statement of the facts in the case, not to include the complainant's name. If the petition is dismissed, all records of the incident or notification created in the school district or the school under this subsection shall be destroyed, and shall not be included in the child's school records. </section><section prefix="4">Notice of adjudication to a district superintendent referenced in subsections (2) and (3) of this section shall be released by the superintendent to the principal. A principal of a public or private school receiving notice of adjudication shall release the information to employees of the school having responsibility for classroom instruction or counseling of the child and may release it to other school personnel as described in subsection (5) of this section, but the information shall otherwise be confidential and shall not be shared by school personnel with any other person or agency except as may otherwise be required by law. The notification in writing of the nature of the offense committed by the child and any probation requirements shall not become a part of the child's student record. </section><section prefix="5">Records or information disclosed pursuant to this section shall be limited to records of that student's criminal petition and the disposition thereof covered by this section, shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 610.320 and 610.340, and shall not be disclosed to any other person, including school personnel, except to a district superintendent, public or private elementary and secondary school administrative, transportation, and counseling personnel, and to any teacher or school employee with whom the student may come in contact. This section shall not authorize the disclosure of any other juvenile record or information relating to the child. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Juvenile Justice shall provide a child's offense history information pursuant to this section to the superintendent of the local school district in which the child, who is committed to the department, is placed. </section><section prefix="7">Records or information received by the school pursuant to this section shall be kept in a locked file, when not in use, to be opened only on permission of the administrator. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 70, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1998; and ch.  606, sec. 182, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20173</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>