<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30">A COURT PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>30A.400</section_number><catch_line>Interpreters -- Appointment -- Hearing to determine need. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a person has been detained in police custody or has been arrested, an interpreter shall be provided prior to any interrogation or taking of a statement from the person if the court determines he meets the criteria set forth in KRS 30A.410. </section><section prefix="2">Any statement made by a person who is entitled to the services of an interpreter under subsection (1) of this section to a law enforcement officer may be used as evidence against that person only if the statement was made, offered, or elicited in the presence of a qualified interpreter. This subsection shall not deny a person the right to make a voluntary confession. </section><section prefix="3">If the eligibility of the individual for an interpreter is challenged, the judge may, on good cause shown, hold a hearing to determine the bona fide need for interpreter services. </section><section prefix="4">If it is determined that the person is not entitled to these services, no portion of KRS 30A.425 to 30A.435 shall apply to him. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 452, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 64, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 405 and 452 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21204</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>