<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.275</section_number><catch_line>Distribution of nonscheduled legend drugs at health department by advanced practice registered nurse or registered nurse -- Written policy -- Record of prescription drugs -- Responsibility for inventory -- Pharmacist -- Dispensing medication or device prescribed for purpose of causing abortion. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The governing board for each local, district, and independent health department shall have a written policy concerning the distribution of nonscheduled legend drugs at the health department by an advanced practice registered nurse or a registered nurse. In a health department, an advanced practice registered nurse or a registered nurse may distribute nonscheduled legend drugs from a list that has been prepared by the commissioner of the Department for Public Health. Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit advanced practice registered nurses from dispensing nonscheduled drug samples under KRS 314.011. Each prescription drug distributed or dispensed at the health department shall be recorded in the patient record. The director of each health department shall be responsible for keeping track of the inventory of stock medications and accounting for the medications dispensed or distributed. </section><section prefix="2">Only a health department board having within its membership a pharmacist holding a valid license issued pursuant to KRS 315.030 shall be authorized to permit advanced practice registered nurses or registered nurses to dispense nonscheduled legend drugs according to the written policy of the board. If a health department is unable to recruit a licensed pharmacist to serve on the board, the board shall document consultation with a pharmacist licensed pursuant to KRS 315.030 in the public health practice of the health department. </section><section prefix="3">No health department shall dispense any medication or device prescribed for the purpose of causing an abortion as defined in KRS 311.720(1). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 37, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>