<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.550</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Equine Industry Program -- Purpose -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established an Equine Industry Program at the University of Louisville, under the general control and direction of the university. The purpose of the Equine Industry Program is to provide training and educational opportunities in the horse racing industry relating to, but not limited to, finance, management, marketing, regulation and administration aspects of the horse racing industry, in accordance with the industry needs as determined by the university. </section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created a trust and revolving fund for the Equine Industry Program, consisting of money allocated to the fund together with money as may be contributed to the fund from all other sources. Money to the credit of the Equine Industry Program fund at the end of each fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the succeeding fiscal year. Money from the Equine Industry Program fund shall be administered by the University of Louisville and shall be allocated for the funding of the Equine Industry Program. </section><section prefix="3">The University of Louisville shall utilize personnel and facilities of the University of Kentucky when appropriate for assistance in any cooperative undertakings the University of Louisville may wish to enter into with the University of Kentucky relating to the Equine Industry Program. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10907</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>