<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.80-310</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Waterway Marina Development Program -- Powers of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>80-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created within the cabinet a Kentucky Waterway Marina Development Program. The cabinet shall study various plans and recommendations that are proposed concerning marina development along Kentucky navigable waterways. Based on these studies, the cabinet shall formulate a comprehensive plan, recommend state and local legislation for the development of marinas, and coordinate the implementation of the plan and legislation. The cabinet may make grants of money to units of local government for the construction or improvement of any marina, if the grants are consistent with the plans, standards, and criteria established by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">If necessary to further the accomplishment of its purposes, the cabinet may do the following: <section prefix="a">Conduct all studies necessary for the performance of its duties; </section><section prefix="b">Publicize, advertise, and distribute reports on its purposes, objectives and findings; </section><section prefix="c">Provide recommendations in matters related to its functions and objectives to political subdivisions in and adjacent to the waterway corridor and to other public and private agencies; </section><section prefix="d">If requested, act as a coordinating agency for programs and activities of other public and private organizations that are related to its objectives; </section><section prefix="e">Acquire and dispose of real or personal property by grant, gift, purchase, lease, devise, or otherwise; and </section><section prefix="f">Hold, use, improve, maintain, operate, own, manage, or lease, as lessor or lessee, real or personal property, or any interest in that property. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may receive grants and appropriations from federal, state, and local governments, individuals, foundations, and other organizations. The cabinet may enter into agreements or contracts regarding the acceptance or use of these grants and appropriations for the purpose of carrying out its activities under this section. </section><section prefix="4">The goal for any marina project under this section shall be to create employment in the private sector. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 40, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification> KRS 154.360 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2982</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>