<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.13-165</section_number><catch_line>Information to be filed by advisory organization. </catch_line><order_by>13-165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every advisory organization shall file with the commissioner every statistical plan, all prospective loss costs, provisions for special assessments, and all supplementary rating information, and every change or amendment or modification of any of the foregoing proposed for use in Kentucky. Each filing shall be filed thirty (30) days before it becomes effective, which period may be extended by the commissioner for an additional period not to exceed thirty (30) days, if written notice is given within the initial thirty (30) day period to the advisory organization that additional time is needed for the consideration of the filing. The commissioner may, upon giving written notice to the advisory organization, request additional information that is needed to complete the review of the filing. If the commissioner requests such additional information prior to the filing becoming effective, the filing shall become effective thirty (30) days after the additional information is provided to the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Upon written application by the advisory organization, the commissioner may authorize an earlier effective date. </section><section prefix="3">All filings shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 304.13-081 and all other provisions of this chapter relating to filings made by insurers. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1133, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17084</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>