<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.331</section_number><catch_line>Review by the senior force judge advocate.   </catch_line><order_by>331</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each general and special court-martial case in which there has been a finding of guilty shall be reviewed by the senior force judge advocate, or a designee. The senior force judge advocate or designee may not review a case under this subsection if that person has acted in the same case as an accuser, investigating officer, member of the court, military judge, or counsel or has otherwise acted on behalf of the prosecution or defense. The senior force judge advocate's review shall be in writing and shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">Conclusions as to whether: <section prefix="1">The court had jurisdiction over the accused and the offense; </section><section prefix="2">The charge and specification stated an offense; and </section><section prefix="3">The sentence was within the limits prescribed as a matter of law; </section></section><section prefix="b">A response to each allegation of error made in writing by the accused; and </section><section prefix="c">If the case is sent for action under subsection (2) of this section, a recommendation as to the appropriate action to be taken and an opinion as to whether corrective action is required as a matter of law. </section></section><section prefix="2">The record of trial and related documents in each case reviewed under subsection (1) of this section shall be sent for action to the adjutant general if: <section prefix="a">The judge advocate who reviewed the case recommends corrective action; </section><section prefix="b">The sentence approved under KRS 35.326(3) extends to dismissal, a bad-conduct or dishonorable discharge, or confinement for more than six (6) months; or </section><section prefix="c">Action is otherwise required by regulations of the adjutant general. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The adjutant general may: <section prefix="1">Disapprove or approve the findings or sentence, in whole or in part; </section><section prefix="2">Remit, commute, or suspend the sentence in whole or in part; </section><section prefix="3">Except where the evidence was insufficient at the trial to support the findings, order a rehearing on the findings, on the sentence, or on both; or </section><section prefix="4">Dismiss the charges. </section></section><section prefix="b">If a rehearing is ordered but the convening authority finds a rehearing impracticable, the convening authority shall dismiss the charges. </section><section prefix="c">If the opinion of the senior force judge advocate, or designee, in the senior force judge's review under subsection (1) of this section is that corrective action is required as a matter of law and if the adjutant general does not take action that is at least as favorable to the accused as that recommended by the judge advocate, the record of trial and action thereon shall be sent to the Governor for review and action as deemed appropriate. </section></section><section prefix="4">The senior force judge advocate, or a designee, may review any case in which there has been a finding of not guilty of all charges and specifications. The senior force judge advocate, or designee, may not review a case under this subsection if that person has acted in the same case as an accuser, investigating officer, member of the court, military judge, or counsel or has otherwise acted on behalf of the prosecution or defense. The senior force judge advocate's review shall be limited to questions of subject matter jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="5">The record of trial and related documents in each case reviewed under subsection (4) of this section shall be sent to the adjutant general. The adjutant general may: <section prefix="a">When subject matter jurisdiction is found to be lacking, void the court-martial ab initio, with or without prejudice to the government, as the adjutant general deems appropriate; or </section><section prefix="b">Return the record of trial and related documents to the senior force judge advocate for appeal by the government as provided by law. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 69, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>