<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.0553</section_number><catch_line>Review and approval of precinct establishment order -- Resubmission of returned orders. </catch_line><order_by>0553</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive director of the State Board of Elections or his designee shall examine each proposed precinct establishment order submitted under KRS 117.0552 to determine if the order would establish precincts in compliance with KRS 117.055 to 117.0552. </section><section prefix="2">If the executive director or his designee determines that the proposed precinct establishment order would comply with KRS 117.055 to 117.0552, the executive director shall approve the proposed precinct establishment order no later than thirty (30) days after its receipt by the executive director. The order shall become effective upon the executive director's approval unless the order contains a different effective date. </section><section prefix="3">If the executive director or his designee determines that the proposed precinct establishment order would not comply with KRS 117.055 to 117.0552, the executive director shall return the proposed precinct establishment order to the county board of elections no later than thirty (30) days after he receives the proposed order. The order shall be accompanied by a letter from the executive director indicating specifically how the order would not comply with KRS 117.055 to 117.0552. </section><section prefix="4">If a proposed precinct establishment order is returned to a county board of elections under this section, the board may: <section prefix="a">Amend the proposed order so that the precincts may be established in compliance with KRS 117.055 to 117.0552; or </section><section prefix="b">Request an exemption under KRS 117.0554; or </section><section prefix="c">Request a hearing under KRS 117.0555. </section></section><section prefix="5">The county board of elections shall resubmit the proposed order to the executive director of the State Board of Elections with the amendment, request for an exemption, or request for a hearing. If the proposed order is resubmitted with an amendment, the executive director or his designee shall review and act upon the amended proposal in accordance with subsections (1) to (3) of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27355</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>