<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-760</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of insurance purchasing outlet. </catch_line><order_by>17A-760</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An insurance purchasing outlet shall: <section prefix="a">Set and collect fees to finance necessary costs incurred in marketing, selling, servicing, and administering its services; </section><section prefix="b">Offer health benefit plans to eligible persons; </section><section prefix="c">Provide premium and voucher collection services for participating insurers; </section><section prefix="d">Establish and adhere to appropriate administrative and accounting procedures for operating the health purchasing outlet; </section><section prefix="e">Establish and adhere to rules, conditions, and procedures for insurance purchasing outlet members and participating insurers; </section><section prefix="f">Establish and adhere to enrollment and participation requirements for insurance purchasing outlet members; </section><section prefix="g">Receive, review, and conduct appeals for persons who have been denied enrollment to an insurance purchasing outlet; </section><section prefix="h">Demonstrate and maintain at all times proof of financial responsibility and solvency; </section><section prefix="i">Prepare an annual report on the operations of the insurance purchasing outlet in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="j">Establish procedures for billing and collection of premiums from insurance purchasing outlet members; </section><section prefix="k">Establish procedures for collecting and redeeming vouchers; and </section><section prefix="l">Maintain an administrator license in accordance with Subtitle 9 of Chapter 304. </section></section><section prefix="2">An insurance purchasing outlet may: <section prefix="a">Contract with qualified third parties for any services necessary to carry out the powers and duties authorized or required by this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">Employ necessary staff; </section><section prefix="c">Sue or be sued; </section><section prefix="d">Contract with independent licensed administrators to adjust or settle claims, since the insurance purchasing outlet is prohibited from these activities in accordance with KRS 304.17A-758; and </section><section prefix="e">Employ, contract, or otherwise use licensed insurance agents to market and service coverage. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1254, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29355</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>