<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.330</section_number><catch_line>Lease of building -- Option to purchase. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text>Immediately upon the execution of the contract provided for by KRS 162.320, the person to whom the site is conveyed shall execute, acknowledge, and deliver to the governing body of the state educational institution, a lease of the site and the building to be erected thereon, for a term of one (1) year from the time the building is completed and ready for occupancy, with an option in the lessee to extend the term of the lease for a term of one <section prefix="1">year from the expiration of the original term of the lease and for one (1) year from the </section>expiration of each extended term of the lease, until the original term of the lease has been extended for a total number of years to be agreed upon by the parties at a rental which, if paid for the original term and for each of the full number of years for which the term of the lease may be extended, will amortize the total cost of the erection of the building and appurtenances. The rent shall be paid at such times as the parties to the lease agree upon. The lease shall provide that the lessee may, at the expiration of the original or any extended term, purchase the leased premises at a stated price, which shall be the balance of the total cost of the erection of the building and appurtenances not amortized by the payments of rent previously made by the lessee. The lease shall provide that in the event of the exercise of the option to purchase the leased premises or in the event the lease has been extended for the full number of years which it is agreed the same may be extended, and all rents and payments provided for in the lease have been made, the lessor shall convey the premises to the lessee in fee simple with covenant of general warranty of title. The lease may provide that the lessee shall, as additional rent for the leased premises, pay all taxes assessed against the leased premises, and the cost of insuring the building erected thereon against loss or damage by fire and windstorm in such sum as may be agreed by the parties thereto. </text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 574, effective July 13, 1990. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4535cc-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4060</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>