<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.675</section_number><catch_line>Prevention of transmission of sexually explicit materials to schools -- Administrative regulations -- Local school district policy on student Internet access. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to prevent sexually explicit material from being transmitted via any video or computer system, software or hardware product, or Internet service managed or provided to local schools or school districts. </section><section prefix="2">Each local school district and school shall utilize the latest available filtering technology to ensure that sexually explicit material is not made available to students. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Department of Education shall make available to school districts and schools upon request and without cost, state-of-the-art software products that enable local districts and schools to prevent access to sexually explicit material. The department shall also notify all school districts and schools of the availability of the software. Any product provided or obtained by a district or school shall meet the requirements of subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Each local school district shall establish a policy regarding student Internet access that shall include, but not be limited to, parental consent for student Internet use, teacher supervision of student computer use, and auditing procedures to determine whether education technology is being used for the purpose of accessing sexually explicit or other objectionable material. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3238</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>