<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.340</section_number><catch_line>Commission's purpose -- Reports -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text>The Kentucky Historical Events Celebration Commission shall: <section prefix="1">Prepare an overall program to include specific plans for celebrating the two hundredth anniversary of the founding of Fort Harrod, the first permanent settlement west of the Allegheny Mountains opening the West, the hundredth running of the Kentucky Derby, both of which occur in 1974, and the national bicentennial celebration to take place in 1976. </section><section prefix="2">Select persons and events to be commemorated and prepare or assist in the preparation of appropriate programs for the Fort Harrod and Kentucky Derby celebrations in 1974 and the national bicentennial celebration in 1976. In preparing its plans and programs, the commission shall give consideration to any plans advanced by civic, patriotic, historical or educational groups, and cooperate with them in all possible ways. The commission may designate special committees with representation from such groups to plan and conduct specific programs. </section><section prefix="3">Encourage the location and preservation of books, documents, manuscripts, letters, relics and other materials pertaining to the settlement of Kentucky, the Kentucky Derby, and Kentucky's important position in a nation which will celebrate 200 years of existence in 1976. </section><section prefix="4">Prepare and submit to the Governor on or before November 1, 1971, and each year thereafter, a complete report of the commission's activities and plans for the celebrations in 1974 and 1976. </section></text><history>Created 1970, Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2468</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>