<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.804</section_number><catch_line>Organizational structure of Office of Career and Technical Education -- Ombudsman.   </catch_line><order_by>804</order_by><text>The Office of Career and Technical Education shall have the following organizational structure: <section prefix="1">The commissioner of education shall appoint an assistant pursuant to KRS 12.050 and 156.010 and assign duties as appropriate; </section><section prefix="2">The appointing authority shall appoint an ombudsman pursuant to KRS 12.050 and specify his or her functions and duties; and </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Technical Education Personnel Board, pursuant to KRS 156.840, shall be attached to the Department of Education for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 45, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 151B.030. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42157</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>