<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.600</section_number><catch_line>Annual evaluation of family preservation services. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for health and family services shall conduct a yearly evaluation of family preservation services which shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The number of families in which family preservation services would be an available alternative to placement of the child if available; </section><section prefix="b">The number of families receiving family preservation services, the number of children in those families, and the number of children in those families who would have been placed in out-of-home care if family preservation services had not been available; </section><section prefix="c">Among those families receiving family preservation services, the number of children placed outside the home; </section><section prefix="d">The average cost per family of providing family preservation services; </section><section prefix="e">The estimated cost of out-of-home placement which would have been expended on behalf of those children who received family preservation services based on average lengths of stay and average costs of out-of-home placements; </section><section prefix="f">The number of children who remain unified with their families six (6) months and one (1) year after completion of family preservation services; and </section><section prefix="g">An overall evaluation of the progress of family preservation services programs during the preceding year, recommendations for improvements in delivery of this service, and a plan for the continued development of family preservation services to ensure progress toward statewide availability. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 208, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 172, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>