<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.070</section_number><catch_line>No liability for damages when serving outside limits of district or municipality -- Fire departments as agents of Commonwealth. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A municipal fire department, fire protection district fire department, and volunteer fire department and the personnel of each, answering any fire alarms, performing fire prevention services, or other duly authorized emergency services inside and outside of the corporate limits of its municipality, fire protection district, or area normally served by a volunteer fire department, shall be considered an agent of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and acting solely and alone in a governmental capacity, and such municipality, fire protection district, or area normally served by a volunteer fire department, shall not be liable in damages for any omission or act of commission or negligence while answering an alarm, performing fire prevention services, or other duly authorized emergency services. </section><section prefix="2">No municipal fire department, fire protection district fire department or volunteer fire department answering any fire alarms, performing fire prevention services or volunteer fire department services inside the corporate limits of the district shall be liable in damages for any omission or act of commission or negligence while answering or returning from any fire or reported fire, or doing or performing any fire prevention work under and by virtue of this chapter and said fire departments shall be considered agents of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and acting solely and alone in a governmental capacity. </section></text><history>Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 6. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 21. -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24443</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>