<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.210</section_number><catch_line>Examination and testing of meters and meter-testing devices. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission may provide instruments for, and carry on, the examination and testing of any meter or appliance used to measure the product or service of any utility, and the examination and testing of any instrument used by a utility to test the accuracy of any meter or appliance used to measure its products or services. </section><section prefix="2">Any patron of a utility may, upon request and payment of the fees fixed by the commission, have a test made of the meter or appliance by which his use of the products or services of the utility is measured. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may establish reasonable fees for testing such meters and appliances at the request of a patron of a utility. If the appliance is found to be commercially defective or inaccurate to the extent of more than two percent (2%) to the disadvantage of the patron, the fees shall be repaid to the patron and paid by the utility. </section><section prefix="4">If a utility demonstrates through sample testing that no statistically significant number of its meters over-register above the limits set out in subsection (3) of this section, the meter testing frequency shall be that which is determined by the utility to be cost effective. This determination by the utility shall be based on established scientific, engineering, and economic methods and shall be documented in an application properly filed with the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 28, effective April 1, 1979. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3952-26. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14075</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>