<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.154</section_number><catch_line>Personal leave days for school employees. </catch_line><order_by>154</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of this section, "school employees" shall mean any person for whom certification is required as a basis of employment in the public schools. </section><section prefix="2">Each district board of education may provide up to three (3) personal leave days per school year to school employees, without loss of salary to the employee and without affecting any other type of leave granted by law, regulation, or school board policy. Local boards of education may establish policy regarding the number of teachers who may take personal leave on any one (1) day. </section><section prefix="3">Personal leave granted under this section shall not be treated as having effect on the provisions of KRS 161.152 to 161.155 and shall be supported by personal affidavit of the school employee stating that the leave taken is personal in nature; no other reason for or verification of the leave shall be required. </section><section prefix="4">Payments to school employees made by a district board of education under the provisions of this section are presumed to be for services rendered and for the benefit of the common schools and such payments do not affect the eligibility of any school district to share in the distribution of funds from the public school foundation program fund as established in KRS Chapter 157. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 477, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>