<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.042</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against licensing of personal motor vehicles without listing of vehicle identification numbers -- Exceptions -- Submission of paper or electronic proof of insurance card to county clerk.   </catch_line><order_by>042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On and after January 1, 2006, a county clerk shall not process an application for, nor issue, a: <section prefix="a">Kentucky title and registration or renewal of registration; </section><section prefix="b">Replacement plate, decal, or registration certificate; </section><section prefix="c">Duplicate registration; </section><section prefix="d">Transfer of registration; or </section><section prefix="e">Temporary tag; </section></section> for any personal motor vehicle as defined in KRS 304.39-087(1) if AVIS does not list the vehicle identification number of the personal motor vehicle as an insured vehicle, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section. <section prefix="2">If AVIS does not list the vehicle identification number of the personal motor vehicle as an insured vehicle, the county clerk may process the application if: <section prefix="a">The applicant has an insurance card in paper or electronic format that indicates the required security is currently in full force on the personal motor vehicle if the paper or electronic proof of insurance card was effective no more than forty-five (45) days before the application is submitted to the county clerk; or </section><section prefix="b">The owner of the motor vehicle is serving in the Armed Forces outside of Kentucky, and the owner provides an affidavit by the provost marshal of the base where the owner is stationed stating that the motor vehicle is covered by security as required by Subtitle 39 of KRS Chapter 304. </section></section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to any transactions involving Kentucky motor vehicle dealers who are licensed as required by KRS 190.030. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">An insurance card in an electronic format means the display of an image subject to immediate download or transmission from the applicant's insurer or agent to the applicant on any portable electronic device, including a cellular phone or any other type of portable electronic device, but shall not include a photographic copy of a paper insurance card on a portable electronic device; and </section><section prefix="b">The county clerk may require the applicant to e-mail the electronic insurance card to the clerk, and the clerk may print a copy of the card for the clerk's records. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>