<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.040</section_number><catch_line>Action to vacate order of department -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any party in interest dissatisfied with an order of the department may commence an equitable action against the department and other interested parties as defendants, to vacate or set aside, in whole or in part, any such order. The action shall be brought in the Circuit Court of the county where the subject matter involved in the order, or the well or workable coal bed or part thereof, is located. The court may grant relief from any unlawful or unreasonable order of the department, and render such judgment as appears to it to be equitable and just. </section><section prefix="2">The pendency of the action shall not of itself suspend the operation of the order of the department, but during the pendency of the action any party may secure from the court an order suspending or staying the operation of the order of the department pending the action by giving to the other parties adequate security, approved by the court, against loss due to the delay in enforcement of the order, in case the order under review is not set aside, and the court may, without security being given, suspend the operation of the order, in whole or in part, on such terms as it deems just and in accordance with the practice of courts of equity; provided, however, that the operation of an order pertaining to safety in coal mines shall not be suspended temporarily pending final decision of the court. </section><section prefix="3">Appeals may be taken to the Court of Appeals as in other cases. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3766b-17. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32891</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>