<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.031</section_number><catch_line>Duties of state registrar. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text>The state registrar, under the supervision of the commissioner of health, shall: <section prefix="1">Administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations issued hereunder; issue instructions for the efficient administration of the system of vital statistics; direct the system and Vital Statistics Branch and be custodian of its records; supervise the activities of all persons when they are engaged in the operation of the system; and conduct training programs to promote uniformity of the system's policy and procedures throughout the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">With the approval of the cabinet, design, furnish, and distribute forms required by this chapter and the administrative regulations issued hereunder, or prescribe other means for transmission of data to accomplish the purpose of complete and accurate reporting and registration; </section><section prefix="3">Coordinate and maintain in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this subsection, a system by which a child's Social Security number is transferred by the Vital Statistics Branch to the Department of Education after receiving parental permission for the number to be used for planning and tracking purposes by the Department of Education, local school districts, and the office. The regulations, at a minimum, shall establish a process to allow a parent or guardian when completing a certificate of birth to request that a Social Security number be assigned the child and that the number be automatically transmitted to the Department of Education for student identification purposes; </section><section prefix="4">Assist in preparing and publishing reports of vital statistics of the Commonwealth and other reports as required; </section><section prefix="5">Provide to local health departments copies of or data derived from certificates and reports required under this chapter. The state registrar shall establish a schedule with each local health department for transmittal of the copies or data. The copies shall remain the property of the Vital Statistics Branch, and the uses which may be made of them and the period of their retention in the county shall be governed by the state registrar; </section><section prefix="6">Prepare and maintain a complete continuous index of all vital records registered under this chapter and provide, at not more than two (2) year intervals, a copy of the index to each local registrar; and </section><section prefix="7">Investigate cases of irregularity or violation of this chapter and when the cabinet deems it necessary, report violations to the Commonwealth's attorney of the proper county for prosecution. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 431, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>