<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.164</section_number><catch_line>Building lockdown procedures -- Practice.   </catch_line><order_by>164</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "building lockdown" means to restrict the mobility of building occupants to maintain their safety and care. </section><section prefix="2">Each local board of education shall require the school council or, if none exists, the principal in each public school building in its jurisdiction to establish procedures to perform a building lockdown, including protective measures to be taken during and immediately following the lockdown. Local law enforcement agencies shall be invited to assist in establishing lockdown procedures. </section><section prefix="3">Students, certified staff, and classified staff shall be informed annually of building lockdown procedures. </section><section prefix="4">A building lockdown practice shall be held at least twice during each school year, with at least one (1) practice being held within the first thirty (30) instructional days of the school year and one (1) practice being held during the month of January. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 133, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). This statute was amended with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 126 and 133, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42584</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>