<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-470</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited practices in replacement or repair of automobile glass -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>9-470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An insurer, its agents, or adjusters shall not: <section prefix="a">Require any policyholder to use a particular company or location for the provision of automobile glass replacement or glass repair services or glass products which shall be replaced, repaired, or provided in whole or in part under the terms of an insurance policy; </section><section prefix="b">Engage in any act or practice of intimidation, coercion, or threat against any policyholder to use a particular company or location to provide automobile glass replacement or repair services or products insured in whole or in part under the terms of an insurance policy. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person selling or engaged in the sale or installation of replacement glass shall advertise, promise to provide, or offer any coupon, credit, or rebate to pay all or part of an insurance deductible under a property and casualty insurance policy. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not be construed to require an insurer to pay more for automobile glass replacement, or glass repair services or glass products than the lowest price available in the market area provided by a qualified, competent glass repair company. </section><section prefix="4">Violation of this section shall be subject to penalties as provided in KRS 304.99-020. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>