<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.0455</section_number><catch_line>Voter registration through motor vehicle driver's license application. </catch_line><order_by>0455</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Each motor vehicle driver's license application, including any renewal application, submitted to the appropriate motor vehicle authority shall serve as an application for voter registration unless the applicant fails to sign the voter registration application. </section><section prefix="b">An application for voter registration submitted under paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be considered as updating any previous voter registration by the applicant. </section></section><section prefix="2">No information relating to the failure of an applicant for a motor vehicle driver's license to sign a voter registration application may be used for any purpose other than voter registration. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Transportation Cabinet shall include a voter registration application form as part of an application for a motor vehicle driver's license. </section><section prefix="b">The voter registration application portion of an application for a motor vehicle driver's license shall comply with the requirements of Section 5 of Public Law 103-31, the National Voter Registration Act of 1993. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any change of address form submitted for purposes of a motor vehicle driver's license shall serve as notification of change of address for voter registration for the registrant involved unless the registrant states on the form that the change of address is not for voter registration purposes. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A completed voter registration portion of an application for a motor vehicle driver's license accepted by a circuit clerk shall be transmitted to the county clerk of the county of the applicant's voting residence not later than ten (10) days after the date of acceptance. </section><section prefix="b">If a voter registration application is accepted within five (5) days before the last day for registration to vote in an election, the application shall be transmitted to the county clerk of the county of the applicant's voting residence not later than five (5) days after the date of acceptance. </section></section><section prefix="6">The circuit clerk shall provide to the county clerk a declination statement signed by an applicant if the applicant has declined to register to vote. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  In Attorney General Opinion 94-42, it was concluded that 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, which enacted this statute "will take effect on January 1, 1995, the date the National Voter Registration Act will take effect with respect to Kentucky." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27300</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>