<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.476</section_number><catch_line>School building fund taxes -- Investment -- Expenditures -- Audit. </catch_line><order_by>476</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of education of any district may, in addition to other taxes for school purposes, levy not less than four cents ($0.04) nor more than twenty cents ($0.20) on each one hundred dollars ($100) valuation of property subject to local taxation, to provide a special fund for the purchase of sites for school buildings and physical education and athletic facilities, for the erection and complete equipping of school buildings and physical education and athletic facilities, and for the major alteration, enlargement and complete equipping of existing buildings and physical education and athletic facilities, provided, however, that such tax shall come within the maximum school tax levy provided by KRS 160.470. In addition to or in lieu of this special tax, any board of education may pay into this special fund at the close of any fiscal year the proceeds from the sale of land or property no longer needed for school purposes and all or any balances remaining in the general fund over and above the amount necessary for discharging obligations for the fiscal year in full. </section><section prefix="2">The special fund provided for herein shall be kept in a separate account designated as "school building fund." The fund shall be kept in a depository selected by the board of education, or invested in bonds of the United States, of this state, or county or municipality in this state, provided, however, that such investments shall be approved by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section><section prefix="3">All expenditures from such fund shall be made solely for the purposes enumerated herein and shall be made in accordance with the school laws of the state at such times as the board of education determines. The board of education shall cause to be made annually an audit of the building fund by a certified public accountant or by an accountant approved by the State Department of Education. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of any other subsection of this section to the contrary, for the 1966 tax year and for all subsequent years no district board of education shall levy a tax at a rate under the provisions of this section which exceeds the compensating tax rate as defined in KRS 132.010. The chief state school officer shall certify the compensating tax rate to the district board of education. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. III, sec. 112, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 4. -- Amended 1965 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 4. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1(3). </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3745</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>