<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.110</section_number><catch_line>Additional duties of commission. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>The commission shall perform the following additional duties: <section prefix="1">On its own initiative or upon a signed request in writing, issue and publish advisory opinions on the requirements of this chapter for those who wish to use the opinion to guide their own conduct. If requested in writing by the person seeking the advisory opinion, the commission shall not release that person's name; </section><section prefix="2">Provide a continuing program of education, assistance, and information to public servants, including, but not limited to, publishing and making available to the persons subject to this chapter and the public explanatory information concerning this chapter, the duties imposed by it, and the means of enforcement; </section><section prefix="3">Promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement this chapter; </section><section prefix="4">Prescribe forms for statements required by this chapter and furnish the forms to persons required to file the statements. The forms shall be adopted as administrative regulations or adopted by reference in an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="5">Prepare and publish a manual of guidelines setting forth uniform methods of reporting for use by persons required to file under this chapter; </section><section prefix="6">Accept and file any information voluntarily supplied that exceeds the requirements of this chapter; </section><section prefix="7">Preserve the disclosure statements filed with it for four (4) years from the date of receipt; </section><section prefix="8">Make statements and reports filed with the commission available for public inspection and copying pursuant to KRS 61.870 to KRS 61.884 (Kentucky Open Records Law); </section><section prefix="9">Compile and maintain a current index of all statements filed with the commission to facilitate public access to the reports and statements; </section><section prefix="10">Prepare and publish reports as it may deem appropriate; </section><section prefix="11">Audit statements and reports filed with the commission; </section><section prefix="12">Make recommendations for legislation relating to governmental ethics and other matters included in this chapter as the commission deems desirable; and </section><section prefix="13">Prepare a biennial written report, no later than December 1 of each odd-numbered year, to the Legislative Research Commission, the Governor, and the public on the activities of the commission in the preceding two (2) fiscal years. The report shall contain the names and duties of each individual employed by the commission and a summary of commission determinations and advisory opinions. The commission shall prevent disclosure of the identity of a person involved in decisions or advisory opinions. The report may contain other information on matters within the commission's jurisdiction and recommendations for legislation as the commission deems desirable. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. --  Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>