<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-252</section_number><catch_line>Health benefit plan not required to include state-mandated benefits enacted after issuance. </catch_line><order_by>17A-252</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, an insurer that issues or renews a health benefit plan on or after January 1, 2005, and before December 31, 2007, shall not be required to include any additional state mandated benefit beyond those statutory requirements in effect for health benefits plans on January 1, 2005. </section><section prefix="2">An insurer issuing or renewing a health benefit plan may elect to expand coverage on any group, individual, or association health benefit plan. </section><section prefix="3">An insurer issuing or renewing a health benefit plan shall not suspend, limit, or modify any state mandated benefit in effect on January 1, 2005. </section><section prefix="4">An insurer issuing or renewing a health benefit plan shall not suspend, limit, or modify any federal mandated benefit in effect on January 1, 2005, or any federal mandated benefit that becomes effective after January 1, 2005. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall affect the fiscal impact statement required by KRS 6.948 to be attached to any legislation mandating health insurance benefits. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>