<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.189</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of officers in positions created under KRS 16.187.   </catch_line><order_by>189</order_by><text>The powers and duties of officers in the positions established by KRS 16.187 shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Commercial vehicle enforcement officers and commercial vehicle enforcement officers R class shall enforce: <section prefix="a">Commercial vehicle licensure, operator, traffic, and criminal violations; </section><section prefix="b">Motor vehicle operator, traffic, and criminal law violations on a highway; and </section><section prefix="c">All the laws and administrative regulations of the Commonwealth at the direction of the commissioner; </section></section><section prefix="2">Arson investigator officers shall enforce: <section prefix="a">All criminal laws pertaining to arson; and </section><section prefix="b">All the laws and administrative regulations of the Commonwealth at the direction of the commissioner; </section></section><section prefix="3">Hazardous devices investigator officers shall enforce: <section prefix="a">All criminal laws pertaining to hazardous devices; and </section><section prefix="b">All the laws and administrative regulations of the Commonwealth at the direction of the commissioner; and </section></section><section prefix="4">Facilities security officers shall have the jurisdiction and duties established pursuant to KRS 61.900 to 61.930. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42239</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>