<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.051</section_number><catch_line>Contents of birth certificate. </catch_line><order_by>051</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The person who assumes the custody of a live-born infant of unknown parentage shall report on a form and in a manner prescribed by the state registrar within ten (10) days to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services the following information: <section prefix="a">The date and place of finding; </section><section prefix="b">Sex, color or race, and approximate birth date of child; </section><section prefix="c">Name and address of the person or institution with which the child has been placed for care; </section><section prefix="d">Name given to the child by the custodian of the child; and </section><section prefix="e">Other data as required by the state registrar to complete a birth certificate. </section></section><section prefix="2">The place where the child was found shall be entered as the place of birth. </section><section prefix="3">A report registered under this section shall constitute the certificate of birth for the child. </section><section prefix="4">If the child is identified and a certificate of birth is found or obtained, the report registered under this section shall be placed in a special file and shall not be subject to inspection except upon order of a Circuit Court. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 435, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 385, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>