<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="454" order_by="454">MISCELLANEOUS CIVIL PRACTICE PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>454.210</section_number><catch_line>Personal jurisdiction of courts over nonresident -- Process, how served -- Fee -- Venue. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "person" includes an individual, his executor, administrator, or other personal representative, or a corporation, partnership, association, or any other legal or commercial entity, who is a nonresident of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A court may exercise personal jurisdiction over a person who acts directly or by an agent, as to a claim arising from the person's: <section prefix="1">Transacting any business in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Contracting to supply services or goods in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="3">Causing tortious injury by an act or omission in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="4">Causing tortious injury in this Commonwealth by an act or omission outside this Commonwealth if he regularly does or solicits business, or engages in any other persistent course of conduct, or derives substantial revenue from goods used or consumed or services rendered in this Commonwealth, provided that the tortious injury occurring in this Commonwealth arises out of the doing or soliciting of business or a persistent course of conduct or derivation of substantial revenue within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="5">Causing injury in this Commonwealth to any person by breach of warranty expressly or impliedly made in the sale of goods outside this Commonwealth when the seller knew such person would use, consume, or be affected by, the goods in this Commonwealth, if he also regularly does or solicits business, or engages in any other persistent course of conduct, or derives substantial revenue from goods used or consumed or services rendered in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="6">Having an interest in, using, or possessing real property in this Commonwealth, providing the claim arises from the interest in, use of, or possession of the real property, provided, however, that such in personam jurisdiction shall not be imposed on a nonresident who did not himself voluntarily institute the relationship, and did not knowingly perform, or fail to perform, the act or acts upon which jurisdiction is predicated; </section><section prefix="7">Contracting to insure any person, property, or risk located within this Commonwealth at the time of contracting; </section><section prefix="8">Committing sexual intercourse in this state which intercourse causes the birth of a child when: <section prefix="a">The father or mother or both are domiciled in this state; </section><section prefix="b">There is a repeated pattern of intercourse between the father and mother in this state; or </section><section prefix="c">Said intercourse is a tort or a crime in this state; or </section></section><section prefix="9">Making a telephone solicitation, as defined in KRS 367.46951, into the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="b">When jurisdiction over a person is based solely upon this section, only a claim arising from acts enumerated in this section may be asserted against him. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">When personal jurisdiction is authorized by this section, service of process may be made on such person, or any agent of such person, in any county in this Commonwealth, where he may be found, or on the Secretary of State who, for this purpose, shall be deemed to be the statutory agent of such person. </section><section prefix="b">The clerk of the court in which the action is brought shall issue a summons against the defendant named in the complaint. The clerk shall execute the summons either by: <section prefix="1">Sending by certified mail two (2) true copies to the Secretary of State and shall also mail with the summons two (2) attested copies of plaintiff's complaint; or </section><section prefix="2">Transmitting an electronically attested copy of the complaint and summons to the Secretary of State via the Kentucky Court of Justice electronic filing system.  </section></section><section prefix="c">The Secretary of State shall, within seven (7) days of receipt thereof in his office, mail a copy of the summons and complaint to the defendant at the address given in the complaint. The letter shall be posted by certified mail, return receipt requested, and shall bear the return address of the Secretary of State. The clerk shall make the usual return to the court, and in addition the Secretary of State shall make a return to the court showing that the acts contemplated by this statute have been performed, and shall attach to his return the registry receipt, if any. Summons shall be deemed to be served on the return of the Secretary of State and the action shall proceed as provided in the Rules of Civil Procedure. </section><section prefix="d">The clerk mailing the summons to the Secretary of State shall mail to him, at the same time, a fee of ten dollars ($10), which shall be taxed as costs in the action. The fee for a summons transmitted electronically pursuant to this subsection shall be transmitted to the Secretary of State on a periodic basis. </section></section><section prefix="4">When the exercise of personal jurisdiction is authorized by this section, any action or suit may be brought in the county wherein the plaintiff resides or where the cause of action or any part thereof arose. </section><section prefix="5">A court of this Commonwealth may exercise jurisdiction on any other basis authorized in the Kentucky Revised Statutes or by the Rules of Civil Procedure, notwithstanding this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 159, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 107, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 20. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 87. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 3. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 46, secs. 1 to 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43279</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>