<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.824</section_number><catch_line>Statements of financial transactions -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>824</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any legislative agent who has had any financial transaction with or for the benefit of any member of the General Assembly, the Governor, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, or any member of the staff of any of the officials listed in this subsection shall describe the details of the transaction, including the name of the official or employee, the purpose and nature of the transaction, and the date it was made or entered into, in a statement filed with the commission with the updated registration statement required by KRS 6.807(3). The statement shall be filed at the times specified in KRS 6.807. Each statement shall describe each financial transaction that occurred during the filing period that ended on the last day of the month immediately preceding the month in which the statement is required to be filed. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, any employer who has had any financial transaction with or for the benefit of any member of the General Assembly, the Governor, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, or any member of the staff of any official listed in this subsection shall describe the details of the transaction, including the name of the official, the purpose and nature of the transaction, and the date it was made or entered into, in a statement filed with the commission with the updated registration statement required by KRS 6.807(3). The statement shall be filed at the times specified in KRS 6.807. Each statement shall describe each financial transaction that occurred during the filing period that ended on the last day of the month immediately preceding the month in which the statement is required to be filed. </section><section prefix="3">No employer shall be required to file any statement under this section or to deliver a copy of the statement to a public official with whom or for whose benefit the transaction was made if the financial transaction to which the statement pertains is reported by a legislative agent engaged by the employer. </section><section prefix="4">Any legislative agent or employer who fails to file a required statement of financial transactions, or who fails to remedy any deficiency in his filing in a timely manner, may be fined by the commission an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) per day, up to a maximum total fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="5">Any legislative agent or employer who intentionally files a statement of financial interests which he knows to contain false information or to omit required information shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></text><history>Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 30, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>September 16, 1993 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=405</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>