<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">G KENTUCKY OFFICE OF HOMELAND SECURITY </unit></structure><section_number>39G.020</section_number><catch_line>Records and reporting -- Education of reporting entities -- Notification of available grants. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Office of Homeland Security shall identify and maintain a record of all federal homeland security funding, including grants, received in Kentucky. The record shall identify, at a minimum, the specific federal source, the amount, the specific recipient, the intended use of the funding, the actual use, and any unspent amount. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Not later than September 15 of each year, each department headed by an elected officer, as identified in KRS 12.020 I., each cabinet headed by an appointed officer, as identified in KRS 12.020 II., and each department headed by an appointed officer, as identified in KRS 12.020 III., shall submit to the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security a record of all federal homeland security funding, including grants, received during the state fiscal year starting with the fiscal year ending June 30, 2005. The record shall identify, at a minimum, the specific federal source, the amount, the specific recipient, the intended use of the funding, the actual use, and any unspent amount. </section><section prefix="b">Not later than August 1 of each year, each city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, and special taxing district shall submit to its area development district a record of all federal homeland security funding, including grants, received during the state fiscal year by the city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, special taxing district, or a public agency thereof, starting with the fiscal year ending June 30, 2005. The record shall identify, at a minimum, the specific federal source, the amount, the specific recipient, the intended use of the funding, the actual use, and any unspent amount. </section><section prefix="c">Not later than August 15 of each year, each area development district shall group the records required under paragraph (b) of this subsection by county and submit them to the Department for Local Government. </section><section prefix="d">Not later than September 20 of each year, the Department for Local Government shall submit the records received under paragraph (c) of this subsection to the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security. </section><section prefix="e">Any funds received for the purpose of homeland security shall be monitored by the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security and subject to audit and compliance inspections as directed by the executive director. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Office of Homeland Security, area development districts, and the Department for Local Government shall educate entities that report under this section about their responsibilities under this section. If an entity is late in reporting under this section, the office, an area development district, or the Department for Local Government shall remind that entity of its reporting requirements under this section. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Office of Homeland Security shall directly notify the chief executive officer of each city, county, urban-county, charter county, and consolidated local government concerning grants for homeland security projects as the grants become available. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 12, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>