<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="201" order_by="201">JEFFERSON COUNTY CHILDREN'S HOME </unit></structure><section_number>201.050</section_number><catch_line>Board to acquire property. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may acquire by lease, purchase, gift or condemnation, all property necessary or suitable for establishing the home, and may erect, equip, operate, and maintain such suitable buildings as may be necessary for the care, custody, maintenance, education, and training of the children committed to it. The board shall provide such buildings, grounds, equipment and units, in the county in which the board is created.  </section><section prefix="2">When the property of any other board or institution within the county is conveyed to the board, and such property is owned, maintained or controlled in whole or in part by any city or division or district in the city, the conveyance shall first be authorized by the legislative body or other city board of such city or division or district; and when the property is owned, maintained or controlled in whole or in part by the county, the conveyance shall first be authorized by the fiscal court of the county. In either case, the governing body of the institution must also authorize and direct the conveyance to be made. Where any such conveyance is made to the board, the board shall receive and maintain in the home, all children who, at the time of the conveyance, are in the care and custody of the institution whose property is so conveyed.  </section><section prefix="3">The board shall not be compelled to accept any conveyance which the board finds unsuited for the purposes of this chapter, or the improvement of which would entail an injudicious expenditure.  </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 938b-3, 938b-12, 938b-13. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7345</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>