<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.325</section_number><catch_line>Mandatory participation in Kentucky Energy Efficiency Program. </catch_line><order_by>325</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In an effort to reduce the rising energy costs that are straining school budgets, on or before January 1, 2010, each board of education shall enroll in the Kentucky Energy Efficiency Program that is offered by the Kentucky Pollution Prevention Center at the University of Louisville in order to obtain information regarding the potential energy savings for every board-owned and board-operated facility. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Pollution Prevention Center may prioritize the provision of assistance and development of energy management plans based upon available resources. </section><section prefix="3">On or before December 1, 2011, and on or before December 1 of each year thereafter, the Kentucky Pollution Prevention Center shall file a report for the preceding fiscal year with the Department for Energy Development and Independence and the Legislative Research Commission. The report shall include: <section prefix="a">The number of boards of education enrolled in the Kentucky Energy Efficiency Program; </section><section prefix="b">The status of the development of energy management plans by those boards of education and anticipated savings to be obtained by those plans; and </section><section prefix="c">The amount and disposition of grants provided by the Department for Energy Development and Independence and any state appropriations for support of the Kentucky Energy Efficiency Program. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 16, effective February 25, 2010; and amended ch. 24, sec. 210, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24 and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5. Notwithstanding KRS 446.260, these Acts do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>