<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.336</section_number><catch_line>Installation of flasher lights near schools -- Speed limits. </catch_line><order_by>336</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Fiscal courts, with respect to school zones situated in unincorporated areas, may authorize by resolution installation at county expense of school flasher lights and other traffic control devices on highways in school zones as they deem reasonable and necessary.  </section><section prefix="2">Cities, with respect to school zones within their incorporated areas, may authorize by ordinance installation at city expense of school flasher lights and other traffic control devices on highways in school zones as they deem reasonable and necessary.  </section><section prefix="3">The speed limit on all highways where school flasher lights are in operation shall be determined by the governmental unit having control of the highway where a school flasher light is in operation. Flasher lights shall be placed one-eighth (1/8) of a mile on each side of the principal school building where practical. The governmental unit having control of the highway where the lights are in operation shall erect signs notifying motorists of the speed limit.  </section><section prefix="4">"Highways" as used in this section shall mean any public road or street maintained by a city, county or the state.  </section><section prefix="5">Any traffic control devices erected by any governmental unit shall conform to standards and specifications authorized by KRS 189.337. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6372</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>