<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.12-090</section_number><catch_line>Rebates prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>12-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No insurer or employee or representative thereof shall knowingly charge, demand, or receive a premium for any insurance policy except in accordance with the applicable filing on file with the commissioner. No such insurer, employee, or representative shall pay, allow, or give, or offer to pay, allow, or give, directly or indirectly, as an inducement to insurance or after insurance has been effected, any rebate, discount, abatement, credit or reduction of the premium named in a policy, or any special favor or advantage in the dividends or other benefits to accrue thereon, or any valuable consideration or inducements whatever, or give, sell, or purchase, or offer to give, sell, or purchase anything of value whatsoever not specified in the policy, except to the extent provided for in such applicable filing. </section><section prefix="2">No insured named in a policy, nor any employee or representative thereof shall knowingly receive or accept, directly or indirectly, any such rebate, discount, abatement or reduction of premium, or any special favor or advantage or valuable consideration or inducement. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (1) and (2) of this section shall not apply as to life insurance and health insurance. Except as expressly provided by law no insurer, employee, or representative shall knowingly permit or offer to make or make any contract of life insurance, life annuity or health insurance, or agreement as to such contract other than as plainly expressed in the contract issued thereon, or pay or allow, or give or offer to pay, allow or give, directly or indirectly, as inducement to such insurance, or annuity, any rebate of premiums payable on the contract, or any special favor or advantage in the dividends or other benefits thereon, or any valuable consideration or inducement whatever not expressed in the contract. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1108, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 12, sec. 9, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17020</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>