<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.055</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited acts. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text>No licensee shall: <section prefix="1">Use a badge for identification or make any statement which would reasonably cause another person to believe that the licensee functions as a sworn peace officer or other official of the state, any of its political subdivisions, or an agency of the federal government; </section><section prefix="2">Divulge to anyone, other than his or her client, or to such persons as his or her client may direct, or as may be required by law, any information acquired during such employment that may compromise the client, the person who is the subject of the investigation, or the investigation to which the licensee has been assigned; </section><section prefix="3">Knowingly make a material misrepresentation as to his or her ability to perform the investigation required by a potential client in order to obtain employment; </section><section prefix="4">Knowingly make a material misrepresentation to the client regarding the investigation; or </section><section prefix="5">Continue an investigation for a client when it becomes obvious to the licensee that a successful completion of an investigation is unlikely, unless the licensee advises the client and obtains the client's approval for continuation of the investigation. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>