<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.385</section_number><catch_line>School district finance corporation -- Definitions -- Construction bonds. </catch_line><order_by>385</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any board of education may obtain buildings for school purposes by proceeding under the provisions of KRS 162.120 to 162.290 utilizing a nonprofit finance corporation established pursuant to the provisions of KRS 273.161 to 273.390, inclusive, and KRS 58.180 as an issuing agency for the bonds instead of a city or county. When applied to such boards of education, KRS 162.120 to 162.290 shall be so read that the term: <section prefix="a">"City" means a finance corporation acting as an agency and instrumentality of the board pursuant to KRS 58.180; </section><section prefix="b">"City clerk" means the secretary of the finance corporation; </section><section prefix="c">"Governing body of the city" means the board of directors of the finance corporation or other governing body thereof; </section><section prefix="d">"Mayor" means president or chief executive officer of the finance corporation; and </section><section prefix="e">"Ordinance" means an ordinance, resolution, or trust indenture or a similar document. </section></section><section prefix="2">In order to promote uniformity in the financing of school facilities, each finance corporation shall include the identity of the school district for which it acts in its title and shall be designated as "................... School District Finance Corporation." </section><section prefix="3">Bonds issued by a finance corporation on behalf of a board of education shall constitute "bonds" within the meaning of KRS 157.615(3) and the School Facilities Construction Commission shall be authorized to assist qualified boards in meeting rental payments due under a lease from the finance corporation to the board which shall constitute a "lease" within the meaning of KRS 157.615(8). </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 13, effective April 3, 1992. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 580, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>April 3, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4066</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>