<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.577</section_number><catch_line>Commission's meetings, purposes, and goals. </catch_line><order_by>577</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission created in KRS 210.575 shall meet at least quarterly or upon the call of the chair, the request of four (4) or more members, or the request of the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall serve in an advisory capacity to accomplish the following: <section prefix="a">Advise the Governor and the General Assembly concerning the needs of persons with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="b">Develop a statewide strategy to increase access to community-based services and supports for persons with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities. The strategy shall include: <section prefix="1">Identification of funding needs and related fiscal impact; and </section><section prefix="2">Criteria that establish priority for services that consider timeliness and service needs; </section></section><section prefix="c">Assess the need and potential utilization of specialized outpatient clinics for medical, dental, and special therapeutic services for persons with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="d">Evaluate the effectiveness of state agencies and public and private service providers, including nonprofit and for-profit service providers, in: <section prefix="1">Dissemination of information and education; </section><section prefix="2">Providing outcome-oriented services; and </section><section prefix="3">Efficiently utilizing available resources, including blended funding streams; </section></section><section prefix="e">Develop a recommended comprehensive ten (10) year plan for placement of qualified persons in the most integrated setting appropriate to their needs; </section><section prefix="f">Recommend an effective quality assurance and consumer satisfaction monitoring program that includes recommendations as to the appropriate role of family members, persons with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities, and advocates in quality assurance efforts; </section><section prefix="g">Develop recommendations for the implementation of a self-determination model of funding services and supports as established under KRS 205.6317(1) for persons who are receiving services or supports under the Supports for Community Living Program as of June 24, 2003. The model shall include, but is not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">The ability to establish an individual rate or budget for each person; </section><section prefix="2">Mechanisms to ensure that each participant has the support and assistance necessary to design and implement a package of services and supports unique to the individual; </section><section prefix="3">The ability to arrange services, supports, and resources unique to each person based upon the preferences of the recipient; and </section><section prefix="4">The design of a system of accountability for the use of public funds. </section></section> The chairperson of the commission shall appoint an ad-hoc committee composed of commission members and other interested parties to develop the recommendations required by this paragraph; and <section prefix="h">Advise the Governor and the General Assembly on whether the recommendations should be implemented by administrative regulations or proposed legislation. </section></section><section prefix="3">The commission shall review the plan annually and shall submit annual updates no later than October 1 to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003; and ch. 161, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 3, effective April 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8301</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>