<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="343" order_by="343">APPRENTICESHIP </unit></structure><section_number>343.050</section_number><catch_line>Apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>Every apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement approved under this chapter shall contain:  <section prefix="1">The names and signatures of the contracting parties and the signature of a parent or guardian if the apprentice is a minor;  </section><section prefix="2">The date of birth of the apprentice or trainee;  </section><section prefix="3">A statement of the occupation or business which the apprentice or trainee is to be taught and the time at which the apprenticeship or on-the-job training will begin and end;  </section><section prefix="4">A statement showing: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The number of hours to be spent by the apprentice or trainee in work on the job in a time-based program; or </section><section prefix="2">A description of the skill sets to be attained by completion of a competency-based program, including the on-the-job training component; or </section><section prefix="3">The minimum number of hours to be spent by the apprentice and a description of the skill sets to be attained by completion of a hybrid program; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The number of hours to be spent in related instruction in technical subjects related to the occupation, which shall be not less than one hundred forty-four (144) hours per year;  </section></section><section prefix="5">A statement setting forth a schedule of the processes in the occupation or industry divisions in which the apprentice or trainee is to be taught and the approximate time to be spent at each process;  </section><section prefix="6">A statement of the graduating scale of compensation to be paid the apprentice or trainee, and whether the required school time shall be compensated; </section><section prefix="7">A statement providing for a period of probation not to exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the length of the program or one (1) year, whichever is shorter, during which the apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement may be canceled by either party to the agreement upon written notice to the registration agency, without adverse impact on the sponsor; and  </section><section prefix="8">A provision that all controversies or differences concerning the apprenticeship or on-the-job training agreement which cannot be adjusted by the parties shall be submitted to the supervisor for determination as provided in KRS 343.070. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599c-35. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42989</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>