<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-305</section_number><catch_line>Law governing perfection and priority of security interests in investment property. </catch_line><order_by>9-305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) of this section, the following rules apply: <section prefix="a">While a security certificate is located in a jurisdiction, the local law of that jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in the certificated security represented thereby. </section><section prefix="b">The local law of the issuer’s jurisdiction as specified in KRS 355.8-110(4) governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in an uncertificated security. </section><section prefix="c">The local law of the securities intermediary’s jurisdiction as specified in KRS 355.8-110(5) governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in a security entitlement or securities account. </section><section prefix="d">The local law of the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in a commodity contract or commodity account. </section></section><section prefix="2">The following rules determine a commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction for purposes of this part of this article: <section prefix="a">If an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer governing the commodity account expressly provides that a particular jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction for purposes of this part of this article, this article, or this chapter, that jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="b">If paragraph (a) of this subsection does not apply and an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer governing the commodity account expressly provides that the agreement is governed by the law of a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="c">If neither paragraph (a) nor paragraph (b) of this subsection applies and an agreement between the commodity intermediary and commodity customer governing the commodity account expressly provides that the commodity account is maintained at an office in a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="d">If none of the preceding paragraphs applies, the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which the office identified in an account statement as the office serving the commodity customer’s account is located. </section><section prefix="e">If none of the preceding paragraphs applies, the commodity intermediary’s jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which the chief executive office of the commodity intermediary is located. </section></section><section prefix="3">The local law of the jurisdiction in which the debtor is located governs: <section prefix="a">Perfection of a security interest in investment property by filing; </section><section prefix="b">Automatic perfection of a security interest in investment property created by a broker or securities intermediary; and </section><section prefix="c">Automatic perfection of a security interest in a commodity contract or commodity account created by a commodity intermediary. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 6, effective July 1, 2001. -- Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 45, effective July 1, 2001. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 175, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 66, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-305, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  Although 2000 Acts ch. 408, sec. 45, has a reference to "subsection (4) of Section 169 of this Act" (which Section was codified as KRS 355.8-103) in subsection (1)(b) of this statute, that reference has been codified as KRS 355.8-110(4) (which was subsection (4) of Section 171 of Chapter 408) in order to match the official text of Revised Article 9. Amendments to the introduced version of this bill in the Senate inadvertently did not make the necessary adjustment to this internal reference; this failure was clearly a manifest typographical or clerical error and has been corrected in codification under KRS 7.136(1)(h).  (7/14/2000).  Although 2000 Acts ch. 408, sec. 45, has a reference to "subsection (5) of Section 169 of this Act" (which Section was codified as KRS 355.8-103) in subsection (1)(c) of this statute, that reference has been codified as KRS 355.8-110(5) (which was subsection (5) of Section 171 of Chapter 408) in order to match the official text of Revised Article 9. Amendments to the introduced version of this bill in the Senate inadvertently did not make the necessary adjustment to this internal reference; this failure was clearly a manifest typographical or clerical error and has been corrected in codification under KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33758</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>