<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.985</section_number><catch_line>Effect of unintentional violation and timely adjustment of error. </catch_line><order_by>985</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A lessor shall not be liable under KRS 367.983 for a violation of KRS 367.976 to 367.985 if the lessor shows by a preponderance of the evidence that the violation was not intentional and resulted from a bona fide error, such as a clerical miscalculation, computer malfunctions, programming error, or printing error, even though the lessor maintained procedures reasonably adapted to avoid such an error. An error of legal judgment with respect to requirements of this title shall not be considered a bona fide error. </section><section prefix="2">A lessor shall not be liable under KRS 367.983 for any act done or omitted in good faith in conformity with any administrative regulation or interpretation promulgated by the Attorney General or by the division or by an official duly authorized by the Attorney General or by the division. This rule shall apply even if, after the act or omission has occurred, the regulation or interpretation is amended, rescinded, or determined by judicial or other authority to be invalid for any reason. </section><section prefix="3">A lessor shall not be liable under KRS 367.983 for any error if, before the thirty-first day after the date the merchant discovers the error and before an action against the lessor has been filed or written notice of the error received by the lessor, the lessor gives the consumer written notice of the error and makes adjustments in the consumer's account as necessary to assure that the consumer will not be required to pay an amount in excess of the amount disclosed and that the agreement otherwise complies with KRS 367.976 to 367.985. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 304, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was created by two separate 1990 Acts which are identical and have therefore been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35157</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>