<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.020</section_number><catch_line>Public servant prohibited from certain conduct -- Exception -- Disclosure of personal or private interest. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No public servant, by himself or through others, shall knowingly: <section prefix="a">Use or attempt to use his influence in any matter which involves a substantial conflict between his personal or private interest and his duties in the public interest; </section><section prefix="b">Use or attempt to use any means to influence a public agency in derogation of the state at large; </section><section prefix="c">Use his official position or office to obtain financial gain for himself or any members of the public servant's family; or </section><section prefix="d">Use or attempt to use his official position to secure or create privileges, exemptions, advantages, or treatment for himself or others in derogation of the public interest at large. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a public servant appears before a state agency, he shall avoid all conduct which might in any way lead members of the general public to conclude that he is using his official position to further his professional or private interest. </section><section prefix="3">When a public servant abstains from action on an official decision in which he has or may have a personal or private interest, he shall disclose that fact in writing to his superior, who shall cause the decision on these matters to be made by an impartial third party. </section><section prefix="4">The prohibitions imposed by subsection (1)(c) of this section shall not apply to Professional Golfers' Association class A members who teach golf lessons and receive a fee or lesson charge at golf courses owned and operated by the Kentucky Department of Parks. Instruction provided by an employee of the Commonwealth shall only be given while the employee is on his or her own personal time. The commissioner of the Department of Parks shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish guidelines for the process by which Professional Golfers' Association class A members are approved to teach golf lessons at Kentucky Department of Parks-owned golf courses. The exception granted by this subsection is in recognition of the benefits that will accrue to the Kentucky Department of Parks due to increased participation at state-owned golf courses. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. --  Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=592</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>