<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXX" order_by="30">CONTRACTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="371" order_by="371">FORMALITY AND ASSIGNABILITY OF CONTRACTS -- INSTALLMENT SALES CONTRACTS </unit></structure><section_number>371.160</section_number><catch_line>Deposit in escrow of amount held back by owner in contract involving improvement of real estate. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If, in any contract in the amount of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) or more involving the improvement of real estate, a certain amount or percentage of the contract is held back by the owner, that retained amount shall be deposited in a separate escrow account with a bank or trust company authorized to do business in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">As of the time of the deposit of the retained funds, they shall become the sole and separate property of the contractor to whom they are owed. </section><section prefix="3">The escrow agent shall promptly invest all escrowed principal in obligations selected by the escrow agent in its discretion. </section><section prefix="4">Upon satisfactory completion of the contract, to be evidenced by a written release by the owner, all funds accumulated in the escrow account, together with any interest thereon, shall be paid immediately to the contractor to whom it is owed. </section><section prefix="5">The escrow agent shall be compensated for its services in an amount agreed to by the owner, contractor, and escrow agent. The compensation shall be a commercially reasonable fee commensurate with fees being charged for handling of escrow accounts of similar size and duration. The compensation shall be paid from the escrow account. </section><section prefix="6">In the event the owner fails or refuses to execute the release provided for in subsection (4) of this section, then the contractor shall have a cause of action against the owner in a court of proper jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="7">This section shall not apply to contracts with the Commonwealth, any county, charter county, urban-county government, or municipality, or any other political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of the Commonwealth, or school boards. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35236</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>