<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="533" order_by="533">PROBATION AND CONDITIONAL DISCHARGE </unit></structure><section_number>533.250</section_number><catch_line>Pretrial diversion program in each judicial circuit -- Elements -- Fee.  </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>(1)A pretrial diversion program shall be operated in each judicial circuit. The chiefjudge of each judicial circuit, in cooperation with the Commonwealth's attorney,shall submit a plan for the pretrial diversion program to the Supreme Court forapproval on or before December 1, 1999. The pretrial diversion program shallcontain the following elements:(a)The program may be utilized for a person charged with a Class D felonyoffense who has not, within ten (10) years immediately preceding thecommission of this offense, been convicted of a felony under the laws ofthis state, another state, or of the United States, or has not been onprobation or parole or who has not been released from the service of anyfelony sentence within ten (10) years immediately preceding thecommission of the offense;(b)The program shall not be utilized for persons charged with offenses forwhich probation, parole, or conditional discharge is prohibited under KRS532.045;(c)No person shall be eligible for pretrial diversion more than once in a five(5) year period;(d)No person shall be eligible for pretrial diversion who has committed a sexcrime as defined in KRS 17.500. A person who is on pretrial diversion onJuly 12, 2006, may remain on pretrial diversion if the person continues tomeet the requirements of the pretrial diversion and the registrationrequirements of KRS 17.510;(e)Any person charged with an offense not specified as precluding a personfrom pretrial diversion under paragraph (b) of this subsection may apply inwriting to the trial court and the Commonwealth's attorney for entry into apretrial diversion program;(f)Any person shall be required to enter an Alford plea or a plea of guilty asa condition of pretrial diversion;(g)The provisions of KRS 533.251 shall be observed; and(h)The program may include as a component referral to the intensivesecured substance abuse treatment program developed under KRS196.285 for persons charged with a felony offense under KRS Chapter218A and persons charged with a felony offense whose record indicates ahistory of recent and relevant substance abuse who have not previouslybeen referred to the program under KRS 533.251.(2)Upon the request of the Commonwealth's attorney, a court ordering pretrialdiversion may order the person to:(a)Participate in a global positioning monitoring system program through theuse of a county-operated program pursuant to KRS 67.372 and 67.374 forall or part of the time during which a pretrial diversion agreement is ineffect; or(b)Use and pay all costs, including administrative and operating costs,associated with the alcohol monitoring device as defined in KRS 431.068.If the court determines that the defendant is indigent, and a person,county, or other organization has not agreed to pay the costs for thedefendant in an attempt to reduce incarceration expenses and increasepublic safety, the court shall consider other conditions of pretrial diversion.(3)A court ordering global positioning monitoring system for a person pursuant tothis section shall:(a)Require the person to pay all or a part of the monitoring costs based uponthe sliding scale determined by the Supreme Court of Kentucky pursuantto KRS 403.761 or 456.100 and administrative costs for participating inthe system;(b)Provide the monitoring system with a written or electronic copy of theconditions of release; and(c)Provide the monitoring system with a contact at the office of theCommonwealth's attorney for reporting violations of the monitoring order.(4)A person, county, or other organization may voluntarily agree to pay all or aportion of a person's monitoring costs specified in subsection (3) of this section.(5)The court shall not order a person to participate in a global positioningmonitoring system program unless the person agrees to the monitoring in opencourt or the court determines that public safety and the nature of the person'scrime require the use of a global positioning monitoring system program.(6)The Commonwealth's attorney shall make a recommendation upon eachapplication for pretrial diversion to the Circuit Judge in the court in which thecase would be tried. The court may approve or disapprove the diversion.(7)The court shall assess a diversion supervision fee of a sufficient amount todefray all or part of the cost of participating in the diversion program. Unlessthe fee is waived by the court in the case of indigency, the fee shall beassessed against each person placed in the diversion program. The fee maybe based upon ability to pay.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 49, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky.Acts ch. 96, sec. 5, effective March 24, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch.182, sec. 49, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 86,effective July 15, 1998.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44797</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>