<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8825</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement proceedings -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>8825</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Enforcement proceedings before a code enforcement board shall be initiated by the issuance of a citation by a code enforcement officer. </section><section prefix="2">When a code enforcement officer, based upon personal observation or investigation, has reasonable cause to believe that a person has committed a violation of a local government ordinance, the officer is authorized to issue a citation by: <section prefix="a">Personal service to the alleged violator; </section><section prefix="b">Leaving a copy of the citation with any person eighteen (18) years of age or older who is on the premises, if the alleged violator is not on the premises at the time the citation is issued; or </section><section prefix="c">Posting a copy of the citation in a conspicuous place on the premises and mailing a copy of the citation by regular, first-class mail of the United States Postal Service to the owner of record of the property if no one is on the premises at the time the citation is issued. </section></section> When authorized by ordinance, a code enforcement officer may, in lieu of immediately issuing a citation, give notice that a violation shall be remedied within a specified period of time. If the person to whom the notice is given fails or refuses to remedy the violation within the time specified, the code enforcement officer is authorized to issue a citation. <section prefix="3">The citation issued by the code enforcement officer shall be in a form prescribed by the local government and shall contain, in addition to any other information required by ordinance or rule of the board: <section prefix="a">The date and time of issuance; </section><section prefix="b">The name and address of the person to whom the citation is issued; </section><section prefix="c">The date and time the offense was committed; </section><section prefix="d">The facts constituting the offense; </section><section prefix="e">The section of the code or the number of the ordinance violated; </section><section prefix="f">The name of the code enforcement officer; </section><section prefix="g">The civil fine that will be imposed for the violation if the person does not contest the citation; </section><section prefix="h">The maximum civil fine that may be imposed if the person elects to contest the citation; </section><section prefix="i">The procedure for the person to follow in order to pay the civil fine or to contest the citation; and </section><section prefix="j">A statement that if the person fails to pay the civil fine set forth in the citation or contest the citation, within the time allowed, the person shall be deemed to have waived the right to a hearing before the code enforcement board to contest the citation and that the determination that a violation was committed shall be final. </section></section><section prefix="4">After issuing a citation to an alleged violator, the code enforcement officer shall notify the code enforcement board by delivering the citation to the administrative official designated by ordinance or by the board. </section><section prefix="5">When a citation is issued, the person to whom the citation is issued shall respond to the citation within seven (7) days of the date the citation is issued by either paying the civil fine set forth in the citation or requesting, in writing, a hearing before the code enforcement board to contest the citation. If the person fails to respond to the citation within seven (7) days, the person shall be deemed to have waived the right to a hearing to contest the citation and the determination that a violation was committed shall be considered final. In this event, the board shall enter a final order determining that the violation was committed and imposing the civil fine set forth in the citation. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>