<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.708</section_number><catch_line>Site assessment report -- Consultant -- Mitigation measures. </catch_line><order_by>708</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person proposing to construct a merchant electric generating facility shall file a site assessment report with the board as required under KRS 278.706(2)(l). </section><section prefix="2">A site assessment report shall be prepared by the applicant or its designee. </section><section prefix="3">A completed site assessment report shall include: <section prefix="a">A description of the proposed facility that shall include a proposed site development plan that describes: <section prefix="1">Surrounding land uses for residential, commercial, agricultural, and recreational purposes; </section><section prefix="2">The legal boundaries of the proposed site; </section><section prefix="3">Proposed access control to the site; </section><section prefix="4">The location of facility buildings, transmission lines, and other structures; </section><section prefix="5">Location and use of access ways, internal roads, and railways; </section><section prefix="6">Existing or proposed utilities to service the facility; </section><section prefix="7">Compliance with applicable setback requirements as provided under KRS 278.704(2), (3), (4), or (5); and </section><section prefix="8">Evaluation of the noise levels expected to be produced by the facility; </section></section><section prefix="b">An evaluation of the compatibility of the facility with scenic surroundings; </section><section prefix="c">The potential changes in property values and land use resulting from the siting, construction, and operation of the proposed facility for property owners adjacent to the facility; </section><section prefix="d">Evaluation of anticipated peak and average noise levels associated with the facility's construction and operation at the property boundary; and </section><section prefix="e">The impact of the facility's operation on road and rail traffic to and within the facility, including anticipated levels of fugitive dust created by the traffic and any anticipated degradation of roads and lands in the vicinity of the facility. </section></section><section prefix="4">The site assessment report shall also suggest any mitigating measures to be implemented by the applicant to minimize or avoid adverse effects identified in the site assessment report. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall have the authority to hire a consultant to review the site assessment report and provide recommendations concerning the adequacy of the report and proposed mitigation measures. The board may direct the consultant to prepare a separate site assessment report. Any expenses or fees incurred by the board's hiring of a consultant shall be borne by the applicant. </section><section prefix="6">The applicant shall be given the opportunity to present evidence to the board regarding any mitigation measures. As a condition of approval for an application to obtain a construction certificate, the board may require the implementation of any mitigation measures that the board deems appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 4, effective April 10, 2014. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 5, effective April 24, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 10, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42955</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>