<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">HUMAN RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>194.280</section_number><catch_line>Abolishment of certain departments, boards, and commissions.   </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text>Except as otherwise provided in 1974 Acts ch. 74, the following departments, boards, commissions, committees, and other statutory bodies and their subcommittees, task forces, advisory committees, bureaus, divisions, offices and other suborganizational units are abolished and terminated in their entirety: the Department of Economic Security, the Department of Health, the Department of Mental Health, the Department of Child Welfare, the Office of Economic Opportunity, the Bureau of Veterans Affairs, the Commission on Aging, the Commission for Handicapped Children, the Commission on Children and Youth, the Office of Youth Affairs, the State Board of Health, the Family Planning Committee, the Kidney Disease Advisory Committee, the Tuberculosis Commission, the Kentucky Manpower Council, the Kentucky Advisory Committee on Day Care, the Kentucky Children's Advisory Council, the State Advisory Committee on Public Assistance, the Kentucky Commission on Employment of the Handicapped, the Advisory Council on Individuals with an Intellectual Disability, the Advisory Council on Mental Health, the Developmental Disabilities Services Act Advisory Council, the Kentucky Commission on Alcohol and Drug Problems, the Radiation Operators' Advisory Committee, the Advisory Council for Health Facilities, the Human Resources Coordinating Commission, the Human Resources Coordinating Council, the Health Planning Commission, the Citizens' Commission for Barkley State Boys' Camp, the Citizens' Commission for Woodsbend Boys' Camp, the Citizens' Commission for the State Reception Center at Lyndon.  </text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 29. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>