<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">A HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>164A.590</section_number><catch_line>Contracting for architectural and engineering services. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the procurement of architectural and engineering services, the governing board of the institution shall encourage firms engaged in the lawful practice of their profession to submit an annual statement of qualifications and performance data. </section><section prefix="2">When the need for architectural and engineering services arise for specific projects, the governing board shall evaluate current statements of qualifications and performance data on file with the Commonwealth, together with those that may be submitted by other firms and shall conduct discussions with no less than three (3) firms regarding anticipated design concepts and the relative utility of alternative methods of approach for furnishing the required services, and after applying the reciprocal preference for resident bidders under KRS 45A.494, shall then select therefrom, in order of preference, based upon criteria established and published, no less than three (3) of the firms deemed to be the most highly qualified to provide the services required. </section><section prefix="3">The governing board shall negotiate a contract with the highest qualified firm for architectural and engineering services at compensation which the governing board determines in writing to be fair and reasonable to the Commonwealth. In making this decision, the governing board shall take into account the estimated value of the services to be rendered, the scope, complexity, and professional nature thereof. Should the governing board be unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with the firm considered to be the most qualified, at a price it determines to be fair and reasonable to the institution, negotiations with that firm shall be formally terminated. The governing board shall then undertake negotiations with the second most qualified firm. Failing accord with the second most qualified firm, the governing board shall formally terminate negotiations with that firm. The governing board shall then undertake negotiations with the third most qualified firm. Should the governing board be unable to negotiate a satisfactory contract with any of the selected firms, it shall select additional firms in order of their competence and qualification and the governing board shall continue negotiations in accordance with this section until an agreement is reached. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4582</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>