<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.272</section_number><catch_line>Bonds of several construction subdistricts -- Purposes, effect. </catch_line><order_by>272</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The district may issue for one or more construction subdistricts bonds to finance construction of trunk, main, connecting sewers and any other facilities necessary to which, directly or indirectly, connect one or more of such construction subdistricts to either the district facilities or to a treatment plant, disposal plant, or outfall sewer which also serves, directly or indirectly, at least one (1) other construction subdistrict. Such bonds may also be used to finance construction of a treatment plant, disposal plant, or outfall sewer of the type described in the preceding sentence.  </section><section prefix="2">Bonds issued pursuant to subsection (1) shall be construction subdistrict obligations for all construction subdistricts for which they are issued.  </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in this section, bonds authorized by subsection (1) shall be governed by KRS 76.254 and 76.261. Such bonds shall be construction subdistrict bonds within the meaning of paragraph (a) of subsection (3) of KRS 76.262. They shall not be considered construction subdistrict bonds within the meaning of subsection (6) of KRS 76.262.  </section></text><history>Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 26. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24537</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>