<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.2717</section_number><catch_line>Annual overweight permit for transporting nondivisible loads over specified routes -- Axle-weight limitation. </catch_line><order_by>2717</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the provisions of KRS 189.222, the department may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A governing the issuance of annual permits for the operation of motor vehicles transporting nondivisible loads in this Commonwealth whose gross weight exceeds the limits prescribed by this chapter. The gross weight of a motor vehicle operating pursuant to this section shall not exceed one hundred twenty thousand (120,000) pounds. The movement of the overweight motor vehicle shall be limited to a specific route set forth on the annual permit. </section><section prefix="2">The following axle weights shall not be exceeded in the loading of a nondivisible load: <section prefix="a">Single axle with axles less than forty-two (42) inches apart and being the steering axle with one (1) wheel on each side of the axle to be considered a single axle shall not be more than fifteen thousand (15,000) pounds; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) axles in tandem arrangement which are spaced forty-two (42) inches or more apart and less than ninety-six (96) inches apart shall not be more than forty thousand (40,000) pounds; </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) axles in tridem arrangement which are spaced forty-two (42) or more inches apart and less than one hundred twenty (120) inches apart shall not be more than sixty-five thousand (65,000) pounds; and </section><section prefix="d">Dual wheel axle with one (1) axle with two (2) wheels on each side of the axle to be considered a dual wheel axle shall not be more than twenty thousand (20,000) pounds each. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each motor vehicle operating pursuant to this section shall comply with the safety provisions set forth in the administrative regulations promulgated by the department pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="4">The fee for the annual permit for each motor vehicle pursuant to this section shall be five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="5">The department may refuse to issue a permit for a requested route because of the inadequacies of the roadway or a structure on that route. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6351</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>