<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.48-060</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of certificate of filing. </catch_line><order_by>48-060</order_by><text>Upon receipt of an application for issuance for a certificate of filing, the commissioner shall issue or deny the same. Issuance of a certificate of filing shall be granted only if the commissioner finds that the applicant has complied with KRS 304.48-050, has paid the application fee, and the commissioner is satisfied that the following conditions are met: <section prefix="1">The persons responsible for the conduct of the affairs of the liability self-insurance group are competent, trustworthy, and possess good reputation; </section><section prefix="2">The liability self-insurance group is financially responsible and may reasonably be expected to meet its obligations to participants and prospective participants. In making this determination, the commissioner may consider: <section prefix="a">The adequacy of working capital; </section><section prefix="b">Any agreement with an insurer, a government, or any other organization for insuring the payment of liability claims or the provision for automatic applicability of an alternative coverage in the event of discontinuance of the self-insurance group; and </section><section prefix="c">Compliance with KRS 304.48-070, as a guarantee that the obligations will be duly performed. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1593, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30197</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>