<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.902</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>902</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares that it is a policy of the Commonwealth to retain agriculture and enhance the contribution that agriculture makes to its economy. A program to retain and enhance agriculture is in the economic best interests of the Commonwealth and, consequently, constitutes a public benefit that contributes to the health, safety, and general welfare of the residents of the Commonwealth and the nation. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly further finds and declares that the use of the Commonwealth's funds for the purpose of paying in whole or part the cost of acquiring agricultural conservation easements as set forth in KRS 262.900 to 262.920, including any costs necessarily incident to the acquisition, sale, issuance, and delivery of the funds, and the monitoring and enforcement of agricultural conservation easements, or to the participation of any party for these purposes, will promote the public health, safety, and general welfare of the people of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Further, it is the purpose of KRS 262.900 to 262.920 to: <section prefix="a">Establish procedures for the acquisition of agricultural conservation easements in order to ensure that lands currently in agricultural use will continue to remain available for agriculture and not be converted to other land uses, and that landowners who participate in this program will be fairly compensated for their agreement to accept deed restrictions limiting the use of their property; </section><section prefix="b">Encourage landowners to make a long-term commitment to agriculture by offering them financial incentives and security that land use will remain stable; </section><section prefix="c">Protect normal farming operations in agricultural areas from incompatible nonfarming uses that may render farming impracticable; </section><section prefix="d">Protect normal farming operations from complaints of public nuisance against normal farming operations; and </section><section prefix="e">Maximize the use of agricultural conservation easement purchase funds and protect the investment of taxpayers in agricultural conservation easements. </section></section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12814</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>