<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.645</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.647 and 211.2970. </catch_line><order_by>645</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.647 and 216.2970, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Commission" means the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs; </section><section prefix="3">"Permanent childhood hearing loss" means a hearing deficit identified in infancy or childhood which prevents the acquisition of speech and language through normal channels; </section><section prefix="4">"Auditory screening report" means a written evaluation of an auditory screening as required under KRS 216.2970; and </section><section prefix="5">"Infant at high risk for late onset, progressive hearing loss, or both" means a child at birth who is at a higher risk than normal of becoming deaf or hard of hearing or having progressively worsening hearing due to one (1) or more of the following factors: <section prefix="a">Family history of a congenital hearing loss; </section><section prefix="b">Rubella or virus during pregnancy; </section><section prefix="c">Neonatal intensive care of more than five (5) days; </section><section prefix="d">Below-normal birth weight; </section><section prefix="e">Neonatal intensive care, regardless of the number of days, for any of the following conditions: <section prefix="1">Extracorporeal membrane oxygenation (ECMO); </section><section prefix="2">Assisted ventilation; </section><section prefix="3">Exposure to ototoxic medications, including but not limited to gentramycin and tobramycin, or loop diuretics, including but not limited to furosemide; </section><section prefix="4">Hyperbilirubinemia that requires an exchange transfusion; </section><section prefix="5">Syndromes associated with hearing loss and progressive or late onset hearing loss, including but not limited to neurofibromatosis, osteopetrosis, and Usher, Waardenburg, Alport, Pendred, and Jervell and Lange-Nielson Syndromes; </section><section prefix="6">Congenital ear, nose, or throat anomalies, including but not limited to those involving the pinna, ear canal, ear tags, ear pits, and temporal bone; or </section><section prefix="7">Culture-positive postnatal infections associated with sensorineural hearing loss, including but not limited to confirmed bacterial and viral meningitis; </section></section><section prefix="f">An auditory screening indicating a hearing loss; or </section><section prefix="g">Any other factor identified by the American Medical Association the American Academy of Pediatrics, or the American Academy of Otolaryngology as a cause of late onset or progressive hearing loss. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 365, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 307, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 75, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 37, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 489, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8449</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>