<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.200</section_number><catch_line>Hearing -- Denial of license or any other disciplinary action -- Appeal -- Stay of judgment pending appeal. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the commission determines after a hearing that any applicant is not entitled to receive a license, a license shall not be granted to the applicant, and if the commission determines after a hearing that any licensee has violated any of the provisions of this chapter, the disciplinary measures in KRS 324.160(1) may be ordered. </section><section prefix="2">Any party aggrieved by the action of the commission in refusing to grant a license or in ordering any disciplinary action may appeal to the Circuit Court where the licensee has his principal place of business or where the applicant resides in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. Disciplinary action imposed by the commission shall be automatically stayed during the pendency of an appeal to a circuit or appellate court, unless otherwise indicated in the final order of the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 19, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 291, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, secs.  4 and 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-7. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31584</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>