<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-232</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240. </catch_line><order_by>20-232</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240 shall be known as the "Kentucky Angel Investment Act." </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of KRS 141.396 and 154.20-230 to 154.20-240 is to encourage capital investment in the Commonwealth by individual investors that will further the establishment or expansion of small businesses, create additional jobs, and foster the development of new products and technologies, by providing tax credits for certain investments in small businesses located in the Commonwealth, operating in the fields of knowledge-based, high-tech, and research and development, and showing a potential for rapid growth. </section><section prefix="3">To participate in the program created by KRS 141.396 and 154.20-230 to 154.20-240: <section prefix="a">Small businesses and individual investors shall request certification from the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-236. To be qualified, the small businesses and individual investors shall fulfill the requirements outlined in KRS 154.20-234; and </section><section prefix="b">Once certified, qualified investors may make investments in qualified small businesses, and may apply to the authority for a credit in return for making the investment if that investment qualifies under KRS 154.20-234. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any qualified investment made in a qualified small business under KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240 shall be used by that business, insofar as possible, to leverage additional capital investments from other sources. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43415</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>