<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="29" order_by="29">A JURIES </unit></structure><section_number>29A.060</section_number><catch_line>Assignment of jurors by Chief Circuit Judge -- Service of summons -- Selection of additional jurors -- Summonsing jurors from adjoining counties. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each Circuit or District Judge shall inform the Chief Circuit Judge or the Chief Circuit Judge's designee of the need for qualified jurors. </section><section prefix="2">The Chief Circuit Judge or designee shall regulate the random assignment of jurors for use in Circuit and District Courts. Any petit juror assigned to a judge of Circuit or District Court may be used by any other judge of any other branch or division of Circuit or District Court when jurors are needed. </section><section prefix="3">If a grand, petit, or other jury is ordered to be drawn, the Chief Circuit Judge or designee thereafter shall cause each person drawn for jury service to be served with a summons requiring that person to report for jury service at a specified time and place, unless otherwise notified by the court, and to be available for jury service for thirty (30) judicial days thereafter. The service of summons shall be made by the court utilizing first class mail, addressed to each person at his or her usual residence, business, or post office address. In the event service cannot be accomplished by first class mail, the court may cause service to be made personally by the sheriff. In either case, notice shall be mailed or served to the prospective juror at least thirty (30) days before he or she is required to attend. </section><section prefix="4">The juror qualification form required by KRS 29A.070 shall be enclosed with the summons. If the summons is served by mail, any prospective juror who does not return the juror qualification form within ten (10) days may be personally served by the sheriff at the discretion of the Chief Circuit Judge or Chief Circuit Judge's designee. </section><section prefix="5">When there is an unanticipated shortage of available jurors obtained from a randomized jury list, the Chief Circuit Judge may cause to be summonsed a sufficient number of jurors selected sequentially from the randomized jury list beginning with the first name following the last name previously selected. The persons so chosen shall be summonsed as provided in this section, but need not be given the notice provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Only persons duly qualified and summonsed under subsection (3) of this section and KRS 29A.070 shall serve as jurors. </section><section prefix="7">If, after making a fair effort in good faith, the judge is satisfied that it will be impracticable to obtain a jury free of bias in the county in which the prosecution is pending, the judge may obtain a sufficient number of jurors from some adjoining county in which the judge believes there is the greatest probability of obtaining impartial jurors. The judge shall request the Chief Circuit Judge for the adjoining county to draw and summon as many jurors as are needed. Jurors summonsed under this subsection need not be given the notice provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 449, sec. 7, effective October 1, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 17, effective September 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21123</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>