<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.115</section_number><catch_line>Department of Natural Resources to adopt rules and administrative regulations after notice and hearing -- Operators to submit production information annually. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department is hereby authorized to adopt all rules, administrative regulations, and amendments to implement the provisions of this chapter. All rules, administrative regulations, and amendments promulgated under this chapter shall be promulgated by the department after notice and a hearing. At all hearings held to consider any rules, administrative regulations, or amendments thereto, any interested person shall be entitled to be heard. </section><section prefix="2">All hearings shall be held at a time and place as is specified by the department according to rules and regulations promulgated under this chapter. A written record of each hearing shall be kept; however, if not at variance with KRS 61.870 to 61.884, the keeping of a record may be waived by all parties who participate therein. All interested persons shall be entitled to be heard at all hearings conducted under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">Operators shall submit annual production information for each coalbed methane well on a form prescribed by the department. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 23, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>