<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.530</section_number><catch_line>Filing of petition -- Contents -- Application of person or entity desiring appointment. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petition for a determination of partial disability or disability and the appointment of a limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator may be filed by any interested person or by an individual needing guardianship or conservatorship. The petition shall set forth the following: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the respondent; </section><section prefix="b">The date of birth of the respondent, if known; </section><section prefix="c">The nature and degree of the alleged disability of the respondent; </section><section prefix="d">The facts and reasons supporting the need for guardianship or conservatorship; </section><section prefix="e">A description and approximation of the value of the respondent's financial resources, including government benefits, insurance entitlements, and anticipated yearly income, if known; </section><section prefix="f">The names and addresses of the respondent's next of kin, if known; </section><section prefix="g">The name and address of the individual or facility, if any, having custody of the respondent; </section><section prefix="h">The name, address and interest of the petitioner; </section><section prefix="i">The name and address of the petitioner's attorney, if any; and </section><section prefix="j">The name and address of any person or entity appointed by the respondent as respondent's attorney in fact under a durable power of attorney, as defined in KRS 386.093(1), or as respondent's surrogate to make health care decisions under an advance directive. </section></section><section prefix="2">The petition shall be accompanied by a verified application of the person or entity desiring appointment as limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator. The application shall state the name, address, and qualifications of the applicant and his relationship to the respondent. If it is proposed that a standby limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator be designated, the petition shall also be accompanied by the application of the person or entity desiring to be so designated. Additional petitions may be filed prior to the date of the hearing by other persons desiring appointment. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 421, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36042</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>