<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.350</section_number><catch_line>Execution of process -- Jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Constables may execute warrants, summons, subpoenas, attachments, notices, rules and orders of court in all criminal, penal and civil cases, and shall return all process placed in his hands to the courts or persons issuing them, on or before the return day, noting the time of execution on them. </section><section prefix="2">A constable may exercise the duties of his office in any part of the county, but shall not execute any process in which he is personally interested except fee-bills for his own service. He shall not levy on or sell land, or any interest therein. </section><section prefix="3">The constable shall not be compelled to receive a precept, fee-bill or order for witness attendance, or other claim against any person who is known to be and to reside out of his district, unless the precept is in behalf of the Commonwealth or is a precept against property in his district. But if a constable voluntarily receives such precept, fee-bill, order for witness attendance or other claim, he and his sureties shall be accountable for the same as if the person it is against resided or was in his district, or had property therein. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 436, 438, 439, 440. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24232</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>