<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.670</section_number><catch_line>Promulgation of regulations -- Hearing -- Written record of hearing. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All rules, regulations and amendments promulgated under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall be promulgated by the department after notice and a hearing. At all hearings held to consider any rules, regulations or amendments thereto, any interested person shall be entitled to be heard. </section><section prefix="2">All hearings held under this section shall be held at such time and place as is specified by the department, and according to rules and regulations promulgated under KRS 353.500 to 353.720. A written record of each hearing shall be kept, unless the keeping of a record shall be waived by all parties who participate therein. All interested persons shall be entitled to be heard at all hearings conducted under KRS 353.500 to 353.720. </section><section prefix="3">The director of the Division of Oil and Gas, or his representatives, shall attend all hearings under this section conducted by the department. </section><section prefix="4">All rules, regulations and orders promulgated or issued under KRS 353.500 to 353.720 shall be in writing, shall be entered in full and indexed in books to be kept by the department for that purpose, shall be public records open for inspection at all times during office hours, and shall be filed in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. A copy of any rule, regulation, or order, certified by the commissioner of the Department for Natural Resources or the director of the Division of Oil and Gas, shall be received in evidence in all courts of this Commonwealth without any further authentication thereof. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1911, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 19, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33136</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>