<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.6451</section_number><catch_line>Legislative declaration on goals for Commonwealth's schools -- Model curriculum framework. </catch_line><order_by>6451</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds, declares, and establishes that: <section prefix="a">Schools shall expect a high level of achievement of all students. </section><section prefix="b">Schools shall develop their students' ability to: <section prefix="1">Use basic communication and mathematics skills for purposes and situations they will encounter throughout their lives; </section><section prefix="2">Apply core concepts and principles from mathematics, the sciences, the arts, the humanities, social studies, and practical living studies to situations they will encounter throughout their lives; </section><section prefix="3">Become self-sufficient individuals of good character exhibiting the qualities of altruism, citizenship, courtesy, hard work, honesty, human worth, justice, knowledge, patriotism, respect, responsibility, and self-discipline; </section><section prefix="4">Become responsible members of a family, work group, or community, including demonstrating effectiveness in community service; </section><section prefix="5">Think and solve problems in school situations and in a variety of situations they will encounter in life; </section><section prefix="6">Connect and integrate experiences and new knowledge from all subject matter fields with what they have previously learned and build on past learning experiences to acquire new information through various media sources; and </section><section prefix="7">Express their creative talents and interests in visual arts, music, dance, and dramatic arts. </section></section><section prefix="c">Schools shall increase their students' rate of school attendance. </section><section prefix="d">Schools shall increase their students' graduation rates and reduce their students' dropout and retention rates. </section><section prefix="e">Schools shall reduce physical and mental health barriers to learning. </section><section prefix="f">Schools shall be measured on the proportion of students who make a successful transition to work, post-secondary education, and the military. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall disseminate to local school districts and schools a model curriculum framework which is directly tied to the goals, outcomes, and assessment strategies developed pursuant to this section and KRS 158.645 and 158.6453. The framework shall provide direction to local districts and schools as they develop their curriculum. The framework shall identify teaching and assessment strategies, instructional material resources, ideas on how to incorporate the resources of the community, a directory of model teaching sites, alternative ways of using school time, and strategies to incorporate character education throughout the curriculum. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 1, effective March 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3552</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>