<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-108</section_number><catch_line>Sufficiency of description. </catch_line><order_by>9-108</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3), (4), and (5) of this section, a description of personal or real property is sufficient, whether or not it is specific, if it reasonably identifies what is described. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, a description of collateral reasonably identifies the collateral if it identifies the collateral by: <section prefix="a">Specific listing; </section><section prefix="b">Category; </section><section prefix="c">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (5) of this section, a type of collateral defined in this chapter; </section><section prefix="d">Quantity; </section><section prefix="e">Computational or allocational formula or procedure; or </section><section prefix="f">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) of this section, any other method, if the identity of the collateral is objectively determinable. </section></section><section prefix="3">A description of collateral as "all the debtor’s assets" or "all the debtor’s personal property" or using words of similar import does not reasonably identify the collateral. </section><section prefix="4">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (5) of this section, a description of a security entitlement, securities account, or commodity account is sufficient if it describes: <section prefix="a">The collateral by those terms or as investment property; or </section><section prefix="b">The underlying financial asset or commodity contract. </section></section><section prefix="5">A description only by type of collateral defined in this chapter is an insufficient description of: <section prefix="a">A commercial tort claim; or </section><section prefix="b">In a consumer transaction, consumer goods, a security entitlement, a securities account, or a commodity account. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 28, effective July 1, 2001. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-108, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>