<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.8-100</section_number><catch_line>Branch offices. </catch_line><order_by>8-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No licensee shall establish or maintain a branch transacting business in Kentucky, either directly or indirectly, without filing the application as described in KRS 286.8-032(5) and receiving prior written approval of the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Each application for approval of the establishment and maintenance of a branch shall state the physical address of the proposed location, the functions to be performed, and other information the commissioner may require if different from that contained in the original application for a license or registration. </section><section prefix="3">Each application under this section shall be sworn to and accompanied by the appropriate fee as set out in KRS 286.8-034(1)(b). </section><section prefix="4">Upon the receipt by the commissioner of an application and the required fee, if he finds that the applicant is otherwise in compliance with the provisions of this subtitle, he shall approve the application. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner may deem an application abandoned and subject to KRS 286.8-090 when the application is received incomplete and the applicant fails to provide any required information or fee under this subtitle or fails to respond to a request by the commissioner for further information. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 776, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 10, effective April 24, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 461, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 294.100. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14868</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>