<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.695</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>695</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Trailers, semitrailers, and manufactured homes as defined in KRS 186.650 to 186.700 are expressly exempted from KRS 138.450 to 138.470. </section><section prefix="2">Trailers and semitrailers in transit between a manufacturing plant and dealer's place of business; between a manufacturing plant and user's place of residence; or between a dealer's place of business and user's place of residence and farm equipment pulled or towed by a motor vehicle not required to be licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 186 shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 186.650 to 186.700. </section><section prefix="3">Recreational vehicles and manufactured homes in transit between a manufacturing plant and dealer's place of business shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 186.650 to 186.700. </section><section prefix="4">Manufactured homes shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 186.650 to 186.700. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, secs. 5 and 8, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 (2nd Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, secs. 11 and 11a. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 42, secs. 5 and 8 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>