<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.705</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>705</order_by><text>Unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Blighted" or "deteriorated" property means any vacant structure or vacant or unimproved lot or parcel of ground in a predominantly built-up neighborhood: <section prefix="a">Which because of physical condition or use is regarded as a public nuisance at common law or has been declared a public nuisance in accordance with a city of any class, or in counties containing a city of the first class or consolidated local government, with the housing, building, plumbing, fire, or related codes; </section><section prefix="b">Which because of physical condition, use, or occupancy is considered an attractive nuisance to children, including but not limited to abandoned wells, shafts, basements, excavations, and unsafe fences or structures; </section><section prefix="c">Which because it is dilapidated, unsanitary, unsafe, vermin-infested, or lacking in the facilities and equipment required by the housing code of a city or county containing a city of the first class or consolidated local government, has been designated by the department responsible for enforcement of the code as unfit for human habitation; </section><section prefix="d">Which is a fire hazard, or is otherwise dangerous to the safety of persons or property; </section><section prefix="e">From which the utilities, plumbing, heating, sewerage, or other facilities have been disconnected, destroyed, removed, or rendered ineffective so that the property is unfit for its intended use; </section><section prefix="f">Which by reason of neglect or lack of maintenance has become a place for accumulation of trash and debris, or a haven for rodents or other vermin; </section><section prefix="g">Which has been tax delinquent for a period of at least three (3) years; or </section><section prefix="h">Which has not been rehabilitated within the time constraints placed upon the owner by the appropriate code enforcement agency. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Redevelopment" means the planning or replanning, design or redesign, acquisition, clearance, development, and disposal or any combination of these, of a property in the preparation of such property for residential and related uses, as may be appropriate or necessary. </section><section prefix="3">"Residential and related use" shall mean residential property for sale or rental and related uses; including but not limited to park and recreation areas, neighborhood community service, and neighborhood parking lots. </section><section prefix="4">"Vacant property review commission" means a commission established by ordinance to review vacant properties to make a written determination of blight and deterioration. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 128, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>