<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.754</section_number><catch_line>Petitioner for protective order may apply for temporary permit to carry concealed deadly weapon -- Criteria -- Denial of application final -- Conversion to concealed carry license -- Automated listing of temporary permit holders. </catch_line><order_by>754</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A petitioner for an order of protection granted under KRS 403.715 to 403.785 may apply for a temporary permit to carry a concealed deadly weapon on or about his or her person into those places and under the same conditions as a person holding a carry concealed deadly weapon license issued under KRS 237.110.  </section><section prefix="2">To request a temporary permit authorized by this section, the petitioner shall apply electronically for a license to carry a concealed deadly weapon in the manner set forth in KRS 237.110 and administrative regulation promulgated by the Department of Kentucky State Police, unless the electronic application is unavailable. If the electronic application is unavailable, applications for temporary permits under this section shall not be accepted. </section><section prefix="3">Prior to the issuance of a temporary permit authorized by this section, the Department of Kentucky State Police, upon receipt of a completed application, application fee, and any documentation required by KRS 237.110 or administrative regulation promulgated by the Department of Kentucky State Police, shall conduct the background check as set forth in KRS 237.110. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall issue a temporary permit authorized by this section if the applicant is not disqualified under the standards set forth in KRS 237.110(4)(a) to (h). </section><section prefix="5">A temporary permit issued under this section shall be valid for forty-five (45) days from the date of issuance and not be subsequently extended or reissued. A temporary permit which has expired shall be void and shall not be valid for any purpose. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall, within one (1) working day or as soon as practically possible after the date of receipt of the completed application, a recent color photograph of the applicant, and, for applicants who are not citizens of the United States, any documentation required under KRS 237.110, either issue the temporary permit or deny the application based solely on the grounds that the applicant fails to qualify under the criteria set forth in KRS 237.110.  </section><section prefix="7">In order to convert the temporary permit issued under this section into a license to carry a concealed deadly weapon issued under KRS 237.110, the applicant shall meet the firearms safety training requirement under KRS 237.110(4) within the forty-five (45) day period the temporary permit is valid. If firearms safety training is not completed within the forty-five (45) day temporary permit period, a new application for a license to carry a concealed deadly weapon shall be required. </section><section prefix="8">If the Department of Kentucky State Police denies the application for a temporary permit, that decision shall be final but the applicant’s application for a license to carry a concealed deadly license shall continue to be processed and either issued or denied in accordance with KRS 237.110. </section><section prefix="9">The holder of a permit issued under this section shall carry the permit at all times the permit holder is carrying a concealed firearm or other deadly weapon and shall display the permit upon request of a law enforcement officer. Violation of the provisions of this subsection shall constitute a noncriminal violation with a penalty of twenty-five dollars ($25), payable to the clerk of the District Court, but no court costs shall be assessed. </section><section prefix="10">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall maintain an automated listing of temporary permit holders and pertinent information under the same circumstances and restrictions set forth in KRS 237.110. </section><section prefix="11">Nothing in this section shall authorize the carrying of a concealed deadly weapon by a person prohibited from possessing such a weapon by state or federal law. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43451</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>