<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.13-081</section_number><catch_line>Filings open to inspection -- Consumer information system. </catch_line><order_by>13-081</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All rates, supplementary rate information, and supporting information filed under KRS 304.13-011 to 304.13-161 shall be open to public inspection at any reasonable time. Copies may be obtained by any person on request and on payment of a charge specified in Subtitle 4 of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall utilize, develop, or cause to be developed a consumer information system that will provide and disseminate price and other relevant information on a readily available basis to purchasers of homeowners or private passenger insurance. The commissioner may utilize, develop, or cause to be developed a consumer information system which will provide and disseminate price and other relevant information on a readily available basis to purchasers of insurance for commercial risks and personal risks not otherwise specified in this section. Such activity may be conducted internally within the department, in cooperation with other state insurance departments, through outside contractors, or in any other appropriate manner. To the extent the commissioner considers necessary and appropriate, insurers, advisory organizations, statistical agents, and other persons or organizations involved in conducting the business of insurance in this state, to which this section applies, shall cooperate with the commissioner in the development and utilization of a consumer information system. The reasonable cost of developing a consumer information system shall be assessed against insurers subject to this chapter on an equitable basis. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1124, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 380, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17067</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>