<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.5089</section_number><catch_line>Use of assessment funds. </catch_line><order_by>5089</order_by><text>The funds, including donations from individuals, concerns, corporations, and grants from the state or governmental agencies, shall be used for the purpose of promoting and stimulating, by research, market development and education, the increased use and sale, domestic and foreign, of small grains and small grains products; and for the prevention, modification, or elimination of trade barriers which obstruct the free flow of small grains and small grains products to market. None of these funds shall be used to lobby as defined in KRS 6.611. The duly certified association receiving the assessment funds shall, upon the advice and consent of the Kentucky Small Grain Promotion Council, use and disburse the same as follows: <section prefix="1">The association may first refund to itself therefrom the costs and expenses incurred in the conduct of the referendum; </section><section prefix="2">The association may spend or disburse the necessary funds therefrom for administrative costs and expenses, but no more than fifteen percent (15%) of the funds collected in any marketing year shall be so utilized; and </section><section prefix="3">The balance remaining shall be used for the purposes provided in this section, as determined by the Kentucky Small Grain Promotion Council. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 66, effective September 16, 1993. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11702</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>