<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.601</section_number><catch_line>Death in the line of duty -- Allowances.   </catch_line><order_by>601</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the death of a member in service occurs on or after August 1, 1992, as a direct result of an "act in line of duty" and the member has on file in the retirement office at the time of his death a written designation of only one (1) beneficiary, who is his spouse, the beneficiary may elect to receive a lump-sum payment of ten thousand dollars ($10,000) and a monthly payment equal to twenty-five percent (25%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay beginning in the month following the member's death and continuing each month until death. </section><section prefix="2">If the death of a member in service occurs on or after July 1, 1968, as a direct result of an "act in line of duty" and the member has on file in the retirement office at the time of his death a written designation of only one (1) beneficiary other than his spouse, who is a dependent receiving at least one-half (1/2) of his support from the deceased member, the beneficiary may elect to receive a lump-sum payment of ten thousand dollars ($10,000). </section><section prefix="3">In the period of time following a member's death during which dependent children survive, monthly payments shall be made for each dependent child who is alive, equal to ten percent (10%) of the deceased member's monthly final rate of pay; however, total maximum dependent children's benefits shall not be greater than forty percent (40%) of the deceased member's monthly final rate of pay at the time any particular payment is due. The payments shall commence in the month following the date of death of the member and shall be payable to the beneficiaries, or to a legally appointed guardian or as directed by the system. Benefits shall be payable under this subsection notwithstanding an election by a beneficiary to withdraw the deceased member's accumulated account balance as provided in KRS 61.625 or benefits under any other provisions of KRS 16.510 to 16.652. </section><section prefix="4">A beneficiary eligible for benefits under subsection (1) or (2) of this section who is also eligible for benefits under any other provisions of KRS 16.510 to 16.652 may elect benefits under this section or any other section of KRS 16.510 to 16.652 but cannot elect to receive both. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 42, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 40. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 9, effective March 26, 1974. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 76. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 25. sec. 6. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42670</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>