<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.721</section_number><catch_line>Title IV-A services available to individuals not receiving public assistance benefits -- Continuation of IV-D services -- Fee for services -- Exemption -- Annual fee. </catch_line><order_by>721</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All services available to individuals receiving public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act benefits shall also be available to individuals not receiving public assistance benefits, upon application by the individual with the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall continue to provide IV-D services when a family ceases to receive public assistance without requiring a formal application and without payment of the application fee specified in subsection (3) of this section. IV-D services shall be discontinued upon the request of the recipient. </section><section prefix="3">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the cabinet may charge an application fee for the services based on a fee schedule, which shall take into account the applicant's net income. No application fee shall be required from individuals receiving public assistance. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall impose an annual fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) pursuant to Public Law 109-171, Section 7310, which shall be satisfied by withholding the fee from a child support disbursement. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998 and ch. 255, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 418, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7807</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>