<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-270</section_number><catch_line>Mental or physical examinations. </catch_line><order_by>39-270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the mental or physical condition of a person is material to a claim for past or future basic or added reparation benefits, the reparation obligor may petition the circuit court for an order directing the person to submit to a mental or physical examination by a physician. Upon notice to the person to be examined and all persons having an interest, the court may make the order for good cause shown. The order shall specify the time, place, manner, conditions, scope of the examination, and the physician by whom it is to be made.  </section><section prefix="2">If requested by the person examined, the reparation obligor causing a mental or physical examination to be made shall deliver to the person examined a copy of a detailed written report of the examining physician setting out his findings including results of all tests made, diagnoses, and conclusions, and reports of earlier examinations of the same condition. By requesting and obtaining a report of the examination ordered or by taking the deposition of the physician, the person examined waives any privilege he may have, in relation to the claim for basic or added reparation benefits, regarding the testimony of every other person who has examined or may thereafter examine him respecting the same condition. This subsection does not preclude discovery of a report of an examining physician, taking a deposition of the physician, or other discovery procedures in accordance with any rule of court or other provision of law. This subsection applies to examinations made by agreement of the person examined and the reparation obligor, unless the agreement provides otherwise.  </section><section prefix="3">If any person refuses to comply with an order entered under this section the court may make any just order as to the refusal, but may not find a person in contempt for failure to submit to a mental or physical examination.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 27, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1975 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30058</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>