<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="385" order_by="385">UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>385.012</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>012</order_by><text>As used in KRS 385.022 to 385.222: <section prefix="1">"Adult" means an individual who has attained the age of eighteen (18) years; </section><section prefix="2">"Benefit plan" means an employer's plan for the benefit of an employee or partner; </section><section prefix="3">"Broker" means a person lawfully engaged in the business of effecting transactions in securities or commodities for the person's own account or for the account of others; </section><section prefix="4">"Conservator" means a person appointed or qualified by a court to act as general, limited, or temporary guardian of a minor's property or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions; </section><section prefix="5">"Court" means District Court; </section><section prefix="6">"Custodial property" means: <section prefix="a">Any interest in property transferred to a custodian under KRS 385.032 to 385.222; and </section><section prefix="b">The income from and proceeds of that interest in property; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Custodian" means a person so designated under KRS 385.092; or a successor or substitute custodian designated under KRS 385.182; </section><section prefix="8">"Financial institution" means a bank, trust company savings institution or credit union, chartered and supervised under state or federal law; </section><section prefix="9">"Legal representative" means an individual's personal representative or conservator; </section><section prefix="10">"Member of the minor's family" means the minor's parent, step-parent, spouse, grandparent, brother, sister, uncle, or aunt, whether of the whole or half blood or by adoption; </section><section prefix="11">"Minor" means an individual who has not attained the age of eighteen (18) years; </section><section prefix="12">"Person" means an individual, corporation, organization, or other legal entity; </section><section prefix="13">"Personal representative" means an executor, administrator, successor personal representative, or special administrator of a decedent's estate or a person legally authorized to perform substantially the same functions; </section><section prefix="14">"State" includes any state of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession subject to the legislative authority of the United States; </section><section prefix="15">"Transfer" means a transaction that creates custodial property under KRS 385.092; </section><section prefix="16">"Transferor" means a person who makes a transfer under KRS 385.032 to 385.222; </section><section prefix="17">"Trust company" means a financial institution, corporation, or other legal entity, authorized to exercise general trust powers. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>