<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.030</section_number><catch_line>Licensing and registration of dentists, dental hygienists, and dental assistants -- Duration, expiration, and renewal -- Disciplinary action by board -- Board's power to extend license or registration. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The license or registration held by a dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant shall be valid for a period of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="2">Each license or registration held by a dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant shall expire on December 31. A dentist's license shall expire in odd-numbered years, while all other licenses or registrations issued by the board shall expire in even-numbered years. </section><section prefix="3">Each license or registration held by any person issued under the provisions of this chapter shall be renewed at least biennially. Upon receipt of the application and fee, the board shall verify the accuracy of the application to determine whether the licensee or person seeking licensure or registration has met all the requirements as set forth in this chapter and in the administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and, if so, shall issue to the applicant a license or registration to practice or engage in the activity for the ensuing licensure or registration period. Such license or registration shall render the holder a legal practitioner of the practice or activity specified in the license or registration for the period stated on it. The board shall prescribe by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A the beginning and ending of the licensure or registration period. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who is licensed or registered by the board who allows his or her license or registration to lapse by failing to renew the license or registration as provided in this section may be reinstated by the board on payment of the current fee for original licensure or registration in addition to any late fees and by meeting the requirements of administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="5">An application for renewal of a license or registration shall be completed online or, if a written request is made to the board prior to November 1 of the year of expiration, a paper application shall be sent to the last known address of each licensee or certified or registered person requesting a paper application. </section><section prefix="6">Any person engaging in any practice or activity regulated by the board during the time his or her license or registration has lapsed shall be considered practicing with an expired license or registration and shall be subject to the penalties provided for violations of this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">Failure to receive the application for renewal of a license or registration shall not relieve a dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant from the duty to renew his or her license or registration prior to December 31 of the year in which the license or registration expires. </section><section prefix="8">The duration of any license or registration issued by the board may be limited by disciplinary action of the board. </section><section prefix="9">Every license or registration issued by the board shall have the seal of the board affixed. A holder of a license or registration shall retain it in his or her possession and be prepared to exhibit it upon demand by an employer or anyone to whom the holder of the license or registration offers treatment or any board or staff member of the Kentucky Board of Dentistry. Each license or registration issued by the board shall be posted in a conspicuous place in each place of employment of the dentist, dental hygienist, or dental assistant. </section><section prefix="10">Failure or refusal to produce a license or registration upon demand shall be prima facie evidence that no such license or registration exists. </section><section prefix="11">In order to ensure a proper transition during the implementation of the provisions of this section, the board may, for a period of no longer than three (3) years, extend a license or registration of any person in order to utilize the expiration date provided for in this section. The board shall, in writing, notify each person whose license or registration is extended of the extension and the new date of expiration. The extension shall be without charge. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 12, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 556, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2636-21. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>