<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.200</section_number><catch_line>Records to be kept by teachers -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each teacher in the public schools shall keep an approved record which shall be left with the superintendent or as he directs at the close of the term. The record shall show the program of recitations, classification, attendance, and grading of all pupils who attended school at any time during the school year, and such other facts as are required. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, approved pupil attendance records, for state accounting purposes and for the purpose of state computation of pupil attendance, may be kept in a central location in the local elementary or secondary school. After attendance is reported and recorded by the classroom teacher, either a certified or noncertified person shall complete and check records in accordance with the methods and regulations approved by the superintendent of the local school district and the chief state school officer. A designated certified person within the local elementary or secondary school shall be responsible for auditing and certifying state attendance documents to verify their accuracy. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 242, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4503-5. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>