<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.007</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth's sentencing policy. </catch_line><order_by>007</order_by><text>It is the sentencing policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that: <section prefix="1">The primary objective of sentencing shall be to maintain public safety and hold offenders accountable while reducing recidivism and criminal behavior and improving outcomes for those offenders who are sentenced; </section><section prefix="2">Reduction of recidivism and criminal behavior is a key measure of the performance of the criminal justice system; </section><section prefix="3">Sentencing judges shall consider: <section prefix="a">Beginning July 1, 2013, the results of a defendant's risk and needs assessment included in the presentence investigation; and </section><section prefix="b">The likely impact of a potential sentence on the reduction of the defendant's potential future criminal behavior; </section></section><section prefix="4">All supervision and treatment programs provided for defendants shall utilize evidence-based practices to reduce the likelihood of future criminal behavior; and </section><section prefix="5">All supervision and treatment programs shall be evaluated at regular intervals to measure and ensure reduction of criminal behavior by defendants in the criminal justice system. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39523</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>