<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="140" order_by="140">INHERITANCE AND ESTATE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>140.275</section_number><catch_line>Exclusion of intangible personal property held in trust, under reciprocal agreements with other states. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby declared to be the legislative policy that Kentucky shall not be a party to interstate double taxation under the terms of the Kentucky inheritance and estate tax laws. Pursuant to this policy, the commissioner of the Department of Revenue is hereby authorized to omit from the property subject to tax under those laws, any intangible personal property of a nonresident decedent (having a domicile in the United States) held in trust by a Kentucky trustee if the jurisdiction (state, territory or District of Columbia) in which the decedent was domiciled grants similar immunity to residents of Kentucky, but only in the event the personal representative shall present evidence that the tax has been or will be paid to the other jurisdiction. If another state, territory, or the District of Columbia of the United States constitutionally imposes a tax on the transfer of estates or of the distributive shares thereof, but grants immunity from the tax in respect of any intangible property of its resident decedents held in trust by a Kentucky trustee, then the commissioner of the Department of Revenue is hereby authorized to exclude from the property subject to tax under the Kentucky inheritance and estate tax laws, the intangible personal property of a Kentucky resident held in trust in that jurisdiction but only in the event the personal representative shall present evidence that the tax has been or will be paid to the other jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="2">It is expressly provided, however, in view of the uncertainty now prevailing with respect to the correct interpretation of the Constitution of the United States regarding the jurisdiction of the several states, that the provisions of this section shall be inoperative under the second alternative until and unless an agreement, approved as to legality by the Attorney General, between the commissioner of the Department of Revenue as agent for Kentucky and the appropriate administrative official of such other state, shall have been executed and an original copy thereof filed with the Kentucky Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="3">This section is intended to apply retroactively to all estates of decedents on or after April 25, 1936, which are subject to Kentucky inheritance tax laws. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 465, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29011</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>