<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="386" order_by="386">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS -- LEGAL INVESTMENTS -- UNIFORM PRINCIPAL AND INCOME ACT </unit></structure><section_number>386.093</section_number><catch_line>Effect of disability, incapacity, or death on power of attorney, durable or otherwise. </catch_line><order_by>093</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "durable power of attorney" means a power of attorney by which a principal designates another as the principal's attorney in fact in writing and the writing contains the words, "This power of attorney shall not be affected by subsequent disability or incapacity of the principal, or lapse of time", or "This power of attorney shall become effective upon the disability or incapacity of the principal", or similar words showing the intent of the principal that the authority conferred shall be exercisable notwithstanding the principal's subsequent disability or incapacity, and, unless it states a time of termination, notwithstanding the lapse of time since the execution of the instrument. </section><section prefix="2">All acts done by an attorney in fact under a durable power of attorney during any period of disability or incapacity of the principal have the same effect and inure to the benefit of and bind the principal and the principal's successors in interest as if the principal were competent and not disabled. Unless the instrument states a time of termination, the power is exercisable notwithstanding the lapse of time since the execution of the instrument. </section><section prefix="3">The death of a principal who has executed a written power of attorney, durable or otherwise, does not revoke or terminate the agency as to the attorney in fact or other person, who, without actual knowledge of the death of the principal, acts in good faith under the power. Any action so taken, unless otherwise invalid or unenforceable, binds successors in interest of the principal. </section><section prefix="4">The disability or incapacity of the principal who has previously executed a written power of attorney that is not a durable power does not revoke or terminate the agency as to the attorney in fact or other person, who, without actual knowledge of the disability or incapacity of the principal, acts in good faith under the power. Any action so taken, unless otherwise invalid or unenforceable, binds the principal and the principal's successors in interest. </section><section prefix="5">If the power of attorney is to become effective upon the disability or incapacity of the principal, the principal may specify the conditions under which the power is to become effective and may designate the person, persons, or institution responsible for making the determination of disability or incapacity. If the principal fails to so specify, the power shall become effective upon a written determination by two (2) physicians that the principal is unable, by reason of physical or mental disability, to prudently manage or care for the principal's person or property, which written determination shall be conclusive proof of the attorney in fact's power to act pursuant to the power of attorney. The two (2) physicians making the determination shall be licensed to practice medicine. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, a durable power of attorney may authorize an attorney in fact to make a gift of the principal's real or personal property to the attorney in fact or to others if the intent of the principal to do so is unambiguously stated on the face of the instrument. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 421, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35836</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>