<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.040</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for licensure as a professional engineer -- Education, experience. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall qualify for licensure as a professional engineer by meeting the requirements set forth in paragraph (a) or (b) of this subsection. <section prefix="a">A person shall qualify if he or she has: <section prefix="1">Graduated from an engineering program of four (4) years or more accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology or any engineering program deemed equivalent by the board; </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) or more additional years of progressive experience in engineering or teaching of a grade and character which indicates to the board that the applicant is competent to practice engineering; and </section><section prefix="3">A passing score on: <section prefix="a">The Principles and Practice of Engineering Examination; and </section><section prefix="b">The Fundamentals of Engineering Examination. The board may allow students enrolled in the final year of an undergraduate engineering program to take this examination. Upon passing the examination, the applicant shall be designated an engineer in training. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">If an instructor in an engineering program accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology or an engineering program deemed equivalent by the board is not eligible for the exemption under subsection (2) of this section, the instructor shall have four (4) years from the date of hire to qualify for licensure by showing that he or she has: <section prefix="1">Graduated from an engineering program of four (4) years or more accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology, or an engineering program deemed equivalent by the board; </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) or more additional years of progressive experience in engineering or teaching of a grade and character which indicates to the board that the applicant is competent to practice engineering; </section><section prefix="3">Passed the Principles and Practice of Engineering Examination; and </section><section prefix="4">Either passed the Fundamentals of Engineering Examination or graduated from a board-approved doctoral engineering degree program. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of teaching engineering design courses only, an instructor who, on January 1, 1999, holds a tenured or tenure-track position in an engineering program defined in KRS 322.010(4)(a)3. shall be exempt from the licensure requirements of KRS 322.020 for the period that instructor is continuously employed by the institution offering that program. However, an instructor may apply and shall qualify for licensure as a professional engineer during this exempt period if he or she: <section prefix="a">Has graduated from an engineering program of four (4) years or more accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology or an engineering program deemed equivalent by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Has graduated from a board-approved doctoral engineering degree program, with an additional three (3) years or more of progressive experience in engineering or teaching of a grade and character which indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice engineering; and </section><section prefix="c">Has passed the Principles and Practice of Engineering Examination. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person having the necessary qualifications prescribed in subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall be eligible to apply for licensure, even if the applicant is not practicing the profession at the time of application. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish requirements for consideration of experience gained prior to graduation from an engineering program as described in subsection (1)(a)1. of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-12. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31421</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>