<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.4081Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 367.4081 to 367.4083.   </catch_line><order_by>4081Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 367.4081 to 367.4083: <section prefix="1">"Healthcare provider" means an individual licensed by any of the following: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, pursuant to KRS Chapter 311; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Chiropractic Examiners, pursuant to KRS Chapter 312; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Board of Nursing, pursuant to KRS Chapter 314; </section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky Board of Physical Therapy, pursuant to KRS Chapter 327; </section><section prefix="e">The Kentucky Board of Occupational Therapy, pursuant to KRS Chapter 319A; or </section><section prefix="f">The Kentucky Board for Massage Therapy, pursuant to KRS 309.350 to 309.364; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Intermediary" means an individual, including but not limited to a telemarketer, agent, employee, or contractor, who solicits a person, on behalf of a healthcare provider, for the provision of reparation benefits, as defined by KRS 304.39-020(2); </section><section prefix="3">"Person" means an individual who was involved in an automobile accident; and </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">"Solicit" means the initiation of communication with a person involved in a motor vehicle accident, including but not limited to any face-to-face contact with the person, in writing, electronically, or by any form of telephonic communication, in anticipation of financial gain or remuneration for the communication itself or for prospective charges for healthcare services. </section><section prefix="b">"Solicit" does not mean: <section prefix="1">Advertising directed to the general public; </section><section prefix="2">Telemarketing, which is; <section prefix="a">Taken from a general list of phone numbers; </section><section prefix="b">Not targeted at motor vehicle accident victims; and </section><section prefix="c">Not in violation of the state's prohibition on telephone solicitation under KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999 and 367.990; or </section></section><section prefix="3">Contact between a healthcare provider and an individual with whom the healthcare provider had a preexisting provider-patient relationship. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44402</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>