<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.47-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>47-010</order_by><text>As used in Subtitle 47 of this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Insurer" means any person, entity, organization, or reinsurer, including fraternal benefit societies as defined in Subtitle 29 of this chapter, nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and health service corporation as defined in Subtitle 32 of this chapter, health maintenance organization as defined in Subtitle 38 of this chapter, prepaid dental plan organization as defined in Subtitle 43 of this chapter, or unauthorized insurer as defined in Subtitle 11 of this chapter, subject to regulation by or registration with the Department of Insurance under this chapter, and any "carrier," "self-insurer," or "insurance carrier" as defined by KRS Chapter 342; </section><section prefix="2">"Insurance policy" or "policy" means any individual or group policy, including those defined by KRS Chapter 342, certificate, or contract of an insurer as defined in subsection (1) of this section including reinsurance affecting the rights of any Kentucky resident or bearing a reasonable relation to Kentucky regardless of whether delivered or issued for delivery in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="3">"Insured" means any person who is a named insured or beneficiary under a policy as defined in subsection (2) of this section or a person who is not a named insured or beneficiary under a policy due to the fraudulent action of another, but who in good faith believes himself or herself to be an insured or beneficiary; </section><section prefix="4">"Law enforcement agency" means any federal, state, county, or consolidated police or law enforcement department and any prosecuting official of the federal, state, county, local, or consolidated government; </section><section prefix="5">"Statement" includes, but is not limited to, any notice, statement, proof of loss, bill of lading, invoice, account, estimate of property damages, bill for services, diagnosis, prescription, hospital or physician record or report, X-ray, test result, or other evidence of loss, injury, or expense. A statement may be in any form, including oral, written, and electronic transmissions; </section><section prefix="6">"Division" means the Division of Insurance Fraud Investigation of the Kentucky Department of Insurance, its employees, or authorized representatives; and </section><section prefix="7">"Criminal syndicate" means five (5) or more persons collaborating to promote or engage in any fraudulent insurance act, as set forth in KRS 304.47-020(1), on a continuing basis. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1581, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 86, effective December 12, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30181</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>