<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.780</section_number><catch_line>Management improvement programs. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall establish a program for voluntary management improvement, for involuntary supervision, and for assuming full control of a local school district. <section prefix="a">The voluntary improvement program shall assist local districts with the development of innovative management practices and help them adopt currently accepted practices. </section><section prefix="b">If the Kentucky Board of Education believes that a critical lack of efficiency or effectiveness in the governance or administration of a local school district exists, it shall conduct an administrative hearing in compliance with KRS Chapter 13B. If it is determined that there is a critical lack of efficiency or effectiveness in the governance or administration, the state board shall assume sufficient supervision of the district to ensure that appropriate corrective action occurs. Neither the state board, the chief state school officer, nor his designee shall assume the supervision of the district until an administrative hearing has been conducted under KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="c">If the Kentucky Board of Education believes that the pattern of a lack of efficiency or effectiveness in the governance or administration of a school district warrants action, it shall conduct an administrative hearing in compliance with KRS Chapter 13B. If it is determined that the pattern does warrant action, it shall declare the district a "state assisted district" or a "state managed district" and the state board shall then assume control of the district as set forth in this section and KRS 158.785. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall adopt necessary administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section and KRS 158.785, including an administrative regulation to more specifically establish and implement the standards for designation as a "state assisted district" and a "state managed district." </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education may delegate to the chief state school officer the authority it deems necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and KRS 158.785. However, neither the state board, the chief state school officer, nor his designee shall assume the supervision of the district until an administrative hearing has been conducted under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch 362, sec 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 214, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 16, effective October 18, 1985. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3584</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>