<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-808</section_number><catch_line>Application for certificate of filing - Fee. </catch_line><order_by>17A-808</order_by><text>A proposed self-insured employer-organized association group shall file with the commissioner an application for a certificate of filing accompanied by a nonrefundable filing fee of five dollars ($5). Each application for a certificate of filing shall be submitted to the commissioner upon a form prescribed by the commissioner and shall set forth or be accompanied by: <section prefix="1">The group's name, location of its principal office, date of organization, and identification of its fiscal year. The application shall also include the name and address of each member if known at the time of application. If this information is unknown, a description of the group to be solicited for membership shall be included; </section><section prefix="2">A copy of the articles of association or governance documents; </section><section prefix="3">A copy of agreements with the administrator and with any service company; </section><section prefix="4">A copy of the bylaws of the proposed group; </section><section prefix="5">Certification of the group's financial solvency as set forth in KRS 304.17A-812; </section><section prefix="6">Designation of the initial board of trustees and administrator; </section><section prefix="7">The address where books and records of the group will be maintained at all times; and </section><section prefix="8">A statement describing the self-insured employer-organized association which shall include: <section prefix="a">The health services to be offered; </section><section prefix="b">The financial risks to be assumed; </section><section prefix="c">The initial geographic area to be served; </section><section prefix="d">Pro forma financial projections for the first three (3) years of operation, including the assumptions the projections are based upon; </section><section prefix="e">The sources of working capital and funding; </section><section prefix="f">A description of the persons to be covered by the self-insured employer-organized association; </section><section prefix="g">Any proposed reinsurance arrangements; </section><section prefix="h">Any proposed management, administrative, or cost-sharing arrangements; and </section><section prefix="i">A description of the self-insured employer-organized association's proposed method of marketing. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1259, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29365</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>