<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-410</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Application of subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>4-410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this subtitle, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of financial institutions; and </section><section prefix="b">"Licensee" means a person licensed under this subtitle; and </section><section prefix="c">"Person" means an individual, partnership, association, trust, corporation and any other legal entity. </section></section><section prefix="2">This subtitle shall not apply to any person doing business under and as permitted by any law of this state or of the United States relating to banks, savings banks, trust companies, building and loan associations, cooperative marketing associations, credit unions, loan and investment companies, or licensed pawnbrokers. This subtitle does not apply to the purchase or acquisition, directly or indirectly, of notes, chattel mortgages, installment or conditional sales contracts, embodying liens or evidencing title retention arising from the bona fide sale of goods or services by a seller of such goods or services. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 656, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.410.</former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>