<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.115</section_number><catch_line>Jail staff training program -- Jailer's training expense for allowance -- Eligibility for allowance.   </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of raising the level of competence of jailers and jail personnel, the department shall maintain a jail staff training program to provide training for jailers and jail personnel consistent with the standards promulgated pursuant to KRS 441.055 and shall keep records of jailers and jail personnel who satisfactorily complete basic and annual continuing education. The training program shall include training on communicable diseases. A curriculum advisory committee composed of jailers, their representatives, and recognized professionals in the field of jail administration shall advise the department concerning the training needs of jailers and jail personnel. The jail staff training program shall be directed and staffed by knowledgeable persons who have sufficient experience, training, and education in jail operations. The department shall not charge a fee for training jailers, their deputies, or jailers-elect. </section><section prefix="2">Beginning in August, 1982, each jailer shall receive an expense allowance to help defray the costs of his participation in the jail staff training program. The expense allowance shall be in the amount of three hundred dollars ($300) per month payable out of the State Treasury. Expense allowance payments shall be discontinued if the jailer fails to satisfactorily complete annual continuing training. Expense allowance payments shall be resumed following a discontinuance for failure to satisfactorily complete basic or annual training only upon the jailer's satisfactory completion of the training. </section><section prefix="3">The allowance authorized in subsections (2) and (4) of this section shall be considered as operating expenses of the jailer's office and shall not be considered as part of his compensation. Jailers shall not be required to keep records verifying the expenditures from the allowance provided by the state. </section><section prefix="4">In order to receive the expense allowance for their first year in office, jailers who have been elected to office for the first time, shall, before taking office, successfully complete a training program designed for new jailers and conducted by the personnel of the jail staff training program. This provision shall not apply if the jailer-elect is ill and unable to complete the training before taking office. In such cases, the jailer-elect shall successfully complete a new jailer training program during his first year in office in order to receive the expense allowance. The county or urban-county government in which the jailer-elect serves shall pay out of the jail budget, once he takes office, all necessary and reasonable travel expenses incurred by the jailer-elect in attending the new jailer training program. </section><section prefix="5">All jailers shall successfully complete the training required. If a jailer does not successfully complete the required training within the time specified, he or she shall not receive the expense allowance specified in subsection (2) of this section until he or she successfully completes the required training. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 324, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 652, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 604, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 121, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 34, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 415, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.017. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>