<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.405</section_number><catch_line>Entry in forest lands during drought -- Emergency proclamation -- Notice. </catch_line><order_by>405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful, when the forest lands, brush lands and fields in this state or any part thereof have become so dry or parched as to create an extraordinary fire hazard endangering lives and property, for any person, except the owner, tenant or owner's authorized agent, persons regularly engaged in cutting, processing, or moving forest products, persons engaged in constructing, maintaining, and operating utility or pipeline rights-of-way, or persons on official duty, to enter or travel in any state, county, municipal or private forest lands, brush lands, fields or idle or abandoned lands in the area so affected except on public highways or well defined private roads. </section><section prefix="2">When such an emergency is found to exist by the secretary for energy and environment, the Governor may proclaim such a condition to exist in the Commonwealth or any described part thereof. The provisions of subsection (1) shall be effective only during the time such proclamation is in force and only in the area where such emergency is declared to exist. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State shall cause notice of such proclamation or any amendments or rescission thereof to be published in a newspaper or newspapers of general circulation in the area affected. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 161, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(3). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1900</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>