<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.180</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for membership on local board of education -- Annual in-service training requirements. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "relative" means father, mother, brother, sister, husband, wife, son, daughter, aunt, uncle, son-in-law, and daughter-in-law. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be eligible to membership on a board of education: <section prefix="a">Unless he has attained the age of twenty-four (24) years; and </section><section prefix="b">Unless he has been a citizen of Kentucky for at least three (3) years preceding his election and is a voter of the district for which he is elected; and </section><section prefix="c">Unless he has completed at least the twelfth grade or has been issued a GED certificate or has received a high school diploma through participation in the external diploma program and he is elected after July 13, 1990; and </section><section prefix="d">An affidavit signed under penalty of perjury certifying completion of the twelfth grade or the equivalent as determined by passage of the twelfth grade equivalency examination held under regulations adopted by the Kentucky Board of Education has been filed with the nominating petition required by KRS 118.315; or </section><section prefix="e">Who holds a state office requiring the constitutional oath or is a member of the General Assembly; or </section><section prefix="f">Who holds or discharges the duties of any civil or political office, deputyship, or agency under the city or county of his residence; or </section><section prefix="g">Who, at the time of his election, is directly or indirectly interested in the sale to the board of books, stationery, or any other property, materials, supplies, equipment, or services for which school funds are expended; or </section><section prefix="h">Who has been removed from membership on a board of education for cause; or </section><section prefix="i">Who has a relative as defined in subsection (1) of this section employed by the school district and is elected after July 13, 1990. However, this shall not apply to a board member holding office on July 13, 1990, whose relative was not initially hired by the district during the tenure of the board member. </section></section><section prefix="3">If, after the election of any member of the board, he becomes interested in any contract with or claims against the board, of the kind mentioned in paragraph (g) of subsection (2) of this section, or if he moves his residence from the district for which he was chosen, or if he attempts to influence the hiring of any school employee, except the superintendent of schools or school board attorney, or if he does anything that would render him ineligible for reelection, he shall be subject to removal from office pursuant to KRS 415.050 and 415.060. </section><section prefix="4">A board member shall be eligible for reelection unless he becomes disqualified. </section><section prefix="5">The annual in-service training requirements for all school board members in office as of December 31, 2014, shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Twelve (12) hours for school board members with zero to three (3) years of experience; </section><section prefix="b">Eight (8) hours for school board members with four (4) to seven (7) years of experience; and </section><section prefix="c">Four (4) hours for school board members with eight (8) or more years of experience. </section></section> The Kentucky Board of Education shall identify the criteria for fulfilling this requirement. <section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">For all board members who begin their initial service on or after January 1, 2015, the annual in-service training requirements shall be twelve (12) hours for school board members with zero to eight (8) years of experience and eight (8) hours for school board members with more than eight (8) years of experience. </section><section prefix="b">Training topics for school board members shall include: <section prefix="1">Three (3) hours of finance, one (1) hour of ethics, and one (1) hour of superintendent evaluation annually for members with zero to three (3) years' experience; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) hours of finance, one (1) hour of ethics, and one (1) hour of superintendent evaluation annually for members with four (4) to seven </section></section></section><section prefix="7">years' experience; and </section>3. One (1) hour of finance, one (1) hour of ethics, and one (1) hour of superintendent evaluation biennially for members with eight (8) or more years' experience.  The Kentucky Board of Education shall identify criteria for fulfilling this requirement. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 416, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 71, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 272, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-22. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43527</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>