<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.4903</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 367.4903 to 367.4917.     </catch_line><order_by>4903</order_by><text>As used in KRS 367.4903 to 367.4917: <section prefix="1">"Underground facility" means an underground line or system used for producing, storing, conveying, transmitting, or distributing telecommunications, electricity, gas, petroleum, petroleum products, cable television, hazardous liquids, water, steam, or sewerage, including storm drainage; </section><section prefix="2">"Damage" means weakening of structural or lateral support or penetration of a facility coating, housing, or other protective device. It also means the partial or complete dislocation or severance of underground facilities or rendering any underground facility permanently inaccessible by the placement of a permanent structure having one (1) or more stories; </section><section prefix="3">"Demolition" means any operation by which a structure or mass of material is wrecked, razed, moved, or removed by means of mechanized equipment, or discharge of explosives; </section><section prefix="4">"Excavator" means any entity or individual, other than those exempted by KRS 367.4915, engaged in excavation, demolition, or timber harvesting using mechanized equipment; </section><section prefix="5">"Operator" means any entity or individual owning or operating underground facilities to serve the public; </section><section prefix="6">"Excavation" means any activity that results in the movement, placement, probing, boring, or removal of earth, rock, or other material in or on the ground by the use of any tools or equipment, by the discharge of explosives, or by the harvesting of timber using mechanized equipment. Forms of excavating include but are not limited to auguring, backfilling, digging, ditching, drilling, driving, grading, piling, pulling-in, ripping, scraping, trenching, and tunneling. Driving wooden stakes by use of hand tools to a depth of six (6) inches or less below existing grade shall not constitute excavation; </section><section prefix="7">"Emergency" means there exists substantial likelihood that loss of life or property, the inability to restore interrupted utility service, an imminent danger to health or the environment, or the blockage of public transportation facilities will result before procedures required under KRS 367.4909 to 367.4913 can be completed; </section><section prefix="8">"Protection notification center" means an operator-provided notification center through which an excavator can contact the operator to enable the operator to provide the excavator with the approximate location of underground facilities; </section><section prefix="9">"Kentucky Contact Center" means Kentucky Underground Protection, Inc., organized as a nonprofit corporation and a multimember protection notification center providing a single telephone contact number and designated by the Kentucky Public Service Commission to be the sole recipient of 811 dialed calls through which an excavator may contact all Kentucky Contact Center members and all affected operators may receive information to enable them to provide the excavator with the approximate location of underground facilities; </section><section prefix="10">"Routine road maintenance" means preservation, including road repairs and resurfacing, and the replacement of signs, posts, and guardrails at the exact same location when no additional penetration of existing grade is necessary, but does not include road construction, installation of signs, posts, and guardrails, or any activity that requires penetration of existing grade; </section><section prefix="11">"Approximate location," when referring to an underground facility, means: <section prefix="a">For underground metallic facilities and underground nonmetallic facilities with metallic tracer wire, a distance not to exceed the combined width of the underground facility plus eighteen (18) inches measured from the outer edge of each side of the underground facility; or </section><section prefix="b">For nonmetallic facilities without metallic tracer wire, the underground facility shall be located as accurately as possible from field location records and shall require notification from the operator of the inability to accurately locate the facility; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Working day" means a twenty-four (24) hour period commencing from the time of receipt of the notification by the Kentucky Contact Center except Saturday, Sunday, and holidays established by federal or state statute; </section><section prefix="13">"Nonintrusive excavating" means excavation using hand tools or equipment that uses air or water pressure as the direct means to break up soil for removal by hand tools or vacuum excavation; </section><section prefix="14">"Mechanized equipment" means mechanical power equipment, including trenchers, bulldozers, power shovels, augers, backhoes, scrapers, drills, cable and pipe plows, skidders, and yarders; </section><section prefix="15">"Normal excavation locate request" means a notification made to a protection notification center where a request for locating utility facilities is processed; </section><section prefix="16">"Emergency locate request" means a notification made to a protection notification center by an excavator to alert facility owners or operators of the need to begin immediate excavation in response to an emergency; </section><section prefix="17">"Design information request" means a notification made to a protection notification center by a person providing professional services and making a request in preparation for bidding, preconstruction engineering, or other advance planning efforts. A design information request may not be used for excavation purposes.; and </section><section prefix="18">"Large project" means an area of excavation occurring on or after July 1, 2016, measuring more than two thousand (2,000) feet in length. Multiple excavation notifications in an area may be considered together in determining if the excavations are part of a large project. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 425, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44308</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>