<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.070</section_number><catch_line>Employment of prisoners -- Manufacture of clothing -- Industrial training. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Corrections shall provide employment for all prisoners in the penitentiaries and it shall exhaust every resource at its command to provide employment for all prisoners in its custody. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall acquire necessary equipment and materials and have manufactured all clothing, except that privately furnished, that is needed for the usual and suitable clothing of all state prisoners, and of all inmates in all state institutions, who are required to be clothed by the state. The department shall acquire equipment for the manufacture and production of all other state supplies, that in the reasonable discretion of the department is deemed practicable, and shall have the products manufactured, sold, and distributed as provided in this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall establish industrial training in the penitentiaries and shall classify state prisoners according to the uses for prison labor and ability and talent of the prisoners, utilizing the best available local talent and other talent that may be obtained at an economical and practical cost, and shall select a suitable number of guards with the qualifications, when possible, and thereby avoid duplicate expense. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 50, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3828c-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6875</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>