<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.095</section_number><catch_line>Method for creating or joining regional park authority -- Powers -- Tax levy -- Governing board -- Compliance with KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of acquiring, building, operating, and maintaining parks and green space, two (2) or more counties may form a regional park authority. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The regional park authority may be established by a vote of the fiscal courts of the participating counties or by a vote of the majority of the voters in each participating county voting in an election. The issue shall be placed upon the ballot if supported by a petition signed by a number of people from the participating counties equal to one percent (1%) of the voters in the last regular election. </section><section prefix="b">A county may join an existing regional park authority by a vote of the fiscal court of each participating county and of the fiscal court of the joining county, or by a vote of the majority of voters from each participating county and the joining county voting in an election. The issue shall be placed upon the ballot if supported by a petition signed by a number of people from the participating and joining counties equal to one per cent (1%) of the voters from each participating county and one percent (1%) of the voters from the joining county, voting in the last regular election. </section></section><section prefix="3">A regional park authority is authorized to: <section prefix="a">Levy taxes and issue bonds; </section><section prefix="b">Accept donations, land, and equipment; </section><section prefix="c">Reject unusable or unmanageable land donations; </section><section prefix="d">Hire employees and contract for services; and </section><section prefix="e">Enter into agreements with public and private entities under the provisions of the Interlocal Cooperation Act, KRS 65.210 to 65.300, and contracts authorizing the use of private facilities for public recreation. </section></section><section prefix="4">A regional park authority may levy taxes not exceeding five cents ($0.05) on each one hundred dollars ($100) of all taxable property within the regional park authority's boundaries. The tax shall not be levied until a public referendum has been conducted in accordance with the provisions of KRS 83A.120 and has been adopted by the majority of the voters voting in an election in each county involved. </section><section prefix="5">A regional park authority shall be governed by a board made up of three (3) citizens from each participating county. Board members shall be appointed by the fiscal court from a list of candidates provided by the cities within the county and by the county planning commission if there is one in that county. </section><section prefix="6">A regional park authority shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 45, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 597, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>