<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.035</section_number><catch_line>Applications for licenses -- Requirements -- Confidentiality. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An application for a private investigator license shall be filed with the board on the prescribed form. <section prefix="a">The application shall include the following information regarding the applicant: <section prefix="1">Full name and address; </section><section prefix="2">Date and place of birth; </section><section prefix="3">Social Security number; </section><section prefix="4">All residences during the past five (5) years; </section><section prefix="5">All employment or occupations engaged in during the past five (5) years; </section><section prefix="6">Three (3) sets of classifiable fingerprints; and </section><section prefix="7">Any other information as the board may reasonably require by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="b">The application shall be subscribed and sworn to by the applicant. </section><section prefix="c">If the applicant intends to conduct fire or arson investigations, proof of current national certification from the National Association of Fire Investigators or the International Association of Arson Investigators shall be filed with the board in addition to the information required in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">An application for an investigating company license shall be filed with the board on the prescribed form. <section prefix="a">The application shall include: <section prefix="1">The information required in subsection (1)(a) of this section for: <section prefix="a">The owner, if the company is a sole proprietorship; </section><section prefix="b">Each partner, if the company is a partnership; or </section><section prefix="c">The qualifying agent, if the company is a corporation; </section></section><section prefix="2">The name under which the company intends to do business; </section><section prefix="3">The address of the principal place of business and any branch offices of the company within this state; and </section><section prefix="4">Other information as the board may reasonably require by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="b">If the company is a corporation, the following information is also required: <section prefix="1">The correct legal name of the corporation; </section><section prefix="2">The state and date of incorporation; </section><section prefix="3">The date the corporation qualified to do business in this state; </section><section prefix="4">The address of the corporate headquarters, if located outside of this state; </section><section prefix="5">The names of two (2) principal corporate officers other than the qualifying agent, their business addresses, residence addresses, and the office held by each in the corporation; and </section><section prefix="6">The identity and license number of all private investigators employed by or affiliated with the company. </section></section><section prefix="c">The application shall be subscribed and sworn to by: <section prefix="1">The owner, if the applicant is a sole proprietorship; </section><section prefix="2">Each partner, if the applicant is a partnership; or </section><section prefix="3">The qualifying agent, if the applicant is a corporation. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Each applicant for an individual license or owner, partner, or qualifying agent for a company license shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least twenty-one (21) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Be a citizen of the United States or a resident alien; </section><section prefix="c">Have a high school education or its equivalent; </section><section prefix="d">Not receive a license until the earlier of: <section prefix="1">The expiration of ten (10) years from the applicant's release from a sentence imposed by any state or territory of the United States or the federal government for the commission of a felony, including a sentence of confinement or time served on probation, parole, or other form of conditional release or discharge; or </section><section prefix="2">The date the applicant received a restoration of the applicant's civil rights; </section></section><section prefix="e">Not have been convicted of a misdemeanor involving moral turpitude or for which dishonesty is a necessary element within the previous five (5) years; </section><section prefix="f">Not have been dishonorably discharged from any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="g">Not have had his or her certification as a peace officer revoked in this or another state; </section><section prefix="h">Not have been declared by any court of competent jurisdiction to be incompetent by reason of mental defect or disease unless a court of competent jurisdiction has since declared the applicant to be competent; </section><section prefix="i">Not have been voluntarily or involuntarily committed to a facility or outpatient program for the abuse of a controlled substance or been convicted of a misdemeanor violation of KRS Chapter 218A or similar laws of any other state relating to controlled substances within the three (3) year period immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted; </section><section prefix="j">Not chronically and habitually use alcoholic beverages as evidenced by: <section prefix="1">The applicant having two (2) or more convictions for violating KRS 189A.010 within the three (3) year period immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted; or </section><section prefix="2">The applicant having been committed as an alcoholic pursuant to KRS Chapter 222, or similar laws of any other state, within the three (3) year period immediately preceding the date on which the application is submitted; </section></section><section prefix="k">Not chronically and habitually use alcoholic beverages or drugs to the extent that his or her normal faculties are impaired; </section><section prefix="l">Be of good moral character; </section><section prefix="m">Pass an examination administered by the board in accordance with KRS 329A.025(2)(c); and </section><section prefix="n">Submit proof of coverage which meets the following requirements: <section prefix="1">Is written by an insurance company which is lawfully engaged to provide insurance coverage in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">Provides for a combined single-limit policy in the amount of at least two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000); and </section><section prefix="3">Insures for liability all of the applicant's employees while acting in the course of their employment. </section></section> Private investigators who limit their practice exclusively to working under the supervision and as employees of an attorney who is licensed to practice law in this state are exempted from the requirement of this paragraph. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall maintain the confidentiality of information relating to the licensee or applicant, except that the board may provide this information to local, state, or federal law enforcement agencies. </section><section prefix="5">Upon inquiry by any individual or entity, the board or the board's administrative staff shall provide or confirm the license status of any private investigator or private investigating company. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 186, sec. 3, effective April 21, 2004. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 21, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31763</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>