<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.382</section_number><catch_line>Minimum qualifications for certification. </catch_line><order_by>382</order_by><text>A person certified after December 1, 1998, under KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall, at the time of becoming certified, meet the following minimum qualifications: <section prefix="1">Be a citizen of the United States; </section><section prefix="2">Be at least twenty-one (21) years of age; </section><section prefix="3">Be a high school graduate or have successfully completed a General Education Development (G.E.D.) examination; </section><section prefix="4">Possess a valid license to operate a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="5">Be fingerprinted for a criminal background check; </section><section prefix="6">Not have been convicted of any felony; </section><section prefix="7">Not be prohibited by federal or state law from possessing a firearm; </section><section prefix="8">Have received and read the Kentucky Law Enforcement Officers Code of Ethics as established by the council; </section><section prefix="9">Have not received a dishonorable discharge, bad conduct discharge, or general discharge under other than honorable conditions, if having served in any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="10">Have passed a medical examination as defined by the council by administrative regulation to determine if he can perform peace officer duties as determined by a validated job task analysis. However, if the employing agency has its own validated job task analysis, the person shall pass the medical examination, appropriate to the agency's job task analysis, of the employing agency. All agencies shall certify passing medical examination results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.315 to 15.510; </section><section prefix="11">Have passed a drug screening test administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation. A person shall be deemed to have passed a drug screening test if the results of the test are negative for the use of an illegal controlled substance or prescription drug abuse. Any agency that administers its own test that meets or exceeds this standard shall certify passing test results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.315 to 15.510; </section><section prefix="12">Have undergone a background investigation established or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine suitability for the position of a peace officer. If the employing agency has established its own background investigation that meets or exceeds the standards of the council, as set forth by administrative regulation, the agency shall conduct the background investigation and shall certify background investigation results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.315 to 15.510; </section><section prefix="13">Have been interviewed by the employing agency; </section><section prefix="14">Not have had certification as a peace officer permanently revoked in another state; </section><section prefix="15">Have taken a psychological suitability screening administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine the person's suitability to perform peace officer duties as determined by a council validated job task analysis. However, if the employing agency has its own validated job task analysis, the person shall take that agency's psychological examination, appropriate to the agency's job task analysis. All agencies shall certify psychological examination results to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.315 to 15.510; </section><section prefix="16">Have passed a physical agility test administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine his suitability to perform peace officer duties as determined by a council validated job task analysis. However, if the employing agency has its own validated job task analysis, the person shall take the physical agility examination of the employing agency. All agencies shall certify physical agility examination results to the council, which shall accept them as demonstrating compliance with KRS 15.315 to 15.510; and </section><section prefix="17">Have taken a polygraph examination administered or approved by the council by administrative regulation to determine his suitability to perform peace officer duties. Any agency that administers its own polygraph examination as approved by the council shall certify the results that indicate whether a person is suitable for employment as a peace officer to the council, which shall accept them as complying with KRS 15.315 to 15.510. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 100, effective December 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=934</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>