<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.220</section_number><catch_line>Political discrimination and political activity prohibited -- Dismissal for violation. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Persons holding positions in the classified service shall not be discriminated against in any way because of their political or religious opinions or affiliations or because of their exercise of their right to vote as they please. </section><section prefix="2">No person in the classified service, and neither the personnel director nor any member of the board, nor the chief of police, assistant chief of police, chief of firefighters, or assistant chief of firefighters, shall, directly or indirectly, give, solicit, receive, or remit, any assessment, subscription, or contribution, to or for any political party or any candidate for public office, or in any manner be concerned therewith; nor shall any such person be a member of any campaign committee or governing committee of any political organization nor an officer in either; nor shall any such person, while on duty or using public resources, propose or oppose the placement of a question or advocate for the adoption or defeat of a question to be voted upon by the voters of the government under which the person is employed; nor shall any such person be an election officer or work at the polls on election day, or participate in the purgation or registration of voters, provided, however, nothing herein shall prevent any such person from freely expressing his or her views as a citizen or from casting his or her vote in any election. </section><section prefix="3">Any such person who shall violate this section shall be summarily dismissed from the service by the appointing authority (or if a member of the board, by the mayor), and may not be employed in any service of the city, classified or unclassified, for a period of one (1) year next thereafter; provided however, that should the appointing authority fail or refuse to so dismiss, the board (except when a member thereof is charged with violation of this section) shall conduct a hearing, which the accused person may attend with counsel; if the board find the accused guilty of violation of this section, the board shall dismiss such violator, with the consequent disqualification. Such action of the board is final. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 17, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25435</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>