<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.4-020</section_number><catch_line>Change of registered office or registered agent.   </catch_line><order_by>4-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An entity or foreign entity may change its registered office or registered agent or both by delivering a statement of change to the Secretary of State for filing that sets forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the entity or foreign entity; </section><section prefix="b">The street address of its current registered office; </section><section prefix="c">If the current registered office is to be changed, the street address of the new registered office; </section><section prefix="d">The name of its current registered agent; </section><section prefix="e">If the current registered agent is to be changed, the name of the new registered agent and the new agent's written consent to the appointment; and </section><section prefix="f">That after the change or changes are made, the street addresses of its registered office and the business office of its registered agent will be identical. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a registered agent changes its business address, it shall change the street address of the registered office of any entity or foreign entity for which it is the registered agent by notifying the entity or foreign entity in writing of the change and signing and delivering to the Secretary of State for filing a statement that complies with the requirements of subsection (1) of this section and reciting that the entity or foreign entity has been notified of the change. </section><section prefix="3">The change of address of the registered office or registered agent shall be effective upon filing by the Secretary of State. The appointment of a new registered agent shall be effective upon filing of the statement of change by the Secretary of State. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 29, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36550</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>