<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.383</section_number><catch_line>Refundable tax credit for motion picture or entertainment production expenses authorized by KRS 148.542 to 148.546. </catch_line><order_by>383</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Above-the-line production crew" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="b">"Approved company" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="c">"Below-the-line production crew" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="d">"Cabinet" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="e">"Office" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="f">"Qualifying expenditure" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="g">"Qualifying payroll expenditure" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; </section><section prefix="h">"Secretary" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542; and </section><section prefix="i">"Tax incentive agreement" means the same as defined in KRS 148.542. </section></section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created a refundable tax credit against the tax imposed under KRS 141.020 or 141.040 and 141.0401, with the ordering of credits as provided in KRS 141.0205. </section><section prefix="3">An approved company may receive a refundable tax credit on and after July 1, 2010, if: <section prefix="a">The cabinet has received notification from the office that the approved company has satisfied all requirements of KRS 148.542 to 148.546; and </section><section prefix="b">The approved company has provided a detailed cost report and sufficient documentation to the office, which has been forwarded by the office to the cabinet, that: <section prefix="1">The purchases of qualifying expenditures were made after the execution of the tax incentive agreement; and </section><section prefix="2">The approved company has withheld income tax as required by KRS 141.310 on all qualified payroll expenditures. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The refundable tax credit shall not apply until the taxable year in which the secretary notifies the approved company of the amount of refundable credit that is available. If the notification of approval is provided prior to July 1, 2010, the company shall not claim the credit and the department shall not issue any refunds until on or after July 1, 2010. </section><section prefix="5">Interest shall not be allowed or paid on any refundable credits provided under this section. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to administer this section. </section><section prefix="7">On or before September 1, 2010, and on or before each September 1 thereafter, for the immediately preceding fiscal year, the cabinet shall report to the office the names of the approved companies and the amounts of refundable income tax credit claimed. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 47, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43406</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>