<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.010</section_number><catch_line>General purpose of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 -- Total number of employees limited. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The general purpose of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 is to establish for the state a system of personnel administration based on merit principles and scientific methods governing the recruitment, examination, appointment, promotion, transfer, lay-off, removal, discipline, and welfare of its classified employees and other incidents of state employment. All appointments and promotions to positions in the state classified service shall be made solely on the basis of merit and fitness, to be ascertained by competitive examination, except as hereinafter specified. The General Assembly finds that this chapter is necessary in order to improve the morale and motivation of state employees and to gain the maximum utilization of human resources in order to provide better service to the citizens of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">The total number of permanent full-time personnel employed in agencies of the executive branch shall not exceed thirty-three thousand (33,000). </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of subsection (2) of this section do not apply to teachers, career guidance coaches and counselors, or school administrators employed in state-operated area technology centers, or employees of the General Assembly, the Legislative Research Commission, the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority, the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation, or the Court of Justice. </section><section prefix="4">As used in this section, "career guidance coach" has the same meaning as in KRS 158.810. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 8, effective April 19, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.010, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982 and created in part ch. 381, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created in part 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> April 19, 2012 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628. See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, G, 1, (3) at 641. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.120. </former-codification><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40077</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>