<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">A HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>164A.580Management</section_number><catch_line>of capital construction projects.   </catch_line><order_by>580Management</order_by><text>Subject to the provisions of KRS 45.750 through 45.800, 45A.180, 45A.183, and 56.870 to 56.874, the governing board of each institution may provide for the management and administration of capital construction projects authorized for such institution including, but not limited to: <section prefix="1">The procurement of necessary consulting services; </section><section prefix="2">The supervision and control of the making of all contracts for building projects, renovation projects, repair projects, and supervision of same; </section><section prefix="3">The prescription of the amount and form of evidences of indebtedness submitted in connection with bids and contracts when not otherwise provided by law; </section><section prefix="4">The preparation of plans and specifications for any construction, alteration, or enlargement of buildings, structures, and other improvements; </section><section prefix="5">The advertisement of bids and the awarding of contracts in connection with such projects; </section><section prefix="6">The supervision and inspection of all related work; </section><section prefix="7">The approval of changes in plans or specifications; and </section><section prefix="8">The acceptance of such improvements when completed according to such plans and specifications. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44589</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>