<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-627</section_number><catch_line>Certification as independent review entity -- Requirements and restrictions. </catch_line><order_by>17A-627</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To be certified as an independent review entity under this chapter, an organization shall submit to the department an application on a form required by the department. The application shall include the following: <section prefix="a">The name of each stockholder or owner of more than five percent (5%) of any stock or options for an applicant; </section><section prefix="b">The name of any holder of bonds or notes of the applicant that exceeds one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); </section><section prefix="c">The name and type of business of each corporation or other organization that the applicant controls or with which it is affiliated and the nature and extent of the affiliation or control; </section><section prefix="d">The name and a biographical sketch of each director, officer, and executive of the applicant and any entity listed under paragraph (c) of this subsection and a description of any relationship the named individual has with an insurer as defined in KRS 304.17A-600 or a provider of health care services; </section><section prefix="e">The percentage of the applicant's revenues that are anticipated to be derived from independent reviews; </section><section prefix="f">A description of the minimum qualifications employed by the independent review entity to select health care professionals to perform external review, their areas of expertise, and the medical credentials of the health care professionals currently available to perform external reviews; and </section><section prefix="g">The procedures to be used by the independent review entity in making review determinations. </section></section><section prefix="2">If at any time there is a material change in the information included in the application, provided for in subsection (1) of this section, the independent review entity shall submit updated information to the department. </section><section prefix="3">An independent review entity shall not be a subsidiary of, or in any way affiliated with, or owned, or controlled by an insurer or a trade or professional association of payors. </section><section prefix="4">An independent review entity shall not be a subsidiary of, or in any way affiliated with, or owned, or controlled by a trade or professional association of providers. </section><section prefix="5">Health care professionals who are acting as reviewers for the independent review entity shall hold in good standing a nonrestricted license in a state of the United States. </section><section prefix="6">Health care professionals who are acting as reviewers for the independent review entity shall hold a current certification by a recognized American medical specialty board or other recognized health care professional boards in the area appropriate to the subject of the review, be a specialist in the treatment of the covered person's medical condition under review, and have actual clinical experience in that medical condition. </section><section prefix="7">The independent review entity shall have a quality assurance mechanism to ensure the timeliness and quality of the review, the qualifications and independence of the physician reviewer, and the confidentiality of medical records and review material. </section><section prefix="8">Neither the independent review entity nor any reviewers of the entity, shall have any material, professional, familial, or financial conflict of interest with any of the following: <section prefix="a">The insurer involved in the review; </section><section prefix="b">Any officer, director, or management employee of the insurer; </section><section prefix="c">The provider proposing the service or treatment or any associated independent practice association; </section><section prefix="d">The institution at which the service or treatment would be provided; </section><section prefix="e">The development or manufacture of the principal drug, device, procedure, or other therapy proposed for the covered person whose treatment is under review; or </section><section prefix="f">The covered person. </section></section><section prefix="9">As used in this section, "conflict of interest" shall not be interpreted to include: <section prefix="a">A contract under which an academic medical center or other similar medical center provides health care services to covered persons, except for academic medical centers that may provide the service under review; </section><section prefix="b">Provider affiliations which are limited to staff privileges; or </section><section prefix="c">A specialist reviewer's relationship with an insurer as a contracting health care provider, except for a specialist reviewer proposing to provide the service under review. </section></section><section prefix="10">On an annual basis, the independent review entity shall report to the department the following information: <section prefix="a">The number of independent review decisions in favor of covered persons; </section><section prefix="b">The number of independent review decisions in favor of insurers; </section><section prefix="c">The average turnaround time for an independent review decision; </section><section prefix="d">The number of cases in which the independent review entity did not reach a decision in the time specified in statute or administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="e">The reasons for any delay. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1243, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 15, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>