<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.220</section_number><catch_line>Duties and functions of arts council. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text>The duties and functions of the arts council shall be to: <section prefix="1">Stimulate and encourage throughout the state the study and presentation of the arts, and foster public interest and participation therein; </section><section prefix="2">Encourage public interest in the cultural heritage of our state and expand the state's cultural resources; </section><section prefix="3">Encourage and assist freedom of artistic expression essential for the well-being of the arts; </section><section prefix="4">Serve as the sole agency in the Commonwealth for administration of a state arts plan developed in coordination with the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; </section><section prefix="5">Establish standards and procedures and advisory committees as necessary to advise the Governor on the selection of the Kentucky poet laureate or writer laureate; </section><section prefix="6">Advise the Governor on matters pertaining to the arts; </section><section prefix="7">Adopt and promulgate regulations for the performance of its duties and functions provided in KRS 153.210 to 153.235; </section><section prefix="8">Receive federal grants, and other money and property of any nature whatsoever which may be given, donated, conveyed, bequeathed, devised, or otherwise transferred, without condition or restriction, except that provided by law, other than that it be used for some purpose of the council as permitted by KRS 153.210 to 153.235; </section><section prefix="9">Contract from time to time, as appropriate, with experts and consultants who may </section>be utilized as deemed necessary, and make other necessary purchases and expenditures, all in accordance with the state plan approved by the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet and with the state purchasing provisions of KRS Chapters 45 and 45A; <section prefix="10">Hold public and private hearings for the purpose of furthering the objectives of the council's programs; and </section><section prefix="11">Make and sign any agreements, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapters 45 and 45A, and do and perform any acts that may be necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 153.210 to 153.235. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 35, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 60, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2(9). </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>