<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="72" order_by="72">CORONERS, INQUESTS, AND MEDICAL EXAMINATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>72.410</section_number><catch_line>Investigation of deaths defined as a coroner's case. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The coroner of each county shall investigate the cause and manner of all deaths that are defined by KRS 72.405 as a coroner's case. </section><section prefix="2">The coroner may, in his sound discretion, when investigating a coroner's case, request the assistance of the district medical examiner and the Office of the Kentucky State Medical Examiner, order an autopsy, and hold an inquest. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Upon notification of the death of a child under the age of eighteen (18) years which meets the criteria for a coroner's case as defined in KRS 72.405 and 72.025, the coroner shall as soon as practicable contact the local office of the Department for Community Based Services, law enforcement agencies with local jurisdiction, and the local health department to determine the existence of relevant information concerning the case. </section><section prefix="b">Any agency of the state or any other agency, institution, or facility providing services to the child or the child's family, shall provide to the coroner upon his or her request the cooperation, assistance, and information to enable the coroner to comply with the provisions of this chapter. This section shall not be deemed to abrogate the attorney-client nor the clergy-penitent privilege or the confidentiality of records provided by KRS 311.377(2). If other privileged or confidential records are disclosed to the coroner pursuant to this section, the records shall remain confidential or privileged and shall not be disclosed except as authorized by this section, to the state or local child fatality response team, or as otherwise required by law. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 152, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>