<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.801</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on sale and use of paint containing lead -- Labeling. </catch_line><order_by>801</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Paint manufactured after July 1, 1972, containing more than one-half of one percent (.5%) lead by weight of the nonvolatile content shall not be sold, or used on any toys, children's furniture, interior surface of any dwelling, or any other surface easily accessible to children under the age of seven (7) years. Such paints shall not be manufactured, sold, or used for any other purpose which would ultimately result in exposure to children under the age of seven (7) years unless proper application and documentation is made to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the cabinet determines that no health hazard or danger to children exists from the intended use. </section><section prefix="2">All paints manufactured in this state after July 1, 1972, which will be used in this state will be clearly labeled as to use and hazard when containing more than one-half of one percent (.5%) lead by weight of the total nonvolatile content. </section><section prefix="3">The above provisions of subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall apply to all paints containing more than six one-hundredths of one percent (.06%) lead by weight of the total nonvolatile content after January 1, 1974. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 519, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 463, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974, Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (11). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 356, paras. (1), (2) and (4). </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9429</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>