<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.300</section_number><catch_line>Duty of clerk concerning instruments lodged for record -- Reproduction of clerk's signature on photographic copy. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every county clerk shall record all deeds, mortgages and powers of attorney that are lodged for record, properly certified, or that are acknowledged or proved before him as required by law. He shall also record the certificates endorsed on such instrument, and shall certify the time when the instrument was lodged in his office for record. If acknowledged or proved before him, he shall also certify the time of acknowledgment or proof, and by whom proved, and that the instrument and the certificate thereon have been duly recorded in his office.  </section><section prefix="2">Whenever, either heretofore or hereafter, any recordable instrument of writing bearing the certificate of the clerk showing its recording shall have been copied of record by any photographic, photocopying, or other mechanical process for reproducing on the record the instrument and certificate, the clerk's signature, by either the clerk or his deputy, so reproduced with such certificate shall have the same effect as if subscribed by the clerk on the record. </section></text><history>Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 511. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1952</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35614</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>