<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.370</section_number><catch_line>Superintendent as executive agent of board -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>The superintendent shall be the executive agent of the board that appoints him and shall meet with the board, except when his own tenure, salary, or the administration of his office is under consideration. As executive officer of the board, the superintendent shall see that the laws relating to the schools, the bylaws, rules, and regulations of the Kentucky Board of Education, and the regulations and policies of the district board of education are carried into effect. He may administer the oath required by the board of education to any teacher or other person. He shall be the professional adviser of the board in all matters. He shall prepare, under the direction of the board, all rules, regulations, bylaws, and statements of policy for approval and adoption by the board. He shall have general supervision, subject to the control of the board of education, of the general conduct of the schools, the course of instruction, the discipline of pupils, and the management of business affairs. He shall be responsible for the hiring and dismissal of all personnel in the district. </text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 89, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-34. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3723</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>