<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">C RESTRUCTURE OF LOCAL GOVERNMENT IN COUNTY CONTAINING CITY OF FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>67C.147</section_number><catch_line>Taxes and services in area of former city of the first class -- Imposition of different tax rates -- Urban service tax district -- Modification of boundaries. </catch_line><order_by>147</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to maintain the tax structure, tax rates, or level of services in the area of the consolidated local government formerly comprising the city of the first class, the legislative council of a consolidated local government may provide in the manner described in this chapter for taxes and services within the area comprising the former city of the first class which are different from the taxes and services which are applicable in the remainder of the county. These differences may include differences in tax rates upon the class of property which includes the surface of the land, differences in ad valorem tax rates upon personal property, and differences in tax rates upon insurance premiums. </section><section prefix="2">Any difference in the ad valorem tax rate on the class of property which includes the surface of the land in the portion of the county formerly comprising the city of the first class and in the portion of the county other than that formerly comprising the city of the first class may be imposed directly by the consolidated local government council. Any change in these ad valorem tax rates shall comply with KRS 68.245, 132.010, 132.017, and 132.027 and shall be used for services as provided by KRS 82.085. </section><section prefix="3">If the consolidated local government council determines to provide for tax rates applicable to health insurance premiums and personal property which are different in the area formerly comprising the city of the first class than the rates applicable in the remainder of the county, it shall do so in the following manner. The consolidated local government council shall by ordinance create a tax district to be known as the "urban service tax district" bounded by the former boundaries of the former city of the first class. The ordinance shall designate the number of members of the board of this taxing district and the manner in which they shall be appointed. The ordinance shall provide that the board of the taxing district shall receive the income derived from the differential in tax rate applicable in the area formerly comprising the city of the first class with respect to personal property, health insurance premiums, or both, and shall contract with the consolidated local government to pay all sums collected to the consolidated local government, in return for the provision of services performed by the consolidated local government within the area formerly comprising the city of the first class which services are in addition to services performed by the consolidated local government in the remainder of the county. </section><section prefix="4">After the initial formation of an urban service taxing district in a consolidated local government, the boundaries of the district may be modified in the following manner. The proposal to alter the boundaries of the urban service taxing district within a consolidated local government may be initiated by: <section prefix="a">A resolution enacted by the consolidated local government describing the boundaries of the area to be added to or deleted from the taxing district and duly passed and signed by the mayor not less than one hundred twenty (120) days before the next regularly scheduled election day within the county; or </section><section prefix="b">A petition signed by a number of qualified voters living within precincts within the area to be added to or deleted from the taxing district equal to ten percent (10%) of the votes cast within each precinct in the last general election for President of the United States and delivered to the clerk of the legislative council more than one hundred twenty (120) days next preceding the next regularly scheduled election day within the county. </section></section> The boundaries so described in either case shall not cross precinct lines. The question of whether the area bounded as described should be added to or deleted from, as the case may be, the urban services taxing district shall then be placed upon the ballot in the precincts in the area to be added or deleted at the next regular election and the question stated on the ballot shall be so phrased that a "Yes" vote shall be cast in favor of making the proposed change and a "No" vote shall be cast to oppose the proposed change. If a majority of those voting in those precincts support the change, then the change in the boundaries of the urban service district shall be implemented. </text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>