<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.512</section_number><catch_line>Office of the Reclamation Guaranty Fund -- Duties of executive director. </catch_line><order_by>512</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall establish an Office of the Reclamation Guaranty Fund and appoint an executive director to manage its affairs. The executive director shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor and have all the authority to hire staff, contract for necessary services, and implement the collection of fees and assessments set forth by the commission. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall be responsible for: <section prefix="a">Collecting and depositing into the fund all fees submitted by permittees; </section><section prefix="b">Assessing permit eligibility of permittees for late payment or nonpayment of fees, in accordance with KRS 350.515 and 350.518; </section><section prefix="c">Compiling information about permittees for use by the commission in assigning or revising classifications and fees; </section><section prefix="d">Paying moneys out of the fund as authorized by the commission; </section><section prefix="e">At each meeting of the commission, reporting to the same, the status of the fund and activities of the fund's executive director; and </section><section prefix="f">Performing other administrative functions as are necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 350.500 to 350.521. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 5, effective March 22, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> March 22, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>