<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-460</section_number><catch_line>License -- Contents -- Required display -- Change in place of business. </catch_line><order_by>4-460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every license shall state the address of the office at which the business is to be conducted, the name of the licensee, and if the licensee is a partnership or association, and the names of the members thereof. </section><section prefix="2">The license shall be kept displayed in the office of the licensee and shall not be transferable or assignable. Not more than one (1) place of business shall be maintained under the same license but the commissioner may issue more than one (1) license to the same licensee upon compliance with all the provisions of this subtitle for each license; provided, however, nothing herein shall be deemed to require a license for any place of business devoted to accounting, recordkeeping or administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever a licensee desires to change his or her place of business to another location within the same county the licensee shall give written notice to the commissioner, who, if he or she finds that the interests of the community will be served thereby, shall indorse on the license a transfer to the new place of business, with the date of transfer, which indorsement shall be authority for the operation of the business at the new location. No change in the place of business of a licensee to a location outside of the original county shall be permitted under the same license. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 6, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.460. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>