<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14">DEPARTMENT OF STATE </unit></structure><section_number>14.304</section_number><catch_line>Permit crime victims to use for voting purposes an address providedby the Secretary of State rather than person's actual physical address --Request to participate in program to include sworn statement ofendangerment -- Two year certification period for program participants --Administrative regulation to govern renewal of certification -- Penalty forproviding false information -- Addresses exempt from disclosure underOpen Records Law.  </catch_line><order_by>304</order_by><text>(1)Upon the creation of the crime victim address protection program, an applicant,a parent or guardian acting on behalf of a minor, a guardian acting on behalf ofa person who is declared incompetent, or a designee of an applicant or aparent or guardian of a minor or a guardian of a person declared incompetentwho cannot for any reason apply themselves, may apply to the Secretary ofState to have an address designated by the Secretary of State serve for votingpurposes as the address of the applicant, the minor, or the incompetentperson. The Secretary of State shall approve an application if it is filed in themanner and on the form prescribed by the Secretary of State by administrativeregulation and if it contains:(a)A sworn statement by the applicant that:1.The applicant or the minor or the incompetent person on whosebehalf the application is made is a victim of a specified offense in anongoing criminal case or in a criminal case that resulted in aconviction by a judge or jury or by a defendant's guilty plea; or2.The applicant or the minor or the incompetent person on whosebehalf the application is made has been granted an order ofprotection as defined in KRS 403.720 and 456.010 by a court ofcompetent jurisdiction within the Commonwealth of Kentucky andthe order is in effect at the time of application;(b)A sworn statement by the applicant that disclosure of the address of theapplicant would endanger the safety of the applicant or the safety of thechildren of the applicant, or the minor or incompetent person on whosebehalf the application is made.(c)The mailing address and the phone number or numbers where theapplicant can be contacted by the Secretary of State;(d)The new address or addresses that the applicant requests not bedisclosed for the reason that disclosure will increase the risk of a specifiedoffense; and(e)The signature of the applicant and of a representative of any officedesignated under KRS 14.310 as a referring agency who assisted in thepreparation of the application, and the date on which the applicant signedthe application.(2)Applications shall be filed with the Office of the Secretary of State.(3)Upon the filing of a properly completed application, the Secretary of State shallcertify the applicant as a program participant if the applicant is not required toregister as a sex offender or is not otherwise prohibited from participating in theprogram.(4)Applicants shall be certified for two (2) years following the date of filing unlessthe certification is withdrawn or invalidated before that date. The Secretary ofState shall promulgate an administrative regulation to establish a renewalprocedure.(5)A person who falsely attests in an application that disclosure of the address ofthe applicant would endanger the safety of the applicant or the safety of thechildren of the applicant, or the minor or incompetent person on whose behalfthe application is made, or who knowingly provides false or incorrectinformation upon making an application may be found guilty of a violation ofKRS 523.030.(6)The addresses of individuals applying for entrance into the crime victimaddress confidentiality program and the addresses of those certified asprogram participants shall be exempt from disclosure under the Kentucky OpenRecords Act, KRS 61.870 to KRS 61.884.(7)A program participant shall notify the Office of the Secretary of State of achange of address within seven (7) days of the change of address.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 37, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>