<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="504" order_by="504">RESPONSIBILITY </unit></structure><section_number>504.030</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of person found not guilty by reason of insanity. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a defendant is found not guilty by reason of insanity, the court shall conduct an involuntary hospitalization proceeding under KRS Chapter 202A or 202B.  </section><section prefix="2">To facilitate the procedure established in subsection (1) of this section, the court may order the detention of the defendant for a period of ten (10) days to allow for proceedings to be initiated against the defendant for examination and possible detention pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 202A or 202B.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 31. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 40, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><lrc-note> This section was amended by 1982 Acts Chapter 113, Section 11 and 1982 Acts Chapter 445, Section 42, which conflict and cannot be compiled together. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the amendment in Chapter 445, Section 42, prevails as the later enactment. (1982). This section was amended in 1982 Acts Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>