<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Deadly physical force" means force which is used with the purpose of causing death or serious physical injury or which the defendant knows to create a substantial risk of causing death or serious physical injury. </section><section prefix="2">"Dwelling" means a building or conveyance of any kind, including any attached porch, whether the building or conveyance is temporary or permanent, mobile or immobile, which has a roof over it, including a tent, and is designed to be occupied by people lodging therein at night. </section><section prefix="3">"Imminent" means impending danger, and, in the context of domestic violence and abuse as defined by KRS 403.720, belief that danger is imminent can be inferred from a past pattern of repeated serious abuse. </section><section prefix="4">"Physical force" means force used upon or directed toward the body of another person and includes confinement. </section><section prefix="5">"Residence" means a dwelling in which a person resides either temporarily or permanently or is visiting as an invited guest. </section><section prefix="6">"Vehicle" means a conveyance of any kind, whether or not motorized, which is designed to transport people or property. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 26, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19665</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>