<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.162</section_number><catch_line>Special license plates for members or supporters of certain groupsand organizations -- Initial and renewal fees -- Combination of speciallicense plate with personalized license plate -- Special license plates formotorcycles.  (Effective January 1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>162</order_by><text>(1)As used in this section and in KRS 186.043, 186.164, 186.166, 186.1722, and186.174:(a)"Special license plate" means a unique license plate issued under thischapter to a group or organization that readily identifies the operator ofthe motor vehicle or motorcycle bearing the plate as a member of a groupor organization, or a supporter of the work, goals, or mission of a group ororganization. The term shall not include regular license plates issuedunder KRS 186.240;(b)"Street rod" means a modernized private passenger motor vehiclemanufactured prior to the year 1949, or designed or manufactured toresemble a vehicle manufactured prior to 1949;(c)"SF" means the portion of an initial or renewal fee to obtain a speciallicense plate that is dedicated for use by the Transportation Cabinet;(d)"CF" means the portion of an initial or renewal fee to obtain a speciallicense plate that is dedicated for use by a county clerk; and(e)"EF" means the portion of an initial or renewal fee to obtain a speciallicense plate that is mandated by this chapter to be dedicated for use by aparticular group or organization.(2)The initial purchase fee and renewal fee for a special license plate createdunder this chapter shall be as established in this subsection and includes thename of group or organization and the total initial and renewal fee required forthe plate. The amount in parentheses indicates how the total fee is required tobe divided:(a)Disabled veterans who receive assistance to purchase a vehicle from theUnited States Department of Veterans' Affairs, veterans declared by theUnited States Department of Veterans' Affairs to be one hundred percent(100%) service-connected disabled, and recipients of the CongressionalMedal of Honor:1.Initial Fee:$0($0 SF/$0 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$0($0 SF/$0 CF/$0 EF).(b)Former prisoners of war and survivors of Pearl Harbor:1.Initial Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).2.Renewal Fee:$3($0 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(c)Members of the Kentucky National Guard and recipients of the PurpleHeart:1.Initial Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).2.Renewal Fee:$8($0 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(d)Members of the Civil Air Patrol; active, retired, veteran, reserve, orauxiliary members of the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, MarineCorps, or Coast Guard; Merchant Marines who served betweenDecember 7, 1941, and August 15, 1945; recipients of the Silver StarMedal, or the Bronze Star Medal awarded for valor; persons who wish toreceive Gold Star Mothers, Gold Star Fathers, or Gold Star Spouseslicense plates beyond the two (2) exempted from fees under KRS186.041(6); individuals eligible for a special military service academylicense plate under KRS 186.041(8); and disabled veterans who havebeen declared to be between fifty percent (50%) and ninety-nine percent(99%) service-connected disabled by the United States Department ofVeterans' Affairs:1.Initial Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(e)Recipients of the Distinguished Service Cross, Navy Cross, or Air ForceCross:1.Initial Fee:$3($0 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$3($0 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(f)Disabled license plates:1.Initial Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(g)Historic vehicles:1.Initial Fee for two plates:$53($50 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee: Do not renew annually.(h)Members of Congress:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(i)Firefighters:1.Initial Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(j)Emergency management:1.Initial Fee:$28($25 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(k)Fraternal Order of Police:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentuckyFOP Death Benefit Fund).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentuckyFOP Death Benefit Fund).(l)Law Enforcement Memorial:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentucky Law Enforcement Memorial Foundation, Inc.).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentucky Law Enforcement Memorial Foundation, Inc.).(m)Personalized plates:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(n)Street rods:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(o)Nature plates:1.Initial Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to KentuckyHeritage Land Conservation Fund established under KRS 146.570).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to KentuckyHeritage Land Conservation Fund established under KRS 146.570).(p)Amateur radio:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(q)Kentucky General Assembly:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(r)Kentucky Court of Justice:1.Initial Fee:$40($37 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$8($0 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(s)Masons:1.Initial Fee:$28($25 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$15($12 SF/$3 CF/$0 EF).(t)Collegiate plates:1.Initial Fee:$50($37 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to the generalscholarship fund of the university whose name will be borne on theplate).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to the generalscholarship fund of the university whose name will be borne on theplate).(u)Independent Colleges:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theAssociation of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities fordistribution to the general scholarship funds of the Association'smembers).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theAssociation of Independent Kentucky Colleges and Universities fordistribution to the general scholarship funds of the Association'smembers).(v)Child Victims:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to the childvictims' trust fund established under KRS 41.400).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the childvictims' trust fund established under KRS 41.400).(w)Kentucky Horse Council:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentucky Horse Council).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the KentuckyHorse Council).(x)Ducks Unlimited:1.Initial Fee:$38($25 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to KentuckyDucks Unlimited).2.Renewal Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to KentuckyDucks Unlimited).(y)Spay neuter:1.Initial Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to the animalcontrol and care fund established under KRS 258.119).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the animalcontrol and care fund established under KRS 258.119).(z)Gold Star Mothers, Gold Star Fathers, or Gold Star Spouses:1.Initial Fee:$0($0 SF/$0 CF/ $0 EF).2.Renewal Fee:$0($0 SF/$0 CF/ $0 EF).3.A person may receive a maximum of two (2) plates under thisparagraph free of charge and may purchase additional plates forfees as established in subsection (2)(d) of this section.(aa)I Support Veterans:1.Initial Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theKentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the KentuckyDepartment of Veterans' Affairs).(ab)Gold Star Siblings:1.Initial Fee:$25($12 SF/$3 CF/$10 EF to theveterans' program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).2.Renewal Fee:$20($12 SF/$3 CF/$5 EF to the veterans'program trust fund established under KRS 40.460).(3)Any special license plate may be combined with a personalized license platefor a twenty-five dollar ($25) state fee in addition to all other fees for theparticular special license plate established in this section and in KRS186.164(3). The twenty-five dollar ($25) fee required under this subsectionshall be divided between the cabinet and the county clerk of the county wherethe applicant is applying for the license plate with the cabinet receiving twentydollars ($20) and the county clerk receiving five dollars ($5).(4)Owners and lessees of motorcycles registered under KRS 186.050(2) may beeligible to receive special license plates issued under this section orestablished under the provisions of KRS 186.164 after the cabinet has receivedthree hundred (300) applications and initial state fees from the sponsoringorganization. Applicants for a special license plate for a motorcycle shall berequired to pay the fee for a special plate as prescribed in this section or inKRS 186.164. The fee paid for the special plate for a motorcycle shall be in lieuof the registration fee required under KRS 186.050(2).</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 91, sec.2, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.  10, sec. 2, effectiveupon contingency. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 15,2010; ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2001; ch. 113, sec. 2, effective July 15,2010; and ch. 129, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch.30, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008; and ch. 164, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. --Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 39, sec.1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effectiveJuly 12, 2006; and ch. 190, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky.Acts ch. 133, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Actsch. 117, Pt. I, A, 19, (7) at 617.</budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). The amendment to thisstatute in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 2, takes effect on July 12, 2012. Theeffective date of that amendment was subject to a contingency, but thecontingency was removed in 2012. Section 5 of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 139, which iseffective July 12, 2012, repeals 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 4, which establishedthe contingency. Section 6 of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 139 states, "KRS 186.162 and186.1722, as created or amended by 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, relating to an ISupport Veterans special license plate, shall be effective on the normal effectivedate for the legislation enacted at the 2012 Regular Session of the GeneralAssembly." The normal effective date for that 2012 legislation is July 12, 2012. (6/20/2005). Under the authority of KRS7.135(1)(h), during codification a manifest clerical or typographical erroroccurring in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1(2)(c)2., has been corrected bychanging "OSF" to "SF" to conform with definitions for that section found inSection 1(1)(c) of that Act.</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44719</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>