<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9117</section_number><catch_line>Display of certification number -- Limitation of activities of persons with dual certifications.   </catch_line><order_by>9117</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person certified and given a certification number by the cabinet as a measurement or mitigation contractor shall: <section prefix="a">Prominently display his or her certification number on all advertising disseminated, whether directly or indirectly, to the general public, except when advertising pertains to novelty items such as small mass-produced items of minimal value; </section><section prefix="b">Prominently display his or her certification number on all vehicles utilized in advertising, using letters and numbers at least three (3) inches in height. The certification number shall be legible and visible at all times the vehicle is being operated; and </section><section prefix="c">When operating under the name of a business entity, satisfy the requirements of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection by displaying the certification number of the measurement or mitigation contractor, as applicable, employed by the business entity. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person certified as both a measurement and mitigation contractor who conducts mitigation on a residential or commercial building shall not conduct measurement on that same building to determine the need for mitigation. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 9, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42263</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>