<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.5-070</section_number><catch_line>Interested transactions.   </catch_line><order_by>5-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each trustee and each person designated pursuant to KRS 386A.1-030(4)(h) owes a duty of loyalty to the statutory trust and any series thereof, including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">To account to the trust or a series thereof and hold as trustee for it any property, profit, or benefit derived in the conduct and winding up of the trust’s or series's business or derived from a use of property, including the appropriation of an opportunity, of the trust or a series thereof; </section><section prefix="b">To refrain from dealing with the trust in the conduct or winding up of the trust’s business as or on behalf of a party having an interest adverse to the trust; and </section><section prefix="c">To refrain from competing with the trust or with any series thereof in the conduct of its business before dissolution. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person subject to subsection (1) of this section who acts through a related party shall be treated as having acted directly. </section><section prefix="3">That a transaction was fair to the statutory trust or a series thereof shall not constitute a defense to the breach of the obligation in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 39, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40381</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>