<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.730</section_number><catch_line>Determination of income benefits for disability -- Survivors' rights -- Termination -- Offsets -- Notification of return to work. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 342.732, income benefits for disability shall be paid to the employee as follows: <section prefix="a">For temporary or permanent total disability, sixty-six and two-thirds percent (66-2/3%) of the employee's average weekly wage but not more than one hundred percent (100%) of the state average weekly wage and not less than twenty percent (20%) of the state average weekly wage as determined in KRS 342.740 during that disability. Nonwork-related impairment and conditions compensable under KRS 342.732 and hearing loss covered in KRS 342.7305 shall not be considered in determining whether the employee is totally disabled for purposes of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">For permanent partial disability, sixty-six and two-thirds percent (66-2/3%) of the employee's average weekly wage but not more than seventy-five percent (75%) of the state average weekly wage as determined by KRS 342.740, multiplied by the permanent impairment rating caused by the injury or occupational disease as determined by the "Guides to the Evaluation of Permanent Impairment," times the factor set forth in the table that follows: </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">If, due to an injury, an employee does not retain the physical capacity to </section><section prefix="2">If an employee returns to work at a weekly wage equal to or greater than </section><section prefix="3">Recognizing that limited education and advancing age impact an </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 342.125, a claim may be </section></section><section prefix="d">For permanent partial disability, if an employee has a permanent disability </section><section prefix="e">For permanent partial disability, impairment for nonwork-related disabilities, </section></section>   AMA Impairment   Factor    0 to 5%     0.65    6 to 10%     0.85    11 to 15%     1.00    16 to 20%     1.00    21 to 25%     1.15    26 to 30%     1.35    31 to 35%     1.50    36% and above    1.70  Any temporary total disability period within the maximum period for permanent, partial disability benefits shall extend the maximum period but shall not make payable a weekly benefit exceeding that determined in subsection (1)(a) of this section. Notwithstanding any section of this chapter to the contrary, there shall be no minimum weekly income benefit for permanent partial disability and medical benefits shall be paid for the duration of the disability. return to the type of work that the employee performed at the time of injury, the benefit for permanent partial disability shall be multiplied by three (3) times the amount otherwise determined under paragraph (b) of this subsection, but this provision shall not be construed so as to extend the duration of payments; or the average weekly wage at the time of injury, the weekly benefit for permanent partial disability shall be determined under paragraph (b) of this subsection for each week during which that employment is sustained. During any period of cessation of that employment, temporary or permanent, for any reason, with or without cause, payment of weekly benefits for permanent partial disability during the period of cessation shall be two (2) times the amount otherwise payable under paragraph (b) of this subsection. This provision shall not be construed so as to extend the duration of payments. employee's post-injury earning capacity, an education and age factor, when applicable, shall be added to the income benefit multiplier set forth in paragraph (c)1. of this subsection. If at the time of injury, the employee had less than eight (8) years of formal education, the multiplier shall be increased by four-tenths (0.4); if the employee had less than twelve (12) years of education or a high school General Educational Development diploma, the multiplier shall be increased by two-tenths (0.2); if the employee was age sixty (60) or older, the multiplier shall be increased by six-tenths (0.6); if the employee was age fifty-five (55) or older, the multiplier shall be increased by four-tenths (0.4); or if the employee was age fifty (50) or older, the multiplier shall be increased by two-tenths (0.2). reopened at any time during the period of permanent partial disability in order to conform the award payments with the requirements of subparagraph 2. of this paragraph. rating of fifty percent (50%) or less as a result of a work-related injury, the compensable permanent partial disability period shall be four hundred twenty-five (425) weeks, and if the permanent disability rating is greater than fifty percent (50%), the compensable permanent partial disability period shall be five hundred twenty (520) weeks from the date the impairment or disability exceeding fifty percent (50%) arises. Benefits payable for permanent partial disability shall not exceed ninety-nine percent (99%) of sixty-six and two-thirds percent (66-2/3%) of the employee's average weekly wage as determined under KRS 342.740 and shall not exceed seventy-five percent (75%) of the state average weekly wage, except for benefits payable pursuant to paragraph (c)1. of this subsection, which shall not exceed one hundred percent (100%) of the state average weekly wage, nor shall benefits for permanent partial disability be payable for a period exceeding five hundred twenty (520) weeks, notwithstanding that multiplication of impairment times the factor set forth in paragraph (b) of this subsection would yield a greater percentage of disability. conditions previously compensated under this chapter, conditions covered by KRS 342.732, and hearing loss covered in KRS 342.7305 shall not be considered in determining the extent of disability or duration of benefits under this chapter. <section prefix="2">The period of any income benefits payable under this section on account of any injury shall be reduced by the period of income benefits paid or payable under this chapter on account of a prior injury if income benefits in both cases are for disability of the same member or function, or different parts of the same member or function, and the income benefits payable on account of the subsequent disability in whole or in part would duplicate the income benefits payable on account of the pre-existing disability. </section><section prefix="3">Subject to the limitations contained in subsection (4) of this section, when an employee, who has sustained disability compensable under this chapter, and who has filed, or could have timely filed, a valid claim in his or her lifetime, dies from causes other than the injury before the expiration of the compensable period specified, portions of the income benefits specified and unpaid at the individual's death, whether or not accrued or due at his or her death, shall be paid, under an award made before or after the death, for the period specified in this section, to and for the benefit of the persons within the classes at the time of death and in the proportions and upon the conditions specified in this section and in the order named: <section prefix="a">To the widow or widower, if there is no child under the age of eighteen (18) or incapable of self-support, benefits at fifty percent (50%) of the rate specified in the award; or </section><section prefix="b">If there are both a widow or widower and such a child or children, to the widow or widower, forty-five percent (45%) of the benefits specified in the award, or forty percent (40%) of those benefits if such a child or children are not living with the widow or widower; and, in addition thereto, fifteen percent (15%) of the benefits specified in the award to each child. Where there are more than two (2) such children, the indemnity benefits payable on account of two (2) children shall be divided among all the children, share and share alike; or </section><section prefix="c">If there is no widow or widower but such a child or children, then to the child or children, fifty percent (50%) of the benefits specified in the award to one (1) child, and fifteen percent (15%) of those benefits to a second child, to be shared equally. If there are more than two (2) such children, the indemnity benefits payable on account of two (2) children shall be divided equally among all the children; or </section><section prefix="d">If there is no survivor in the above classes, then the parent or parents wholly or partly actually dependent for support upon the decedent, or to other wholly or partly actually dependent relatives listed in paragraph (g) of subsection (1) of KRS 342.750, or to both, in proportions that the commissioner provides by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="e">To the widow or widower upon remarriage, up to two (2) years, benefits as specified in the award and proportioned under paragraphs (a) or (b) of this subsection, if the proportioned benefits remain unpaid, to be paid in a lump sum. </section></section><section prefix="4">All income benefits payable pursuant to this chapter shall terminate as of the date upon which the employee qualifies for normal old-age Social Security retirement benefits under the United States Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 301 to 1397f, or two (2) years after the employee's injury or last exposure, whichever last occurs. In like manner all income benefits payable pursuant to this chapter to spouses and dependents shall terminate when such spouses and dependents qualify for benefits under the United States Social Security Act by reason of the fact that the worker upon whose earnings entitlement is based would have qualified for normal old-age Social Security retirement benefits. </section><section prefix="5">All income benefits pursuant to this chapter otherwise payable for temporary total and permanent total disability shall be offset by unemployment insurance benefits paid for unemployment during the period of temporary total or permanent total disability. </section><section prefix="6">All income benefits otherwise payable pursuant to this chapter shall be offset by payments made under an exclusively employer-funded disability or sickness and accident plan which extends income benefits for the same disability covered by this chapter, except where the employer-funded plan contains an internal offset provision for workers' compensation benefits which is inconsistent with this provision. </section><section prefix="7">If an employee receiving a permanent total disability award returns to work, that employee shall notify the employer, payment obligor, insurance carrier, or special fund as applicable. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1841, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 90, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 30, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 30, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 7, sec. 25, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 99, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 55, effective October 26, 1987. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1977. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 9. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 63. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 90, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32544</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>