<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-722</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations on claims payment practices. </catch_line><order_by>17A-722</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No later than ninety (90) days following July 15, 2002, the department shall promulgate administrative regulations requiring all insurers to report information on a calendar quarter basis on prompt payment of claims to providers, as defined in KRS 304.17A-700, that shall be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">The number of clean claims received by the insurer, its agent, or designee during the reporting period; </section><section prefix="b">The percentage of clean claims received by the insurer, its agent, or designee that were: <section prefix="1">Adjudicated within the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="2">Adjudicated within one (1) to thirty (30) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="3">Adjudicated within thirty-one (31) to sixty (60) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="4">Adjudicated within sixty-one (61) to ninety (90) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="5">Adjudicated more than ninety (90) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; and </section><section prefix="6">Not yet adjudicated; </section></section><section prefix="c">The percentage of clean claims received during the reporting quarter that were paid and not denied or contested: <section prefix="1">Within the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="2">Within one (1) to thirty (30) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="3">Within thirty-one (31) to sixty (60) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="4">Within sixty (60) to ninety (90) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; </section><section prefix="5">More than ninety (90) days from the end of the claims payment timeframe; and </section><section prefix="6">Not yet paid; </section></section><section prefix="d">Amount of interest paid; and </section><section prefix="e">For clean claims received during the reporting quarter that were not denied or contested, the percentage of the total dollar amount of those claims that were paid within the claims payment timeframe. </section></section><section prefix="2">Data required in subsection (1) of this section shall be reported for hospitals, physicians, and all other providers, excluding pharmacies. </section><section prefix="3">Insurers shall submit information required in subsection (1) of this section to the department no later than one hundred eighty (180) days following the close of the reporting quarter. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall, as part of the market conduct survey of each insurer, audit the insurer to determine compliance with KRS 304.17A-700 to 304.17A-730 and KRS 304.14-135 and 304.99-123. Findings shall be made available to the public upon request. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner shall annually present to the Interim Joint Committee on Banking and Insurance and to the Governor a report on the payment practices of insurers and compliance with the provisions of KRS 304.17A-700 to 304.17A-730 and KRS 205.593, 304.14-135, and 304.99-123 and the commissioner's enforcement activities, including the number of complaints received and those acted upon by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1250, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29340</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>