<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.240</section_number><catch_line>Pledge of securities required of depositories -- Qualifications for a reduced pledge -- Eligible securities and other obligations.   </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Before any bank shall be named as a state depository to receive public funds, it shall either pledge or provide to the State Treasurer, as collateral, securities or other obligations having an aggregate current face value or current quoted market value at least equal to the deposits or provide to the State Treasurer a surety bond or surety bonds in favor of the State Treasurer in an amount at least equal to the deposits, provided, however, that amounts insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation or the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation need not be so collateralized. The president or cashier of each depository bank shall submit to the Treasurer and the State Investment Commission a statement subscribed and sworn to by him showing: <section prefix="1">The face value or current quoted market value of the securities or other obligations pledged or provided as of the time the securities or other obligations are offered as collateral; and </section><section prefix="2">The value of surety bonds provided as of the time such surety bonds are provided as collateral. </section></section> The valuation of all pledged or provided collateral and the face amount of all surety bonds provided as collateral shall be reported to the State Treasurer and State Investment Commission upon receipt of deposit and within ten (10) days of the close of each quarter after the quarter beginning December 31. Such value with respect to pledged collateral other than surety bonds shall be as of the end of the quarter or the preceding business day and, as to market values, shall be obtained from a reputable bond pricing service. The State Treasurer and Governor may from time to time call for additional collateral to adequately secure the deposits as aggregate face or current market values may require. <section prefix="b">No deposit of state collected demand and time funds shall collectively exceed at any time the depository's sum of capital, reserves, undivided profits and surplus or ten percent (10%) of the total deposits of any particular depository, whichever is less. Deposits will be valued at the end of each business day. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">As an alternative to subsection (1)(a) of this section, a Kentucky depository insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation may either pledge to the State Treasurer, as collateral, securities or other obligations having an aggregate face value or a current quoted market value or provide to the State Treasurer a surety bond or surety bonds in an amount equal to eighty percent (80%) of the value of the state deposit including demand and time accounts, if the depository is determined by the State Investment Commission to have very strong credit with little or no credit risk at any maturity level and the likelihood of short-term unexpected problems of significance is minimal or not of a serious or long-term nature. The value of the state deposit will be determined at the end of the business day of deposit and as of the end of business on the last day of each quarter that funds are so deposited. </section><section prefix="b">Valuation of all pledged or provided collateral and the face amount of surety bonds provided shall be reported to the State Treasurer and the State Investment Commission upon receipt of the state deposit and within ten (10) days of the close of each quarter after the quarter beginning December 31. </section><section prefix="c">Depositories designated as qualified for reduced pledging shall be so recorded in the executive journal. </section><section prefix="d">The State Investment Commission shall determine eligibility for the reduced pledging option based on totally objective and quantifiable measures of financial intermediary performance. The information for such eligibility shall be obtained from publicly available documents. The State Investment Commission shall promulgate the particular criteria of eligibility by regulations issued pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="3">Depositories which do not qualify or do not choose to qualify under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall not receive state deposits in excess of amounts that are insured by an instrumentality of the United States. </section><section prefix="4">Only the following securities and other obligations may be accepted by the State Treasurer as collateral under this section: <section prefix="a">Bonds, notes, letters of credit, or other obligations of or issued or guaranteed by the United States, or those for which the credit of the United States is pledged for the payment of the principal and interest thereof, and any bonds, notes, debentures, letters of credit, or any other obligations issued or guaranteed by any federal governmental agency or instrumentality, presently or in the future established by an Act of Congress, as amended or supplemented from time to time, including, without limitation, the United States government corporations listed in KRS 66.480(1)(c); </section><section prefix="b">Obligations of the Commonwealth of Kentucky including revenue bonds issued by its statutory authorities, commissions, or agencies; </section><section prefix="c">Revenue bonds issued by educational institutions of the Commonwealth of Kentucky as authorized by KRS 162.340 to 162.380; </section><section prefix="d">Obligations of any city of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or any county, for the payment of principal and interest on which the full faith and credit of the issuing body is pledged; </section><section prefix="e">School improvement bonds issued in accordance with the authority granted under KRS 162.080 to 162.100; </section><section prefix="f">School building revenue bonds issued in accordance with the authority granted under KRS 162.120 to 162.300, provided that the issuance of such bonds is approved by the Kentucky Board of Education; and </section><section prefix="g">Surety bonds issued by sureties rated in one (1) of the three (3) highest categories by a nationally recognized rating agency. </section></section><section prefix="5">The State Treasurer shall accept letters of credit issued by federal home loan banks as collateral under this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 24, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 554, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4693. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, รยง 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>