<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.143</section_number><catch_line>Commemorative copy of birth or marriage certificate -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>143</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application and payment of a thirty-five dollar ($35) fee, the state registrar shall issue a commemorative copy of a certificate of birth or a certificate of marriage. Fees collected under this section that exceed the administrative costs of this program shall be deposited in a trust and agency account for the Emergency Medical Services for Children Program as provided under KRS 311A.045. </section><section prefix="2">To assist with offsetting the cost of the initial design and printing of the commemorative certificates of birth and commemorative certificates of marriage, the state registrar shall not be required to issue commemorative certificates of birth or commemorative certificates of marriage until application and payment have been made for a total of two hundred fifty (250) commemorative certificates under subsection (1) of this section. The cabinet shall place each thirty-five dollar fee ($35) received for the commemorative certificates into a trust and agency account and dedicate those funds to offset the cabinet's design and administrative costs. After the issuance of the first two hundred fifty (250) commemorative certificates, the state registrar shall issue each subsequent commemorative certificate in a timely manner upon receipt of each application and payment and shall not permit subsequent requests to accumulate. If the cabinet has not received two hundred fifty (250) applications accompanied by the thirty-five dollar ($35) fee within one (1) year of June 24, 2003, the cabinet shall refund all fees received for the commemorative certificates to the appropriate applicants. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>