<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.040</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful discrimination by employers -- Difference in health plan contribution rates for smokers and nonsmokers and benefits for smoking cessation program participants excepted. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is an unlawful practice for an employer: <section prefix="a">To fail or refuse to hire, or to discharge any individual, or otherwise to discriminate against an individual with respect to compensation, terms, conditions, or privileges of employment, because of the individual's race, color, religion, national origin, sex, age forty (40) and over, because the person is a qualified individual with a disability, or because the individual is a smoker or nonsmoker, as long as the person complies with any workplace policy concerning smoking; </section><section prefix="b">To limit, segregate, or classify employees in any way which would deprive or tend to deprive an individual of employment opportunities or otherwise adversely affect status as an employee, because of the individual's race, color, religion, national origin, sex, or age forty (40) and over, because the person is a qualified individual with a disability, or because the individual is a smoker or nonsmoker, as long as the person complies with any workplace policy concerning smoking; or </section><section prefix="c">To require as a condition of employment that any employee or applicant for employment abstain from smoking or using tobacco products outside the course of employment, as long as the person complies with any workplace policy concerning smoking. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A difference in employee contribution rates for smokers and nonsmokers in relation to an employer-sponsored health plan shall not be deemed to be an unlawful practice in violation of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The offering of incentives or benefits offered by an employer to employees who participate in a smoking cessation program shall not be deemed to be an unlawful practice in violation of this section. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 3. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 3, sec. 302. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (10/19/2004). 2004 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 4, sets forth different employee contribution rates to the state health insurance plan for the period January 1, 2005, through December 31, 2005, for smokers and nonsmokers and provides, "A difference in employee contribution rates for smokers and nonsmokers under this plan shall not be deemed to be an unlawful practice in violation of KRS 344.040." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>