<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-020</section_number><catch_line>Departments within the cabinet -- Offices and divisions within the departments -- Appointments.   </catch_line><order_by>10-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the cabinet a Department for Natural Resources, a Department for Environmental Protection, and a Department for Energy Development and Independence. Each department shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050. The commissioners shall be directly responsible to the secretary and shall perform such functions, powers, and duties as provided by law and as the secretary may prescribe. </section><section prefix="2">There is established within the Department for Natural Resources a Division of Forestry, a Division of Conservation, a Division of Technical and Administrative Support, a Division of Mine Reclamation and Enforcement, a Division of Mine Permits, a Division of Abandoned Mine Lands, a Division of Oil and Gas, a Division of Mine Safety, and an Office of the Reclamation Guaranty Fund. The Kentucky Mining Board is attached to the Department for Natural Resources for administrative purposes. Each division shall be headed by a director, and each office shall be headed by an executive director. Directors and executive directors shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050, except for the director of the Division of Conservation, who shall be appointed in accordance with KRS 146.100. Both directors and executive directors shall be directly responsible to the commissioner and shall perform the functions, powers, and duties as provided by law and as prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="3">There is established within the Department for Environmental Protection a Division of Water, a Division for Air Quality, a Division of Waste Management, a Division of Enforcement, a Division of Compliance Assistance, and a Division of Environmental Program Support. Each division shall be headed by a director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050. Directors shall be directly responsible to the commissioner and shall perform the functions, powers, and duties as provided by law and as prescribed by the secretary. </section><section prefix="4">There is established within the Department for Energy Development and Independence a Division of Energy Efficiency and Conservation, a Division of Renewable Energy, a Division of Biofuels, a Division of Energy Generation, Transmission and Distribution, a Division of Carbon Management, and a Division of Fossil Energy Development. Each division shall be headed by a director. Directors shall be appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 349, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 21, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 399, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 122, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 2, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.012. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44521</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>