<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.137</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary action. </catch_line><order_by>137</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue a license or may deny any application, or suspend, or revoke, impose probationary conditions upon, issue a written reprimand or admonishment, or perform any combination thereof regarding any license held or applied for under the provisions of KRS 309.133 if the person: <section prefix="a">Is found guilty of fraud, deceit, or misrepresentation in procuring or renewing or attempting to procure or renew a license to practice art therapy; </section><section prefix="b">Committed any unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive act or practice; </section><section prefix="c">Has been negligent in the practice of art therapy; </section><section prefix="d">Is adjudicated mentally incompetent; </section><section prefix="e">Is found guilty of a felony or misdemeanor involving sexual misconduct or a crime where dishonesty is a necessary element. Conviction includes all instances in which a plea of no contest is the basis of the conviction; </section><section prefix="f">Is found guilty of unprofessional or unethical conduct in this or any other jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="g">Has been using any controlled substance or alcoholic beverage to an extent or in a manner dangerous to the person, any other person, or the public, or to an extent that the use impairs the ability to perform as a licensed professional art therapist; </section><section prefix="h">Has violated any provision of KRS 309.130 to 309.1399 or administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="i">Failed to comply with an order issued by the board or an assurance of voluntary compliance; or </section><section prefix="j">Willfully or negligently divulges a professional confidence. </section></section><section prefix="2">A certified copy of the record of conviction shall be conclusive evidence of the conviction. </section><section prefix="3">Disciplinary proceedings may be initiated upon the receipt by the board of a sworn complaint by any person, including members of the board. </section><section prefix="4">Two (2) years from the date of revocation, any person whose license has been revoked may petition the board for reinstatement. The board shall investigate the petition and may reinstate the licensee if the board finds that the individual has complied with any terms prescribed by the board and is able to competently engage in the practice of art therapy. </section><section prefix="5">If, after an investigation that includes an opportunity for the licensee to respond, the board determines that a violation took place but was not of a serious nature, it may issue a written admonishment to the licensee. A copy of the admonishment shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to file a response to the admonishment within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have the response placed in the permanent licensure file. The licensee may alternatively, within thirty (30) days of the receipt, file a request for a hearing with the board. Upon receipt of this request, the board shall set aside the written admonishment and set the matter for a hearing under KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="6">The surrender of a license shall not deprive the board of its jurisdiction to proceed with disciplinary actions authorized under KRS 309.130 to 309.1399. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30346</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>