<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.081</section_number><catch_line>License and eligibility requirements for participants in show. </catch_line><order_by>081</order_by><text>A person shall not participate in a show in any of the following enumerated capacities or in any other capacity as set out in administrative regulations promulgated by the authority without holding a license issued by the authority and meeting all eligibility requirements as established by the authority by promulgation of administrative regulations: <section prefix="1">Bout Assistant; </section><section prefix="2">Contestant; </section><section prefix="3">Judge; </section><section prefix="4">Manager; </section><section prefix="5">Physician; </section><section prefix="6">Referee; </section><section prefix="7">Second; </section><section prefix="8">Timekeeper; or </section><section prefix="9">Trainer. </section>Licenses issued under this section shall expire on December 31 of the year in which they are issued. The authority may establish a schedule of compensation to be paid to officials for participating in a professional match by promulgation of administrative regulations. The compensation shall be paid by the person conducting the match, and by no other person. </text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 11, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 2, effective March 30, 1990. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>