<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.320</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of the Commission. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Legislative Research Commission or a subcommittee authorized by it shall study and examine expenditures of state agencies. To facilitate optimum effectiveness and economy in the performance of this function, the Legislative Research Commission or a committee or subcommittee authorized by it, shall employ electronic data processing equipment including computers and other necessary support equipment capable of providing read only access to the desired expenditure records.  The Commission may organize and adopt rules for the conduct of its business and do whatever else it considers necessary or advisable to carry out the purposes of KRS 7.310 to 7.380. </section><section prefix="2">The Commission may adopt rules and prescribe procedures for the conduct of its affairs. </section><section prefix="3">The Commission or any member thereof or any employee duly authorized by the Commission or the co-chairmen thereof may administer oaths, issue subpoenas, compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of papers, books, accounts, documents, and testimony, and have the deposition of witnesses taken in the manner prescribed by law for taking depositions in civil actions. If a person disobeys or refuses to comply with a subpoena, or if a witness refuses to testify to a matter regarding which he may be lawfully interrogated, the Franklin Circuit Court may on application of the Commission compel obedience by proceedings for contempt in the same manner as in the case of disobedience of the requirements of a subpoena issued from the court or a refusal to testify in the court. Each witness who appears before the Commission by its order, other than an officer or employee of the state, is entitled to the fees and mileage provided for witnesses in civil cases in courts of record, which shall be audited and paid upon the presentation of proper vouchers sworn to by such witnesses and approved by the co-chairmen of the Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 167, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 131, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 533, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 3, effective June 21, 1974. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1966.</history><metadata><effective> July 13, 1984</effective><former-codification> KRS 6.370.</former-codification><lrc-note>(1984).  This section was amended by two 1984 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together.This is former KRS 6.370 as amended, renumbered by the Reviser of Statutes in 1974. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=482</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>