<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.295</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for promulgation of code of student rights and responsibilities for secondary schools -- Prohibited student activities. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of education of each public school district in the Commonwealth may adopt and promulgate a code of student rights and responsibilities for secondary schools from recommendations of a committee composed of students, faculty, parents, and school district administrative personnel. </section><section prefix="2">Such committee shall consist of two (2) students, two (2) parents of students, two (2) faculty members, two (2) representatives from administrative personnel of the district, and one (1) member of the local school board. </section><section prefix="3">The student and faculty members of such committee shall be elected by their peers in the local school district; the administrative personnel shall be appointed by the school district superintendent, and the parents selected by the faculty and student body. Members of such committee shall serve for a term of one (1) year and may be reelected or reappointed in following years. Initial composition of the elected members of such committee shall be by the following: <section prefix="a">The district superintendent shall notify each school within the district, each school principal or head teacher, the students of the district, and the parents of students within the district as to the method for receiving nominations for membership on the committee and of the methods by which the election of members shall take place. Such notification shall take place on or before the first day of school for each school term. </section><section prefix="b">Nominations for the student, faculty, and parent members of the committee shall be received in writing by the district superintendent within thirty (30) days following the commencement of each school term. </section><section prefix="c">The election of student, faculty, and parent members of the committee shall be held within fourteen (14) days following the closing of nominations under the supervision of the district superintendent. </section><section prefix="d">The initial meeting of the elected and appointed members shall be no later than fourteen (14) days following the election. </section></section><section prefix="4">Each committee member shall be entitled to a single vote and any code of student rights and responsibilities adopted by a majority of the committee membership shall be submitted to the district board of education which may cause such code, in whole or in part, to be implemented in the public schools of the district. </section><section prefix="5">All meetings of the committee shall be open to the public and the committee shall hold at least one (1) public hearing on the proposed code before it is adopted and submitted to the district board of education for implementation. </section><section prefix="6">The code of student rights and responsibilities adopted by the committee may define rights and responsibilities regarding, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">Right of expression, including, but not limited to, appearance, assembly, association, and circulation of petitions and literature; </section><section prefix="b">Right to participate in decision-making procedures directly affecting students; </section><section prefix="c">Right to procedural due process concerning major disciplinary action, as defined by the code; </section><section prefix="d">Right to receive academic grades based only upon academic performance; </section><section prefix="e">Right to freedom from abuse and threat of abuse by members of school faculties and administration personnel; and </section><section prefix="f">Right of access by a student to his or her own records and guarantee of the confidentiality of a student's academic records outside of the school system, except upon written authorization of the student or his or her parents or guardians. </section></section><section prefix="7">Students shall refrain from activity which materially or substantially disrupts the educational process or presents a clear and present danger to the health and safety of persons or property, or infringes on the rights of others. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 432, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>