<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.706</section_number><catch_line>Prosecutors Advisory Council to collect data on sexual offenses involving minors.   </catch_line><order_by>706</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Prosecutors Advisory Council shall collect statistical data regarding the investigation, prosecution, dismissal, conviction, or acquittal of any person charged with committing, attempting to commit, or complicity to a sexual offense defined by KRS Chapter 510 involving a minor, human trafficking offenses involving a minor engaged in commercial sexual activity, incest involving a minor, use of a minor in a sexual performance, or unlawful transaction with a minor. </section><section prefix="2">Each Commonwealth's attorney, each county attorney, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police, each Circuit Court clerk, and the Administrative Office of the Courts shall provide any data requested by the council for this purpose, on a form prescribed by the council, at intervals as the council may direct. </section><section prefix="3">The council may contract with any other public agency to collect the data in lieu of collecting the data itself. </section><section prefix="4">The Prosecutors Advisory Council may promulgate administrative regulations to specify information to be reported. </section><section prefix="5">The information required to be reported by this section shall be provided by each Commonwealth's attorney and county attorney at the end of each quarter of the calendar year or as otherwise directed by the Prosecutors Advisory Council. </section><section prefix="6">The Prosecutors Advisory Council and the Office of the Attorney General shall compile the information by county and issue a public report at least annually. </section><section prefix="7">The public report shall not contain the name or identifying information of a victim or person not formally charged with the commission of child sexual abuse or human trafficking of a child. Information collected by the Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney or by the Prosecutors Advisory Council containing data which cannot be published shall be excluded from inspection, unless by court order, from the Open Records Law. </section><section prefix="8">Any Commonwealth's attorney or any county attorney who fails to report information as defined by this section or administrative regulation shall be subject to salary reduction as authorized by KRS 61.120. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 33, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 82, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 66, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41846</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>