<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.11-042</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure agreement for compensation received by an agent from an insurer or client for placement of insurance and service rendered to client. </catch_line><order_by>11-042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">"Agent" means an agent as defined in KRS 304.9-020; </section><section prefix="2">"Agent" does not include the following: <section prefix="a">A managing general agent; </section><section prefix="b">A surplus lines broker; </section><section prefix="c">A licensed insurance agent who is employed by an insurer; or </section><section prefix="d">An exclusive agent under contract with one (1) insurer or a group of affiliated insurers who receives his sole compensation from the insurer; </section></section></section><section prefix="b">"Client" means a person that purchases insurance covering the business operations and exposures to loss of that person, and that has entered into an agreement with an agent pursuant to a written disclosure agreement as provided in subsection (2) of this section, and: <section prefix="1">For the purpose of health insurance as defined in KRS 304.5-040, life insurance as defined in KRS 304.5-020, but only as it relates to group life contracts, and ancillary employee benefits, the person meets or exceeds at least one (1) of the following measures from subdivisions a. and b. of this subparagraph and one (1) from subdivisions c. and d. of this subparagraph for the size of the business for the most recent fiscal year end closed: <section prefix="a">Total assets of the business of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000); or </section><section prefix="b">Total sales or revenue of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000) per year; and </section><section prefix="c">Total number of eligible employees of at least one hundred (100); or </section><section prefix="d">Annual health and employee benefits premiums of at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); </section></section><section prefix="2">A person whose health benefit plan is procured through an employer-organized association as defined in KRS 304.17A-005; </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of property insurance as defined in KRS 304.5-050 and casualty insurance as defined in KRS 304.5-070, the person meets or exceeds at least one (1) of the following measures from subdivisions a. and b. of this subparagraph and one (1) from subdivisions c. and d. of this subparagraph for the size of the business for the most recent fiscal year end closed: <section prefix="a">Total assets of the business of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000); or </section><section prefix="b">Total sales or revenue of at least twenty-five million dollars ($25,000,000) per year; and </section><section prefix="c">Total number of eligible employees of at least one hundred (100); or </section><section prefix="d">Annual property and casualty policy premiums of at least four hundred thousand dollars ($400,000); or </section></section><section prefix="4">A person purchasing an unbundled insurance program either with fixed costs exceeding one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) or with a deductible relative to any one (1) line of coverage of at least one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000); </section></section><section prefix="c">"Compensation" means any commissions or payments received by an agent from an insurer or a client for the sale of insurance or any other service rendered on behalf of the client; </section><section prefix="d">"Written disclosure agreement" means a written document signed by an agent and a client that describes the compensation arrangement agreed to between the agent and the insurer or the client, the method of payment of the compensation, and the services to be provided for the compensation, and that otherwise complies with this section; </section><section prefix="e">"Service" means any assistance or programs provided by the agent to the client that is intended to reduce the future cost of insurance of the client or the probability or severity of loss and means any assistance or programs designed to assist in the efficient administration of the client's insurance program or to assist the client in complying with any state or federal law; and </section><section prefix="f">"Unbundled insurance program" means a large account where the insurer provides the insurance coverage and related underwriting services for the insured, then the insured obtains claim adjustment services from another entity engaged in the business of providing such services and not from the insurer itself. </section></section><section prefix="2">An agent may receive from an insurer or client, compensation in any amount agreed to by the agent and the insurer or client for placement of insurance and for a service rendered on behalf of the client if, prior to the placement of the insurance, the provision of a service as a result of the placement, or for the provision of any other service, the agent and the client enter into a written disclosure agreement. A disclosure agreement shall: <section prefix="a">Include a description of the services to be provided pursuant to the agreement, specify if any policy or service is exempt from the agreement, and specify the compensation to be received by the agent from the insurer or client; </section><section prefix="b">Be signed by the client prior to the placement of insurance or provision of services; and </section><section prefix="c">Be retained by the agent for a period of five (5) years from the date the agreement expires or is otherwise terminated. </section></section><section prefix="3">The agent shall verify, prior to the sale, solicitation, or negotiation with the client, that the person qualifies as a client under subsection (1)(b) of this section. The agent shall retain sufficient documentation in the agent’s files to show the client meets the qualification criteria in subsection (1)(b) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">An agent, when operating under a written disclosure agreement with a client under this section, may: <section prefix="a">Use an authorized property and casualty insurer; </section><section prefix="b">Use an unauthorized property and casualty insurer if the business is exported in accordance with Subtitle 10 of this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">Use only an authorized life, health, or workers' compensation insurer. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Any insurer writing business in accordance with this section shall comply with applicable rate and form filing requirements. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding applicable rate and form filing requirements, an agent placing business for a client may provide for alternative compensation in a written disclosure agreement as provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to personal lines of insurance issued for personal or family protection to a person. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17006</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>