<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.544</section_number><catch_line>Web site to provide public access to expenditure records of sanitation district -- Monthly updates -- Exemption -- Registration with Department for Local Government -- Application of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090 for fiscal periods beginning on or after July 1, 2014. </catch_line><order_by>544</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By January 1, 2012, each district board of directors of a district shall provide public access to records relating to expenditures of the district through display of the records on a Web site. </section><section prefix="2">The Web site shall be in a searchable format and shall provide financial information about expenditures not exempt under the provisions of state or federal law, including: <section prefix="a">The payee name; </section><section prefix="b">The category or type of expenditure; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the reason for the expenditure, if available; </section><section prefix="d">The expenditure amount; </section><section prefix="e">An electronic link to documents relating to the expenditure, if the documents are available electronically; </section><section prefix="f">The budget adopted by the district and subsequent amendments to that budget; </section><section prefix="g">The completed annual audit; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other information deemed relevant by the district. </section></section><section prefix="3">Information on the Web site shall be updated at least on a monthly basis and shall be maintained on the Web site for at least three (3) years. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of this section shall not apply to sanitation districts with fewer than ten thousand (10,000) customer accounts. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The district shall register with the Department for Local Government as required by KRS 65A.090. </section><section prefix="b">For fiscal periods beginning on and after July 1, 2014, the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090 shall apply to districts. District board members shall work with the Department for Local Government to provide the information required by this section through the registry established by KRS 65A.020. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 70, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec.15, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>