<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-762</section_number><catch_line>Outlet to act as policyholder for member -- Certificate of coverage for each member -- Disclosure to members. </catch_line><order_by>17A-762</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For administrative purposes, an insurance purchasing outlet shall be the policyholder or contract holder of the health benefit plan on behalf of an insurance purchasing outlet member. </section><section prefix="2">The participating insurer shall issue a certificate of coverage to each insurance purchasing outlet member. </section><section prefix="3">The insurance purchasing outlet shall provide the following disclosures to an insurance purchasing outlet member at the time of enrollment: <section prefix="a">The insurance purchasing outlet is not an insurer and does not pay benefits or claims. It collects and distributes premiums on behalf of insurance purchasing outlet members; </section><section prefix="b">The insurance purchasing outlet is registered with the Kentucky Department of Insurance to provide specific administrative services and may not assume any risk for claim and benefit payments; and </section><section prefix="c">Other disclosures as the commissioner shall require by administrative regulation. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1255, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>