<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="405" order_by="405">PARENT AND CHILD </unit></structure><section_number>405.075</section_number><catch_line>Anonymity of parent who places newborn infant with emergency provider, police station, fire station, or hospital -- Transport to emergency room -- Implied consent to treatment -- Waiver by parent -- Short title. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "newborn infant" means an infant who is medically determined to be less than seventy-two (72) hours old. </section><section prefix="2">A parent who places a newborn infant with an emergency medical services provider, police station, fire station, or hospital and expresses no intent to return for the infant shall have the right to remain anonymous and not be pursued and shall not be considered to have abandoned or endangered the newborn infant under KRS Chapters 508 and 530. </section><section prefix="3">Any emergency medical services provider, police officer, or firefighter who accepts physical custody of a newborn infant in accordance with this section shall immediately arrange for the infant to be taken to the nearest hospital emergency room and shall have implied consent to any and all appropriate medical treatment. </section><section prefix="4">By placing a newborn infant in the manner described in this section, the parent: <section prefix="a">Waives the right to notification required by subsequent court proceedings conducted under KRS Chapter 620 until such time as a claim of parental rights is made; and </section><section prefix="b">Waives legal standing to make a claim of action against any person who accepts physical custody of the newborn infant. </section></section><section prefix="5">The provisions of subsection (2) of this section shall not apply when indicators of child physical abuse or child neglect are present. </section><section prefix="6">KRS 211.951, 216B.190, 311.6526, 405.075, 620.350, and 620.355 shall be known as "The Representative Thomas J. Burch Safe Infants Act." </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 4, effective April 9, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>