<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.867</section_number><catch_line>Zoning jurisdiction -- Regulations -- Public files. </catch_line><order_by>867</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall require that every military and public use airport, heliport, and sea plane base in the state file with it, from time to time, as required, maps showing the airport and area surrounding the airport used for approach or landing purposes. The commission shall thereafter designate on the maps, by reference to the regulations or standards promulgated by the Federal Aviation Administration concerning the area required for the safe maneuvering approach and landing of aircraft, the area over which jurisdiction will be assumed for zoning purposes. The commission shall notify any local zoning bodies of the area so designated and may exercise jurisdiction of the area insofar as it pertains to the safe and proper maneuvering of aircraft and the safe and proper use of the airport involved. The local zoning body may retain jurisdiction of zoning in such areas as to all other matters. </section><section prefix="2">The commission may adopt regulations pertaining to the zoning of areas over which jurisdiction is assumed as will provide for the proper and safe use of the area and airport. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall maintain a public file in the offices of the cabinet showing maps of each military and public use airport, heliport, and sea plane base within the state and the area around the airport over which it has assumed jurisdiction for zoning purposes and such shall constitute public notice of the restrictions and zoning applicable to the areas or airport. The commission shall also maintain a public file showing any regulations adopted pertaining to land uses in areas zoned and these regulations shall constitute public notice of same. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 6. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 24. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 58. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5864</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>