<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.8505</section_number><catch_line>Purpose of KRS 260.850 to 260.869 declared to be the support of industrial hemp production, development, and commercialization -- Accomplishment of purpose achieved through auspices of Industrial Hemp Commission, research, and pursuit of federal permits or waivers -- General Assembly finds that development of industrial hemp is proper governmental purpose and important to Commonwealth's well-being.   </catch_line><order_by>8505</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of KRS 260.850 to 260.869 is to assist the Commonwealth in moving to the forefront of industrial hemp production, development, and commercialization of hemp products in agribusiness, alternative fuel production, and other business sectors, both nationally and globally and to the greatest extent possible. These purposes shall be accomplished, in part, through: <section prefix="a">The auspices of the Industrial Hemp Commission created by KRS 260.857; </section><section prefix="b">The industrial hemp research program overseen by the commission, working in conjunction with the staff of the University of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station, along with the University of Louisville, the various comprehensive universities as defined in KRS 164.001, and other research partners. This research program shall include the planting, cultivation, and analysis of industrial hemp demonstration plots by selected growers that are licensed by the commission pursuant to KRS 260.854; and </section><section prefix="c">The pursuit of any federal permits or waivers necessary to allow industrial hemp to be grown in the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares that the authority granted in KRS 260.850 to 260.869 and the purposes accomplished hereby are proper governmental and public purposes, and that the development of industrial hemp production and commercial markets for hemp products within the Commonwealth is important to its economic well-being. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42600</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>