<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.480Authority</section_number><catch_line>to require permits -- Proof of licensure under KRS Chapter 227A -- Inspectors -- Inspection standards.   </catch_line><order_by>480Authority</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government or the state shall, according to the Uniform State Building Code as it pertains to the plan review and inspection responsibilities of local governments or the state, require any person to obtain a permit before commencing construction, alteration, or repairs of any electrical system. </section><section prefix="b">The city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government or the state shall require all inspections that are deemed necessary by the department for the safety of life and property. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to describe the circumstances where inspections are required. </section></section><section prefix="2">A city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government or the state shall not issue a permit unless the applicant submits proof of being licensed as an electrical contractor under KRS Chapter 227A or of acting on behalf of a licensed electrical contractor. However, the provisions of this subsection shall not apply to a homeowner or farmer who does construction, alteration, or repairs of any electrical system on his or her own premises or any other person exempt from licensing under KRS 227A.030 or 227A.150. This subsection shall not apply to electrical work performed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, a city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government, or any subdivision thereof. </section><section prefix="3">A city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government shall appoint and may fix the compensation of city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government electrical inspectors, and may by ordinance fix reasonable fees and establish other requirements for the conduct of electrical inspections within its boundaries. All electrical inspectors must be certified under KRS 227.489. </section><section prefix="4">Reasonable standards for the construction, alteration, and repair of any electrical system shall be those adopted in the Uniform State Building Code, as promulgated by the Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction, and shall have as a minimum standard the requirements of the National Electrical Code. These standards shall be used by the electrical inspector in making his inspections. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 404, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1, effective April 6, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 16, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 44, effective July 1, 1978; and ch. 384, sec. 92, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 6, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known and may be cited as "Isaac's Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>