<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.780</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 171.780 to 171.788. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text>As used in KRS 171.780 to 171.788, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commission" means the Kentucky Military Heritage Commission. </section><section prefix="2">"Military heritage" means any peacetime, wartime, or other military activity engaged in by any or all of the thirteen (13) original colonies prior to the creation of the United States, activities engaged in by the United States, activities engaged in by the Confederate States of America, and activities of the Kentucky Militia, the Kentucky National Guard, the Kentucky Air National Guard, and any other military, quasi-military, or partisan unit operating under the jurisdiction of the Commonwealth, or which operated within the Commonwealth. It includes, but is not limited to, the activities of any person who was born in Kentucky, who was a resident of Kentucky, or whose remains are interred in Kentucky as well as the activities of formal or informal military units, paid or volunteer. </section><section prefix="3">"Military heritage site" means any historic geographic site of military heritage significance declared as such by the commission, pursuant to KRS 171.782, 171.784, and 171.786. </section><section prefix="4">"Military heritage object" means any building, fortification, statue, monument, marker, work of art, flag, aircraft, field piece, item of military equipment, weapon, or other physical object of military heritage significance declared as such by the commission, pursuant to KRS 171.782, 171.784, and 171.786, including but not limited to buildings, sites, and other landmarks. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4858</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>