<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.060</section_number><catch_line>Rock-dusting. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The following rules shall govern in the rock-dusting of mines: <section prefix="1">All mines, or parts of mines, or sections thereof, shall be rock-dusted if conditions are found to be dusty or hazardous, after proper inspection. In the event such conditions are found to exist, then the commissioner or his authorized representative shall require the necessary rock-dusting to make the mine, part of the mine, or section safe. </section><section prefix="2">In all mines, accumulations of excessive loose coal and fine dry coal dust shall be removed from the mine, and all operating sections kept thoroughly rock-dusted, and the dust on the mine floor allayed by methods approved by the commissioner, but in every mine, or in any part or section thereof, rock-dusting shall be applied to maintain at all times a minimum percentage of sixty-five percent (65%) of noncombustible matter to within forty (40) feet of the faces, including last open crosscuts, and under certain special conditions the department may require that places be rock-dusted to the faces, and that additional rock-dust be added. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 25, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 22. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 8. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 6. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 18, effective March 5, 1952. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 7. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-20. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32977</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>