<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">C STATE AID TO LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39C.080</section_number><catch_line>Performance evaluations -- Records and reports -- Review of program progress and compliance -- Correction of deficiencies -- Appeal process. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The performance of each local emergency management agency or local director receiving funding pursuant to KRS 39C.010 and 39C.020 shall be evaluated quarterly as to compliance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, satisfactory program administration, and the achievement of scheduled program objectives by the local emergency management agency or local director. Based upon this evaluation: <section prefix="a">Programs which are judged deficient, or otherwise not in compliance with KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, or program guidance of the division, may have funds withheld and those funds which have been withheld may be transferred to other local emergency management agencies. </section><section prefix="b">Programs which meet or exceed their minimum program objectives and have needs for additional funds for program improvements may be granted additional requested funds, or portions thereof, for use by the local emergency management agency in making the improvements, subject to the availability of funds. </section></section><section prefix="2">Within fifteen (15) days after the end of each quarter, the local emergency management director shall prepare and submit all documentation, records, or reports required by the division to substantiate and document the work activity of the local director and the local emergency management agency in performing official duties or work plan objectives during each quarter. </section><section prefix="3">Program progress and compliance shall be reviewed quarterly by the area manager of the geographical area in which the local emergency management agency is located. The area manager shall review training records, exercise reports, financial records and budget expenditure rates, all work plan documentation reports or materials submitted by the local director at the end of each quarter, program guidance materials, or other sources of information, and make an assessment as to whether the local emergency management agency or local director is in compliance with current program requirements or guidance, or is making satisfactory progress toward the full achievement of the objectives outlined in the work plan of the annual program paper. The area manager shall transmit an assessment report to the director of the division together with any recommendations thereon. </section><section prefix="4">The director shall then review the material submitted, together with the area manager's recommendations, and submit it to the advisory committee for its evaluation and recommendations with regard thereto. </section><section prefix="5">The advisory committee shall transmit to the director its determination of the local emergency management agency's state of compliance or progress, and that of the local director, and the committee's recommendations with regard thereto. The director shall review the report and all recommendations thereon. The director shall then make a final determination with regard to compliance and progress and, if a deficiency is found, the measures which shall be taken to assure compliance. </section><section prefix="6">Local emergency management agencies or local directors determined not to be making satisfactory progress toward the accomplishment or completion of work plan objectives as outlined in the annual program paper, or not performing in accordance with the written program guidance or the requirements of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, shall be given thirty (30) days to correct the deficiencies in the manner outlined by the director. </section><section prefix="7">A local emergency management agency aggrieved by a decision of the director may appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court within twenty (20) days of the receipt of the director's decision. The court's review shall be from the record and shall not be de novo, unless the record is insufficient. </section><section prefix="8">If a decision has been made by the director to withhold funding from the local emergency management agency, that funding shall remain withheld during the pendency of any appeals of the decision. </section><section prefix="9">At the end of the thirty (30) day period further funding may be withdrawn by the director, if the deficiencies have not been corrected. The funds may then be reallocated to other local emergency management agencies. </section><section prefix="10">The director, during the review process outlined in this section, shall also review the expenditure rate of each local emergency management agency receiving funds. If it is determined that a local agency will not utilize all allocated funds, appropriate portions of the allocation may be withdrawn and reallocated to another local emergency management agency. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21758</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>