<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="402" order_by="402">MARRIAGE </unit></structure><section_number>402.100</section_number><catch_line>Marriage license -- Marriage certificate -- Confidentiality of Social Security numbers. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>Each county clerk shall use the form prescribed by the Department for Libraries and Archives when issuing a marriage license. This form shall provide for the entering of all of the information required in this section, and may also provide for the entering of additional information prescribed by the Department for Libraries and Archives. The form shall consist of: <section prefix="1">A marriage license which provides for the entering of: <section prefix="a">An authorization statement of the county clerk issuing the license for any person or religious society authorized to perform marriage ceremonies to unite in marriage the persons named; </section><section prefix="b">Vital information for each party, including the full name, date of birth, place of birth, race, condition (single, widowed, or divorced), number of previous marriages, occupation, current residence, relationship to the other party, and full names of parents; and </section><section prefix="c">The date and place the license is issued, and the signature of the county clerk or deputy clerk issuing the license. </section></section><section prefix="2">A marriage certificate which provides for the entering of: <section prefix="a">A statement by the person performing the marriage ceremony or the clerk of the religious society authorized to solemnize the marriage ceremony that the ceremony was performed. The statement shall include the name and title of the person performing the ceremony or the name of the religious society solemnizing the marriage, the names of persons married, the date and place of the marriage, and the names of two (2) witnesses; </section><section prefix="b">A statement by the person performing the marriage ceremony of his legal qualification under this chapter to perform the ceremony, such statement to include the name of the county or city where his license to perform marriage ceremonies was issued or, in the case of religious societies authorized by KRS 402.050(c) to solemnize marriages, the name of the city or county where the religious society is incorporated. The provisions of this paragraph shall not be construed to require the clerk of a religious society to be present at the marriage so long as the witnesses of the society are present; </section><section prefix="c">A dated signature of the person performing the ceremony; and </section><section prefix="d">A signed statement by the county clerk or a deputy county clerk of the county in which the marriage license was issued that the marriage certificate was recorded. The statement shall indicate the name of the county and the date the marriage certificate was recorded. </section></section><section prefix="3">A certificate to be delivered by the person performing the marriage ceremony or the clerk of the religious society performing the marriage ceremony to the parties married. This certificate shall provide for the entering of: <section prefix="a">A statement by the person performing the marriage ceremony or the clerk of the religious society performing the marriage ceremony that the ceremony was performed. The statement shall include the name and title of the person performing the ceremony, or the name of the religious society performing the ceremony, the names of persons married, the date and place of the marriage, the names of two (2) witnesses, and the following information as recorded on the license authorizing the marriage: the date the license was issued, the name of the county clerk under whose authority the license was issued, and the county in which the license was issued; and </section><section prefix="b">A dated signature of the person performing the ceremony or the clerk of the religious society performing the ceremony. </section></section><section prefix="4">A Social Security number shall be requested as a means of identification of each party but shall not be recorded on the marriage license or certificate. Other means of identification may also be requested if a party does not have a Social Security number. The Social Security number shall be forwarded to the appropriate agency within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services that is responsible for enforcing child support, and the number shall be stored by that agency with a nonidentifying numeric. The Social Security number shall not be available for public release. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 621, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2103. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 158, and 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 2, which are in conflict and cannot be compiled together. Pursuant to KRS 7.123, the amendment in ch. 279, sec. 2, the nonrevisory Act, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>