<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.230</section_number><catch_line>Chief state school officer to prepare publications. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief state school officer shall annually prepare or cause to be prepared, and submit for approval and publication by the Kentucky Board of Education, a list of all public and private high schools or other secondary schools in the state, showing the classification of each. </section><section prefix="2">He shall, from time to time, prepare or cause to be prepared, and submit for approval and publication by the Kentucky Board of Education, such bulletins, programs, outlines of courses, placards, and courses of study as he deems useful in the promotion of the interests of the public schools. </section><section prefix="3">He shall also prepare for publication the administrative regulations, minimum standards for schools, and educational policies or programs adopted by the board for the operation, regulation, and government of the schools under its supervision. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 51, effective July 1, 1990; and ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 138, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 92, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4384-19, 4384-31. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails, pursuant to KRS 446.250.  </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3153</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>