<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.590</section_number><catch_line>Minor's negligence imputed to person signing application or allowing him to drive. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any negligence of a minor under the age of eighteen (18) who has been licensed upon an application signed as provided by KRS 186.470, when driving any motor vehicle upon a highway, shall be imputed to the person who signed the application of the minor for the license. That person shall be jointly and severally liable with the minor for any damages caused by the negligence. </section><section prefix="2">If a minor deposits or there is deposited in his behalf, a proof of financial responsibility in form and amounts required by KRS Chapter 187, the person who signed the application shall not, while such proof is maintained, be subject to the liability imposed by subsection (1). If the minor is the owner of a motor vehicle, the proof of financial responsibility shall be with respect to the operation of that motor vehicle; if not an owner, then with respect to the operation of any motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="3">Every motor vehicle owner who causes or knowingly permits a minor under the age of eighteen (18) to drive the vehicle upon a highway, and any person who gives or furnishes a motor vehicle to the minor shall be jointly and severally liable with the minor for damage caused by the negligence of the minor in driving the vehicle. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739m-41, 2739m-53, 2739m-54. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6089</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>