<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.050</section_number><catch_line>Appointment and compensation of personnel -- Department of Kentucky State Police Personnel Board -- Organization, duties, and compensation. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall appoint or promote to the ranks and grades and positions of the department such officers as are considered by him or her to be necessary for the efficient administration of the department. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 64.640, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police and the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall biennially conduct a salary survey, by rank, of State Police/highway patrol officers in those states adjoining Kentucky. The salaries of such officers of equal rank in those states surveyed shall be averaged, and such averages where the average for that rank exceeds the salary paid to Kentucky officers of that rank in the preceding biennium shall be included in the department's budget request submitted to the Kentucky General Assembly. </section><section prefix="2">All initial appointments of officers to the department shall be made for merit and fitness after a competitive examination. </section><section prefix="3">There is created a Department of Kentucky State Police Personnel Board consisting of the commissioner and four (4) other members to be appointed by the Governor, two (2) to be appointed from each of the two (2) major political parties. </section><section prefix="4">The initial appointment of members of the board shall be for terms of one (1), two (2), three (3), and four (4) years. Thereafter each appointment shall be for a term of four (4) years, except that a person appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of a term shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the board may be removed by the Governor only for cause, after being given a copy of charges against them and an opportunity to be heard publicly on such charges before the Governor. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall elect one (1) of its members chairman. It shall meet at such time and place as shall be specified by call of the commissioner. Three (3) members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. Members of the board other than the commissioner shall receive compensation of fifty dollars ($50) and reimbursement of travel expenses for each meeting of the board which they attend. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the purposes herein, which shall include provisions for: <section prefix="a">Open competitive examination as to fitness of applicants for employment as officers; and </section><section prefix="b">Establishment of eligible lists as a result of such competitive examinations, from which lists vacancies shall be filled. </section></section><section prefix="8">The board shall hear appeals from applicants for employment for which examinations are being given or have been conducted and from eligibles on examination registers subject to the procedural rules which the board may adopt pursuant to the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 57, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, secs. 24(4) and 25. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 12. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 2. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>.  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1090</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>