<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.095</section_number><catch_line>Professional development programs -- Professional development coordinator -- Long-term improvement plans -- Suicide prevention awareness information -- Evidence-informed trainings on child abuse and neglect -- Electronic consumer bulletin board -- Training to address needs of students at risk -- Teacher academics -- Annual report to Juvenile Justice Oversight Council.   </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Department of Education shall establish, direct, and maintain a statewide program of professional development to improve instruction in the public schools. </section><section prefix="2">Each local school district superintendent shall appoint a certified school employee to fulfill the role and responsibilities of a professional development coordinator who shall disseminate professional development information to schools and personnel. Upon request by a school council or any employees of the district, the coordinator shall provide technical assistance to the council or the personnel that may include assisting with needs assessments, analyzing school data, planning and evaluation assistance, organizing districtwide programs requested by school councils or groups of teachers, or other coordination activities. <section prefix="a">The manner of appointment, qualifications, and other duties of the professional development coordinator shall be established by Kentucky Board of Education through promulgation of administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="b">The local district professional development coordinator shall participate in the Kentucky Department of Education annual training program for local school district professional development coordinators. The training program may include, but not be limited to, the demonstration of various approaches to needs assessment and planning; strategies for implementing long-term, school-based professional development; strategies for strengthening teachers' roles in the planning, development, and evaluation of professional development; and demonstrations of model professional development programs. The training shall include information about teacher learning opportunities relating to the core content standards. The Kentucky Department of Education shall regularly collect and distribute this information. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Department of Education shall provide or facilitate optional, professional development programs for certified personnel throughout the Commonwealth that are based on the statewide needs of teachers, administrators, and other education personnel. Programs may include classified staff and parents when appropriate. Programs offered or facilitated by the department shall be at locations and times convenient to local school personnel and shall be made accessible through the use of technology when appropriate. They shall include programs that: address the goals for Kentucky schools as stated in KRS 158.6451, including reducing the achievement gaps as determined by an equity analysis of the disaggregated student performance data from the state assessment program developed under KRS 158.6453; engage educators in effective learning processes and foster collegiality and collaboration; and provide support for staff to incorporate newly acquired skills into their work through practicing the skills, gathering information about the results, and reflecting on their efforts. Professional development programs shall be made available to teachers based on their needs which shall include but not be limited to the following areas: <section prefix="a">Strategies to reduce the achievement gaps among various groups of students and to provide continuous progress; </section><section prefix="b">Curriculum content and methods of instruction for each content area, including differentiated instruction; </section><section prefix="c">School-based decision making; </section><section prefix="d">Assessment literacy; </section><section prefix="e">Integration of performance-based student assessment into daily classroom instruction; </section><section prefix="f">Nongraded primary programs; </section><section prefix="g">Research-based instructional practices; </section><section prefix="h">Instructional uses of technology; </section><section prefix="i">Curriculum design to serve the needs of students with diverse learning styles and skills and of students of diverse cultures; </section><section prefix="j">Instruction in reading, including phonics, phonemic awareness, comprehension, fluency, and vocabulary; </section><section prefix="k">Educational leadership; and </section><section prefix="l">Strategies to incorporate character education throughout the curriculum. </section></section><section prefix="4">The department shall assist school personnel in assessing the impact of professional development on their instructional practices and student learning. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall assist districts and school councils with the development of long-term school and district improvement plans that include multiple strategies for professional development based on the assessment of needs at the school level. <section prefix="a">Professional development strategies may include, but are not limited to, participation in subject matter academies, teacher networks, training institutes, workshops, seminars, and study groups; collegial planning; action research; mentoring programs; appropriate university courses; and other forms of professional development. </section><section prefix="b">In planning the use of the four (4) days for professional development under KRS 158.070, school councils and districts shall give priority to programs that increase teachers' understanding of curriculum content and methods of instruction appropriate for each content area based on individual school plans. The district may use up to one (1) day to provide district-wide training and training that is mandated by state or federal law. Only those employees identified in the mandate or affected by the mandate shall be required to attend the training. </section><section prefix="c">State funds allocated for professional development shall be used to support professional development initiatives that are consistent with local school improvement and professional development plans and teachers' individual growth plans. The funds may be used throughout the year for all staff, including classified and certified staff and parents on school councils or committees. A portion of the funds allocated to each school council under KRS 160.345 may be used to prepare or enhance the teachers' knowledge and teaching practices related to the content and subject matter that are required for their specific classroom assignments. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">By August 1, 2010, the Kentucky Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall post on its Web page suicide prevention awareness information, to include recognizing the warning signs of a suicide crisis. The Web page shall include information related to suicide prevention training opportunities offered by the cabinet or an agency recognized by the cabinet as a training provider. </section><section prefix="b">By September 1, 2010, and September 1 of each year thereafter, every public middle and high school administrator shall disseminate suicide prevention awareness information to all middle and high school students. The information may be obtained from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or from a commercially developed suicide prevention training program. </section></section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Department of Education shall develop and maintain a list of approved comprehensive evidence-informed trainings on child abuse and neglect prevention, recognition, and reporting that encompass child physical, sexual, and emotional abuse and neglect. </section><section prefix="b">The trainings shall be Web-based or in-person and cover, at a minimum, the following topics: <section prefix="1">Recognizing child physical, sexual, and emotional abuse and neglect; </section><section prefix="2">Reporting suspected child abuse and neglect in Kentucky as required by KRS 620.030 and the appropriate documentation; </section><section prefix="3">Responding to the child; and </section><section prefix="4">Understanding the response of child protective services. </section></section><section prefix="c">The trainings shall include a questionnaire or other basic assessment tool upon completion to document basic knowledge of training components. </section><section prefix="d">Each local school board shall adopt one (1) or more trainings from the list approved by the Department of Education to be implemented by schools. </section><section prefix="e">All current school administrators, certified personnel, office staff, instructional assistants, and coaches and extracurricular sponsors who are employed by the school district shall complete the implemented training or trainings by January 31, 2017, and then every two (2) years after. </section><section prefix="f">All school administrators, certified personnel, office staff, instructional assistants, and coaches and extracurricular sponsors who are employed by the school district hired after January 31, 2017, shall complete the implemented training or trainings within ninety (90) days of being hired and then every two (2) years after. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Department of Education shall establish an electronic consumer bulletin board that posts information regarding professional development providers and programs as a service to school district central office personnel, school councils, teachers, and administrators. Participation on the electronic consumer bulletin board shall be voluntary for professional development providers or vendors, but shall include all programs sponsored by the department. Participants shall provide the following information: program title; name of provider or vendor; qualifications of the presenters or instructors; objectives of the program; program length; services provided, including follow-up support; costs for participation and costs of materials; names of previous users of the program, addresses, and telephone numbers; and arrangements required. Posting information on the bulletin board by the department shall not be viewed as an endorsement of the quality of any specific provider or program. </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Education shall provide training to address the characteristics and instructional needs of students at risk of school failure and most likely to drop out of school. The training shall be developed to meet the specific needs of all certified and classified personnel depending on their relationship with these students. The training for instructional personnel shall be designed to provide and enhance skills of personnel to: <section prefix="a">Identify at-risk students early in elementary schools as well as at-risk and potential dropouts in the middle and high schools; </section><section prefix="b">Plan specific instructional strategies to teach at-risk students; </section><section prefix="c">Improve the academic achievement of students at risk of school failure by providing individualized and extra instructional support to increase expectations for targeted students; </section><section prefix="d">Involve parents as partners in ways to help their children and to improve their children's academic progress; and </section><section prefix="e">Significantly reduce the dropout rate of all students. </section></section><section prefix="10">The department shall establish teacher academies to the extent funding is available in cooperation with postsecondary education institutions for elementary, middle school, and high school faculty in core disciplines, utilizing facilities and faculty from universities and colleges, local school districts, and other appropriate agencies throughout the state. Priority for participation shall be given to those teachers who are teaching core discipline courses for which they do not have a major or minor or the equivalent. Participation of teachers shall be voluntary. </section><section prefix="11">The department shall annually provide to the oversight council established in KRS 15A.063, the information received from local schools pursuant to KRS 158.449. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 8, effective March 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 452, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 527, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998.; and ch. 609, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective October 18, 1985; Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. II, sec. 2. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 162, 452, and 527. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. As to subsection (7) of this section, a conflict exists, in part, between Acts chs. 452 and 527. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 527, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails in this conflict. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44040</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>