<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.30-080</section_number><catch_line>Form of premium finance agreement. </catch_line><order_by>30-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A premium finance agreement shall: <section prefix="a">Be dated, signed by or on behalf of the insured, and the printed portion thereof shall be in at least eight-point type; </section><section prefix="b">Contain the name and place of business of the insurance agent negotiating the related insurance contract, the name and residence or the place of business of the premium finance company to which payments are to be made, a description of the insurance contracts involved and the amount of the premium therefor; and </section><section prefix="c">Set forth the following items where applicable: <section prefix="1">The total amount of the premium, </section><section prefix="2">The amount of the down payment, </section><section prefix="3">The principal balance (the difference between items 1. and 2.), </section><section prefix="4">The amount of the service charge, </section><section prefix="5">The balance payable by the insured (sum of items 3. and 4.), and </section><section prefix="6">The number of installments required, the amount of each installment expressed in dollars, and the due date or period thereof. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The items set out in paragraph (c) of subsection (1) of this section need not be stated in the sequence or order in which they appear, and additional items may be included to explain the computations made in determining the amount to be paid by the insured. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 30, sec. 8, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29752</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>