<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.550</section_number><catch_line>Role of Legislative Research Commission in development of population data for redistricting -- Computerized map -- Review of precinct establishment orders and requests for exemption. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Legislative Research Commission shall serve as the legislative department's liaison with the United States Bureau of the Census for purposes of Kentucky's participation in and receipt of census maps and data under programs implementing United States Public Law 94-171, relating to the development of population data for redistricting. </section><section prefix="2">The Legislative Research Commission shall maintain and continuously update a computerized map of Kentucky containing census geography and election precinct boundaries. </section><section prefix="3">The Legislative Research Commission shall review any proposed precinct establishment order and request for an exemption made under KRS 117.0552 to 117.0554 to determine the effect of the proposed order or exemption upon the Commonwealth's participation in programs to implement United States Public Law 94-171. If the Commission determines that the proposed order or exemption would have an adverse effect upon the Commonwealth's ability to participate in the programs, it shall so advise the State Board of Elections. </section><section prefix="4">The Legislative Research Commission may direct its interim joint subcommittee of appropriate jurisdiction to perform or oversee the performance of the responsibilities assigned to the Commission by this section. </section></text><history> Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 7, effective April 13, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=494</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>