<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-300</section_number><catch_line>Purpose. </catch_line><order_by>20-300</order_by><text>For the purpose of adopting the Asbestos Hazard Emergency Response Act, called AHERA, Public Law (99-519), as amended, the cabinet may develop, adopt, and maintain a comprehensive statewide asbestos assessment and response program and an accreditation program that shall replicate the federal environmental protection agency model plan issued April 30, 1987 and the provisions of Title 40 of the Code of Federal Regulations, Part 763, Subpart E. The programs shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Identifying and controlling asbestos hazards in public and private schools, grades K-12; </section><section prefix="2">Providing for accreditation of asbestos inspectors, management planners, abatement project designers, abatement contractors, supervisors, and abatement workers; </section><section prefix="3">Reviewing training courses to determine if they are approvable under the criteria established in the April 30, 1987 model plan and any other criteria adopted by the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="4">Reviewing school asbestos management plans and inspecting school buildings for compliance with this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 413, sec. 1, effective April 8, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.550. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>