<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="369" order_by="369">INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>369.118</section_number><catch_line>Acceptance and distribution of electronic records by governmental agencies. </catch_line><order_by>118</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 369.112(6), each governmental agency of this state, in compliance with standards established by the Commonwealth Office of Technology, shall determine whether, and the extent to which, it will send and accept electronic records and electronic signatures to and from other persons and otherwise create, generate, communicate, store, process, use, and rely upon electronic records and electronic signatures. </section><section prefix="2">To the extent that a governmental agency uses electronic records and electronic signatures under subsection (1) of this section: <section prefix="a">The Commonwealth Office of Technology, giving due consideration to security, may specify the manner and format in which the electronic records must be created, generated, sent, communicated, received, and stored and the systems established for those purposes; </section><section prefix="b">If electronic records must be signed by electronic means, each governmental agency, giving due consideration to security, may specify the type of electronic signature required, the manner and format in which the electronic signature must be affixed to the electronic record, and the identity of, or criteria that must be met by, any third party used by a person filing a document to facilitate the process; </section><section prefix="c">The Commonwealth Office of Technology and the Department for Libraries and Archives, giving due consideration to security, may specify control processes and procedures as appropriate to ensure adequate preservation, disposition, integrity, security, confidentiality, and auditability of electronic records; and </section><section prefix="d">Each governmental agency, giving due consideration to security, may specify any other required attributes for electronic records which are specified for corresponding nonelectronic records or reasonably necessary under the circumstances. </section></section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 369.112(6), KRS 369.101 to 369.120 does not require a governmental agency of this state to use or permit the use of electronic records or electronic signatures. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 693, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 18, effective August 1, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>