<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.33-554Contents</section_number><catch_line>of applications for loans, grants, or investments.   </catch_line><order_by>33-554Contents</order_by><text>Applications for loans, grants, or investments submitted under KRS 154.33-552 shall include the following: <section prefix="1">The name of the applicant and identification of all parties contributing to or taking a leadership role with regard to the development project; </section><section prefix="2">A detailed description of the project, including its location and the total project cost; </section><section prefix="3">The projected number of jobs, if any, to be created as a result of the project and a description of the types of jobs; </section><section prefix="4">If the applicant is an entity other than a city or county, a letter of support from all local governmental entities affected by the project; </section><section prefix="5">A detailed description of any other funding sources that will be used to pay for the project; </section><section prefix="6">A plan for making the project self-sustaining if it is expected or intended that the initiative will have recurring expenses, and an explanation of the stream of revenue or other resources that will cover future costs, including operational costs, administrative costs, and upkeep on any property, buildings, equipment, or other capital assets funded; and </section><section prefix="7">Any other information that the commissioner may require. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44444</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>