<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Amateur athletics" means any interscholastic athletics in which the participating athletes are elementary or secondary school students of any public or private institution of learning; any intercollegiate athletics in which the participating athletes are students of any public or private institution of higher education; or any athletics sponsored or regulated by the following amateur athletic associations including, but not limited to: <section prefix="a">United States Olympic Committee; </section><section prefix="b">National Collegiate Athletic Association; </section><section prefix="c">National Association of Intercollegiate Athletics; </section><section prefix="d">Kentucky High School Athletic Association; </section><section prefix="e">Kentucky Amateur Athletics Union; </section><section prefix="f">Bluegrass State Games; </section><section prefix="g">Little League Baseball; </section><section prefix="h">Amateur Softball Association; </section><section prefix="i">Babe Ruth Leagues of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="j">American Legion Baseball; </section><section prefix="k">Kentucky Youth Soccer Association; or </section><section prefix="l">Kentucky Special Olympics; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Corporation" means the Kentucky Lottery Corporation; </section><section prefix="3">"Lottery" means any game of chance approved by the corporation and operated pursuant to this chapter, except for games prohibited by the General Assembly as provided for in KRS 154A.063; </section><section prefix="4">"Major lottery-specific procurement" means any gaming product or service including, but not limited to, major advertising contracts, annuity contracts, prize payment agreements, consulting services, personal service contracts, equipment, tickets, and all other products and services unique to the operation of the corporation in its lottery activities, but not including materials, supplies, equipment, and services common to the ordinary operations of a corporation; </section><section prefix="5">"President" means the president of the Kentucky Lottery Corporation who shall also serve as chief executive officer of the corporation; </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">With respect to an individual, "related entity" means any spouse, child, brother, sister, or parent residing as a member of the same household in the principal place of abode of the individual, and any entity with respect to which the individual, or spouse, child, brother, sister, or parent of the individual has a financial interest of five percent (5%) or more, or is an officer, director, employee, or partner; and </section><section prefix="b">With respect to any partnership, corporation, joint venture, or other entity, "related entity" means any officer, director, employee, partner, or owner of a financial interest of five percent (5%) or more of the total value thereof; any parent, subsidiary, or brother corporation; and any other entity with which the given entity has an identity of ownership of fifty percent (50%) or more. </section></section><section prefix="7">"Retailer" means any person with whom the corporation has contracted to sell lottery tickets to the public; </section><section prefix="8">"Security" means the protection of information that would provide an unfair advantage to any individual or other entity involved or seeking involvement in the operation of the lottery or the supply of major lottery-specific procurement items to the corporation, and the protection of: <section prefix="a">Information that relates to detection or deterrence of, or could assist in the perpetration of, crimes against the corporation or its retailers, their locations, or their employees; or </section><section prefix="b">Information which could impair or adversely impact the ability of the corporation or its retailers to protect the integrity of the lottery or protect lottery equipment, supplies, or proceeds; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Sports contest" means any professional or amateur sport, athletic game or contest, or race or contest involving machines, persons, or animals, except horses, that is viewed by the public; and </section><section prefix="10">"Vendor" means any person who has entered into a major lottery-specific procurement contract with the corporation. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 74, effective July 1, 1990. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3007</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>