<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.918</section_number><catch_line>Duties of commissioners. </catch_line><order_by>918</order_by><text>The board of commissioners shall:  <section prefix="1">Study the need for new parking facilities within the urban-county and report the results of such study to the legislative body.  </section><section prefix="2">Study the need for parking space to be provided without charge to certain classes of users within one or more districts of the urban-county and report the results of such study to the legislative body.  </section><section prefix="3">If the authority finds a need for one or more parking districts it may make a report which shall:  <section prefix="a">Describe the outside boundaries of the proposed local parking district giving due consideration to benefit rendered to each parcel or tract of real estate so included.  </section><section prefix="b">Describe the boundaries within the proposed parking district or such subdistricts as may be required to properly adjust for various degrees of benefit to each subdistrict within the local parking district.  </section><section prefix="c">Propose parking facilities or structures to be acquired or constructed and give the expected cost of such facilities.  </section><section prefix="d">Propose a plan of assessment or taxation or both to be imposed on businesses, professions, and real estate located within the proposed parking district consistent with the fiscal needs of the district.  </section></section><section prefix="4">The authority shall report the results of its study to the legislative body, describing the outside boundaries of the area to be benefited, the nature and extent of benefit, the nature and cost of the facilities proposed, and the details of the plan of assessment or taxation, or both, proposed to be imposed on businesses, professions, and real estate located within the proposed parking district. If the legislative body finds that the general plan is in the public interest, the legislative body shall set by resolution a time and place for a first public hearing on the proposal.  A notice of the time and place of the hearing, including the complete text of the report of the authority to the legislative body, shall be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424.  The hearing shall be held before the legislative body, with the mayor presiding.  </section><section prefix="5">After the public hearing the legislative body may:  <section prefix="a">By resolution determine that no local parking district is in the best interests of the urban-county government.  </section><section prefix="b">Resubmit the original study and report to the authority with directions to make specific changes.  </section><section prefix="c">Make such changes to the proposed boundaries of the district and subdistricts (if any) as may be deemed necessary and make such changes to the proposed ad valorem tax rates or occupational taxes as may be found necessary in keeping with the revenue needs of the district and the benefit expected to be derived to the various recipients. Once such changes are made, the legislative body may create by ordinance the existence of a local parking district incorporating into the ordinance any amendments.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 13, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1976</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23982</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>