<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.010</section_number><catch_line>Automated motor vehicle and trailer registration and titling -- Transportation Cabinet to develop system. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An automated motor vehicle and trailer registration and titling system shall be developed and implemented as expeditiously as practicable in all counties of the Commonwealth. The automated motor vehicle and trailer registration system shall be designed to enable Kentucky's county clerks to produce motor vehicle and trailer certificates of registration in their offices, and certificates of title in Frankfort, by automated means utilizing telecommunication terminals and associated devices supplied by the Commonwealth, to inhibit registration and transfer of stolen motor vehicles or trailers, to improve the capability of detecting and recovering such vehicles, to ensure development of a common vehicle information database to improve efficiency in auditing motor vehicle usage tax, license fee collections, and in collecting personal property tax to provide information to the traffic record system, and to provide improved security interest protection to potential creditors throughout Kentucky while simultaneously reducing the number of forms that must be processed and stored each year in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet is hereby directed to, as expeditiously as practicable, develop an automated motor vehicle and trailer registration and titling system, having, as a minimum, the capabilities or functions described in this chapter, and to acquire and assure the installation of such equipment or services as are necessary to enable the system as described in this chapter to be operated in all counties of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">All departments of state government affected by the system are hereby directed to cooperate with the Transportation Cabinet for purposes of assuring orderly implementation of this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 22. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>