<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.120</section_number><catch_line>Safety glass required in motor vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall sell any new motor vehicle in this state nor shall any new motor vehicle be registered in this state unless the vehicle is equipped with safety glass wherever glass is used in the windshield, doors or windows. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section, "safety glass" means any product composed of glass, so manufactured, fabricated, or treated as substantially to prevent shattering and flying of the glass when struck or broken, or such other or similar product as may be approved by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall compile and publish a list of types of glass by name approved by the department as meeting the requirements of this section, and shall cause a copy of the list to be furnished to each county clerk. No motor vehicle which is subject to the provisions of this section shall be registered unless it is equipped with an approved type of safety glass as required by this section, and the Department of Vehicle Regulation may prescribe and enforce such regulations as are necessary to effectuate this section. If the rules of the Interstate Commerce Commission differ the common carriers may elect to apply the rules of the Interstate Commerce Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 334, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 24. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-28a, 2739g-28b. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>