<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.1575</section_number><catch_line>Charitable community foundations -- Relationship with local governments. </catch_line><order_by>1575</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Foundation" means a charitable community foundation established to accept gifts, bequests, devises, or other transfers for the purpose of meeting charitable objectives for the citizens of the community; </section><section prefix="b">"Local government" means every city, regardless of classification, every county, and every charter county and urban-county government; </section><section prefix="c">"Component fund" means an individual fund treated as part of a foundation and that meets the requirements established under regulations promulgated implementing 26 U.S.C. sec. 170 as amended from time to time; and </section><section prefix="d">"Nonprofit organization" means an organization incorporated under KRS Chapter 273 and exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A local government may donate to a foundation the proceeds from the sale of any utility or facility or any grant, bequest, or devise received by it. </section><section prefix="b">A local government may contribute to a nonprofit organization exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code for the development and operation of a community center or recreational facilities. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the foundation receives a gift from a local government that is subject to conditions, limitations, or requirements by the donor, the gift shall be segregated in a component fund within the foundation, which shall be subject to conditions, limitations, or requirements that are substantially identical to those established by the donor. </section><section prefix="4">If the foundation receives a gift from a local government that is not subject to any specified conditions, limitations, or requirements by the donor, the gift amount shall be maintained in a component fund. The income from the fund shall be distributed to the local government for charitable purposes as directed by an ordinance of the governing body of the local government. </section><section prefix="5">If a nonprofit organization receives a gift from a local government, it shall maintain the financial records so as to be able to ascertain the use of the donated funds. </section><section prefix="6">The foundation or nonprofit organization exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code shall return any donations to the general fund of a local government if: <section prefix="a">The foundation or nonprofit organization exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code loses its status as a public charitable organization; </section><section prefix="b">The foundation or nonprofit organization exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code is liquidated; or </section><section prefix="c">The foundation or nonprofit organization exempt under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code violates any condition, limitation, or requirement as established by the local government governing body. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23348</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>