<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.710</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text>The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby finds and declares: <section prefix="1">That it is in the interest of the people of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that every precaution be taken to insure the protection of every viable unborn child being aborted, and every precaution be taken to provide life-supportive procedures to insure the unborn child its continued life after its abortion; and </section><section prefix="2">That currently, in the Commonwealth, there is inadequate legislation to protect the life, health and welfare of pregnant women and unborn human life; and </section><section prefix="3">That it is in the interest of the people of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to maintain accurate statistical data to aid in providing proper maternal health regulations. </section><section prefix="4">It is the intention of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to assure the integrity and autonomy of a woman's decision whether to submit to an abortion or to carry her child to term, to protect the rights and interests of a minor incompetent woman and her parents in the context of abortion, to further the Commonwealth's compelling interest in protecting the formal integrity of the marital relation and the procreative rights and interests of the husband, and to provide for the development of statistical data. The General Assembly finds as fact that the rights and interests furthered by this chapter are not secure in the context in which abortion is presently performed. </section><section prefix="5">It is the present intention of the General Assembly to protect the valid and compelling interests of the Commonwealth and its inhabitants without unduly burdening a woman's constitutional privacy rights as delineated by the courts. If, however, the United States Constitution is amended or relevant judicial decisions are reversed or modified, the declared policy of this Commonwealth to recognize and to protect the lives of all human beings regardless of their degree of biological development shall be fully restored. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>