<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 15A.210 to 15A.240 and KRS 15A.990. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>As used in KRS 15A.210 to 15A.240 and KRS 15A.990: <section prefix="1">"Certified juvenile facility staff" means individuals who meet the qualifications of, and who have completed a course of education and training developed and approved by, the Department of Juvenile Justice; </section><section prefix="2">"Secure juvenile detention facility" means any facility used for the secure detention of children other than a jail, police station, lockup, or any building which is a part of or attached to any facility in which adult prisoners are confined or which shares staff with a facility in which adult prisoners are confined; </section><section prefix="3">"Youth alternative center" means a nonsecure facility, approved by the Department of Juvenile Justice, for the nonsecure detention of juveniles; and </section><section prefix="4">The term "facility" or "facilities" as used in KRS 15A.210 to 15A.240 shall mean the facilities defined in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 534, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 72, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 443, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 130, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 172, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/98).  This statute has been amended by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443 (making a substantive nonrevisory change) and ch. 426 (which made a name change due to reorganization and is revisory in nature). The nonrevisory change prevails. KRS 7.136(3). .  Acts 1986, ch. 423, รยง 199 provides: "KRS 446.250 to 446.320 to the contrary notwithstanding, Acts 1986, ch. 423 shall prevail in the event of a conflict between Acts 1986, ch. 423 and other Acts passed by the 1986 Regular Session of the General Assembly." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>