<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.443</section_number><catch_line>Terms of board members -- Meetings -- Selection of administering university -- Duties of board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>443</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each nonstate-government employee member of the board of directors for the Center for School Safety shall serve a term of two (2) years and may be reappointed, but a member shall not serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="2">The members who are nonstate-government employees shall be reimbursed for travel, meals, and lodging and expenses relating to official duties of the board from funds appropriated for this purpose. </section><section prefix="3">The board of directors shall meet a minimum of four (4) times per year. The board of directors shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="4">The board of directors shall annually elect a chair and vice chair from the membership. The board may form committees as needed. </section><section prefix="5">Using a request-for-proposal process, the board of directors shall select a public university to administer the Center for School Safety for a period of not less than four (4) years unless funds for the center are not appropriated or the board determines that the university is negligent in carrying out its duties as specified in the request for proposal and contract. The initial request for proposals shall be issued not later than September 15, 1998. The board shall select a university no later than January 1, 1999. The university shall be the fiscal agent for the center and: <section prefix="a">Receive funds based on the approved budget by the board of directors and the General Assembly's appropriation for the center. The center shall operate within the fiscal policies of the university and in compliance with policies established by the board of directors per the request for proposal and contract; and </section><section prefix="b">Employ the staff of the center who shall have the retirement and employee benefits granted other similar university employees. </section></section><section prefix="6">The board of directors shall annually approve: <section prefix="a">A work plan for the center; </section><section prefix="b">A budget for the center; </section><section prefix="c">Operating policies as needed; and </section><section prefix="d">Recommendations for grants, beginning in the 1999-2000 school year and subsequent years, to local school districts and schools to assist in the development of programs and individualized approaches to work with violent, disruptive, or academically at-risk students, and consistent with provisions of KRS 158.445. </section></section><section prefix="7">The board of directors shall prepare a biennial budget request to support the Center for School Safety and to provide program funds for local school district grants. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall develop model interagency agreements between local school districts and other local public agencies, including, among others, health departments, departments of social services, mental health agencies, and courts, in order to provide cooperative services and sharing of costs for services to students who are at risk of school failure, are at risk of participation in juvenile crime, or have been expelled from the school district. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 49, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 88, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 4, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3518</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>