<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.540</section_number><catch_line>Licensee to apply for corrected license upon change of address or name -- No charge for corrected license if street name or postal address changed. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, when any person, after applying for or receiving an operator's license, moves from the address named in the application or license issued to him or when the name of a licensee is changed, by marriage or otherwise, the person shall within ten (10) days after the change apply to the circuit clerk in his county of residence for the issuance of a corrected license. </section><section prefix="2">If a license holder's street name or postal address is changed and the license holder has not moved to a new residence, the license holder shall apply to the circuit clerk for a corrected license, free of charge. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 10, effective January 1, 1995. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-68. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  In Attorney General Opinion 94-42, it was concluded that 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393, which amended this statute "will take effect on January 1, 1995, the date the National Voter Registration Act will take effect with respect to Kentucky." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6076</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>