<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.360</section_number><catch_line>Disposition of unclaimed balances of payroll deductions for war bond purchases. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Where any officer or employee of the state government or of any agency of the state government has authorized the State Treasurer to deduct from his compensation as such officer or employee a sum or sums for the purchase of United States Series E savings bonds, and thereafter, for any cause, has departed from such office or employment leaving unclaimed in the hands of the State Treasurer a sum arising from such deduction not equal to the amount for which such a bond may be purchased, the State Treasurer shall, within ninety (90) days after the date of the last deduction, mail to such officer or employee, at his last-known address as shown on the records of the Personnel Cabinet, a notice stating the sum held by the State Treasurer for such officer or employee, and requesting that he make claim for the same within six (6) months thereafter. A duplicate of such notice, addressed to the officer or employee, shall at the same time be delivered to the state agency of which the person was an officer or employee. If, at the expiration of six (6) months from the date of mailing the letter, the officer or employee has not made claim for the sum due him, the sum shall, as of July 1 following the expiration of such six-months' period, be presumed abandoned. </section><section prefix="2">On or before September 1 of each year, the State Treasurer shall report to the Department of Revenue, in duplicate, a list of the sums presumed to be abandoned as of the preceding July 1, giving the name of the officer or employee and his last-known address. The Department of Revenue shall cause the report to be posted and published as provided in KRS 393.110. If, by November 15 following such posting and publication, the sums involved have not been claimed, the State Treasurer shall place the sums to the credit of the general fund in the State Treasury and shall report that fact to the Department of Revenue. Thereafter such sums shall have the same status as other property turned over to the Department of Revenue as provided in KRS 393.110, and the rights of any person to make claim for the same shall rest upon the same principles as the rights of other claimants of property presumed to be abandoned under the provisions of KRS Chapter 393. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 47, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 61, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21925</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>