<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.022</section_number><catch_line>Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources Commission -- Definition of "sportsman". </catch_line><order_by>022</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources Commission shall consist of nine (9) members, one (1) from each wildlife district, as set out by the commissioner with the approval of the commission, and not more than five (5) of the same political party. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint the members of the commission subject to confirmation by the Senate. Each of the members shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years and may be reappointed only once. No person who has been convicted of a felony offense, in Kentucky or under the law of any other state, or any other law of the United States shall be eligible to serve on the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies through the expiration of terms of the members of the commission shall be filled by appointment by the Governor from a list of five (5) names from each wildlife district, recommended and submitted by the sportsmen of each respective district. When the term of a member expires, the commissioner shall call a meeting of the sportsmen in that district not later than thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of the member's term. Notice of the meeting shall be given by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. At the meeting, the sportsmen in attendance shall select and submit to the Governor a list of five (5) residents and citizens of the district who are well informed on the subject of wildlife conservation and restoration. Each sportsman may vote for one (1) candidate only, and the list submitted to the Governor shall be made up of the names of the five (5) candidates receiving the five (5) highest vote totals. The Governor shall appoint a successor to the member whose term is about to expire within sixty (60) days following the submission to him of the list referred to in this subsection, and in no event later than August 13. </section><section prefix="4">Upon appointment to the commission of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, each commissioner shall execute a bond of one thousand dollars ($1,000) in favor of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, the premium on this bond to be paid out of department funds. </section><section prefix="5">In the event of vacancies other than by expiration, the Governor shall fill the vacancy for the unexpired part of the term from the names remaining on the list previously submitted for the district from which the vacancy arose. </section><section prefix="6">Each member of the commission shall take the constitutional oath of office. </section><section prefix="7">The Governor shall remove any member of the commission for cause under subsection (2) of this section and may remove any member of the commission for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or misconduct in office; but shall first deliver to the member a copy of all charges in writing and afford to him an opportunity of being publicly heard in person or by counsel in defense of the charges, upon not less than ten (10) days' notice. If a member shall be removed, the Governor shall file in the office of the Secretary of State a complete statement of all charges made against the member and his findings thereon, together with a complete record of the proceedings. </section><section prefix="8">Each member of the commission shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary traveling and other expenses incurred by him in the discharge of his official duties and to be paid from the game and fish fund. </section><section prefix="9">A majority of the commission shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any business, for the performance of any duty or for the exercise of any power vested in the commission. </section><section prefix="10">The department shall have its principal office in Franklin County, and is authorized to purchase all supplies, equipment, and printed forms and to issue any notices and publications as the commissioner may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="11">The word "sportsman" as used in this section shall mean a resident hunter or fisherman who has been licensed in Kentucky for each of the past two (2) consecutive years. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 143 -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 2 -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 4 -- Created 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1931</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>