<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.857</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Industrial Hemp Commission -- Membership.   </catch_line><order_by>857</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Industrial Hemp Commission is created and is attached to the University of Kentucky Agricultural Experiment Station for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the commission shall consist of at least the following members: <section prefix="a">The Commissioner of the Department of Agriculture or the Commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police or the commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="c">The executive director of the Governor's Office of Agricultural Policy or the executive director's designee; </section><section prefix="d">The dean of the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture or the dean's designee; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member representing each of the following institutions choosing to participate in the commission: <section prefix="1">Eastern Kentucky University; </section><section prefix="2">Kentucky State University; </section><section prefix="3">Morehead State University; </section><section prefix="4">Murray State University; </section><section prefix="5">Northern Kentucky University; </section><section prefix="6">University of Louisville; and </section><section prefix="7">Western Kentucky University; </section></section><section prefix="f">The president of the Kentucky Hemp Growers Cooperative Association; </section><section prefix="g">The president of the Kentucky Sheriffs' Association or the association president's designee; </section><section prefix="h">The president of the Kentucky Association of Chiefs of Police or the association president's designee; </section><section prefix="i">Six (6) members, three (3) appointed by the Speaker of the House and three </section></section><section prefix="3">by the President of the Senate, representing the following interests: </section>1. Kentucky farmers with an interest in growing industrial hemp; 2. Retailers of industrial hemp products; 3. Wholesalers of industrial hemp products; and 4. Manufacturers of industrial hemp products; and (j) Two (2) at-large members on a recommendation of the chair and approved by a majority of the members of the commission. (3) (a) Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, members appointed pursuant to subsection (2)(i) and (j) of this section shall serve a term of four <section prefix="4">years, and may be reappointed. </section>(b) The term of office of each member appointed pursuant to subsection (2)(i) and (j) of this section, who is serving on the commission on June 25, 2013, shall expire on December 31, 2013. Upon the expiration of a member's term of office pursuant to this paragraph, that position shall be filled by appointment as provided in this section. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 278, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43439</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>