<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-170</section_number><catch_line>Calculation of reserves.   </catch_line><order_by>6-170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Reserves for any category of policies, contracts, or benefits as established by the commissioner, which are subject to subsection (2) of KRS 304.6-140, may be calculated, at the option of the insurer, according to any standards which produce greater aggregate reserves for such category than those calculated according to the minimum standard herein provided, but the rate or rates of interest used for policies and contracts, other than annuity and pure endowment contracts, shall not be greater than the corresponding rate or rates of interest used in calculating any nonforfeiture benefits provided for therein. </section><section prefix="2">Any such company which at any time shall have adopted any standard of valuation producing greater aggregate reserves than those calculated according to the minimum standard herein provided may, with the approval of the commissioner, adopt any lower standard of valuation, but not lower than the minimum required by this subtitle, except that for the purposes of this section, the holding of additional reserves previously determined by the appointed actuary to be necessary to render the opinion requested by KRS 304.6-171 shall not be deemed to be the adoption of a higher standard of valuation. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1005, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 6, sec. 17, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44437</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>