<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture. </section><section prefix="2">"Concentrated commercial feeding stuff" includes linseed meals, corn and corncob meals, cocoanut meals, gluten feeds, gluten meals, germ feeds, corn feeds, starch feeds, sugar feeds, dried brewers' grains, malt sprouts, dried distillers' grains, dried beet refuse, hominy feeds, cerealine feeds, rice meals, rice bran, rice polish, peanut meals, oat feeds, corn and oat feeds, corn bran, wheat bran, wheat midlings, wheat shorts and other mill products, ground beef, fish scraps, mixed feeds, clover meal, alfalfa meal and feeds, pea-vine meal, cottonseed meal, velvet bean meal, feeds and meals mixed or unmixed, made from seeds or grains, and all materials of similar nature used for food for domestic animals, condimental feeds, poultry feeds, stock feeds, patented proprietary or trade and market stock, and poultry feeds. </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department of Agriculture. </section><section prefix="4">"Director" means the director of the Agricultural Experiment Station or his designee. </section><section prefix="5">"Experiment station" means the Agricultural Experiment Station. </section><section prefix="6">"Weed seeds" means all seeds that are not agricultural, vegetable, or flower seeds. It includes noxious weed seeds. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 11, effective April 8, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 42h-1, 1376b-14. 1376b-15, 1719a-2. </history><metadata><effective> April 8, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>