<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-274</section_number><catch_line>Legislative intent -- Requirement that cabinet support modernization, increase, and improvement in the Commonwealth's production process -- Cabinet to contract with Kentucky Manufacturing Assistance Center. </catch_line><order_by>12-274</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "cluster" shall have the same meaning as in KRS 164.6011. </section><section prefix="2">It is the intention of the General Assembly to recognize that a strong manufacturing base for the economy of the Commonwealth requires not only modernization of the production process but also an increase in the number of products developed, so that through the creation of new product lines, additional value-added products, and new manufacturing methods the economy will grow and quality job opportunities will increase. The Cabinet for Economic Development shall support this intention through its authority in KRS 154.12-050. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Economic Development shall enter into contracts or agreements with the Kentucky Manufacturing Assistance Center, a nonprofit organization with the mission to assist Kentucky small and medium-size manufacturers to become more competitive in the global marketplace. The contracts or agreements shall require the Kentucky Manufacturing Assistance Center to undertake the following activities: <section prefix="a">Negotiate contractual agreements with existing manufacturers to deliver modernization services that are likely to lead to the creation of new product lines, additional value-added products, and new manufacturing methods; </section><section prefix="b">Deliver engineering, technical, and business improvement services in Kentucky manufacturing facilities, through the network of Kentucky Technology Service locations in the state, that lead to the development of new product lines, additional value-added products, and new manufacturing methods; </section><section prefix="c">Coordinate services for and support the activities of Kentucky manufacturers that need additional projects, activities, and expertise beyond those available through the Kentucky Manufacturing Assistance Center; </section><section prefix="d">Promote, along with other economic development entities, the development of supplier chains, the linkages among suppliers, and the growth of clusters within the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="e">Provide to the Cabinet for Economic Development and Kentucky Innovation Commission a report of the advances made in the manufacturing modernization projects initiated. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 19, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>