<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="80" order_by="80">LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>80.290</section_number><catch_line>Manners in which public body may aid authority. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of aiding and cooperating in the planning, undertaking, construction or operation of housing projects located within the area in which it is authorized to act, any public body may, upon such terms, with or without consideration, as it may determine:  <section prefix="a">Dedicate, sell, convey or lease any of its interest in any property, or grant easements, licenses or any other rights or privileges therein to a housing authority or the federal government;  </section><section prefix="b">Cause parks, playgrounds, recreational, community, educational, water, sewer or drainage facilities, or any other works which it is otherwise empowered to undertake, to be furnished adjacent to or in connection with housing projects;  </section><section prefix="c">Furnish, dedicate, close, pave, install, grade, regrade, plan or replan public ways or other places which it is otherwise empowered to undertake;  </section><section prefix="d">Plan or replan, zone or rezone any part of the public body; make exceptions from building regulations and ordinances; any city also may change its map;  </section><section prefix="e">Cause services to be furnished to the housing authority of the character which the public body is otherwise empowered to furnish;  </section><section prefix="f">Enter into agreements with respect to the exercise by such public body of its powers relating to the repair, closing or demolition of unsafe, unsanitary or unfit dwellings;  </section><section prefix="g">Employ any funds belonging to or within the control of such public body, including funds derived from the sale or furnishing of property or facilities to a housing authority, in the purchase of the bonds or other obligations of a housing authority; and exercise all the rights of any holder of such bonds or other obligations;  </section><section prefix="h">Do any and all things necessary or convenient to aid and cooperate in the planning, undertaking, construction or operation of housing;  </section><section prefix="i">Incur the entire expense of any public improvements made by such public body in exercising the powers granted in this section; and  </section><section prefix="j">Enter into agreements, which may extend over any period, with a housing authority respecting action to be taken by such public body pursuant to any of the powers granted by this section.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Any sale, conveyance, lease or agreement provided for in this section may be made by a public body without appraisal, public notice, advertisement or public bidding.  </section><section prefix="3">With respect to any housing which a housing authority has acquired or taken over from the federal government and which the housing authority by resolution has found and declared to have been constructed in a manner that will promote the public interest and afford necessary safety, sanitation and other protection, no public body shall require any changes to be made in the housing project or the manner of its construction or take any other action relating to the construction. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2741x-19. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24844</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>