<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.690</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement by Attorney General or county attorney -- Civil penalty. </catch_line><order_by>690</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Attorney General or county attorney may enforce the provisions of KRS 365.650 to 365.695 by civil action for injunctive relief in the Circuit Court of his county. In the action to obtain the injunction, it shall be sufficient to allege and prove that a violation of KRS 365.650 to 365.695 has occurred or is about to occur, and it shall not be necessary to allege or prove that any person has been damaged or sustained any loss as a result of any violation of KRS 365.650 to 365.695. </section><section prefix="2">When the provisions of KRS 365.650 to 365.695 are enforced through civil action, the Attorney General or county attorney may ask for and the court may assess a civil penalty for the benefit of the Commonwealth, not to exceed the sum of two thousand dollars ($2,000). The penalty shall be in lieu of all penalties set forth in KRS 365.990(8). </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 365.650 to 365.695 shall be construed to limit or restrict the exercise of powers or the performance of duties the Attorney General is authorized to exercise or perform under any provision of law. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34839</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>