<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9523</section_number><catch_line>Abolition of category of nonemergency health transportation provider -- Conversion to disabled persons carrier or Class II ground ambulance provider. </catch_line><order_by>9523</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The category of nonemergency health transportation provider shall be abolished effective December 31, 1996. </section><section prefix="2">A provider licensed as of March 31, 1996, as a nonemergency health transportation provider may apply to convert to either a disabled persons carrier pursuant to KRS 281.6185 or a Class II ground ambulance provider without requiring an additional certificate of need. Prior to licensure or certificate approval, the provider shall meet the respective licensing or certificate requirements. </section><section prefix="3">No later than August 15, 1996, the Cabinet for Human Resources shall notify each nonemergency health transportation provider of the provisions of this section and the procedures necessary to apply for the conversion. </section><section prefix="4">To apply for the conversion provided for in subsection (2) of this section, each nonemergency health transportation provider shall notify the appropriate agency of its intentions within ninety (90) days of July 15, 1996, or cease to act as a nonemergency health transportation provider effective December 31, 1996. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8537</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>