<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.7685</section_number><catch_line>Credit report from consumer reporting agency. </catch_line><order_by>7685</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall request information from a certified consumer reporting agency only when a full credit report is needed for the purpose of establishing an individual's capacity to make child support payments or to determine the obligation amount, and paternity has been established or acknowledged. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall provide at least ten (10) days' prior notice by certified mail to the obligor whose report shall be requested from a certified consumer reporting agency and inform the obligor of the methods available to contest the accuracy of the information in compliance with due process of law, and 15 U.S.C. sec. 1681(i). <section prefix="a">The report will be kept confidential and be used solely for the purpose of establishing an individual's capacity to make child support payments or determining the appropriate level of the payments; and </section><section prefix="b">The report will not be used in connection with any other civil, administrative, or criminal proceeding or for any other purpose. </section></section><section prefix="3">Methods by which an obligor may contest the accuracy of the information shall be set forth by administrative regulations promulgated by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7825</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>