<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-460</section_number><catch_line>Duties of examiners. </catch_line><order_by>3-460</order_by><text>In examinations under KRS 286.3-450 the examining officer shall investigate: <section prefix="1">The cash, bills, collateral, securities, other assets, books of account, and all other papers and books of the bank or trust company; </section><section prefix="2">The condition and resources of the bank, the mode of conducting and managing its affairs, the actions of its directors, the investment and disposition of its funds, the safety and prudence of its management and the security afforded to those by whom its engagements are held; </section><section prefix="3">Whether the requirements of its charter and of the laws of this state have been complied with in the administration of its affairs; and </section><section prefix="4">Such other matters as the commissioner deems necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 640, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 165a-8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.460. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>