<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-138</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against health benefit plan excluding coverage for telehealth -- Benefits subject to deductible, co-payment, or coinsurance -- Payment subject to provider network arrangements -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>17A-138</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A health benefit plan shall not exclude a service from coverage solely because the service is provided through telehealth and not provided through a face-to-face consultation if the consultation is provided through the telehealth network established under KRS 194A.125. A health benefit plan may provide coverage for a consultation at a site not within the telehealth network at the discretion of the insurer. </section><section prefix="b">A telehealth consultation shall not be reimbursable under this section if it is provided through the use of an audio-only telephone, facsimile machine, or electronic mail. </section></section><section prefix="2">Benefits for a service provided through telehealth required by this section may be made subject to a deductible, copayment, or coinsurance requirement. A deductible, copayment, or coinsurance applicable to a particular service provided through telehealth shall not exceed the deductible, copayment, or coinsurance required by the health benefit plan for the same service provided through a face-to-face consultation. </section><section prefix="3">Payment made under this section may be consistent with any provider network arrangements that have been established for the health benefit plan. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall promulgate an administrative regulation in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to designate the claim forms and records required to be maintained in conjunction with this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1215, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 28, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17373</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>