<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The definitions in KRS Chapter 600 shall apply to this chapter. In addition, as used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Case permanency plan" means a document identifying decisions made by the cabinet, for both the biological family and the child, concerning action which needs to be taken to assure that the child in foster care expeditiously obtains a permanent home; </section><section prefix="2">"Case progress report" means a written record of goals that have been achieved in the case of a child; </section><section prefix="3">"Case record" means a cabinet file of specific documents and a running record of activities pertaining to the child; </section><section prefix="4">"Children's advocacy center" means an agency that advocates on behalf of children alleged to have been abused; that assists in the coordination of the investigation of child abuse by providing a location for forensic interviews and medical examinations, and by promoting the coordination of services for children alleged to have been abused; and that provides, directly or by formalized agreements, services that include, but are not limited to, forensic interviews, medical examinations, mental health and related support services, court advocacy, consultation, training, and staffing of multidisciplinary teams; </section><section prefix="5">"Foster care" means the provision of temporary twenty-four (24) hour care for a child for a planned period of time when the child is: <section prefix="a">Removed from his parents or person exercising custodial control or supervision and subsequently placed in the custody of the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="b">Placed in a foster home or private child-caring facility or child-placing agency but remains under the supervision of the cabinet; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Local citizen foster care review board" means a citizen board which provides periodic permanency reviews of children placed in the custody of the cabinet by a court order of temporary custody or commitment under this chapter; </section><section prefix="7">"Multidisciplinary teams" means local teams operating under protocols governing roles, responsibilities, and procedures developed by the Kentucky Multidisciplinary Commission on Child Sexual Abuse pursuant to KRS 431.600; </section><section prefix="8">"Pediatric abusive head trauma" means the various injuries or conditions that may result following the vigorous shaking, slamming, or impacting the head of an infant or young child. These injuries or conditions, also known as pediatric acquired abusive head trauma, have in the past been called "Shaken Baby Syndrome" or "Shaken Infant Syndrome." Pediatric abusive head trauma injuries or conditions have included but are not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Irreversible brain damage; </section><section prefix="b">Blindness; </section><section prefix="c">Retinal hemorrhage; </section><section prefix="d">Eye damage; </section><section prefix="e">Cerebral palsy; </section><section prefix="f">Hearing loss; </section><section prefix="g">Spinal cord injury; </section><section prefix="h">Paralysis; </section><section prefix="i">Seizures; </section><section prefix="j">Learning disability; </section><section prefix="k">Death; </section><section prefix="l">Central nervous system injury as evidenced by central nervous system hemorrhaging; </section><section prefix="m">Closed head injury; </section><section prefix="n">Rib fracture; and </section><section prefix="o">Subdural hematoma; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Permanence" means a relationship between a child and an adult which is intended to last a lifetime, providing commitment and continuity in the child's relationships and a sense of belonging; </section><section prefix="10">"Preventive services" means those services which are designed to help maintain and strengthen the family unit by preventing or eliminating the need for removal of children from the family; </section><section prefix="11">"Reasonable efforts" means the exercise of ordinary diligence and care by the department to utilize all preventive and reunification services available to the community in accordance with the state plan for Public Law 96-272 which are necessary to enable the child to safely live at home; </section><section prefix="12">"Reunification services" means remedial and preventive services which are designed to strengthen the family unit, to secure reunification of the family and child where appropriate, as quickly as practicable, and to prevent the future removal of the child from the family; and </section><section prefix="13">"State citizen foster care review board" means a board created by KRS 620.310. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 301, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 258, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 350, sec. 41, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 63, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20184</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>