<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">C STATE AID TO LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39C.060</section_number><catch_line>Request for financial aid -- Review and evaluation criteria. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Local emergency management agencies requesting financial aid from the fund created pursuant to KRS 39C.010 and 39C.020, shall submit, not later than July 15 of each year, a local "Annual Program Paper" application to the area manager of the division. </section><section prefix="2">The area manager shall review the application and accompanying documents and forward them to the director of the division along with the area manager's assessments and recommendations, not later than August 15 of each year. </section><section prefix="3">The director shall submit the request for financial aid to the advisory committee for its review and recommendations. The advisory committee shall review the application, accompanying documents, and the assessment and recommendation of the area manager and make a recommendation to the director with regard to the application and the request for funding. </section><section prefix="4">Requests for funding shall be evaluated by the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Meeting the eligibility criteria specified in KRS 39C.050, unless some aspect thereof has been waived as provided in KRS 39C.090. </section><section prefix="b">Meeting all the requirements specified by the division for developing, preparing, maintaining, and submitting the annual program paper. </section><section prefix="c">Local emergency operations plans submitted and a determination of their conformity to the Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan, and an assessment of their capability, state of currency, sign of official adoption, and general adequacy to provide for the coordination of disaster and emergency response operations. </section><section prefix="d">Past program performance of the local director in fully carrying out the duties of local director as specified in KRS 39B.030, and overall program performance as it relates to completeness, adequacy, and timeliness in accomplishing program tasks, objectives, or goals. </section><section prefix="e">Historical spending records for this and similar programs. </section><section prefix="f">Local resources committed to the program on a per capita basis. </section></section><section prefix="5">If available funds do not meet the total funds requested by all local emergency management agencies, then funding allocations may be reduced after a reevaluation of the criteria set forth in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The director of the Division of Emergency Management shall then review and evaluate each application, together with the recommendations thereon, and not later than September 15 of each year, designate and approve funds for eligible local emergency management agencies and notify the local director. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>