<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.515</section_number><catch_line>Registration fee -- Display of registration receipt -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon registration, every solicitor shall pay the county clerk a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012, and the county clerk shall issue the solicitor a numbered receipt to be effective for a period of one (1) year from the date of registration. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to actual solicitation, the solicitor shall display to the potential purchaser the registration receipt issued by the county clerk if soliciting in person or cite to the potential purchaser the number of the registration receipt if soliciting by telephone. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of KRS 367.513 to 367.530 shall not apply to minors soliciting orders for articles mentioned in KRS 367.510 when such sales are made for the sole purpose of obtaining funds for a school band, club or other organization and such sales are approved in writing by the superintendent of the school system at which the minors are students. The written approval of the superintendent shall identify the product or products being sold, the solicitors to be involved and the duration of sales and shall be filed with the county clerk. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 31, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 499, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>