<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-611</section_number><catch_line>Notification before disposition of collateral. </catch_line><order_by>9-611</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "notification date" means the earlier of the date on which: <section prefix="a">A secured party sends to the debtor and any secondary obligor an authenticated notification of disposition; or </section><section prefix="b">The debtor and any secondary obligor waive the right to notification. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, a secured party that disposes of collateral under KRS 355.9-610 shall send to the persons specified in subsection (3) of this section a reasonable authenticated notification of disposition. </section><section prefix="3">To comply with subsection (2) of this section, the secured party shall send an authenticated notification of disposition to: <section prefix="a">The debtor; </section><section prefix="b">Any secondary obligor; and </section><section prefix="c">If the collateral is other than consumer goods: <section prefix="1">Any other person from which the secured party has received, before the notification date, an authenticated notification of a claim of an interest in the collateral; </section><section prefix="2">Any other secured party or lienholder that, ten (10) days before the notification date, held a security interest in or other lien on the collateral perfected by the filing of a financing statement that: <section prefix="a">Identified the collateral; </section><section prefix="b">Was indexed under the debtor’s name as of that date; and </section><section prefix="c">Was filed in the office in which to file a financing statement against the debtor covering the collateral as of that date; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Any other secured party that, ten (10) days before the notification date, held a security interest in the collateral perfected by compliance with a statute, regulation, or treaty described in KRS 355.9-311(1). </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Subsection (2) of this section does not apply if the collateral is perishable or threatens to decline speedily in value or is of a type customarily sold on a recognized market. </section><section prefix="5">A secured party complies with the requirement for notification prescribed by subsection (3)(c)2. of this section if: <section prefix="a">Not later than twenty (20) days or earlier than thirty (30) days before the notification date, the secured party requests, in a commercially reasonable manner, information concerning financing statements indexed under the debtor’s name in the office indicated in subsection (3)(c)2. of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">Before the notification date, the secured party: <section prefix="1">Did not receive a response to the request for information; or </section><section prefix="2">Received a response to the request for information and sent an authenticated notification of disposition to each secured party or other lienholder named in that response whose financing statement covered the collateral. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 129, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33843</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>