<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.315</section_number><catch_line>.   Possession of manufacturer's identification number plates prohibited -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>315</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall have in his possession a manufacturer's vehicle identification number plate unless it is attached to the vehicle, or vehicle part, to which it was originally affixed by the manufacturer, nor shall any person have any facsimile of such a plate. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not prohibit possession of legitimate plates by persons: <section prefix="a">Whose possession is incident to a contract to supply them to a manufacturer of new motor vehicles, or when such plates are in the possession of a manufacturer of new vehicles, or such manufacturer's employee, who possesses them within the scope of his work when his work involved the manufacture or storage of such plates, for legitimate placement upon newly manufactured vehicles, legitimate affixing of such plates upon newly manufactured vehicles, or legitimate affixing of a replacement plate. </section><section prefix="b">Who possess such plate immediately incident to transferring it from being legitimately attached to a wrecked part or portion of a vehicle to a replacement part or portion for installation on, or installed on, the same vehicle on which the plate was originally placed by the manufacturer, when such possession and transfer is authorized in writing by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="c">Who are authorized in writing, by the commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation under the provisions of KRS 186.1911 to possess such plates. </section></section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6200</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>