<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.330</section_number><catch_line>Seizure and forfeiture of illegal drug shipments. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any drug which is ordered or shipped in violation of any provision of this chapter or KRS Chapter 218A shall be considered as contraband and may be seized by any peace officer or any employee of the Board of Pharmacy designated to enforce the provisions of this chapter or KRS Chapter 218A. </section><section prefix="2">The officer, prior to seizing the drug, shall make a reasonable effort to determine: <section prefix="a">The person who ordered the drug; </section><section prefix="b">The pharmacy from which the drug was ordered; </section><section prefix="c">The shipper of the drug; </section><section prefix="d">The intended recipient of the drug; and </section><section prefix="e">Whether or not the shipment was legal. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless the matter is the subject of a criminal prosecution, if, after thirty (30) days of investigation, the officer seizing the drug cannot adequately determine the information required by subsection (2) of this section, the drug that has been seized shall be considered as abandoned and escheat to the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">If a drug seized pursuant to this section is the subject of a criminal investigation, the drug shall be retained as evidence and, if there is a conviction of any person or pharmacy relating to the ordering or shipment of the drug, the drug shall be forfeited to the Commonwealth. If the defendant is found not guilty or the charges are dismissed with prejudice, the drug shall be returned to the defendant. </section><section prefix="5">Drugs which have been seized and which have been forfeited or abandoned and escheat to the Commonwealth shall be destroyed. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 17, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31041</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>