<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.11-032</section_number><catch_line>Definition -- Commissioner's power to order submission of required filings to the registry, its parent or affiliate, and other agencies or authorities -- Power to establish relationships or contracts with governmental agencies and the registry or its affiliates -- Report of violations, enforcement actions, and other relevant information -- Procedure for requesting information from and distributing information to the United States Department of Justice.   </catch_line><order_by>11-032</order_by><text> (1) As used in this section, "registry" means the State Regulatory Registry, LLC, or its successor organization. (2) When an application, report, or approval request is required by this subtitle to be filed with the commissioner, the commissioner may by rule or order require the filing of the application, report, or approval request, including the applicable fees, be submitted to: (a) The State Regulatory Registry, LLC, or its successor organization; (b) The registry's parent, affiliate, or operating subsidiary; or (c) Other agencies or authorities, as part of a nationwide licensing system; which may act as an agent for receiving, requesting, and distributing information to and from any source directed by the commissioner. (3) (a) The commissioner is authorized to establish relationships or contracts with other governmental agencies, the registry, or entities affiliated with the registry that he or she deems necessary to carry out the purpose of this section. (b) The commissioner may report violations of this subtitle, enforcement actions, and other relevant information to governmental agencies, the registry, or affiliated entities with which the commissioner has established a relationship or contract, notwithstanding any provision to the contrary in this subtitle. (4) For purposes of this section and to reduce the points of contact which the Federal Bureau of Investigation may have to maintain for purposes of this subtitle, the commissioner may use other governmental agencies, the registry, or entities affiliated with the registry, as an agent for requesting information from and distributing information to the United States Department of Justice or other governmental agencies. </text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42388</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>