<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.505</section_number><catch_line>Court-appointed special advocate program -- Local board of directors -- Program director -- CASA volunteers. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of providing an independent, efficient, and thorough representation for children who enter the court system as a result of dependency, abuse, or neglect, there may be established a court-appointed special advocate program by the chief judge of family court or, if none, then by the Chief District Judge. </section><section prefix="2">Local CASA programs shall be governed by a local board of directors. For new CASA programs, the board shall initially be appointed by the chief judge of family court or, if none, then by the Chief District Judge. Members shall be selected by the existing board members thereafter. Each board shall include at least fifteen (15) members. Each board member shall have a demonstrated interest in child welfare issues and commitment to the purpose and role of the court-appointed special advocate volunteers. Cabinet employees shall not be eligible to serve as officers of the board. Members shall, as far as practicable, be representative of the racial and ethnic composition of the area served by the CASA program. The board shall: <section prefix="a">Determine major personnel, organization, fiscal, and program policies including, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Measures to be taken to safeguard the CASA program's information relating to children, their families, and the CASA volunteers; </section><section prefix="2">The procedures for the recruitment, screening, training, and supervision of CASA volunteers; and </section><section prefix="3">The procedure for and circumstances warranting dismissal of a CASA volunteer from the CASA program; </section></section><section prefix="b">Determine overall plans and priorities for the CASA program, including provisions for evaluating progress against performance; </section><section prefix="c">Approve the program budget; </section><section prefix="d">Enforce compliance with all conditions of all grants contracts; </section><section prefix="e">Determine rules and procedures for the governing board; </section><section prefix="f">Select the officers and the executive committee, if any, of the governing board; </section><section prefix="g">Meet at least four (4) times each year; </section><section prefix="h">Submit an annual report to the association in the uniform manner required which shall include, but need not be limited to, the following information: <section prefix="1">Number of CASA volunteers in the program; </section><section prefix="2">Number of program staff; </section><section prefix="3">Number of children served; </section><section prefix="4">Number of volunteers receiving initial training; </section><section prefix="5">Number of and topics for in-service training; </section><section prefix="6">The type of source of the funds received and the amount received from each type of source during the previous fiscal year; </section><section prefix="7">The expenditures during the previous year; and </section><section prefix="8">Other information as deemed appropriate. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Local CASA programs shall comply with the National CASA Association and Kentucky CASA Association Standards for Programs. Local programs shall ensure that CASA volunteers are adequately supervised by providing at least one (1) supervisory staff person for every thirty (30) CASA volunteers that have been appointed by the court and assigned by the program director. Each local CASA program shall be managed by a qualified director whose service may be voluntary or who may be paid a salary. The program director's duties shall include: <section prefix="a">Administration of the CASA program as directed by the local and state boards; </section><section prefix="b">Recruitment, screening, training, and supervision of CASA volunteers and other program staff; </section><section prefix="c">Facilitation of the performance of the court-appointed special advocates' duties; and </section><section prefix="d">Ensuring that the security measures established by the local and state boards for safeguarding the information relating to children, their families, and the CASA volunteers are maintained. </section></section><section prefix="4">CASA volunteers shall, as far as practicable, be representative of the socioeconomic, racial, and ethnic composition of the area served. </section><section prefix="5">CASA volunteers may be removed by the court for nonparticipation or other cause or by the program director pursuant to subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">All written court-appointed special advocate reports submitted pursuant to KRS 620.525 shall become part of the cabinet's record of the child. </section><section prefix="7">Employees of the cabinet shall not become volunteers or employees of the court-appointed special advocate program. </section><section prefix="8">Each CASA volunteer, program director, and other program staff shall take an oath, administered by a member of the Court of Justice, to keep confidential all information related to the appointed case except in conferring with or reports to the court, parties to the case, the cabinet, the Citizen Foster Care Review Board, others designated by the court, and as provided by law. </section><section prefix="9">CASA volunteers shall be appointed by the presiding judge to represent the best interest of the child, subject to judicial discretion, and only after confirmation from the program director that the CASA volunteer has been properly screened and trained. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20228</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>