<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159">COMPULSORY ATTENDANCE </unit></structure><section_number>159.250</section_number><catch_line>Nature of census. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>The director of pupil personnel of each school district, working under the direction of the superintendent of schools, shall institute and maintain a complete, accurate, permanent, and continuous census of all children between the ages of five (5) and twenty-one (21) enrolled in the public schools in the district. A child's age is between five (5) and twenty-one (21)  when the child has reached his fifth birthday and has not passed the twenty-first birthday. The school census shall specify the name, date of birth, and sex of each child; the name, nationality, and post-office address of each parent, guardian, or custodian of the child; the school district in which the child resides; and the school in which the child is enrolled. The school shall be described by number and name. The census shall contain any other data required by the chief state school officer. Each board of education shall furnish its director of pupil personnel with assistance it deems necessary for the institution and maintenance of the census. </text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 222, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4434-25, 4434-26. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>