<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.32-050</section_number><catch_line>Enhanced incentive counties -- Annual identification and certification or decertification -- Criteria -- Multicounty industrial park projects. </catch_line><order_by>32-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall identify and certify or decertify enhanced incentive counties on an annual basis as provided in this section. </section><section prefix="2">Each fiscal year, the authority shall: <section prefix="a">Obtain from the Office of Employment and Training within the Department of Workforce Investment in the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, the final unemployment figures for the prior calendar year for each county and for the Commonwealth as a whole; </section><section prefix="b">Identify those counties which have had: <section prefix="1">A countywide unemployment rate that exceeds the statewide unemployment rate in the most recent five (5) consecutive calendar years; or </section><section prefix="2">An average countywide rate of unemployment exceeding the statewide unemployment rate by two hundred percent (200%) in the most recent calendar year; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Certify the counties identified in paragraph (b) of this subsection as enhanced incentive counties. </section></section><section prefix="3">A county not certified under subsection (2) of this section may also be certified by the authority as an enhanced incentive county if the authority determines the county is one (1) of the sixty (60) most distressed counties in the Commonwealth based on the following criteria with equal weight given to each criterion: <section prefix="a">The average countywide rate of unemployment in the most recent three (3) consecutive calendar years, using the information obtained under subsection (2)(a) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">The percentage of adults twenty-five (25) years of age and older who have attained at least a high school education or equivalent, on the basis of the most recent data available from the United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census; and </section><section prefix="c">The quality of the roads in the county. Quality of roads shall be determined by the access within a county to roads, ranked in descending order from best quality to worst quality, as certified to the authority by the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) or more interstate highways; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) interstate highway; </section><section prefix="3">A state four (4) lane parkway; </section><section prefix="4">A four (4) lane principal arterial access to an interstate highway; </section><section prefix="5">A state two (2) lane parkway; and </section><section prefix="6">None of the preceding road types. </section></section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">If the authority determines that an enhanced incentive county no longer meets the criteria to be certified as an enhanced incentive county under this section, the authority shall decertify that county. </section><section prefix="b">Any economic development project located in an enhanced incentive county that was decertified by the authority after May 1, 2009, shall have until July 1 of the third year following the fiscal year in which the county was decertified to obtain final approval from the authority. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">As used in this subsection, "industrial park" means a regional industrial park as defined in KRS 42.4588, or an industrial park created pursuant to an interlocal agreement in which revenues are shared as provided in KRS 65.245. </section><section prefix="b">An economic development project undertaken in an industrial park that is located in two (2) or more counties, one (1) of which is an enhanced incentive county, may be approved for the enhanced incentive county incentives set forth in this subchapter. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 13, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2860</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>