<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="165" order_by="165">A PROPRIETARY EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>165A.510</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text>The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A governing the following: <section prefix="1">Standards for CDL driver training school office facilities, branch office facilities, classroom facilities, and off-the-road testing facilities; </section><section prefix="2">Conflict of interest by persons associated with a CDL driver training school; </section><section prefix="3">Requirements for the testing and licensing of CDL driver training instructors, including qualifications for classroom instructors and off-the-road and on-the-road instructors; </section><section prefix="4">Maintenance and inspection of student instruction records, including documentation verifying the minimum course hours required under KRS 332.095 have been completed before the student is issued a release from the CDL driver training school; </section><section prefix="5">A schedule of fees or all charges made by the school, including but not limited to administrative fees, registration fees, fees for classroom instruction, and fees for off-the-road and on-the-road training; </section><section prefix="6">Contracts and agreements involving CDL driver training schools; </section><section prefix="7">Advertising and solicitation of students by CDL driver training schools; </section><section prefix="8">Inspections of commercial motor vehicles used by CDL driver training schools, including mandatory equipment and out-of-service criteria; </section><section prefix="9">Insurance requirements for commercial motor vehicles used by CDL driver training schools; and </section><section prefix="10">Procedures for the suspension, revocation, nonrenewal, and denial of an application for licensure as a CDL driver training school or licensure as a CDL driver training instructor. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 13, effective April 9, 2002. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(2). -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification>KRS 332.100. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40333</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>