<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.650</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner to determine date, hours, polling places for voting and details of assessment -- Limits -- Exceptions.   </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With respect to any referendum conducted under the provisions of KRS 247.610 to 247.685, the Commissioner of Agriculture shall, before calling and announcing the referendum, fix, determine, and publicly announce at least thirty (30) days before the date determined for the referendum, the date, hours, and polling places for voting in the referendum, the effective date of the assessment, if adopted, the amount and basis of the assessment proposed to be collected, the means by which the assessment shall be collected if authorized by the producers, and the general purposes to which the amount collected shall be applied. No assessment levied under the provisions of any single referendum shall exceed one dollar ($1) on each bovine animal marketed in the state by any producer included in the group to which the referendum was submitted or by any person subsequently becoming a new producer in the area in which the referendum was held. </section><section prefix="2">No assessment shall be made on any bovine animal marketed in the state which sells for ten dollars ($10) or less. </section><section prefix="3">Any assessment levied after June 25, 2013, shall be in addition to the federal assessment referenced in KRS 247.652. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42594</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>