<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.735</section_number><catch_line>Overcrowding of passenger vehicles -- Maximum width.   </catch_line><order_by>735</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall, in its safety regulations, prescribe rules prohibiting overcrowding in the various types of motor vehicles carrying passengers for hire. </section><section prefix="2">The owner or driver of any motor vehicle for the transportation of passengers shall not permit any passengers to ride upon the steps or running-board of any such motor vehicle, nor shall he permit any passenger to ride on the top of any such motor vehicle unless the top has been designed and equipped with seats constructed for such use and provided with protecting railing or protective enclosure on all four (4) sides of the top of the vehicle, and unless such use has been authorized by a certificate issued by the department. </section><section prefix="3">No motor carrier shall operate a motor vehicle for the transportation of persons for hire, except buses, with an extreme width exceeding ninety-six (96) inches, except upon such highways which are a part of the state-maintained system upon which increased widths have been authorized by order of the commissioner of highways as provided by law. The extreme width of a bus shall not exceed one hundred two (102) inches. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 21, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 2. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 34, effective June 15, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44170</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>