<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.662</section_number><catch_line>Creation of multicounty emergency services board -- Replacement of existing fire, ambulance, and rescue squad boards -- Boundaries -- Taxing powers -- Dissolution or alteration of boundaries. </catch_line><order_by>662</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Two (2) or more fiscal courts of which one (1) county shall have a county-wide fire protection district formed under KRS Chapter 75 that has entered into an interlocal agreement to provide fire service to the largest city in the county may, through the adoption of concurrent ordinances in accordance with KRS 67.075 and 67.077, merge the boards of the following special districts that are wholly contained within their counties: <section prefix="a">Ambulance districts created under KRS 108.080 to 108.180; </section><section prefix="b">Fire protection districts created under KRS 75.010 to 75.260; and </section><section prefix="c">Local rescue squad districts created under KRS Chapter 39F. </section></section><section prefix="2">Once the fiscal courts have merged any of the boards listed in paragraphs (a) to (c) of subsection (1) of this section, no additional special districts listed in paragraphs <section prefix="a">to (c) of subsection (1) of this section shall be permitted to be created in any of </section>the member counties whose administration and taxing authority are not transferred to the emergency services board, and no boundary of a district shall exceed the boundaries of the counties that the multicounty emergency services district represents. </section><section prefix="3">A multicounty emergency services board's jurisdiction shall encompass the boundaries of the special districts within the member counties whose boards and taxing authority it is replacing. </section><section prefix="4">A multicounty emergency services board shall have the powers that constitute a taxing district within the meaning of Section 157 of the Constitution of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">If a multicounty emergency services board chooses to levy the tax allowed in KRS 65.670, a certified copy of the ordinance levying the tax shall be filed with the county clerk of each member county who shall add the levy to the tax bills of the county. For taxing purposes, the effective date of the tax levy shall be January 1 of the year following the certification of the creation of the emergency services board. </section><section prefix="6">A multicounty emergency services board may be dissolved or the boundaries altered if the procedures under KRS 65.164 to 65.176 are followed. If the emergency services board is dissolved, then the boards of the special districts of which it assumed the board duties shall be reappointed according to statute within thirty (30) days of the emergency services board's dissolution, and the original taxing protocol applicable to the specific special district shall apply. Each special district shall assume that portion of the debt attributable to its service. Any unattributable debt shall be assumed equally by each fiscal court formerly participating in the multicounty emergency services board. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23439</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>