<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-220</section_number><catch_line>Timetables for issuance of permits -- Effects of failure to file timetables and inaction before established deadlines. </catch_line><order_by>10-220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall adopt administrative regulations establishing reasonable timetables for the issuance of all permits by the cabinet, except those permits for which a timetable is set out by statute. The timetables shall set specific time periods for actions to be taken in the consideration of permit applications. </section><section prefix="2">The timetables adopted pursuant to subsection (1) of this section shall be proposed for adoption and filed with the Legislative Research Commission no later than January 1, 1993. In the event that the timetables required by subsection (1) of this section are not proposed for adoption and filed with the Legislative Research Commission by the January 1, 1993 deadline, the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall cease the collection of permit fees for all permits for which timetables have not been established until the required timetables have been proposed for adoption. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall waive the permit fee for any permit not acted upon, either favorably or unfavorably, in accordance with the established timetables. The approach of an impending deadline for action on a permit pursuant to the established timetables shall not be a reason for denial of a permit. However, nothing in this section shall require the cabinet to issue a permit which would violate this chapter or the administrative regulations adopted pursuant thereto. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 353, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10317</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>