<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="241" order_by="241">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- ADMINISTRATION AND CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>241.170</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of city administrator and employees in cities of first class or consolidated local government -- Police powers -- Right to inspect premises -- Appointment in other cities -- Qualifications of city administrators and employees -- Jurisdictional enforcement conflicts.   </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The city administrator in each city of the first class or the administrator in a consolidated local government, and such investigators and clerks as are deemed necessary for the proper conduct of his office, shall be appointed by the mayor. The city administrator in each city of the first class or the administrator in a county containing a consolidated local government, and his investigators, shall have full police powers of peace officers, and their jurisdiction shall be coextensive with boundaries of the city of the first class or the boundaries of the county in a county containing a consolidated local government. They may inspect any premises where alcoholic beverages are manufactured, sold, stored, or otherwise trafficked in, without first obtaining a search warrant.  </section><section prefix="b">Only those cities with a population equal to or greater than three thousand (3,000) or more based upon the most recent federal decennial census, or those cities with a population of less than three thousand (3,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census that had appointed an administrator prior to August 1, 2014, that are located in a county containing a consolidated local government are authorized to appoint an administrator. If a city authorized under this paragraph appoints its own administrator under this paragraph and KRS 241.160, the administrator of a consolidated local government in that county shall have jurisdiction over only that portion of the county which lies outside the corporate limits of such a city, unless the department determines that the city does not have an adequate police force of its own or pursuant to KRS 70.150, 70.160, 70.170, and 70.540. </section></section><section prefix="2">The city administrator in each city, other than a consolidated local government, shall be appointed by the city manager if there is one. If there is no city manager, the city administrator shall be appointed by the mayor. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall be an administrator, an investigator, or an employee of the city or a consolidated local government under the supervision of the administrator, who would be disqualified to be a member of the board under KRS 241.100. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 289, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 556, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 216, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-111. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43874</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>