<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.7603</section_number><catch_line>School-to-Careers Grant Program -- Authority for administrative regulations -- Advisory committee. </catch_line><order_by>7603</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The School-to-Careers Grant Program shall be provided by the General Assembly to provide matching funds to school districts or consortia of school districts for the development and implementation of comprehensive plans that include: <section prefix="a">A comprehensive career awareness and exploration program for all students in grades K-8 to include study of Kentucky's fourteen (14) career clusters; </section><section prefix="b">High level academic and vocational courses for all secondary students to replace a general track curriculum; </section><section prefix="c">A comprehensive career guidance program to assist all secondary students in developing individual graduation plans; </section><section prefix="d">Applied academic instructional models for all disciplines and integration of academics and vocational education curriculum; </section><section prefix="e">Implementation of industry skill standards within all relevant academic and vocational education programs; </section><section prefix="f">Planned instructional programs to meet the needs of students with disabilities and other special needs students; </section><section prefix="g">Opportunity for students to receive, in addition to a high school diploma, a Career Major Certificate upon completion of the high school graduation requirements, work-based learning experiences, specific course work, and a career culminating project; </section><section prefix="h">Opportunity for students to participate in structured workbased learning; </section><section prefix="i">Linkages with postsecondary institutions that create a smooth and seamless transition from secondary to postsecondary education; </section><section prefix="j">Professional development for faculty and staff focused on developing integrated and applied curriculum; and </section><section prefix="k">A School-to-Careers Partnership Council composed of representatives of business, labor, education agencies, parents, students, teachers, administrators, and community organizations. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations that set forth the request for proposal process, the criteria for grant awards, the responsibilities of local districts and consortia seeking matching funds, the level of funding available, and criteria for evaluating the success of the programs. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Education shall administer the funds and shall provide technical assistance to local districts and consortia in developing, implementing, and evaluating School-to-Careers programs. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner of education shall establish a state advisory committee composed of business, industry, labor, education, and government with a minimum of fifty-one percent (51%) of its membership from the employment sector to advise the department in the School-to-Careers program. The members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for necessary travel expenses. </section><section prefix="5">The grant funds may be used to enhance on-going efforts such as Tech Prep, School-to-Work, and High Schools that Work initiatives. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 444, sec. 2, effective April 9, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>