<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="525" order_by="525">RIOT, DISORDERLY CONDUCT, AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>525.155</section_number><catch_line>Interference with a funeral. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of interference with a funeral when, at any point in time between one (1) hour prior to the commencement of an event specified in this subsection and one (1) hour following its conclusion, he or she blocks, impedes, inhibits, or in any other manner obstructs or interferes with access into or from any building or parking lot of a building in which a funeral, wake, memorial service, or burial is being conducted, or any burial plot or the parking lot of the cemetery in which a funeral, wake, memorial service, or burial is being conducted. </section><section prefix="2">Interference with a funeral is a Class B misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 5, effective March 27, 2006; and ch. 51, sec. 5, effective March 27, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/07).  A reference to "paragraph (a) of this subsection" in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 3, has been corrected in codification by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136 to read simply "this subsection" since the division of the subsection into paragraphs was eliminated. (3/27/06). This section was created by 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 5, and 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 5, which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>