<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 532.210 to 532.250. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>As used in KRS 532.210 to 532.250, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Home" means the temporary or permanent residence of a defendant consisting of the actual living area. If more than one (1) residence or family is located on a single piece of property, "home" does not include the residence of any other person who is not part of the social unit formed by the defendant's immediate family. A hospital, nursing care facility, hospice, half-way house, group home, residential treatment facility, or boarding house may serve as a "home" under this section; </section><section prefix="2">"Home incarceration" means the use of a monitoring device approved by the commissioner of the Department of Corrections to facilitate a prisoner's ability to maintain gainful employment or to participate in programs approved as a condition of his or her incarceration, or both, using the person's home for purposes of confinement; </section><section prefix="3">"Violent felony offense" means an offense defined in KRS 507.020 (murder), 507.030 (manslaughter in the first degree), 508.010 (assault in the first degree), 508.020 (assault in the second degree), 509.040 (kidnapping), 510.040 (rape in the first degree), 510.070 (sodomy in the first degree), 510.110 (sexual abuse in the first degree), 511.020 (burglary in the first degree), 513.020 (arson in the first degree), 513.030 (arson in the second degree), 513.040 (arson in the third degree), 515.020 (robbery in the first degree), 515.030 (robbery in the second degree), 520.020 (escape in the first degree), any criminal attempt to commit the offense (KRS 506.010), or conviction as a persistent felony offender (KRS 532.080) when the offender has a felony conviction for any of the above-listed offenses within the five (5) year period preceding the date of the latest conviction; </section><section prefix="4">"Terminal illness" means a medically recognized disease for which the prognosis is death within six (6) months to a reasonable degree of medical certainty; and </section><section prefix="5">"Approved monitoring device" means an electronic device or apparatus which is capable of recording, tracking, or transmitting information as to the prisoner's location or verifying the prisoner's presence or non-presence in the home, or both. The devices shall be minimally intrusive. Devices shall not be used without the prisoner's knowledge to record or transmit: <section prefix="a">Visual images other than the defendant's face; </section><section prefix="b">Oral or wire communications or any auditory sound other than the defendant's voice; or </section><section prefix="c">Information as to the prisoner's activities while inside the home. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 8, effective July 1, 2008. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 137, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010). 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 12, provides that "The intent of the General Assembly in repealing and reenacting KRS 439.320, 439.340, and 532.200 in Sections 4, 5, and 10 of this Act is to affirm the amendments made to these sections in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 158. The specific textual provisions of Sections 4, 5, and 10 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 158 shall be deemed effective as of April 24, 2008, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text from those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." This statute is affected by that language. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>