<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="107" order_by="107">MUNICIPAL IMPROVEMENTS -- ALTERNATE METHODS </unit></structure><section_number>107.140</section_number><catch_line>Benefited property, what constitutes, assessment of governmental property -- Procedure against state.   </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">In the case of improvements of public ways, the benefited property shall consist of all real property abutting upon both sides of the improvement project, and the cost of improving intersections shall be included in the total costs to be assessed and apportioned, unless and to the extent the city shall appropriate, within constitutional limitations, from available funds, a definite and specified sum as a contribution thereto, or a portion of the aggregate cost, or the cost of specified portions of the improvement; provided, however, that if provisions shall be made for sidewalk improvements, as an integral part of the improvement of a "public way," as defined in subsection (3) of KRS 107.020, upon only one side of the project, the costs of the sidewalk improvement shall be ascertained and assessed separately against the property abutting upon that side only, but the governing body may provide that such assessment shall include a fair share of the over-all costs as herein defined, other than the amounts of the actual construction contracts. </section><section prefix="b">In the case of improvements for draining sewage, storm water, or a combination thereof, the benefited properties shall consist of all properties which are thereby afforded a means of drainage, including not only the properties which may be contiguous to the improvements, but also adjacent properties within a reasonable distance therefrom as the governing body may in the proceedings set forth. </section><section prefix="c">In the case of an improvement project consisting in whole or in part of a sewage treatment plant, or enlargement or substantial reconstruction of an existing sewage treatment plant, the benefited properties shall be all those properties the sewage from which is treated in such plant, including properties already provided with sewer drainage facilities as well as those properties which the improvement project will provide with such drainage facilities, but the governing body may classify properties according to the extent of benefits to be afforded to them, and may establish one (1) rate of assessment applicable to all properties participating in the benefits of the sewage treatment installations, and an additional rate of assessment applicable to properties for which the improvement project will also provide sewer drainage facilities. In relation to wastewater collection projects constructed by metropolitan sewer districts, benefited property shall consist of all property whether improved or unimproved to which the project affords a means of discharging wastewater. </section><section prefix="d">The governing body may, either in the proceedings initiating an improvement project, or in subsequent proceedings, recognize the necessity or desirability in the interest of the public health, safety and general welfare, that properties other than the properties originally benefited by an improvement under paragraphs (b) or (c) of this subsection, be permitted to connect to such sewer drainage and/or treatment facilities, and may make equitable provisions which may be adjustable from year to year as bonds are retired, whereby the owners of such later-connecting properties, may, by paying charges for the privilege of connecting, and/or by assuming a share of improvement assessments, or otherwise, be placed as nearly as practicable on a basis of financial equity with the owners of properties initially provided to be assessed. </section><section prefix="e">The governing body may, either in the proceedings initiating an improvement project, or in subsequent proceedings, recognize the necessity or desirability in the interest of the public health, safety and general welfare that residential properties within one thousand feet (1000'), measured along paved roads, of a fire hydrant in cities with a population of less than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census may be assessed on the same basis as property abutting upon a street where a fire hydrant is to be installed. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Benefited property owned by the city or county, or owned by the United States government or any of its agencies, if such property is subject to assessment by Act of Congress, shall be assessed annually the same as private property, and the amount of the annual assessment shall be paid by the city, county, or United States government, as the case may be. The same right of action shall lie against the county as against a private owner. </section><section prefix="b">Benefited property owned by the state, except property the title to which is vested in the Commonwealth for the benefit of a district board of education pursuant to KRS 162.010, shall be assessed as follows: Before assessing the state, the governing body shall serve written notice on the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet setting forth specific details including the estimated total amount of any improvement assessment proposed to be levied against any state property relative to any proposed improvement project. Said written notice shall be served prior to the next even-numbered-year regular session of the General Assembly so that the amount of any specific improvement assessment may be included in the biennial executive branch budget recommendation to be submitted to the General Assembly. Payment of any assessment shall be made only from funds specifically appropriated for that assessment. If an amount sufficient to pay the total amount of any assessment has been appropriated, then the total amount shall be paid; if an amount sufficient only to pay annual assessments has been appropriated, then only the amount of the annual assessment shall be paid. The amount of the assessment shall be certified by the city treasurer to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, which shall thereupon draw a warrant upon the State Treasurer, payable to the city treasurer, and the State Treasurer shall pay the same. </section><section prefix="c">In the case of property the title to which is vested in the Commonwealth for the benefit of a district board of education, the amount of the annual assessment shall be paid by the city or other local governmental agency or authority which undertook the improvement project. </section></section><section prefix="3">No benefited property shall be exempt from assessment. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 207, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 14, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 64, effective July 1, 1983. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 20. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 3; and ch. 175, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 5. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(1982).  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>