<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.337</section_number><catch_line>Traffic control signs, uniform standards to be prescribed -- Sign to conform -- Prohibited activities. </catch_line><order_by>337</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this chapter, "official traffic control devices" shall mean all signs, signals, markings, and devices placed or erected by authority of a public body or official having jurisdiction, for the purpose of regulating, warning, or dividing traffic. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Highways shall promulgate and adopt a manual of standards and specifications for a uniform system of official traffic control devices for use upon all roads and streets open to public travel. The manual and its future revisions and supplements shall be applicable to all roads and streets under the control of the Department of Highways or any county or incorporated city. </section><section prefix="3">All traffic control devices installed on any road or street after the adoption of the manual shall conform to the provisions thereof. Satisfactory operating traffic devices in use on the date of the adoption of the manual may continue to be used; however, if such devices are replaced or revised, they must be replaced or revised in conformance with the provisions of the manual. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall place, maintain, or display on or in the view of any highway any authorized sign, signal, marking, or device which resembles, purports to be, or is an imitation of an official traffic control device or signal. </section><section prefix="5">A person shall not attempt to or in fact alter, twist, deface, injure, knock down, or interfere with the effective operation of any official traffic control device or signal, or any part thereof. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 46, secs. 1 to 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6373</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>