<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261">STOCKYARDS </unit></structure><section_number>261.200</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Kentucky Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the State Board of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="4">"Stockyard" means a facility regulated by: <section prefix="a">The United States Secretary of Agriculture under the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 (42 Stat. 159), as amended, and regulations promulgated under these statutes by the Secretary of Agriculture; or </section><section prefix="b">The department under this chapter and administrative regulations promulgated under this chapter. </section></section> A stockyard includes any place, establishment, or facility commonly known as a stockyard, which is conducted, operated, or managed for profit or nonprofit as a public market for livestock producers, feeders, market agencies, and buyers, consisting of pens or other enclosures and their appurtenances, in which livestock are received, held, or kept for sale or shipment in commerce; <section prefix="5">"Buying station" means a facility that is conducted, operated, or managed as a private livestock market that offers stockyard services; </section><section prefix="6">"Stockyard services" means services or facilities furnished at a stockyard or buying station in connection with the: <section prefix="a">Receiving, buying, or selling of livestock in commerce on a commission basis or otherwise; or </section><section prefix="b">Marketing, feeding, watering, holding, delivering, shipping, weighing, or handling of livestock in commerce; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Owner or operator" means persons responsible for the operation of each individual stockyard or buying station; </section><section prefix="8">"Market agency" means a person engaged in the business of: <section prefix="a">Buying or selling livestock in commerce on a commission basis; or </section><section prefix="b">Furnishing stockyard services; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Livestock dealer" means any person, not a market agency, who: <section prefix="a">Is regularly engaged in the business of buying or selling livestock in commerce, either on his or her own account or as the employee or agent of the vendor or purchaser; or </section><section prefix="b">Owns or operates a buying station; and </section></section><section prefix="10">"Livestock" means cattle, sheep, swine, or goats of all kinds and species. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>.Pursuant to Acts 1962, ch. 139, sec. 2, the reviser has substituted "department of agriculture" for "department of agriculture, labor and statistics" in this chapter. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40142</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>