<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.630</section_number><catch_line>War memorial commissions in cities of the home rule class.   </catch_line><order_by>630</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city of the first class that has constructed a war memorial under the provisions of Chapter 23 of the Acts of 1922 shall have a memorial commission consisting of seven (7) members. Members shall be not less than twenty-five (25) years of age and shall be bona fide residents of the county in which the city is situated. Upon the expiration of the terms of the members of the commission appointed or elected under the provisions of Chapter 23 of the Acts of 1922, the remaining members of the commission shall elect members to succeed those whose terms have expired, to serve for terms of seven (7) years each, and annually thereafter members to succeed those whose terms have expired shall be elected for terms of seven (7) years each by the remaining members of the commission. Vacancies in the terms of members shall be filled by the remaining members of the commission. Members selected to fill vacancies shall serve for the unexpired term. The members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be allowed their necessary expenses for travel when engaged on the business of the commission. </section><section prefix="2">A city of the home rule class that has constructed a war memorial under the provisions of Chapter 128 of the Acts of 1946, may, by ordinance, have a memorial commission consisting of fifteen (15) members. Members of the commission shall be nominated and appointed by the mayor and approved by the city legislative body. Five (5) of said members shall be appointed to serve five (5) years; five (5) members shall be appointed to serve six (6) years; and five (5) members shall be appointed to serve seven (7) years. Thereafter, members to succeed those whose terms have expired shall be elected by the remaining members of the commission for terms of three (3) years. Vacancies in the terms of members shall be filled by the remaining members of the commission. Members selected to fill vacancies shall serve for the unexpired term. The members of the commission shall serve without compensation, but shall be allowed their necessary expenses for travel when engaged in the business of the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 182, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3037i-1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>