<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.010</section_number><catch_line>Purposes -- Exemptions -- Amnesty period.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the purpose and policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to protect the public from being misled by incompetent and unauthorized persons, and from unprofessional conduct on the part of qualified social workers by providing regulatory authority over persons who hold themselves out to the public as social workers. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 is to promote high standards of professional performance for those engaged in the profession of social work by regulating the title, and by setting standards of qualification, training, and experience for those who seek to engage in the practice of social work. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing contained in KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 shall be applicable to employees of the State Department of Education or local boards of education who meet the certification requirements in the area of social work as established, or which may be established, by the Kentucky Board of Education. Nor shall anything in KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 be construed to apply to, limit, or restrict the regulation of the title, setting of standards, qualifications, training, or experience of those who seek to engage in the practice of social work and who have been, or will be, certified by the Kentucky Board of Education for the position for which they have been employed. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing contained in KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 shall require persons employed by the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the director or administrative head of a social service agency or division of a city, county or urban-county government, or applicants for such employment to be licensed. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Nothing contained in KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 shall require persons employed by an organization that is exempt from federal income taxation under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, and provides evidence of its tax-exempt status, to be licensed. </section><section prefix="b">The provisions of KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990 shall not be construed to apply to, limit, or restrict the regulation of the title, setting of standards, qualifications, training, and experience of those engaged as employees of a tax-exempt organization in the practice of social work. </section><section prefix="c">The exemption provided in this subsection shall not apply to the practice of clinical social work, which shall be undertaken only by a certified social worker licensed pursuant to KRS 335.080 or a licensed clinical social worker licensed pursuant to KRS 335.100. </section></section><section prefix="6">Nothing contained in KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and 335.990 shall prohibit volunteer health practitioners from providing services under KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366. </section><section prefix="7">Beginning on July 12, 2012, and continuing through December 31, 2016, there shall exist an amnesty period during which no disciplinary action, administrative fees, or fines shall be imposed by the board for unlicensed practice against an individual who is currently serving or who formerly served as an employee of a tax-exempt organization specified in subsection (5) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 77, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 18, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 261, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 288, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40968</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>