<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.342</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP -- Authority for administrative regulations -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>342</order_by><text>The Office of Drug Control Policy shall be responsible for all matters relating to the research, coordination, and execution of drug control policy and for the management of state and federal grants, including but not limited to the prevention and treatment related to substance abuse. By December 31 of each year, the Office of Drug Control Policy shall review, approve, and coordinate all current projects of any substance abuse program which is conducted by or receives funding through agencies of the executive branch. This oversight shall extend to all substance abuse programs which are principally related to the prevention or treatment, or otherwise targeted at the reduction, of substance abuse in the Commonwealth. The Office of Drug Control Policy shall promulgate administrative regulations consistent with enforcing this oversight authority. In addition, the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP shall: <section prefix="1">Develop a strategic plan to reduce the prevalence of smoking and drug and alcohol abuse among both the youth and adult populations in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">Monitor the data and issues related to youth alcohol and tobacco access, smoking cessation and prevention, and substance abuse policies, their impact on state and local programs, and their flexibility to adapt to the needs of local communities and service providers; </section><section prefix="3">Make policy recommendations to be followed to the extent permitted by budgetary restrictions and federal law, by executive branch agencies that work with smoking cessation and prevention and alcohol and substance abuse issues to ensure the greatest efficiency in agencies and to ensure that a consistency in philosophy will be applied to all efforts undertaken by the administration in initiatives related to smoking cessation and prevention and alcohol and substance abuse; </section><section prefix="4">Identify existing resources in each community that advocate or implement programs for smoking cessation or prevention, or drug and alcohol abuse prevention, education, or treatment; </section><section prefix="5">Encourage coordination among public and private, state and local, agencies, organizations, and service providers, and monitor related programs; </section><section prefix="6">Act as the referral source of information, utilizing existing information clearinghouse resources within the Department for Public Health and CHAMPIONS for a Drug Free Kentucky Office, relating to youth tobacco access, smoking cessation and prevention, and substance abuse prevention, cessation, and treatment programs. The Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP shall identify gaps in information referral sources; </section><section prefix="7">Search for grant opportunities for existing programs within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="8">Make recommendations to state and local agencies and local tobacco addiction and substance abuse advisory and coordination boards; </section><section prefix="9">Observe programs from other states; </section><section prefix="10">Coordinate services among local and state agencies, including but not limited to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Department of Agriculture, the Public Protection Cabinet, the Administrative Office of the Courts, and the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet; </section><section prefix="11">Assure the availability of training, technical assistance, and consultation to local service providers for programs funded by the Commonwealth that provide services related to tobacco addiction, smoking cessation or prevention, or alcohol or substance abuse; </section><section prefix="12">Review existing research on programs related to smoking cessation and prevention and substance abuse prevention and treatment; </section><section prefix="13">Comply with any federal mandate regarding smoking cessation and prevention and substance abuse, to the extent authorized by state statute; </section><section prefix="14">Establish a mechanism to coordinate the distribution of funds to support any local prevention, treatment, and education program based on the strategic plan developed in subsection (1) of this section that could encourage smoking cessation and prevention through efficient, effective, and research-based strategies; </section><section prefix="15">Oversee a school-based initiative that links schools with community-based agencies and health departments to implement School Programs to Prevent Tobacco Use, based upon the model recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. To the extent permitted by resources, the initiative shall involve input by and services from each of the family resource and youth services centers, regional prevention centers, and existing school-based antidrug programs; </section><section prefix="16">Work with community-based organizations to encourage them to work together to establish comprehensive tobacco addiction and substance abuse prevention education programs and carry out the strategic plan developed in this section. These organizations shall be encouraged to partner with district and local health departments and community mental health centers to plan and implement interventions to reach youths before tobacco addiction and substance abuse become a problem in their lives; </section><section prefix="17">Coordinate media campaigns designed to demonstrate the negative impact of smoking and the increased risk of tobacco addiction, substance abuse, and the development of other disease in children, young people, and adults. To accomplish this objective, KY-ASAP shall work with local media to reach all segments of the community quickly and efficiently; </section><section prefix="18">Certify to the Governor, the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and the General Assembly during the budget request process established under KRS Chapter 48 the extent to which each entity receiving state funds has cooperated with the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP, coordinated with community resources, and vigorously pursued the philosophy of the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP; </section><section prefix="19">Promulgate, with the approval of the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, any administrative regulations necessary to implement this section and KRS 15A.340 and 15A.344; and </section><section prefix="20">Report annually to the Legislative Research Commission and Governor regarding the proper organization of state government agencies that will provide the greatest coordination of services, and report semiannually to the Legislative Research Commission and Governor on the status of the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP programs, services, and grants, and on other matters as requested by the Legislative Research Commission and Governor. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 11, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 11, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 536, sec. 26, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 12.332. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1071</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>