<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.140</section_number><catch_line>Operation of cages and cars. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Only a certified hoistman shall be placed in charge of any mechanism used for lowering or hoisting any persons employed in the mine. Where automatic elevators are used and all safety devices are provided, the services of a hoistman are not required. A certified hoistman shall pass a test as to his knowledge of hoisting equipment and the precautions to be taken when raising or lowering men or materials. Certification of hoistmen shall be under such conditions and by tests prescribed by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">No hoistman in charge of such machinery shall allow any person except such as may be designated for this purpose by the operator or superintendent to interfere with any part of the machinery. </section><section prefix="3">In a mine worked by shaft, slope, or incline, no more than twenty (20) persons shall ride in any cage or car at one (1) time, without the approval of the mine inspector and the commissioner of the department, and no person shall ride on a loaded cage or car, except that where special man-cars or cages are employed to haul workmen on inclines the commissioner may regulate the method and procedure of handling of man-cars, cages, and workmen. Each cage or elevator installed after June 16, 1972, which is used for lowering and raising men shall have at least two and one-half (2-1/2) square feet of floor space for each person. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 16, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 14. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-23. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32987</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>