<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.074</section_number><catch_line>Titling of all-terrain vehicles. </catch_line><order_by>074</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "all-terrain vehicle" has the same meaning as in KRS 189.010. </section><section prefix="2">The titling of all-terrain vehicles shall be administered through the automated motor vehicle and trailer registration and titling system developed and implemented under KRS 186A.010. </section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A requiring the procedures for titling of all-terrain vehicles to be consistent as far as practicable with motor vehicle titling. These regulations may pertain but shall not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Conditions and characteristics of certificate of title forms; </section><section prefix="b">Comparison and identification of identification or serial numbers of all-terrain vehicles; </section><section prefix="c">Application for title; </section><section prefix="d">Processing of title applications; </section><section prefix="e">Form of certificate of title; </section><section prefix="f">Notation of security interests on title; </section><section prefix="g">Title lien statements; </section><section prefix="h">Transfer of all-terrain vehicle ownership; and </section><section prefix="i">Duplicate certificate of title. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Transportation Cabinet shall ensure that the automated motor vehicle and trailer registration and titling system is capable of receiving and discharging a lien associated with the owner of an all-terrain vehicle. An all-terrain vehicle dealer shall not be responsible for the payment of a lien on an all-terrain vehicle which is received as trade-in or otherwise obtained by the dealer. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>