<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 278.010 to 278.450, 278.541 to 278.544, 278.546 to 278.5462, and 278.990. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 278.010 to 278.450, 278.541 to 278.544, 278.546 to 278.5462, and 278.990, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Corporation" includes private, quasipublic, and public corporations, and all boards, agencies, and instrumentalities thereof, associations, joint-stock companies, and business trusts; </section><section prefix="2">"Person" includes natural persons, partnerships, corporations, and two (2) or more persons having a joint or common interest; </section><section prefix="3">"Utility" means any person except a regional wastewater commission established pursuant to KRS 65.8905 and, for purposes of paragraphs (a), (b), (c), (d), and (f) of this subsection, a city, who owns, controls, operates, or manages any facility used or to be used for or in connection with: <section prefix="a">The generation, production, transmission, or distribution of electricity to or for the public, for compensation, for lights, heat, power, or other uses; </section><section prefix="b">The production, manufacture, storage, distribution, sale, or furnishing of natural or manufactured gas, or a mixture of same, to or for the public, for compensation, for light, heat, power, or other uses; </section><section prefix="c">The transporting or conveying of gas, crude oil, or other fluid substance by pipeline to or for the public, for compensation; </section><section prefix="d">The diverting, developing, pumping, impounding, distributing, or furnishing of water to or for the public, for compensation; </section><section prefix="e">The transmission or conveyance over wire, in air, or otherwise, of any message by telephone or telegraph for the public, for compensation; or </section><section prefix="f">The collection, transmission, or treatment of sewage for the public, for compensation, if the facility is a subdivision collection, transmission, or treatment facility plant that is affixed to real property and is located in a county containing a city of the first class or is a sewage collection, transmission, or treatment facility that is affixed to real property, that is located in any other county, and that is not subject to regulation by a metropolitan sewer district or any sanitation district created pursuant to KRS Chapter 220; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Retail electric supplier" means any person, firm, corporation, association, or cooperative corporation, excluding municipal corporations, engaged in the furnishing of retail electric service; </section><section prefix="5">"Certified territory" shall mean the areas as certified by and pursuant to KRS 278.017; </section><section prefix="6">"Existing distribution line" shall mean an electric line which on June 16, 1972, is being or has been substantially used to supply retail electric service and includes all lines from the distribution substation to the electric consuming facility but does not include any transmission facilities used primarily to transfer energy in bulk; </section><section prefix="7">"Retail electric service" means electric service furnished to a consumer for ultimate consumption, but does not include wholesale electric energy furnished by an electric supplier to another electric supplier for resale; </section><section prefix="8">"Electric-consuming facilities" means everything that utilizes electric energy from a central station source; </section><section prefix="9">"Generation and transmission cooperative" or "G&amp;T" means a utility formed under KRS Chapter 279 that provides electric generation and transmission services; </section><section prefix="10">"Distribution cooperative" means a utility formed under KRS Chapter 279 that provides retail electric service; </section><section prefix="11">"Facility" includes all property, means, and instrumentalities owned, operated, leased, licensed, used, furnished, or supplied for, by, or in connection with the business of any utility; </section><section prefix="12">"Rate" means any individual or joint fare, toll, charge, rental, or other compensation for service rendered or to be rendered by any utility, and any rule, regulation, practice, act, requirement, or privilege in any way relating to such fare, toll, charge, rental, or other compensation, and any schedule or tariff or part of a schedule or tariff thereof; </section><section prefix="13">"Service" includes any practice or requirement in any way relating to the service of any utility, including the voltage of electricity, the heat units and pressure of gas, the purity, pressure, and quantity of water, and in general the quality, quantity, and pressure of any commodity or product used or to be used for or in connection with the business of any utility, but does not include Voice over Internet Protocol (VoIP) service; </section><section prefix="14">"Adequate service" means having sufficient capacity to meet the maximum estimated requirements of the customer to be served during the year following the commencement of permanent service and to meet the maximum estimated requirements of other actual customers to be supplied from the same lines or facilities during such year and to assure such customers of reasonable continuity of service; </section><section prefix="15">"Commission" means the Public Service Commission of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="16">"Commissioner" means one (1) of the members of the commission; </section><section prefix="17">"Demand-side management" means any conservation, load management, or other utility activity intended to influence the level or pattern of customer usage or demand, including home energy assistance programs; </section><section prefix="18">"Affiliate" means a person that controls or that is controlled by, or is under common control with, a utility; </section><section prefix="19">"Control" means the power to direct the management or policies of a person through ownership, by contract, or otherwise; </section><section prefix="20">"CAM" means a cost allocation manual which is an indexed compilation and documentation of a company's cost allocation policies and related procedures; </section><section prefix="21">"Nonregulated activity" means the provision of competitive retail gas or electric services or other products or services over which the commission exerts no regulatory authority; </section><section prefix="22">"Nonregulated" means that which is not subject to regulation by the commission; </section><section prefix="23">"Regulated activity" means a service provided by a utility or other person, the rates and charges of which are regulated by the commission; </section><section prefix="24">"USoA" means uniform system of accounts which is a system of accounts for public utilities established by the FERC and adopted by the commission; </section><section prefix="25">"Arm's length" means the standard of conduct under which unrelated parties, each party acting in its own best interest, would negotiate and carry out a particular transaction; </section><section prefix="26">"Subsidize" means the recovery of costs or the transfer of value from one (1) class of customer, activity, or business unit that is attributable to another; </section><section prefix="27">"Solicit" means to engage in or offer for sale a good or service, either directly or indirectly and irrespective of place or audience; </section><section prefix="28">"USDA" means the United States Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="29">"FERC" means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; </section><section prefix="30">"SEC" means the Securities and Exchange Commission; </section><section prefix="31">"Commercial mobile radio services" has the same meaning as in 47 C.F.R. sec. 20.3 and includes the term "wireless" and service provided by any wireless real time two (2) way voice communication device, including radio-telephone communications used in cellular telephone service, personal communications service, and the functional or competitive equivalent of a radio-telephone communications line used in cellular telephone service, a personal communications service, or a network radio access line; and </section><section prefix="32">"Voice over Internet Protocol" or "VoIP" has the same meaning as in federal law. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.20, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 15, effective April 24 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 511, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 238, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 1, effective April 1, 1979. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3952-1. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>