<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.110</section_number><catch_line>Rescue aid fund -- Duties of director of division -- Local director's responsibilities. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director of the division shall have overall responsibility for policy, guidance, administration, implementation, and proper utilization of the rescue aid fund. </section><section prefix="2">The director shall serve as principal liaison between the division and local officials participating in programs affected by the rescue aid fund, and shall ensure proper utilization of the rescue aid fund. </section><section prefix="3">The director shall appoint an advisory committee consisting of seven (7) members, including no more than four (4) employees of the staff of the division to assist in making determinations related to rescue grant fund allocations, compliance with fund requirements, releasing equipment to rescue squads, and withdrawal and reallocation of equipment or funds. The members of the committee shall serve at the pleasure of the director, but for no more than four (4) years without reappointment, and shall serve without reimbursement, except when funded through the Emergency Management Assistance Program. The decisions of the committee shall be advisory only and shall not be binding upon the director. </section><section prefix="4">The director, with the advice of the advisory committee, shall make determinations relating to rescue grant fund applications, releasing equipment to rescue squads, and withdrawal and reallocation of equipment or funds. </section><section prefix="5">Area managers of the division shall fully explain rescue grant opportunities and requirements to local elected officials, local emergency management directors, and local rescue squads; review rescue grant fund applications, documentation and program submissions; and make recommendations to the director. </section><section prefix="6">Local emergency management directors shall be responsible for submitting rescue grant fund applications and documentation of expenditures to the division, as required, and shall facilitate and ensure the coordination of local rescue programs to meet the needs of the communities served. </section><section prefix="7">The chief officer of the rescue squad shall initiate rescue grant fund applications, submit all applications or documentation to the local emergency management director, and ensure that all funds are expended for items or services as approved. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 93, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21804</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>