<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.678</section_number><catch_line>Information reported under KRS 211.672 to 211.678 -- Annual publication of data regarding reports made relating to neonatal abstinence syndrome. </catch_line><order_by>678</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, all information reported or furnished to the Kentucky Department for Public Health pursuant to KRS 211.672 to 211.678 shall be privileged and confidential, shall not be considered a public record under KRS 61.870 to 61.884, and shall not be discussed at any meeting as defined in KRS 61.805, unless conducted in a closed session in accordance with KRS 61.815. </section><section prefix="2">Information reported in compliance with KRS 211.672 to 211.678 shall not be disclosed by any person or entity, and shall not be subject to subpoena, court order, or discovery, or admissible as evidence in any civil or administrative proceeding in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section, "information" shall be liberally construed to include reports; statements; interviews; memoranda; data, whether kept individually or aggregated; or summaries of same. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing within this section is intended to limit the Kentucky Department for Public Health's internal use of such information to fulfill the express purposes of KRS 211.672 to 211.678. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Department for Public Health shall publish on at least an annual basis de-identified statistical data on the number of reports made under KRS 211.676 relating to a diagnosis of neonatal abstinence syndrome. The report may segregate the data into reporting blocks no smaller than the regional or county level. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43236</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>