<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.150</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by brewer's license -- Sale and service of malt beverages.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A brewer's license shall authorize the licensee to engage in the business of a brewer at the premises specifically designated in the license, and to transport for himself only any malt beverage which he is authorized by his license to manufacture or sell, but he shall transport any malt beverages in accordance with the requirements provided by KRS 243.120 for distillers. </section><section prefix="2">A brewer may sell any malt beverage produced under his license to: <section prefix="a">A licensed wholesaler from the licensed premises; </section><section prefix="b">Any of its employees for home consumption; and </section><section prefix="c">Charitable or fraternal organizations holding group meetings, picnics, or outings. </section></section><section prefix="3">A brewer may serve on the premises of its brewery complimentary samples of malt beverages produced at the brewery in an amount not to exceed sixteen (16) ounces per patron per day, if the brewery is located in wet territory. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 205, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-198. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42232</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>