<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.290</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Propane Education and Research Council -- Appointment of members -- Terms and compensation. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Kentucky Propane Education and Research Council composed of eleven (11) members appointed by the commissioner. Five (5) members shall represent retail marketers, five (5) members shall represent producers and suppliers, and one (1) member shall be the public member as defined in KRS 234.272. </section><section prefix="2">Council members representing retail marketers, producers, and suppliers shall be appointed based on the nomination of an industry trade association certified according to KRS 234.280. No member representing these categories may be appointed unless recommended by a certified industry trade association. Members in these categories shall be full-time employees or owners of businesses in the industry. </section><section prefix="3">No employee of a certified industry trade association shall serve as a member of the council and no member of the council may serve concurrently as an officer or member of the board of directors of a certified industry trade association. A director of a certified association may serve as an ex officio nonvoting member of the council. </section><section prefix="4">No more than one (1) representative from any company or its affiliate may serve on the council at any time. </section><section prefix="5">In nominating members to the council, a certified association shall consider broad-based representation including: <section prefix="a">Gas processors and oil refiners among producers; </section><section prefix="b">Interstate and intrastate operators among retail marketers; </section><section prefix="c">Large and small companies among producers, suppliers, and retail marketers; and </section><section prefix="d">Diverse geographic regions of the state. </section></section><section prefix="6">Council members shall serve three (3) year terms except that for initial appointments, four (4) members shall be appointed to one (1) year terms, four (4) members to two (2) year terms, and three (3) members to three (3) year terms. Within ninety (90) days after July 15, 1998, certified industry trade organizations shall submit nominations to the commissioner. No member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="7">Council members shall receive no compensation for their services. Only the public member may be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses directly related to attendance at council meetings. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 509, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11018</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>