<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.804</section_number><catch_line>Agritourism Advisory Council -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>804</order_by><text>An Agritourism Advisory Council shall be established within the Department of Agriculture to advise and assist the Office of Agritourism. The Agritourism Advisory Council shall be composed of: <section prefix="1">One (1) representative from each of the following entities: <section prefix="a">Department of Agriculture, appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="b">Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, appointed by the secretary of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, appointed by the secretary of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="d">Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources Commission, appointed by the commissioner of the department; </section><section prefix="e">University of Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service; </section><section prefix="f">Kentucky Tourism Council; </section><section prefix="g">Kentucky Farm Bureau; </section><section prefix="h">Kentucky Association of Fairs and Horse Shows; </section><section prefix="i">Southern and Eastern Kentucky Tourism Development Association; </section><section prefix="j">Licking River Valley Resource Conservation and Development Council; </section><section prefix="k">Buffalo Trace Covered Bridge Authority; </section><section prefix="l">Kentucky Chamber of Commerce; </section><section prefix="m">Kentucky Council of Area Development Districts; and </section><section prefix="n">Jackson Purchase Resource Conservation and Development Foundation, Inc.; </section></section><section prefix="2">The Governor, or a designee; </section><section prefix="3">Two (2) members of the General Assembly who hold an interest in agriculture, one (1) appointed by the President of the Senate and one (1) appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and </section><section prefix="4">Nine (9) representatives of agriculture or the agritourism industry, appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture from a list of candidates compiled by the tourism regions as set forth in KRS 247.802(4). Each tourism region shall submit three (3) candidates with a business interest in agritourism who reside within that region, and the Commissioner shall appoint one (1) candidate from each region from those names submitted. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 64, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 65, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 211, sec. 126, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 50, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  This section was amended by 2009 Ky. Acts chs. 11 and 16, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11831</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>