<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.030</section_number><catch_line>Duties of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall be the executive and administrative head of the cabinet and shall supervise and control all examinations and work of the cabinet. He shall advise the board on matters pertaining to the classified service of this state. Within the limitations of the budget, the secretary shall appoint and supervise the staff needed in the cabinet to carry out the purposes of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 except employees of the board who shall be appointed as provided in KRS 18A.090. </section><section prefix="2">Subject to the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13A, the secretary shall, with the aid of his staff: <section prefix="a">Attend all meetings of the board; </section><section prefix="b">As provided by this chapter, promulgate comprehensive administrative regulations consistent with the provisions of KRS Chapters 13A and 18A, and with federal standards for the administration of a personnel system in the agencies of the state government receiving federal grants; </section><section prefix="c">Establish general procedures for personnel recruitment, for certification, and for improving the efficiency of employed personnel; </section><section prefix="d">Appoint the examiners and technicians necessary for the conduct of the personnel program, whether on a permanent or temporary basis; </section><section prefix="e">Prepare and maintain a record of all employees, showing for each employee his name, address, title of position held, rate of compensation, changes in status, compensation, or title, transfer, and to make the data and the class specifications for all positions available to the press and public; </section><section prefix="f">Prepare, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 and the administrative regulations adopted thereunder, examinations, eligible lists, and ratings of candidates for appointment; </section><section prefix="g">Make certification for appointment or promotion within the classified service, in accordance with the provisions of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200; </section><section prefix="h">Make investigations concerning all matters touching the enforcement and effect of the provisions of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 and administrative regulations prescribed thereunder; </section><section prefix="i">Prepare, in cooperation with appointing authorities and others, programs for employee training, safety, morale, work motivation, health, counseling, and welfare, and exercise leadership in the development of effective personnel administration within the several departments of the Commonwealth, and make available the facilities of the department to this end; </section><section prefix="j">Provide personnel services to unclassified employees in agreement with the agencies involved not otherwise provided for in KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200; </section><section prefix="k">Present, in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 48, budget requests for the support of the personnel system created by KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200, excluding the board, which shall present its own budget estimates; </section><section prefix="l">Make a report and submit the same to the board, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Governor not later than October first of each year; </section><section prefix="m">Propose selection method changes for any classification to the Personnel Board with documentation justifying the need for the selection method change. The Personnel Board shall, at its next regularly scheduled monthly meeting, review and comment on any proposed selection method change. A classification shall not have its selection method changed without review and comment by the Personnel Board; and </section><section prefix="n">Discharge the other duties imposed upon him by KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200. </section></section><section prefix="3">The secretary on behalf of the cabinet may join or subscribe to any association or service having as its purpose the interchange of information relating to the improvement of the public service and especially improvement of personnel administration. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary shall keep records relative to employee turnover and report to the board, the Governor, and the Legislative Research Commission quarterly. The report shall reflect employee turnover rates by cabinet, department, bureau, division, and section. If any cabinet, department, bureau, division, or section has a turnover rate of fifteen percent (15%) or more in any twelve (12) month period, the secretary shall conduct an investigation into the reasons for the turnover and report the findings to the board, the Governor, and the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary shall provide to each new state employee and to each existing state employee, classified or otherwise, on an annual basis an informational pamphlet about human immunodeficiency virus infection and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. The pamphlet shall be approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and shall contain information about the nature and extent of these diseases, methods of transmission, preventive measures, and referral services. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary shall establish and maintain a list of all filled positions exempted from classified service under KRS 18A.115(1) (e), (g), (h), (i), (k), (t), (w), (aa), and (ab). The list shall include the following information for each filled position: <section prefix="a">The name of the agency where the position is assigned; </section><section prefix="b">The statutory authority for the unclassified status of the position; </section><section prefix="c">The title of the position; </section><section prefix="d">The pay grade of the position; </section><section prefix="e">The annual salary of the employee in the position; and </section><section prefix="f">The work county of the employee in the position. </section></section><section prefix="7">Beginning September 1, 2010, and every six (6) months thereafter, the secretary shall provide the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission with a copy of the list described in subsection (6) of this section, and shall indicate on the list any position that has been added to the list since the last submission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 2, effective April 13, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 95, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 77, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 31, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.030, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982; and amended ch. 450, sec. 53, effective July 1, 1983. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 4. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 5. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.190. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1342</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>