<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="172" order_by="172">COUNTY LAW LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>172.110</section_number><catch_line>Circuit clerk is librarian -- Duties -- Salary -- Inventory. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The circuit clerk shall be ex officio librarian of the county law library, and he shall see that county and state officials have access to the library at reasonable hours each day except Sunday and holidays. He shall receive a salary of not less than fifty dollars ($50) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) per month for his services as librarian. </section><section prefix="2">He shall keep the library rooms in order, preserve, arrange and index all the books, charts, maps and furniture belonging in the library, and see that no books or other things are taken from the library rooms without a receipt being given therefor. </section><section prefix="3">He shall receipt for all books, maps and furniture placed in the library. The receipts shall be given to the state law librarian and preserved in his office at Frankfort. </section><section prefix="4">He shall take an inventory each December of all the books, maps, charts or other property in the library belonging to the state and report the inventory under oath to the state law librarian before January 1 of the following year. </section></text><history>Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 22. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2438c-8. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4890</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>