<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.716</section_number><catch_line>Nonresident licensees -- Service of process -- Credit for out-of-state training programs. </catch_line><order_by>716</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A nonresident whom the board determines meets the requirements of KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 and who files the written consent described in subsection (2) of this section may be licensed as a home inspector in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">A nonresident applicant shall file with the board a written consent stating that, if licensed: <section prefix="a">The applicant agrees to the commencement of any action arising out of the conduct of the applicant's business in Kentucky in the county in which the events giving rise to the cause of action occurred; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant: <section prefix="1">Agrees to provide to the board the name and address of an agent to receive service of process in Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="2">Consents to the board acting as the applicant's agent for the purpose of receiving service of process if: <section prefix="a">An agent's name and address have not been filed with the board; or </section><section prefix="b">The agent's name and address on file with the board are incorrect; and </section></section></section><section prefix="c">The applicant agrees that service of process in accordance with the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure is proper service and subjects the applicant to the jurisdiction of Kentucky courts. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board may consider and accept the successful completion by a nonresident of a training program or course of study completed in another state in lieu of the requirements of KRS 198B.712(3)(c) if the board determines the training program or course of study meets or exceeds the requirements of KRS 198B.712(3)(c) and its implementing administrative regulations, or the board may give credit for such program or course of study towards meeting the requirements of KRS 198B.712(3)(c). The nonresident shall still be subject to the examination requirements of KRS 198B.712(3)(c). </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 9, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7087</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>