<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-213</section_number><catch_line>Consultation with governmental agencies, studies and projections, development offices, and promotional advertising by cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>12-213</order_by><text>The cabinet, as it deems necessary and advisable, may: <section prefix="1">Consult with agencies of the state, federal, and local government in order to coordinate development programs and plans and to articulate agriculture, industry, and commerce in the light of the needs of particular localities; </section><section prefix="2">Make studies of land utilization so as to determine areas suitable for industrial and commercial development; </section><section prefix="3">Make studies and projections and publish information relating to the economic development of the Commonwealth and make appropriate recommendations to the board and the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="4">Establish and maintain development offices in out-of-state centers of industrial and commercial management; </section><section prefix="5">Place advertising in appropriate media promoting Kentucky's resources and locational advantages for industrial and commercial enterprises. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. – Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 154.12-213, 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 69, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 4. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 4. -- Created 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. IX, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 152.080 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2631</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>