<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.080</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>Each board of directors shall have the power and authority to: <section prefix="1">Adopt and have a common seal and alter the same at pleasure; </section><section prefix="2">Sue and be sued; </section><section prefix="3">Adopt bylaws and make rules and regulations for the conduct of its business; </section><section prefix="4">Make and enter into all contracts or agreements necessary or incidental to the performance of its duties; </section><section prefix="5">Provide upon request basic administrative, research, and planning services for any planning and development body located within the district; </section><section prefix="6">Accept, receive, and administer loans, grants, or other funds or gifts from public and private agencies including the Commonwealth and the federal government for the purpose of carrying out the functions of the district; </section><section prefix="7">Expend such funds as may be considered by it to be advisable or necessary in the performance of its duties; </section><section prefix="8">Acquire, hold as may be necessary and convenient, encumber, or dispose of real and personal property, except that no board shall have the power of eminent domain; </section><section prefix="9">Charge fees, rents, and otherwise charge for services provided by the board, except that no board shall have any power to levy taxes; </section><section prefix="10">Enter into interlocal agreements or interstate compacts to the extent authorized by laws of the Commonwealth. An area development district organization shall be deemed a "public agency" as defined by the Interlocal Cooperation Act in KRS Chapter 65; </section><section prefix="11">Promote, organize, and advise special districts or other authorities in accordance with laws of the Commonwealth and act as the regional clearinghouse for such programs and projects as prescribed by federal regulation; </section><section prefix="12">Perform such other and further acts as may be necessary to carry out the duties and responsibilities created by KRS 147A.050 to 147A.120. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 29, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1655</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>