<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.660</section_number><catch_line>Department to administer program for ginseng -- Regulations. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The department shall administer a program for ginseng in Kentucky which provides a framework, including a limited harvesting season, in which ginseng shall be eligible for exportation in compliance with federal requirements. </section><section prefix="b">Information relating to the purchase or sale of ginseng that is furnished to or acquired by the department shall constitute proprietary information and not be subject to public disclosure, except to the extent the department deems necessary in any administrative or judicial proceeding involving the administration or enforcement of its administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out this </section>program and may enter into agreements with any other agency of this state, any other state, or the federal government to carry out this program. <section prefix="b">The department shall establish licensing requirements for dealers of ginseng. </section><section prefix="c">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations relating to the ginseng program that establish: <section prefix="1">A comprehensive set of administrative violations and civil penalties, each not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000); and </section><section prefix="2">The procedure for the suspension or revocation of any license or certificate issued by the department. </section></section></section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 08, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>