<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.420</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of corporation. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text>The Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation: <section prefix="1">Shall supervise construction of the Kentucky Center for the Arts in conjunction with the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and shall provide all management functions for the facility and for any other property acquired or leased pursuant to its powers under this section; </section><section prefix="2">May take, acquire and hold property, and all interests therein, by deed, purchase, gift, devise, bequest, lease or eminent domain, or by transfer from the State Property and Buildings Commission, and may dispose of any property so acquired in any manner provided by law. In the exercise of its power of eminent domain, it shall proceed in the manner provided in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky, KRS 416.540 to 416.680; </section><section prefix="3">May consult or enter into agreements with other segments of the arts and entertainment industry to provide technical, professional, or management support or assistance, consistent with its purpose and mission; </section><section prefix="4">May issue revenue bonds, subject to procedures which shall be established by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, solely payable from the charges, revenues, rentals, and other funds pledged for their payment for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any project or for the acquisition of property; </section><section prefix="5">Shall promote the growth and development of the arts, convention trade, tourism and the hotel industry within Jefferson County and the Commonwealth, through utilization of the Kentucky center and activities authorized in this section to enhance these and the public interest; </section><section prefix="6">May adopt administrative regulations, as provided in KRS Chapter 13A, governing the operation, maintenance or use of property under its custody and control; </section><section prefix="7">May levy a surcharge on tickets for all functions held within the center to contribute to operating revenue; </section><section prefix="8">May receive tax revenues from any governmental unit, and financial contributions of local governments, private persons and foundations; </section><section prefix="9">Shall have exclusive control of all exhibitions, performances and concessions in the Center for the Arts. The corporation shall have a prior lien upon the property of any private exhibitor, concessionaire, or other person holding an exhibition or performance or operating a concession in the center, and may sell such property upon ten (10) days' notice to satisfy any indebtedness; </section><section prefix="10">Shall develop in conjunction with local hotels, and the arts and entertainment industry, tourist packages including performance and group plans, and shall participate with local hotels and convention bureaus in attracting non-arts related conferences and conventions; </section><section prefix="11">May establish an executive committee from among its membership with full authority to act between its meetings to the extent delegated by the corporation; </section><section prefix="12">May sue and be sued and maintain and defend legal actions in its corporate name; </section><section prefix="13">May, if the corporation elects, be exempt from the provisions of KRS 56.065 to 56.180, and, with the approval of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the Department of Insurance, purchase from the funds allotted to the corporation property insurance for buildings and contents from responsible insurance companies doing business in this state; and </section><section prefix="14">May purchase liability insurance for the protection of the corporation and its employees from liability arising in the operation of the center. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 190, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 382, sec. 3, effective April 9, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2482</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>