<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.5277</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 64.5277 to 64.5279. </catch_line><order_by>5277</order_by><text>As used in KRS 64.5277 to 64.5279: <section prefix="1">"City" means: <section prefix="a">Any city of any class; </section><section prefix="b">An urban-county government that does not participate in the county officers training program under KRS 64.5275; and </section><section prefix="c">A consolidated local government that does not participate in the county officers training program under KRS 64.5275; </section></section><section prefix="2">"City officer" means: <section prefix="a">Any individual elected to a city office existing under KRS Chapter 83A; </section><section prefix="b">Any individual elected to a city office existing under KRS Chapter 67A or 67C, if the respective government does not participate in the county officers training program under KRS 64.5275; </section><section prefix="c">Any individual appointed to fill a vacancy in an elected city office as defined under paragraph (a) or (b) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="d">Any individual serving in a nonelected city office as defined by KRS 83A.080 that is designated by the city as eligible for participation in the city officers training program in the ordinance adopted pursuant to KRS 64.5278; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Training incentive multiplier" means a number of one (1) to four (4) that is used to calculate the final training incentive to be paid to a city officer eligible to participate in the training incentive program; and </section><section prefix="4">"Training unit" means fifteen (15) clock hours of attendance or participation in qualifying courses during a calendar year. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).The order of subsections (3) and (4) in 2011 Ky. Acts. ch.44, sec.1, has been reversed so that definitions in this section are now in alphabetical order. The Reviser of Statutes has rearranged these subsections under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39695</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>