<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.440</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of employees of former health agencies. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the board has qualified and organized as herein provided, the employees of the department of public health of such city, and the employees of the county health department of such county, at that time in their employ, shall be transferred to and continued in the service of the board herein created. Provided, however, any and all of such employees who at said time are in the classified service of such city or county health departments shall be continued in the classified service of the board as herein provided, and shall be given and have in the classified service of the board the same status they had in the classified service of said city and county health departments, respectively. </section><section prefix="2">When the board has qualified and organized as herein provided, the employees of any board of tuberculosis hospital in such county, at that time in its employ, shall be transferred to and continued in the service of the board herein created. Said employees, except as provided in any law or laws, or amendment thereof, or any rules and regulations issued pursuant thereto governing any city board or commission empowered to administer and enforce civil service laws, rules and regulations in and for such city, herein made applicable to the board, shall then and thereafter be subject to said laws, rules and regulations. Provided, however, the employees then holding such offices, positions, or places of employment which are within the classified service, as herein provided for, shall be considered as having satisfied all of the qualifications for obtaining original appointment under such law, or laws, and shall be considered as having been given probationary appointments as defined in such law or laws of the date they are so placed in the classified service thereunder. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8627</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>