<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.603</section_number><catch_line>Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Advisory Council -- Membership, duties, and personnel. </catch_line><order_by>603</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disorders Advisory Council is created. The council shall report directly to the office. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall be composed of a minimum of fifteen (15) members appointed by the Governor. Three (3) members shall represent agencies of state government dealing with dementia, three (3) shall represent local health departments, one (1) shall represent the University of Kentucky Alzheimer's Disease Research Center at the Sanders-Brown Center on Aging, at least one (1) shall be appointed from each of the chapters of the Alzheimer's Disease and Related Disease Association that serve the Commonwealth, and the remainder shall represent consumers, health-care providers, and the medical research community. Members who are not state employees shall be reimbursed for necessary and actual expenses. The council shall meet quarterly. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the council's business. </section><section prefix="3">The council shall: <section prefix="a">Elect its own chairperson and establish other officers and subcommittees as needed to execute the duties of the council; </section><section prefix="b">Adopt bylaws and operate under its bylaws; </section><section prefix="c">Select the director of the office; </section><section prefix="d">Establish and evaluate goals and outcomes for the office that may facilitate treatment and care of persons with dementia; </section><section prefix="e">Assist with the dissemination of information about the availability of program materials, education materials, and curriculum guides; and </section><section prefix="f">Prepare a report of its activities, at least annually, for submission to the office. </section></section><section prefix="4">The office shall provide requested personnel to assist the council in fulfilling its responsibilities. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6692</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>