<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.400</section_number><catch_line>Energy Cost Assistance Program established -- Eligibility requirements -- Allocation of funds -- Payments. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services an Energy Cost Assistance Program for making money payments to or on behalf of citizens of the Commonwealth for the purpose of purchasing or supplementing the cost of energy for household use. </section><section prefix="2">Citizens of the Commonwealth who incur expenses for providing energy by purchase from suppliers, by their own labors, or through the payment of rent, whether or not included in a charge for other goods and services, which includes the cost of energy supplied to premises occupied as their principal residence, shall be eligible to receive the benefit of the payments to themselves or to providers of energy to such household if: <section prefix="a">The citizen is sixty-two (62) years of age or older and has or is a member of a family having a gross income equal to or less than one hundred twenty-five percent (125%) of the poverty level of income for an individual or family of that size designated by the Community Services Administration of the United States government; or </section><section prefix="b">The citizen is blind or permanently and totally disabled and receiving supplemental security income benefits under the Social Security Act or is blind or permanently and totally disabled and is currently eligible for Medicaid benefits under the Medical Assistance Program. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall establish by regulation a schedule of payments and benefit levels under this program to be based on income, resources, and family size. In no event shall payments be made to or on behalf of any person or family whose gross income from all sources exceeds one hundred twenty-five percent (125%) of the poverty level of income as provided for such individuals or family by the Community Services Administration of the United States government. </section><section prefix="4">Payments made under this section shall be for a period of four (4) months during each twelve (12) month period for which funds are available. At its discretion and to insure the proper application of the funds appropriated for this purpose, the cabinet may elect to make payments to vendors or suppliers or jointly to vendors and eligible recipients. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 225, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 192, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7685</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>