<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.260</section_number><catch_line>Small Coal Operators Advisory Council. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text>There is hereby created a Small Coal Operators Advisory Council which shall report directly to the secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet. The council shall advise on matters affecting coal production and utilization including coal market development, transportation, and storage problems. The council shall have the function of coordinating and improving the working relationships between those state agencies administering programs which regulate, serve, or aid small coal mine operators. The council shall consist of fifteen (15) members. Ten (10) of those members shall be appointed by the Governor. Seven (7) of the ten (10) members shall be full-time operators producing three hundred thousand (300,000) or fewer tons of coal per year. Three (3) of the ten (10) appointees shall be with backgrounds in one (1) or more of the following areas: transportation, marketing, mining education, and mining engineering. The secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the commissioners of the Department of Agriculture and the Department for Natural Resources, and the special assistant to the Governor for coal and energy policy shall be ex officio members. Each individual appointment shall be for a four (4) year term which shall begin on July 15, 1984. Members may serve successive terms if reappointed. Vacancies shall be filled in a manner consistent with the provisions for initial appointments. At the first meeting held on or after July 1 of each year, a chairman shall be elected by and from the membership. The council shall meet at least quarterly during each year and may meet more often at the call of the chairman. The council shall be attached to the Energy and Environment Cabinet for administrative purposes. Council members shall be eligible for reimbursement by the cabinet for actual expenses directly related to serving on the council. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1884, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 53, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 64, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32831</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>