<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.353</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by malt beverage storage license -- Issuance of temporary storage license in case of emergency. </catch_line><order_by>353</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A malt beverage storage license may be issued as a supplementary license to a distributor's license, a nonquota retail malt beverage package license, or a Nonquota type 4 retail malt beverage drink license. A malt beverage storage license may also be issued as a primary or supplementary license in conformity with administrative regulations promulgated by the department. </section><section prefix="2">The holder of a malt beverage storage license may: <section prefix="a">Store malt beverages at the storage licensed premises convenient to his or her regular retail malt beverage licensed premises; </section><section prefix="b">Transport the malt beverages as belonging to the holder of the license to and from the warehouse by way of the nearest route to his or her regular licensed retail malt beverage premises, if the licensee sells no malt beverages except at his or her regular malt beverage licensed premises; </section><section prefix="c">Transport and store malt beverages belonging to the distributor to, from, and at the storage licensed premises; and </section><section prefix="d">Conduct business as authorized by the department through the promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="3">The malt beverage administrator may issue a temporary storage license to a licensed distributor for storage of malt beverages if there is an emergency. The malt beverage administrator shall have sole discretion to determine the existence of any emergency. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 18, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 32, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43040</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>