<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.350</section_number><catch_line>Organization and function of state federation. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text>Any state federation organized pursuant to KRS 247.330 and 247.340 shall have the following organization and function in the following manner: <section prefix="1">The said federation shall hold an annual meeting at a date to be fixed by its bylaws, which annual meeting may be referred to as the "annual convention" of said federation; </section><section prefix="2">Each county farm bureau shall be entitled to no less than two (2) voting delegates at the annual convention of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation. When a county farm bureau has received, during the fiscal year ending prior to said state convention, one hundred fifty (150) paid-in regular memberships, as defined in the bylaws of the federation, each additional one hundred (100) paid-in regular memberships or major portion thereof shall entitle the county farm bureau to an additional voting delegate. No voting delegate shall vote by proxy, unless the proxy is in writing in a form approved by the board of directors of the state federation; </section><section prefix="3">The governing body of said state federation shall consist of a board of directors of not less than seven (7) members. The distribution of said directors shall be by state federation districts, and set forth in the bylaws of the corporation. Each director shall be elected for a term of two (2) years, shall be a resident of the district from which he is elected, must be actively engaged in farming, or evidencing a primary interest therein by reason of his position or occupation, and shall be nominated by the voting delegates of said district and elected by a majority vote of the voting delegates voting either in person or by proxy at said election; </section><section prefix="4">Said state federation, by bylaws, shall have authority to provide for additional directors representing cooperating agricultural agencies; </section><section prefix="5">The officers of said federation shall consist of a president, a first vice president, and a second vice president, who shall be elected by majority vote cast by the voting delegates at the annual convention, and there shall be an executive officer of the corporation, who shall be elected by the board of directors, and who shall be an ex officio member of the board, without power to vote; and </section><section prefix="6">The board of directors shall select from its membership an executive committee composed of three (3) persons, and said committee shall have general charge of the management of the business of the federation in the interim between meetings of the board of directors and shall possess such powers, duties and responsibilities as may be provided in the bylaws of the federation or by resolution of the board of directors. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986 -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 6, effective June 19, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42d-18. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11627</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>