<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="14" order_by="14">DEPARTMENT OF STATE </unit></structure><section_number>14.312</section_number><catch_line>Program participants to vote by mail-in absentee ballot -- Modification of county clerk's system to safeguard confidentiality of participant's voting records -- No waiver or modification of legal qualifications to vote.   </catch_line><order_by>312</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A program participant who is otherwise qualified to vote may register to vote and apply for and submit a mail-in absentee ballot under this section. </section><section prefix="2">Using the authority granted under KRS 14.318(1), the State Board of Elections shall design a system allowing a county clerk to shield from public view all voting records of a program participant, including the name and address of a program participant, and allowing a program participant to vote by mail-in absentee ballot. This authority may be used to modify statutory or regulatory requirements that would lead to disclosure of the program participant's name and address, but shall not include authority to waive or modify any other requirements relative to the program participant's qualifications to vote, including age and geographic residency. </section><section prefix="3">The program participant may receive mail-in absentee ballots for all elections in the jurisdiction in which that individual resides in the same manner as a person requesting an absentee ballot under KRS 117.085(1)(a). The county clerk shall transmit a mail-in absentee ballot to the program participant at the address designated by the participant in his or her application. </section><section prefix="4">Neither the name nor the address of a program participant shall be included in any list of registered voters available to the public, including any list inspected under KRS 116.095. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>