<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">MOTOR VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190.085</section_number><catch_line>Civic event license plate. </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A vehicle which has been donated or loaned by a licensed motor vehicle dealer for use in a civic event may be operated during preparation for and during the civic event with a civic event license plate. </section><section prefix="2">Application for approval of the use of a civic event license plate shall be made to the Department of Vehicle Regulation on forms prescribed and furnished by the department at least sixty (60) days prior to the event. The licensed motor vehicle dealer in his application shall provide the name of the event for which the motor vehicles will be used, date and duration of the event, the number of vehicles to be loaned or donated and other information required by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. The application shall be accompanied by five dollars ($5) for each civic event license plate applied for. The commissioner of the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall approve or deny the use of the license plate within thirty (30) days after receiving the application and inform the dealer as to his decision. </section><section prefix="3">At least ten (10) days prior to the date approved for the use of civic event license plate, the motor vehicle dealer shall provide to the department the vehicle identification number for each vehicle which is anticipated to be lent or donated to the civic event. </section><section prefix="4">Any motor vehicle bearing a civic event license plate authorized by subsection (1) of this section shall be restricted to use in providing services for events for which approval is granted. The services may include, but not be limited to, parades, transportation of visitors or dignitaries to and from event activities, use by event personnel or event volunteers and any other activity for which a vehicle may be required in the furtherance of the civic event. </section><section prefix="5">The use of the civic event license plate shall be limited to the time set forth in the approved application. A copy of the approved application shall be carried in the vehicle at all times. When the civic event license plate expires, the dealer shall remove the plate and return it to the Department of Vehicle Regulation. The vehicle shall then be registered in a manner required by KRS Chapter 186. A misuse of civic event license plates shall be deemed a violation of the motor vehicle dealer's license. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Vehicle Regulation may promulgate administrative regulations to implement this section. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6559</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>