<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.243</section_number><catch_line>Service capacity upgrade fund. </catch_line><order_by>243</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created within the State Treasury a special fund known as the service capacity upgrade fund that shall be administered separate and apart from all public money or funds of the state. </section><section prefix="2">The service capacity upgrade fund shall be used solely for acquisition and upgrading of the technology base, program integrity functions, and service delivery capacity in support of the programs administered by the Office of Employment and Training. The secretary shall have full power, authority, and jurisdiction over the fund, including all money, property, and securities belonging thereto, and shall perform any act necessary or convenient in the administration of the fund consistent with this section. The secretary shall provide an annual report to the Interim Joint Committee on Labor and Industry detailing all receipts and expenditures of the fund. </section><section prefix="3">Any money collected under the provisions of this section shall be invested at interest in banks or other interest-bearing obligations of the United States. Investments shall at all times be made so that all the assets of the service capacity upgrade fund shall be convertible into cash when needed for the payment of expenses incurred in upgrading the service capacity of the Office of Employment and Training. All interest income received under this section shall be credited to the fund. The State Treasurer shall dispose of securities or other property belonging to the fund only under the direction of the secretary and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Effective January 1, 1999, all rates otherwise established under KRS 341.270 and 341.272 shall be reduced by subtracting seventy-five thousandths percent (0.075%) from each rate, but only if the trust fund balance as of December 31 of the preceding year is equal to or greater than one and eighteen hundredths percent (1.18%) of the total wages paid in the state during the state fiscal year ended as of June 30 of that year. <section prefix="a">If the trust fund balance as of December 31, 1999, is less than the trust fund balance as of December 31, 1998, the amount of the rate reduction for calendar year 2000 shall be reduced by forty percent (40%) to the level of forty-five thousandths percent (0.045%). </section><section prefix="b">If the trust fund balance as of December 31, 2000, is less than the trust fund balance as of December 31, 1999, the amount of the rate reduction for calendar year 2001 shall be forty percent (40%) less than the amount of the rate reduction which was in effect in calendar year 2000. </section></section><section prefix="5">For any calendar year in which all rates have been reduced in accordance with subsection (4) of this section, all contributory employers shall pay into the service capacity upgrade fund an amount equal to the percentage by which rates were reduced multiplied by their taxable wages paid during that calendar year. Payments shall be made at the same time and in the same manner as prescribed for payment of contributions under KRS 341.260 and all regulations prescribed by the secretary in support of that section. The restrictions in KRS 341.470(1) apply equally to the provisions of this section. Failure to make these payments shall be subject to interest and all other collection actions provided for failure to make contributions under KRS 341.300. </section><section prefix="6">All payments required under subsection (5) of this section, along with any interest due to late payment of these assessments, shall be deposited in the service capacity upgrade fund. </section><section prefix="7">The provisions of this section shall expire with regard to rates assigned for calendar years beginning after December 31, 2001, and any balance of moneys or property in the fund not expended or obligated for purposes consistent with this section by June 30, 2002, shall be deposited in the unemployment insurance trust fund. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 140, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>