<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.145</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky National Guard and Reserve Employers' Council -- Membership -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a committee to be known as the Kentucky National Guard and Reserve Employers' Council, which shall be attached to the Office of the Adjutant General for administrative purposes only. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall be composed of the following: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Kentucky Personnel Cabinet or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members appointed by the President of the Senate, selected from a list of five (5) names submitted by each of the following organizations: <section prefix="1">Associated Industries of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Chamber of Commerce; and </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Chapter of the National Federation of Independent Business; </section></section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, selected from a list of five (5) names submitted by each of the following organizations: <section prefix="1">The Kentucky League of Cities; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Association of Counties; and </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky State AFL-CIO; and </section></section><section prefix="d">One (1) member appointed by the Governor, selected from a list of five (5) names submitted by the Kentuckiana Chapter of Associated Builders and Contractors. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall select one (1) of the appointed members as chairman. </section><section prefix="4">Initially, three (3) of the members shall be appointed to serve for a period of four (4) years, two (2) of the members shall be appointed to serve for a period of three (3) years, and two (2) of the members shall be appointed to serve for a period of two (2) years. Thereafter, members shall be appointed for a period of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="5">Members shall serve without pay, and shall not be reimbursed for travel expenses. </section><section prefix="6">A majority of members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="7">The council shall meet as often as necessary, but it shall meet not less than two (2) and not more than six (6) times annually. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2003).  Although 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, directed that this section be created as a new section of KRS Chapter 40, the statute has been codified in KRS Chapter 36 because, given the subject matter of the section, this is the more logical placement. See KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21445</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>