<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-120</section_number><catch_line>Purposes of council. </catch_line><order_by>47-120</order_by><text>The council shall cooperate with the Cabinet for Economic Development and with wood products industries applying for economic revitalization and development project inducements for the following purposes: <section prefix="1">To analyze the impacts of an applicant's projects on forest productivity and watershed protection; </section><section prefix="2">To develop a comprehensive program that addresses those impacts in the proposed procurement area through the appropriate use of: <section prefix="a">Best management practices as established in Kentucky Forest Practices Guidelines published by the Division of Forestry of the Department for Natural Resources; </section><section prefix="b">Logger education, training, and contracting programs; </section><section prefix="c">Forest stewardship and other assistance programs for landowners; and </section><section prefix="d">Ground water protection plans; and </section></section><section prefix="3">To develop measures to ensure that the program developed for the procurement area becomes an integral part of the applicant's plan. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 224, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was created by 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 4, and ch. 224, sec. 20, which are substantively identical and have been codified together. In resolving minor variations, Acts ch. 224, the later enactment, has been given precedence. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2950</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>