<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.090</section_number><catch_line>Citizen advisory bodies -- Public Health Services Advisory Council -- Institute for Aging -- Council for Families and Children. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall include citizen advisory bodies within its structure to provide independent advice from the general public. </section><section prefix="2">A Public Health Services Advisory Council is created within the cabinet. <section prefix="a">The council may advise the secretary for health and family services, the commissioner for public health, and officials of the Commonwealth on policy matters concerning the delivery of health services, including the assessment of needs, the development of program alternatives, the determination of priorities, the formulation of policy, the allocation of resources, and the evaluation of programs. The council shall be utilized by the cabinet to fulfill federal requirements for citizen's advisory councils associated with programs designed to provide health services and to advise the cabinet on the development and content of the state health plan. </section><section prefix="b">The council shall be composed of no more than nineteen (19) citizen members appointed by the Governor. Six (6) members of the council shall be chosen to broadly represent public interest groups concerned with health services, recipients of health services provided by the Commonwealth, minority groups, and the general public. Thirteen (13) members of the council shall represent providers of health care and not less than one-half (1/2) of the providers shall be direct providers of health care. At least one (1) of the direct providers of health care shall be a person engaged in the administration of a hospital, and one (1) shall be a physician in active practice. At least one (1) member shall be a registered sanitarian or sanitary engineer, one (1) a public health nurse, one (1) a member of the current minority advisory council, and one (1) a practicing public health physician. Nominations for health care provider members of the council shall be solicited from recognized health care provider organizations. Membership of the council shall be geographically distributed in order that area development districts are represented. Members shall serve for terms of three (3) years. If a vacancy occurs, the person appointed as a replacement shall serve only for the remainder of the vacated term. Members shall serve until the term begins for their appointed successors. No member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. The chair of the council shall be appointed by the Governor. The secretary for health and family services and the commissioner for public health shall be nonvoting, ex officio members of the council, and the commissioner for public health shall be a staff director for, and secretary to, the council. The council shall meet at least quarterly and on other occasions as may be necessary on the call of the secretary for health and family services or the commissioner for public health. A majority of the appointed members shall constitute a quorum. </section></section><section prefix="3">An Institute for Aging is created within the cabinet. <section prefix="a">The institute shall advise the secretary for health and family services and other officials of the Commonwealth on policy matters relating to the development and delivery of services to the aged. </section><section prefix="b">The institute shall be composed of no more than fifteen (15) citizen members appointed by the Governor. Members of the institute shall be chosen to broadly represent public interest groups concerned with the needs of the aged, professionals involved in the delivery of services to the aged, minority groups, recipients of state-provided services to the aged, and the general public. The Governor shall appoint a chair of the institute. The secretary for health and family services shall be a nonvoting, ex officio member of, staff director for, and secretary to the institute. The institute shall meet at least quarterly and on other occasions as may be necessary, on the call of the secretary for health and family services. A majority of the appointed members shall constitute a quorum. </section></section><section prefix="4">A Council for Families and Children is created within the cabinet. <section prefix="a">The council may advise the secretary for health and family services, the commissioner for community based services, and other officials of the Commonwealth on policy matters relating to the human service needs. </section><section prefix="b">The council shall be composed of no more than twenty-one (21) citizen members appointed by the Governor. Members of the council shall be chosen to broadly represent public interest groups concerned with social insurance and social service programs operated by the Commonwealth, professionals involved in the delivery of human services, minority groups, the poor, the disadvantaged, recipients of human services provided by the state, and the general public. The Governor shall appoint the chair of the council. The secretary for health and family services and the commissioner for community based services shall be nonvoting, ex officio members of the council, and the commissioner for community based services shall be staff director for, and secretary to, the council. The council shall meet at least quarterly and on other occasions as may be necessary, on call of the secretary for health and family services. A majority of appointed members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="c">When the Council for Families and Children is assigned a responsibility for qualifying the Commonwealth for federal programs with representations and membership formulas that conflict with the council's membership, the secretary may create special subcommittees to this citizens' body that meet federal requirements. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 27, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6645</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>