<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.920</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Family Health Care Providers. </catch_line><order_by>920</order_by><text>There is hereby created the Kentucky Board of Family Health Care Providers. <section prefix="1">The board shall be composed of one (1) representative from each of the following organizations: the Kentucky Medical Association, the Kentucky Nursing Association, a physician from the Kentucky Public Health Association, the Kentucky Dental Association, the Kentucky Hospital Association, the Kentucky Primary Care Association, the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, the Kentucky Board of Nursing, the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy, the Kentucky Academy of Family Practitioners, a physician from either family practice or community medicine representing each of the colleges of medicine in the Commonwealth, and a consumer. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Certify new midlevel health-care practitioners, recertify midlevel health-care practitioners annually, and revoke certification as necessary; </section><section prefix="b">Develop and administer qualifying examinations for midlevel health-care practitioners to test knowledge of the most frequently occurring protocols; </section><section prefix="c">Identify continuing education requirements for midlevel health-care practitioners and qualify the continuing education courses provided to them; </section><section prefix="d">Approve or prescribe the treatment protocols utilized by each network; </section><section prefix="e">Approve the quality assurance programs of each network; </section><section prefix="f">Approve the drug formulary used by each network; and </section><section prefix="g">Issue administrative regulations necessary to implement this section and KRS 216.925. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall meet at least quarterly. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide necessary staff assistance to the board and shall reimburse board members at the rate of reimbursement for the advisory councils and committees. </section><section prefix="4">Applicants for certification and recertification shall pay a fee of fifty dollars ($50). These fees shall be placed in a trust and agency fund and shall be used to cover the cost of board operations and the administration of examinations. </section><section prefix="5">Upon appeal of a board decision, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 499, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 446, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 119, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9148</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>