<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5307Duties</section_number><catch_line>of support enforcement agency.   </catch_line><order_by>5307Duties</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A support enforcement agency of this state, upon request, shall provide services to a petitioner in a proceeding under this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">A support enforcement agency of this state that is providing services to the petitioner shall: <section prefix="a">Take all steps necessary to enable an appropriate tribunal of this state, another state, or a foreign country to obtain jurisdiction over the respondent; </section><section prefix="b">Request an appropriate tribunal to set a date, time, and place for a hearing; </section><section prefix="c">Make a reasonable effort to obtain all relevant information, including information as to income and property of the parties; </section><section prefix="d">Within two (2) days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of notice in a record from initiating, responding, or registering tribunal, send a copy of the notice to the petitioner; </section><section prefix="e">Within two (2) days, exclusive of Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays, after receipt of notice in a record from the respondent or the respondent's attorney, send a copy of the communication to the petitioner; and </section><section prefix="f">Notify the petitioner if jurisdiction over the respondent cannot be obtained. </section></section><section prefix="3">A support enforcement agency of this state that requests registration of a child support order in this state for enforcement or for modification shall make reasonable efforts: <section prefix="a">To ensure that the order to be registered is the controlling order; or </section><section prefix="b">If two (2) or more child support orders exist and the identity of the controlling order has not been determined, to ensure that a request for such a determination is made in a tribunal having jurisdiction to do so. </section></section><section prefix="4">A support enforcement agency of this state that requests registration and enforcement of a support order, arrears, or judgment stated in a foreign currency shall convert the amounts stated in the foreign currency into the equivalent amounts in dollars under the applicable official or market exchange rate as publicly reported. </section><section prefix="5">A support enforcement agency of this state shall issue or request a tribunal of this state to issue a child support order and an income-withholding order that redirect payment of current support, arrears, and interest if requested to do so by a support enforcement agency of another state pursuant to KRS 407.5319. </section><section prefix="6">KRS 407.5101 to 407.5902 does not create or negate a relationship of attorney and client or other fiduciary relationship between a support enforcement agency or the attorney for the agency and the individual being assisted by the agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 20, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 7, effective March 23, 1998.-- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 31, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44096</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>