<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.010</section_number><catch_line>Department of Military Affairs attached to Office of Governor -- Functions -- Organization. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The Department of Military Affairs shall be attached to the Office of the Governor, have charge of and be responsible to the Governor for the proper functioning of the Kentucky National Guard, militia, and all other military or naval matters of the state, and shall consist of the following offices and divisions: <section prefix="1">Office of Management and Administration, containing the: <section prefix="a">Division of Administrative Services; </section><section prefix="b">Division of Facilities; </section><section prefix="c">Bluegrass Station Division; and </section><section prefix="d">Logistics Operations Division; </section></section><section prefix="2">Division of Emergency Management; </section><section prefix="3">Office of the Chief of Staff for Federal Army Guard; </section><section prefix="4">Office of the Chief of Staff for Federal Air Guard; </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky Guard Youth Challenge Division; and </section><section prefix="6">Kentucky Civil Air Patrol. </section>In order to promote greater efficiency, economy, and improved administration, the divisional structure of the Department of Military Affairs may be changed, redesignated, or reorganized in accordance with KRS Chapter 12. Notwithstanding KRS Chapter 12, the department's attachment to the Office of Governor as a separate organizational unit not attached to any cabinet shall not be changed except by action of the General Assembly. </text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001 -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 102, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 401, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1983. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 40, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2711a-142, 2711a-145i, 4618-81. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>