<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.151</section_number><catch_line>Conciliation and mediation of labor disputes. </catch_line><order_by>151</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the secretary, in order to prevent or minimize interruptions growing out of labor disputes, to assist parties to labor disputes to settle such disputes through conciliation and mediation. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary may proffer his or her services in any labor dispute either upon his or her own motion or upon the request of one or more of the parties to the dispute. Whenever the secretary proffers his or her services in any dispute and the services of the secretary have been accepted, it shall be the duty of the secretary to put himself or herself in communication with the parties and to use his or her best efforts, by mediation and conciliation, to bring them to agreement. </section><section prefix="3">If the secretary is not able to bring the parties to agreement by mediation within a reasonable time, he or she shall seek to induce the parties voluntarily to seek other means of settling the dispute without resort to strike, lockout, or other coercion. The failure or refusal of either party to agree to any procedure suggested by the secretary shall not be deemed a violation of any duty or obligation imposed by KRS 336.151 and 336.152. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1713, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32005</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>