<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.135</section_number><catch_line>Advisory opinion by registry -- Effect -- Publication. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may file a written request with the registry for an advisory opinion concerning the application of the provisions of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated by the registry with respect to a specific transaction or activity by the person. The registry shall render a written advisory opinion relating to the specific transaction or activity to the person making the request not later than thirty (30) days after the registry receives the request. </section><section prefix="2">If a candidate, slate of candidates, or either of their campaign committees files a written request with the registry for an advisory opinion not more than thirty (30) days before the date of an election at which the candidate or slate of candidates shall appear on the ballot, the registry shall render a written advisory opinion relating to the request not later than twenty (20) days after the registry receives a complete request. </section><section prefix="3">No advisory opinion shall be issued by the registry or any of its employees except in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Any advisory opinion rendered by the registry under subsection (1) or (2) of this section may be relied upon only by the person or committee involved in the specific transaction or activity with respect to which the advisory opinion is rendered. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any person or committee to whom a written advisory opinion has been rendered who relies upon any provision or finding of the advisory opinion and who acts in good faith in accordance with the provisions and findings of the advisory opinion shall not, as a result of any act with respect to a transaction or activity addressed by the advisory opinion, be subject to any sanction provided by this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated by the registry. </section><section prefix="c">It shall be no defense in any civil or criminal proceeding regarding a violation of any provision of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated by the registry for a person or committee to claim that he relied upon and acted in good faith based upon any provision or finding of an advisory opinion if the person or committee was not the person or committee involved in the specific transaction or activity with respect to which the advisory opinion was rendered. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The registry shall make public all written requests for an advisory </section>opinion made under subsection (1) or (2) of this section. Before rendering an advisory opinion, the registry shall accept written comments submitted by any interested party within the ten (10) day period following the date the request is made public. <section prefix="b">The registry shall make public all advisory opinions rendered under subsection (1) or (2) of this section. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 45, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27863</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>