<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="500" order_by="500">GENERAL PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>500.095</section_number><catch_line>Alternative sentence of community work. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In every case in which a person pleads guilty to or is convicted of a crime punishable by imprisonment, the judge shall consider whether the person should be sentenced to a term of community service as an alternative to the prison term. The term of community service shall not be shorter than the length of the prison term nor longer than twice the length of the prison term. Failure to complete the prescribed term of community service shall be deemed a probation violation and shall subject the defendant to serve the prison service originally fixed by the court or jury. </section><section prefix="2">The clerk of the Circuit Court, under the direction of the Circuit Judges of the circuit and in cooperation with the Administrative Office of the Courts and the governmental units within the jurisdiction of the Circuit Court, shall maintain a schedule of community service work and projects for use by judges in setting alternative sentences. Any city, county, urban-county, or other governmental unit desiring to participate in alternative sentence community service work and projects shall submit to the clerk, on or before January 1, 1991, and every six (6) months thereafter, a list of community service work and projects it proposes for inclusion in the schedule. </section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Office of the Courts, under the direction of the Supreme Court, shall prepare a schedule of approved categories of alternative sentences which shall be disseminated to all judges and circuit clerks. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19646</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>