<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.940</section_number><catch_line>Hearings. </catch_line><order_by>940</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Public hearings shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A by the department prior to the promulgation of any administrative regulations which pertain to the prevention, abatement, or control of automobile, vehicle, machinery, or material recycling establishments or places of business. Administrative hearings shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B before the issuance of any final order prohibiting the performance by any person of any act or acts deemed to be in contravention of any administrative regulations, orders, or permits of the department; or before denial, revocation, or modification of any permit provided for by KRS 177.905 to 177.950; or before any other final determination is made by the department which directly affects the activities of any person. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall grant an administrative hearing to any person, not previously heard in connection with the issuance of any order or the making of any determination, who may consider himself aggrieved by any order or determination and who shall file with the department a verified petition alleging that the order or determination is contrary to law or that is injurious to him, stating the grounds and reasons therefor and requesting a hearing thereon. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 65, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 5. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>