<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.027</section_number><catch_line>Occupational qualification development program -- State payments to participating municipal junior colleges. </catch_line><order_by>027</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall have authority to provide for a program of occupational qualification development in the Commonwealth. The program may be provided for by contract with any recognized and accredited municipal junior college located within the Commonwealth. The contract shall provide that the college shall admit to its course of instruction, up to such percentage of its full teaching capacity as may be fixed by contract, residents of the Commonwealth who make application to pursue the course of study of the college; provided, however, that the persons shall be classified as residents according to council administrative regulations and shall be eligible for admissions to the junior college. </section><section prefix="2">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall pay to the college not more than two hundred dollars ($200) per school year for each student enrolled. The payments shall be additional to the annual tuition fees paid by each student. The council shall have authority to provide by contract that it pay the expense of specific research projects or programs conducted by the college. The council shall make an annual report of its occupational qualification development program after June 30 of each year, including an accounting of all moneys received and disbursed. The council shall have no authority to incur any obligation in excess of the sums that have been appropriated to it. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 77, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 8, effective March 2, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4179</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>