<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.047</section_number><catch_line>Alternate requirements for licensure as a professional land surveyor until June 30, 2011 -- Education, experience. </catch_line><order_by>047</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Until June 30, 2011, the following shall apply to licensure as a professional land surveyor: <section prefix="a">In addition to the requirements listed in KRS 322.045(1)(c), a person may qualify for licensure as a professional land surveyor by meeting one of the following alternate requirements: <section prefix="1">Graduation from a program of four (4) years or more in an area other than land surveying accredited by one of the Commissions of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology and not less than six (6) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying. Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination upon completion of two (2) years of progressive experience in land surveying. Applicants possessing education credentials of this subparagraph may pursue licensure under KRS 322.045(1)(c)2., providing the core curriculum in land surveying requirement is satisfied; </section><section prefix="2">Graduation from a two (2) year board-approved program in land surveying and not less than six (6) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying. Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination upon completion of two (2) years of progressive experience in land surveying; or </section><section prefix="3">Graduation from high school, or the equivalent, and not less than ten (10) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying. Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination upon completion of four (4) years of progressive experience in land surveying. </section></section><section prefix="b">As it may apply to the experience qualifications for land surveyors: <section prefix="1">The satisfactory completion of each year as a full-time student of a board-approved program in civil engineering or land surveying without graduation may be considered as equivalent to one (1) year of experience required by subsection (1)(a)2. and 3. of this section; </section><section prefix="2">Graduation from a program other than as provided in KRS 322.045(1)(c) or subsection (1)(a)1. and 2. of this section from a college or university of recognized standing may be considered as equivalent to two (2) years of experience required by subsection (1)(a)2. and 3. of this section; </section><section prefix="3">No applicant shall receive credit for more than four (4) years of experience based on undergraduate educational qualifications. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish requirements for consideration of experience gained prior to graduation from programs as described in subsection (1)(a)1. and 2. of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The board may promulgate administrative regulations to provide an exemption to the licensure requirements contained in subsection (1)(a) of this section based on a finding of hardship or medical necessity. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>