<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.575</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with an Intellectual Disability and Other Developmental Disabilities -- Membership -- Chair -- Compensation.   </catch_line><order_by>575</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created the Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with an Intellectual Disability and Other Developmental Disabilities. The commission shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner of the Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="d">The executive director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="e">The director of the University Affiliated Program at the Interdisciplinary Human Development Institute of the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="f">The director of the Kentucky Council on Developmental Disabilities; </section><section prefix="g">Two (2) members of the House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="h">Two (2) members of the Senate, appointed by the Senate President; and </section><section prefix="i">Public members, appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="1">Five (5) family members, at least one (1) of whom shall be a member of a family with a child with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities, and one (1) of whom shall be a member of a family with an adult with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities. Of these five (5) family members, at least two (2) shall be members of a family with an individual with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities residing in the home of the family member or in a community-based setting, and at least two (2) shall be members of a family with an individual with an intellectual disability or other mental disabilities residing in an institutional residential facility that provides service to individuals with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="2">Three (3) persons with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="3">Two (2) business leaders; </section><section prefix="4">Three (3) direct service providers representing the Kentucky Association of Regional Programs and the Kentucky Association of Residential Resources; and </section><section prefix="5">One (1) representative of a statewide advocacy group. </section></section> The six (6) appointments made under subparagraphs 1. and 2. of this paragraph shall be chosen to reflect representation from each of Kentucky's six (6) congressional districts. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall serve as chair of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Members defined in subsection (1)(a) to (h) of this section shall serve during their terms of office. All public members appointed by the Governor shall serve a four </section><section prefix="4">year term and may be reappointed for one (1) additional four (4) year term. </section>(4) All public members of the commission shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for attending each meeting. All commission members shall be reimbursed for necessary travel and other expenses actually incurred in the discharge of duties of the commission. </text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 93, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 40, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 125, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 55, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 2, effective April 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 22, changed "Kentucky Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with Mental Retardation" to "Kentucky Commission on services and Supports for Individuals with Intellectual Disabilities." It is apparent from an examination of other sections of this Act and from consultation with the drafter that "Individuals with Intellectual Disabilities" should have been "Individuals with an Intellectual Disability," to conform with changes made to other sections of the Act. The Reviser of Statutes had made this change under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40821</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>