<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.470</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations for the conduct of persons placed on probation or parole, except that the commissioner shall not promulgate any administrative regulation which conflicts with the conditions of probation imposed by the court or conditions of release imposed by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may utilize an approved monitoring device as defined in KRS 532.200(5) in the supervision of persons placed on probation or parole and to impose a reasonable fee on the probationer or parolee, as a condition of probation or parole, for equipment usage. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner or his or her designee shall: <section prefix="a">Be responsible for any reports of investigation and supervision as may be requested by the board or the courts; </section><section prefix="b">Divide the Commonwealth into districts and assign probation and parole officers to serve in the various districts and courts; </section><section prefix="c">Direct the work of the officers and other employees assigned to him or her; </section><section prefix="d">Formulate methods of investigation, supervision, record keeping, and reports; </section><section prefix="e">Conduct training courses for the staff; </section><section prefix="f">Negotiate with public or private groups or institutions for further training of employees and authorize the expenditure of funds for that purpose when needed; and </section><section prefix="g">Develop policies on probation and parole work in the light of other welfare administration policies. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 320, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 111, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(16). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 23, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  A manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes in codifying 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 320 (this section). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19195</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>