<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.200</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance -- Court may grant order for either spouse. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a proceeding for dissolution of marriage or legal separation, or a proceeding for maintenance following dissolution of a marriage by a court which lacked personal jurisdiction over the absent spouse, the court may grant a maintenance order for either spouse only if it finds that the spouse seeking maintenance:  <section prefix="a">Lacks sufficient property, including marital property apportioned to him, to provide for his reasonable needs; and  </section><section prefix="b">Is unable to support himself through appropriate employment or is the custodian of a child whose condition or circumstances make it appropriate that the custodian not be required to seek employment outside the home.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The maintenance order shall be in such amounts and for such periods of time as the court deems just, and after considering all relevant factors including:  <section prefix="a">The financial resources of the party seeking maintenance, including marital property apportioned to him, and his ability to meet his needs independently, including the extent to which a provision for support of a child living with the party includes a sum for that party as custodian;  </section><section prefix="b">The time necessary to acquire sufficient education or training to enable the party seeking maintenance to find appropriate employment;  </section><section prefix="c">The standard of living established during the marriage;  </section><section prefix="d">The duration of the marriage;  </section><section prefix="e">The age, and the physical and emotional condition of the spouse seeking maintenance; and  </section><section prefix="f">The ability of the spouse from whom maintenance is sought to meet his needs while meeting those of the spouse seeking maintenance.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 10. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1453</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>