<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="80" order_by="80">LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>80.264</section_number><catch_line>Legal effects of creation of city-county authority. </catch_line><order_by>264</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On the day set in the resolutions of the city and contiguous county governing bodies:  <section prefix="a">Any housing commission in said city and any housing commission in the contiguous county shall cease to exist as a body politic and corporate;  </section><section prefix="b">All property, real and personal and mixed, belonging to the abolished city and contiguous county housing commissions shall vest in, belong to, and be the property of the city-county housing authority;  </section><section prefix="c">All judgments, liens, rights of liens, and causes of action of any nature, in favor of the abolished commissions, shall remain, vest in, and inure to the benefit of the city-county housing authority;  </section><section prefix="d">All rentals, taxes, assessments, and any other funds, charges or fees, owing to the abolished commissions shall be owed to and collected by the city-county housing authority;  </section><section prefix="e">Any actions, suits, and proceedings pending against, or having been instituted by the abolished housing commissions shall not be abated by such abolition, but all such actions, suits and proceedings shall be continued and completed in the same manner as if abolition had not occurred, and the city-county housing authority shall be a party to all such actions, suits, and proceedings in the place and stead of the abolished housing commissions and shall pay or cause to be paid any judgments rendered against the abolished housing commissions in any such actions, suits, or proceedings, and no new process need be served in any such actions, suits or proceedings;  </section><section prefix="f">All obligations of the abolished housing commissions, including outstanding indebtedness, shall be assumed by the city-county housing authority, and all such obligations and outstanding indebtedness shall be constituted obligations and indebtedness of the city-county housing authority; and  </section><section prefix="g">All rules, regulations and policies of the abolished housing commissions shall continue in full force and effect until repealed or amended by the city-county housing authority.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The creation of a city-county housing authority shall be subject to the same provisions and limitations of KRS 80.320 to 80.610 as are applicable to a regional housing authority.  </section><section prefix="3">The area of operation of a city-county housing authority shall include all of the territory within the boundaries of the city and contiguous county joining in the creation of the authority.  </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 17, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24840</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>