<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="411" order_by="411">RIGHTS OF ACTION AND SURVIVAL OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>411.252</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 411.250 to 411.266. </catch_line><order_by>252</order_by><text>As used in KRS 411.250 to 411.266, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Action" means any civil lawsuit or action in contract or tort for damages or indemnity brought against a construction professional to assert a claim, whether by complaint, counterclaim, or cross-claim, for damage or the loss of use of real or personal property caused by a defect in the construction of a residence. "Action" does not include any civil action in tort alleging personal injury or wrongful death to a person or persons resulting from a construction defect; </section><section prefix="2">"Claimant" means a homeowner who asserts a claim against a construction professional concerning a defect in the construction of a residence; </section><section prefix="3">"Construction professional" means a builder; </section><section prefix="4">"Homeowner" means any person, company, firm, partnership, corporation, association, or other entity that contracts with a construction professional for the construction of a residence. "Homeowner" includes but is not limited to a subsequent purchaser of a residence from any homeowner; </section><section prefix="5">"Residence" means a single-family house, duplex, triplex, or quadraplex, or a unit in a multiunit residential structure in which title to each individual unit is transferred to the owner under a condominium regime as established in KRS 381.815 and shall include general common elements and limited common elements as defined in KRS 381.810; and </section><section prefix="6">"Serve" or "service" means personal service or delivery by certified mail to the last known address of the addressee. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>