<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.103</section_number><catch_line>Suspension, revocation, or modification of consultant's license -- Grounds -- Application for new license. </catch_line><order_by>103</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department may suspend for not longer than ten (10) days, pending inquiry, and, after opportunity for a hearing, the department may deny, suspend, revoke, or modify the provision of any license issued under KRS 217B.100 if it finds that the applicant or licensee or his employee has committed any of the following acts, each of which is declared to be a violation of this section: <section prefix="a">Made false or fraudulent claims through any media, misrepresenting the effect of materials or methods to be utilized or sold; </section><section prefix="b">Made a pesticide recommendation not in accordance with the label registered as provided by KRS 217.541 to 217.640; </section><section prefix="c">Violated any provision of this chapter or any administrative regulation promulgated by the department or of any lawful order of the department; </section><section prefix="d">Failed to pay the original or renewal license fee when due; </section><section prefix="e">Was guilty of gross negligence, incompetency, or misconduct in acting as a consultant, or used fraud or misrepresentation in making an application for a license or renewal of a license; </section><section prefix="f">Refused or neglected to comply with any limitations or restrictions on or in a duly issued license; </section><section prefix="g">Aided or abetted a licensed or an unlicensed person to evade the provisions of this chapter, combined or conspired with a licensed or unlicensed person to evade the provisions of this chapter, or allowed one's license to be used by an unlicensed person; or </section><section prefix="h">Impersonated any state, county, or city inspector or official. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any licensee whose license is revoked under the provisions of this section shall not be eligible to apply for a new license until the time has elapsed from the date of the order revoking the license as established by the department, not to exceed two (2) years, or if an appeal is taken from the order or revocation, not to exceed two (2) years from the date of the order or final judgment sustaining the revocation. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 71, effective June 17, 1978. --  Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 26. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9534</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>