<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.050</section_number><catch_line>Conspiracy -- General provisions. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person may be convicted of conspiracy to commit a crime unless an overt act in furtherance of the conspiracy is alleged and proved to have been committed by one (1) of the conspirators. </section><section prefix="2">A person who conspires to commit more than one (1) crime, all of which are the object of the same agreement or continuous conspiratorial relationship, is guilty of only one (1) conspiracy. The classification of this crime under subsection (2) of KRS 506.040 shall be determined by the most serious offense which he is found guilty of conspiring to commit. </section><section prefix="3">If a person guilty of conspiracy, as defined by KRS 506.040, knows that a person with whom he conspires to commit a crime has conspired with another person or persons to commit the same crime, he is guilty of conspiring to commit the crime with the other person or persons, whether or not he knows their identity. </section><section prefix="4">No person may be convicted of conspiracy to commit a crime when an element of that crime is agreement with the person with whom he is alleged to have conspired or when that crime is so defined that his conduct is an inevitable incident to its commission. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 53, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19705</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>