<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.120</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of inspection -- Fee -- Term -- Posting -- Termination -- Suspension -- Reissuance.   </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If, upon inspection, a boiler or pressure vessel is found to comply with the administrative regulations of the department, the owner, user, or insurance company of it shall pay to the department the sum of fifteen dollars ($15). When the inspection is made by a special inspector, the inspector shall attach the certificate fee to his or her report. The chief boiler inspector, or his or her duly authorized representative, shall issue to the owner or user a certificate of inspection for the boiler or pressure vessel bearing the date of inspection and specifying the maximum pressure under which the boiler or pressure vessel may be operated. An inspection certificate shall be valid for not more than fourteen (14) months from its date in the case of power boilers, and twenty-six (26) months in the case of low pressure steam or vapor heating boilers, hot water heating boilers, or hot water supply boilers. The most recently issued certificate of inspection shall be posted in the room containing the boiler inspected or, in the case of a portable boiler, shall be kept in a tool box accompanying the boiler. The most recently issued certificate of inspection for each pressure vessel shall be kept in the owner's files. </section><section prefix="2">No certificate of inspection issued for an insured boiler, inspected by a special inspector, shall be valid after the insurance on the boiler for which it was issued terminates. Boilers shall be insured by a company duly authorized by this state to carry the insurance. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner or his or her authorized representative may at any time suspend a certificate of inspection if, in his or her opinion, the boiler or pressure vessel for which it was issued cannot be operated without menace to the public safety, or if the boiler or pressure vessel is found not in compliance with this chapter or the administrative regulations of the department. A special boiler inspector shall have corresponding powers with respect to suspending certificates of inspection for boilers or pressure vessels insured by the company employing him or her. The suspension of a certificate of inspection shall continue in effect until the boiler or pressure vessel conforms to this chapter and administrative regulations of the board, and until the inspection certificate is reinstated. </section><section prefix="4">A suspended certificate of inspection shall be reissued on the recommendation of the boiler inspector or special boiler inspector who first caused the suspension or at the discretion of the chief boiler inspector. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 525, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40116</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>