<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.020</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of convenience and necessity required for construction provision of utility service or of utility -- Exceptions -- Approval required for acquisition or transfer of ownership -- Public hearing on proposed transmission line -- Severability of provisions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, partnership, public or private corporation, or combination thereof shall commence providing utility service to or for the public or begin the construction of any plant, equipment, property, or facility for furnishing to the public any of the services enumerated in KRS 278.010, except retail electric suppliers for service connections to electric-consuming facilities located within its certified territory and ordinary extensions of existing systems in the usual course of business, until that person has obtained from the Public Service Commission a certificate that public convenience and necessity require the service or construction. Upon the filing of an application for a certificate, and after any public hearing which the commission may in its discretion conduct for all interested parties, the commission may issue or refuse to issue the certificate, or issue it in part and refuse it in part, except that the commission shall not refuse or modify an application submitted under KRS 278.023 without consent by the parties to the agreement. The commission, when considering an application for a certificate to construct a base load electric generating facility, may consider the policy of the General Assembly to foster and encourage use of Kentucky coal by electric utilities serving the Commonwealth. The commission, when considering an application for a certificate to construct an electric transmission line, may consider the interstate benefits expected to be achieved by the proposed construction or modification of electric transmission facilities in the Commonwealth. Unless exercised within one (1) year from the grant thereof, exclusive of any delay due to the order of any court or failure to obtain any necessary grant or consent, the authority conferred by the issuance of the certificate of convenience and necessity shall be void, but the beginning of any new construction or facility in good faith within the time prescribed by the commission and the prosecution thereof with reasonable diligence shall constitute an exercise of authority under the certificate. </section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of this section, construction of any electric transmission line of one hundred thirty-eight (138) kilovolts or more and of more than five thousand two hundred eighty (5,280) feet in length shall not be considered an ordinary extension of an existing system in the usual course of business and shall require a certificate of public convenience and necessity. However, ordinary extensions of existing systems in the usual course of business not requiring such a certificate shall include: <section prefix="a">The replacement or upgrading of any existing electric transmission line; or </section><section prefix="b">The relocation of any existing electric transmission line to accommodate construction or expansion of a roadway or other transportation infrastructure; or </section><section prefix="c">An electric transmission line that is constructed solely to serve a single customer and that will pass over no property other than that owned by the customer to be served. </section></section><section prefix="3">No utility shall exercise any right or privilege under any franchise or permit, after the exercise of that right or privilege has been voluntarily suspended or discontinued for more than one (1) year, without first obtaining from the commission, in the manner provided in subsection (1) of this section, a certificate of convenience and necessity authorizing the exercise of that right or privilege. </section><section prefix="4">No utility shall apply for or obtain any franchise, license, or permit from any city or other governmental agency until it has obtained from the commission, in the manner provided in subsection (1) of this section, a certificate of convenience and necessity showing that there is a demand and need for the service sought to be rendered. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall acquire or transfer ownership of, or control, or the right to control, any utility under the jurisdiction of the commission by sale of assets, transfer of stock, or otherwise, or abandon the same, without prior approval by the commission. The commission shall grant its approval if the person acquiring the utility has the financial, technical, and managerial abilities to provide reasonable service. </section><section prefix="6">No individual, group, syndicate, general or limited partnership, association, corporation, joint stock company, trust, or other entity (an "acquirer"), whether or not organized under the laws of this state, shall acquire control, either directly or indirectly, of any utility furnishing utility service in this state, without having first obtained the approval of the commission. Any acquisition of control without prior authorization shall be void and of no effect. As used in this subsection, the term "control" means the possession, directly or indirectly, of the power to direct or cause the direction of the management and policies of a utility, whether through the ownership of voting securities, by effecting a change in the composition of the board of directors, by contract or otherwise. Control shall be presumed to exist if any individual or entity, directly or indirectly, owns ten percent (10%) or more of the voting securities of the utility. This presumption may be rebutted by a showing that ownership does not in fact confer control. Application for any approval or authorization shall be made to the commission in writing, verified by oath or affirmation, and be in a form and contain the information as the commission requires. The commission shall approve any proposed acquisition when it finds that the same is to be made in accordance with law, for a proper purpose and is consistent with the public interest. The commission may make investigation and hold hearings in the matter as it deems necessary, and thereafter may grant any application under this subsection in whole or in part and with modification and upon terms and conditions as it deems necessary or appropriate. The commission shall grant, modify, refuse, or prescribe appropriate terms and conditions with respect to every such application within sixty (60) days after the filing of the application therefor, unless it is necessary, for good cause shown, to continue the application for up to sixty (60) additional days. The order continuing the application shall state fully the facts that make continuance necessary. In the absence of that action within that period of time, any proposed acquisition shall be deemed to be approved. </section><section prefix="7">Subsection (6) of this section shall not apply to any acquisition of control of any: <section prefix="a">Utility which derives a greater percentage of its gross revenue from business in another jurisdiction than from business in this state if the commission determines that the other jurisdiction has statutes or rules which are applicable and are being applied and which afford protection to ratepayers in this state substantially equal to that afforded such ratepayers by subsection (6) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">Utility by an acquirer who directly, or indirectly through one (1) or more intermediaries, controls, or is controlled by, or is under common control with, the utility, including any entity created at the direction of such utility for purposes of corporate reorganization; or </section><section prefix="c">Utility pursuant to the terms of any indebtedness of the utility, provided the issuance of indebtedness was approved by the commission. </section></section><section prefix="8">In a proceeding on an application filed pursuant to this section, any interested person, including a person over whose property the proposed transmission line will cross, may request intervention, and the commission shall, if requested, conduct a public hearing in the county in which the transmission line is proposed to be constructed, or, if the transmission line is proposed to be constructed in more than one county, in one of those counties. The commission shall issue its decision no later than ninety (90) days after the application is filed, unless the commission extends this period, for good cause, to one hundred twenty (120) days. The commission may utilize the provisions of KRS 278.255(3) if, in the exercise of its discretion, it deems it necessary to hire a competent, qualified and independent firm to assist it in reaching its decision. The issuance by the commission of a certificate that public convenience and necessity require the construction of an electric transmission line shall be deemed to be a determination by the commission that, as of the date of issuance, the construction of the line is a prudent investment. </section><section prefix="9">If any provision of this section or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the invalidity shall not affect other provisions or applications of this section which can be given effect without the invalid provision or application, and to that end the provisions are declared to be severable. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 22, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 335, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 6, effective April 1, 1979. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 388, sec. 3. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3952-25. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, E, 6, (3) at 638. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14042</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>