<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.120</section_number><catch_line>Stairways or hoisting devices in shafts -- Passageways to be unobstructed -- Direction signs -- Height and width of escapeway outlets. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In every shaft designated as an escape outlet there shall be provided a stairway or ladderway of suitable strength, design, and angle, with platforms or landings at each turn, the stairway or ladderway to be approved by the mine inspector, or in lieu thereof a properly equipped hoisting arrangement, consisting of facilities suitable for hoisting men, a wire hoisting rope of ample strength, and an adequate and safe hoisting engine and drum, which hoisting arrangement shall be ready for use at any time of emergency. </section><section prefix="2">All shafts by which men enter or leave the mine and all passageways to escape outlets shall be carefully examined by the mine foreman, or by a person designated by him, at least once each week that the mine is operating, and the date and findings of the examination shall be entered in a book at the mine and for that purpose. </section><section prefix="3">No debris, water, or other material that would obstruct the free passage of men shall be allowed to accumulate in the passageway to the escape outlet, and if any obstructions accumulate or exist they shall be promptly removed. </section><section prefix="4">At points where the passageway to the escape outlet is intersected by roadways or entries calculated to produce doubt as to the proper direction to the outlet, conspicuous signboards shall be placed indicating the direction to escape outlets. </section><section prefix="5">The height of the escapeway outlets shall be maintained to at least the height of the coal seam and at least six (6) feet in width, where practicable. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 29, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 12. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-21. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32983</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>