<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.056</section_number><catch_line>Filing of delayed birth certificate. </catch_line><order_by>056</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a certificate of birth of a living person born in the Commonwealth has not been filed within the time period as provided in KRS 213.046, a certificate of birth may be filed in accordance with the administrative regulations of the cabinet. The certificate shall be registered subject to such evidentiary requirements as the cabinet shall by regulation prescribe to substantiate the alleged facts of birth. </section><section prefix="2">In accordance with the provisions of this section and the administrative regulations established thereunder, the state registrar may issue a record of foreign birth for a person born outside the United States registration area who is subsequently adopted by a Kentucky resident and whose record of birth cannot be obtained from the country of birth. Such certificates shall be plainly endorsed, "not evidence of United States citizenship." </section><section prefix="3">Certificates of birth registered one (1) year or more after the date of birth shall be made on forms prescribed and furnished by the state registrar marked "delayed" and shall show on the face of the certificate the date of the delayed registration. </section><section prefix="4">A summary statement of the evidence submitted in support of the delayed registration shall be endorsed on the certificate. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may refuse to accept any application for a delayed birth certificate or record of foreign birth on which the applicant fails to provide such information as the cabinet may require. </section><section prefix="6">Each birth certificate filed under this section shall include all Social Security numbers that have been issued to the parents of the child. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. --Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8718</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>