<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.37-055</section_number><catch_line>Supervisory colleges for certain domestic insurers -- Powers of commission.   </catch_line><order_by>37-055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With respect to any insurer registered pursuant to KRS 304.37-020, and in accordance with subsection (3) of this section, the commissioner shall have the authority to participate in a supervisory college for any domestic insurer that is part of an insurance holding company system with international operations in order to determine compliance by the insurer with this subtitle. The powers of the commissioner with respect to supervisory colleges include, but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Initiating the establishment of a supervisory college; </section><section prefix="b">Clarifying the membership and participation of other supervisors in the supervisory college; </section><section prefix="c">Clarifying the functions of the supervisory college and the role of other regulators, including the establishment of a groupwide supervisor; </section><section prefix="d">Coordinating the ongoing activities of the supervisory college, including planning meetings, supervising activities, and establishing processes for information sharing; and </section><section prefix="e">Establishing a crisis management plan. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each registered insurer subject to this section shall be liable for and shall pay the reasonable expenses of the commissioner’s participation in a supervisory college in accordance with subsection (3) of this section, including reasonable travel expenses. For purposes of this section, a supervisory college may be convened as either a temporary or permanent forum for communication and cooperation between the regulators charged with the supervision of the insurer or its affiliates, and the commissioner may establish a regular assessment to the insurer for the payment of these expenses. </section><section prefix="3">In order to assess the business strategy, financial position, legal and regulatory position, risk exposure, risk management, and governance processes, and as part of the examination of individual insurers in accordance with KRS 304.37-040, the commissioner may participate in a supervisory college with other regulators charged with supervision of the insurer or its affiliates, including other state, federal, and international regulatory agencies. The commissioner may enter into agreements in accordance with KRS 304.37-050 providing the basis for cooperation between the commissioner and the other regulatory agencies, and the activities of the supervisory college. Nothing in this section shall delegate to the supervisory college the authority of the commissioner to regulate or supervise the insurer or its affiliates within its jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41137</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>