<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">B ADMINISTRATIVE HEARINGS </unit></structure><section_number>13B.125</section_number><catch_line>Emergency action -- Hearing -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An agency may take emergency action affecting the legal rights, duties, privileges or immunities of named persons without a hearing only if duly authorized by statute to so act. If an agency takes emergency action, the agency shall conduct an emergency hearing in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">An agency head or an official of an agency duly authorized by law to summarily act in emergency situations may issue an emergency order to stop, prevent, or avoid an immediate danger to the public health, safety, or welfare. The emergency order shall contain findings of fact and conclusions of law upon which the agency bases the emergency order. The agency shall give notice of the emergency order to all affected parties as is practicable under the circumstances, and notice shall be served in the same manner as provided in KRS 13B.050(2). The emergency order is effective when received by the affected party or his representative. </section><section prefix="3">Any person required to comply with an emergency order issued under subsection (2) of this section may request an emergency hearing to determine the propriety of the order. The agency shall conduct an emergency hearing within ten (10) working days of the request for hearing. The agency shall give all affected parties reasonable notice of the hearing and to the extent practicable shall conduct the hearing in conformity with this chapter. The hearing on the emergency order may be conducted by a hearing officer qualified in accordance with KRS 13B.040. Within five (5) working days of completion of the hearing, the agency or hearing officer shall render a written decision affirming, modifying, or revoking the emergency order. The emergency order shall be affirmed if there is substantial evidence of a violation of law which constitutes an immediate danger to the public health, safety, or welfare. </section><section prefix="4">The decision rendered under subsection (3) of this section shall be a final order of the agency on the matter, and any party aggrieved by the decision may appeal to Circuit Court in the same manner as provided in KRS 13B.140. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=797</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>