<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.940</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for making grants to local task forces. </catch_line><order_by>940</order_by><text>In making grants to a local task force, the state board shall consider the degree to which the local task force meets the following criteria: <section prefix="1">Has as its primary purpose the development and facilitation of a collaborative community prevention program in a specific geographical area. The prevention program shall utilize trained volunteers and existing community resources wherever practicable; </section><section prefix="2">Is comprised of local law enforcement and social services representatives and does not exclude any organization or person that the state board deems necessary; </section><section prefix="3">Demonstrates a willingness and ability to provide prevention program models and consultation to organizations and communities regarding prevention program development and maintenance; </section><section prefix="4">Agrees to match fifty percent (50%) of the amount requested from the trust fund. At least ten percent (10%) of the amount requested shall be matched through dollars, and the remaining match shall be through in-kind contributions. The amount and types of in-kind services are subject to the approval of the state board; and </section><section prefix="5">Other criteria that the state board deems appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1018</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>