<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.460</section_number><catch_line>Services provided by Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs -- Medical and hospital care -- Expenditures -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs shall provide through contractual agreement, or otherwise, such services as may be necessary to locate, diagnose, treat, habilitate, or rehabilitate children with disabilities, and may include any necessary auxiliary services, such as room and board and travel for patients and parents or parent substitutes. </section><section prefix="2">Children referred to the care of the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs for treatment shall be placed under the care of those physicians or surgeons that the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs deems qualified and may be placed in a hospital or home properly equipped to render the necessary treatment or services required by the child. </section><section prefix="3">The Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs is authorized to make those expenditures necessary to carry out the provisions of this section and KRS 200.470 to 200.490. </section><section prefix="4">Any administrative appeal of a decision of the commission shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 93, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. --Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 56, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(24). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>