<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.910</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of network. </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any licensed network shall be permitted to establish one (1) extension site per full-time physician on the staff of the network. Extension sites shall not be required to have a separate license but shall conform to administrative regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and shall be inspected on a regular basis. </section><section prefix="2">Each network shall establish protocols for the treatment of the twenty (20) most common patient problems. At a minimum, the protocols shall identify for each problem a working definition, patient symptoms, diagnostic techniques, acceptable values for laboratory findings, conditions under which a physician shall be consulted, and treatment methods. These protocols shall be approved by the board. The protocols shall be listed in a handbook provided to each midlevel health-care practitioner and shall be available to patients upon request. </section><section prefix="3">Each network shall have a system of patient and family medical records which employs the problem-oriented medical record format. </section><section prefix="4">A network shall employ a primary-care physician who has admitting privileges at a local hospital. The network shall hire ancillary personnel as necessary to provide the basic services of the network. The network may hire midlevel health-care practitioners to assist the physician but there shall be one (1) physician on staff for each midlevel health-care practitioner. </section><section prefix="5">A physician shall see each patient for whom services are provided by a midlevel health-care practitioner not less than twice a year. A medical chart auditor shall review the medical record entries for each patient encounter on the day of the encounter and will refer to the physician immediately any deviation from protocol. </section><section prefix="6">Each network shall develop a quality assurance program which shall be approved by the board. At a minimum, the quality assurance program shall address: <section prefix="a">Program goals and objectives; </section><section prefix="b">Program organization, including identification of responsible parties, the nature of their responsibilities, and the persons to whom they report; and </section><section prefix="c">Identification of the patient care process. </section></section><section prefix="7">Each network shall establish a process by which it regularly evaluates the health-care needs of its community and the services it provides in response to those needs. </section><section prefix="8">Each network shall provide the following educational opportunities: <section prefix="a">Ninety (90) minutes each week of continuing education to its health-care providers on topics relating to patient care needs; and </section><section prefix="b">One and one-half (1.5) days leave and fifty percent (50%) of expenses up to three hundred dollars ($300) per year to its midlevel health-care practitioners for approved continuing education outside of the network. </section></section><section prefix="9">Each network shall either provide directly for twenty-four (24) hour, seven (7) day per week access to care for its patients or have formal written agreements with local providers to insure twenty-four (24) hour, seven (7) day per week access to care for its patients. </section><section prefix="10">No network may charge or collect more money for the services of any midlevel health-care practitioner than is allowable under Medicaid for other nonphysician practitioners. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 497, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 444, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9146</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>