<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.110</section_number><catch_line>Annual and biennial reports. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall prepare and submit to the Legislative Research Commission annual reports of the finances and operations of the state and such other reports as the General Assembly may prescribe or as the Governor may desire. The head of each statutory department shall make to the Governor an annual report and may at any time be required by the Governor to make any special report concerning the work under his charge, with his observations and recommendations thereon and pertinent statistics concerning the work of the department, each of which the Governor shall transmit to the Legislative Research Commission online, with such comments as the Governor may desire to make. All such annual reports shall observe the fiscal year of the state as the reporting year, and shall be published only to the extent ordered in writing by the Governor in accordance with KRS 57.390. </section><section prefix="2">Agencies shall file all annual and biennial reports required by law to be made by agencies with the Governor, and a copy thereof in the office of the Secretary of State, which shall be preserved as a public record. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3956b-1, 4618-160. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39690</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>