<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.079</section_number><catch_line>Petition seeking expungement to include certification of eligibility for expungement from Department of Kentucky State Police and Administrative Office of the Courts -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>079</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Beginning January 1, 2014, every petition filed seeking expungement shall include a certification of eligibility for expungement. The Department of Kentucky State Police and the Administrative Office of the Courts shall certify that the agencies have conducted a criminal background check on the petitioner and whether or not the petitioner is eligible to have the requested record expunged. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement this section, in consultation with the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of this section and KRS 431.076 and 431.078, "expungement" means the removal or deletion of records by the court and other agencies which prevents the matter from appearing on official state-performed background checks. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013).Although 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 15, subsec. (2), defines expungement for the purposes of "this section and Sections 2 and 3 of this Act" (KRS 346.040 and 346.135), the references have been codified as "this section and KRS 431.076 and 431.078" (2013 Ky. Acts ch. 69, secs. 16 and 17) under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h), in order to correct a manifest typographical or clerical error that occurred when the provisions of House Bill 57/HCS were drafted as an amendment to Senate Bill 78, but the internal references were not changed to conform. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42279</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>