<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="80" order_by="80">LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>80.490</section_number><catch_line>Consolidated housing authority for two or more cities. </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the governing body of each of two (2) or more cities (whether or not contiguous) by resolution declares that there is a need for one (1) housing authority to be created for all of such cities to exercise in such cities the powers and other functions prescribed for a consolidated housing authority, a public body corporate and politic to be known as a "consolidated housing authority" (with such corporate name as it selects) shall thereupon exist for all of such cities and exercise its powers and other functions within its area of operation (as herein defined), including the power to undertake projects therein.  </section><section prefix="2">The creation of a consolidated housing authority and the finding of need therefor shall be subject to the same provisions and limitations of KRS 80.320 to 80.610 as are applicable to the creation of a regional housing authority, and all of the provisions of KRS 80.310 to 80.610 applicable to regional housing authorities and the members thereof shall be applicable to consolidated housing authorities and the members thereof.  </section><section prefix="3">The area of operation of a consolidated housing authority shall include all of the territory within the boundaries of each city joining in the creation of such authority, except that such area of operation may be changed to include or exclude any city or cities in the same manner and under the same provisions as provided in KRS 80.320 to 80.610 for changing the area of operation of a regional housing authority by including or excluding a county or counties.  </section><section prefix="4">If the area of operation of a consolidated housing authority is decreased to only one (1) city, such authority shall thereupon constitute and become a housing authority for such city, in the same manner as though such authority were thereupon created pursuant to KRS 80.010 to 80.250; and for all such purposes the term "county" shall be construed as meaning "city," the terms "county housing authority" and "regional housing authority" shall be construed as meaning "housing authority of the city" and "consolidated housing authority," respectively, and the term "governing body" as used in KRS 80.420, 80.430 and 80.440 shall be construed as meaning "mayor," unless a different meaning clearly appears from the context. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 31, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24864</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>