<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.152</section_number><catch_line>Witnesses under subpoena. </catch_line><order_by>152</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subpoenas for witnesses, whose evidence is deemed material to an investigation or hearing authorized by KRS 312.150 and this section, may be issued by the board or any officer of the board and under the seal of the board, commanding the witness to appear before the board at a time and place to be named, and to bring books, records, and documents that may be specified, or to submit books, records, and documents for inspection. Subpoenas may be served by any sheriff or deputy. </section><section prefix="2">When any witness who has been served with a subpoena fails or refuses to appear at the time and place named; or fails or refuses to answer any lawful question propounded; or fails to produce the books, records, or documents required; or is guilty of disorderly or contumacious conduct at the hearing, the board may invoke the aid of the Franklin Circuit Court and any order or subpoena of the court requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence may be enforced and shall be valid anywhere in the state. </section><section prefix="3">Witnesses shall be entitled to the same fees and mileage as they may be entitled to by law for attending as witnesses in a Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="4">Witnesses who testify under subpoena shall be entitled to the same protection and immunities as witnesses in judicial proceedings. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30791</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>