<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.433</section_number><catch_line>Proceedings for involuntary treatment -- Duties of court -- Disposition. </catch_line><order_by>433</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon receipt of the petition, the court shall examine the petitioner under oath as to the contents of the petition. </section><section prefix="2">If, after reviewing the allegations contained in the petition and examining the petitioner under oath, it appears to the court that there is probable cause to believe the respondent should be ordered to undergo treatment, then the court shall: <section prefix="a">Set a date for a hearing within fourteen (14) days to determine if there is probable cause to believe the respondent should be ordered to undergo treatment for alcohol and other drug abuse; </section><section prefix="b">Notify the respondent, the legal guardian, if any and if known, and the spouse, parents, or nearest relative or friend of the respondent concerning the allegations and contents of the petition and the date and purpose of the hearing; and the name, address, and telephone number of the attorney appointed to represent the respondent; and </section><section prefix="c">Cause the respondent to be examined no later than twenty-four (24) hours before the hearing date by two (2) qualified health professionals, at least one (1) of whom is a physician. The qualified health professionals shall certify their findings to the court within twenty-four (24) hours of the examinations. </section></section><section prefix="3">If, upon completion of the hearing, the court finds the respondent should be ordered to undergo treatment, then the court shall order such treatment for a period not to exceed sixty (60) consecutive days from the date of the court order or a period not to exceed three hundred sixty (360) consecutive days from the date of the court order, whatever was the period of time that was requested in the petition or otherwise agreed to at the hearing. Failure of a respondent to undergo treatment ordered pursuant to this subsection may place the respondent in contempt of court. </section><section prefix="4">If, at any time after the petition is filed, the court finds that there is no probable cause to continue treatment or if the petitioner withdraws the petition, then the proceedings against the respondent shall be dismissed. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>