<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.510</section_number><catch_line>Information obtained by probation or parole officer to be privileged -- Exception.   </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text>All information obtained in the discharge of official duty by any probation or parole officer shall be privileged and shall not be received as evidence in any court. Such information shall not be disclosed directly or indirectly to any person other than the court, board, cabinet, or others entitled under KRS 439.250 to 439.560 to receive such information, unless otherwise ordered by such court, board or cabinet. Information shall be made available to sex offender treatment programs operated or approved by the Department of Corrections or the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities who request the information in the course of conducting an evaluation or treatment pursuant to KRS 439.265(6), 532.045(3), or 532.050(4). </text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 118, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 76, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 27, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40843</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>