<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-2033</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility of endorsed capital construction projects for state economic development incentives. </catch_line><order_by>12-2033</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any capital construction project endorsed by the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs as preserving or creating jobs at military facilities located in Kentucky shall be eligible for state economic development incentives prescribed in this chapter, including but not limited to those provided in KRS 154.22-010 to 154.22-070, KRS 154.24-010 to 154.24-150, KRS 154.26-010 to 154.26-100, KRS 154.28-010 to 154.28-090 and KRS 141.400, and KRS 154.33-501 to 154.33-585; however, no project shall receive state financial assistance unless first approved by the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority. No project shall be located on federally owned or leased property. </section><section prefix="2">All standards, procedures, and requirements applicable to projects approved by the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority for state economic development incentives pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be applicable to all economic development projects submitted by the commission and approved by the authority for assistance. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any laws of the Commonwealth to the contrary, costs of highway and other transportation related construction and other infrastructure facilities improvements associated with a project endorsed by the commission may be eligible for state funding under programs administered by the Transportation Cabinet and the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2617</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>