<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.844</section_number><catch_line>Mathematics achievement fund -- Creation -- Use and disposition of moneys -- Administrative regulations -- Requirements for grant applicants -- Department to provide information to schools and to make annual report to Interim Joint Committee on Education. </catch_line><order_by>844</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The mathematics achievement fund is hereby created to provide developmentally appropriate diagnostic assessment and intervention services to students, primary through grade 12, to help them reach proficiency in mathematics on the state assessments under KRS 158.6453 and in compliance with the "No Child Left Behind Act of 2001," 20 U.S.C. secs. 6301 et seq., as required under KRS 158.840. </section><section prefix="2">The grant funds may be used to support the implementation of diagnostic and intervention services in mathematics. The use of funds may include: pay for extended time for teachers, released time for teachers to serve as coaches and mentors or to carry out other responsibilities needed in the implementation of intervention services, payment of substitute teachers needed for the support of mathematics teachers, purchase of materials needed for modification of instruction, and other costs associated with diagnostic and intervention services or to cover other costs deemed appropriate by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section><section prefix="3">The fund shall: <section prefix="a">Provide funding for the Center for Mathematics created in KRS 164.525 and the costs of training selected teachers in the diagnostic assessment and intervention skills that are needed to assist struggling students in the primary program and other grade levels; </section><section prefix="b">Provide renewable, two (2) year local grants to school districts and for purposes described in subsection (2) of this section; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide operational funding for the Committee for Mathematics Achievement created in KRS 158.842. </section></section><section prefix="4">Any funds appropriated to the mathematics achievement fund that are specifically designated by the General Assembly to support the Center for Mathematics shall be appropriated to the Council on Postsecondary Education and distributed to the university administering the center, as determined by the council under KRS 164.525. </section><section prefix="5">Any moneys in the fund at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to be used for the purposes specified in this section. </section><section prefix="6">Any interest earnings of the fund shall become a part of the fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Any funds appropriated to the mathematics achievement fund and specifically designated by the General Assembly as funding for grants to local school districts or to support the Committee for Mathematics Achievement shall be administered by the Kentucky Department of Education. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations relating to the grants for local school districts based on recommendations from the Committee for Mathematics Achievement, the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, the commissioner of education, and the Center for Mathematics established in KRS 164.525. The administrative regulations shall: <section prefix="1">Identify eligibility criteria for grant applicants; </section><section prefix="2">Specify the criteria for acceptable diagnostic assessments and intervention programs and coaching and mentoring programs; </section><section prefix="3">Establish the minimum annual evaluation process for each grant recipient; </section><section prefix="4">Identify the annual data that must be provided from each grant recipient; </section><section prefix="5">Define the application and approval process; </section><section prefix="6">Establish matching fund requirements if deemed necessary by the board; </section><section prefix="7">Define the obligations for professional development and continuing education for teachers, administrators, and staff of each grant recipient; </section><section prefix="8">Establish the conditions for renewal of a two (2) year grant; and </section><section prefix="9">Specify other conditions necessary to implement the purposes of this section. </section></section><section prefix="c">As part of the application process, the board shall require that a grant applicant provide assurances that the following principles will be met if the applicant's request for funding is approved: <section prefix="1">Mathematics instruction will be standards-based and utilize research-based practices; </section><section prefix="2">Intervention and support services will supplement, not replace, regular classroom instruction; and </section><section prefix="3">Intervention services will be provided to primary program students and other students who are at risk of mathematics failure within the school based upon ongoing assessments of their needs. </section></section><section prefix="d">If matching funds are required, the school council or, if none exists, the principal or the superintendent of schools, shall allocate matching funds. Funding for professional development allocated to the school council under KRS 160.345 and for continuing education under KRS 158.070 may be used to provide a portion or all of a school's required match. </section><section prefix="e">The Department of Education shall make available to schools: <section prefix="1">Information from the Center for Mathematics regarding diagnostic assessment and intervention programs and coaching and mentoring programs of proven-practice in meeting the needs of primary students and other students who are at risk of failure; </section><section prefix="2">Technical assistance to potential applicants and grant recipients; </section><section prefix="3">A list of professional development providers offering teacher training in diagnostic assessment and intervention strategies and coaching and mentoring; and </section><section prefix="4">Information from the Center for Mathematics on how to communicate to parents effective ways of interacting with their children to improve their mathematics concepts, skills, and understanding. </section></section><section prefix="f">The Department of Education shall submit a report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education no later than September 1 of each year outlining the use of grant funds. By November 1, 2007, the Department of Education with input from the Committee for Mathematics Achievement and the Center for Mathematics shall conduct a statewide needs assessment of the resources needed in each school to help each child achieve proficiency in mathematics by the year 2014 and report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education an estimate of the cost and a specific timeline for meeting the goal established by the Commonwealth. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 52, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 3, effective March 18, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch.164, sec. 3, contained three references to the Mathematics Achievement Committee. The correct name for this entity is the Committee for Mathematics Achievement. The Statute Reviser, under the authority of KRS 7.136, has changed these references to be consistent with sec. 2 of this Act, which created the Committee for Mathematics Achievement and was codified as KRS 158.842. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3615</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>