<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.455</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>455</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly recognizes that many persons with disabilities and their families receive some level of support and services that are funded or administered by state agencies. The support and services are provided to persons with disabilities or their families, if appropriate, either directly or through arrangements with local community-based vendors, organizations, or agencies. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly recognizes that persons with disabilities who receive the services and support, directly or indirectly, are often not consulted for their perspectives, nor are their viewpoints sought regarding the efficiency, strengths, or weaknesses of the services and support. </section><section prefix="3">Persons with disabilities and their families face obstacles in the court system through lack of understanding and difficulty of access. </section><section prefix="4">Various agencies in state government promulgate standards that govern the administration or operation of the services and support. Seldom are persons with disabilities or their families involved in the development of standards that directly affect the quality of the services and support that they receive. In addition, there are legislative commissions that serve in an advisory capacity concerning the services provided to persons with disabilities and their families, whose membership does not include persons with disabilities and their families. </section><section prefix="5">It is the finding of the General Assembly that: <section prefix="a">Some forms of discrimination against persons with disabilities continue. These persons are a discrete minority who have been faced with restrictions and limitations, subjected to a history of purposeful unequal treatment, and relegated to a position of political powerlessness in our society; </section><section prefix="b">Persons with disabilities and their families have a significant contribution to make in the decision-making processes that shape the support and services they receive through state government; </section><section prefix="c">Persons with disabilities and their families should be provided with meaningful opportunities to contribute their perspectives through their experiences concerning issues relating to services, support, and standards that ultimately affect them; </section><section prefix="d">Services and support should be responsive and sensitive to the cultural, racial, age, language, and gender characteristics of persons with disabilities and their families; and </section><section prefix="e">Meaningful opportunities to contribute their perspectives will help provide adequate information in a manner that facilitates and allows for participation by persons with disabilities and their families. </section></section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=679</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>