<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="116" order_by="116">VOTER REGISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>116.046</section_number><catch_line>Voter registration forms for high school students -- Public education program. </catch_line><order_by>046</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county clerk shall provide voter registration forms to each principal or assistant principal of every public high school, each area vocational school, and upon request, private schools, who shall designate a person in each school who shall be responsible for informing students and school personnel of the availability of the registration forms and assist them in properly registering. The completed forms shall be returned to the county clerk, for official registration by the county clerk. </section><section prefix="2">Any person designated to assist in registration in subsection (1) of this section shall fulfill this responsibility in an impartial and fair manner and shall not recruit a registrant for any particular party. </section><section prefix="3">The State Board of Education shall implement programs of public education regarding elections, voting procedures, and election fraud, which shall include an audio-visual presentation for high school juniors and seniors. The State Board of Education, after consultation with the State Board of Elections, shall update the public education programs required by this section as relevant statutory changes occur, as different types of voting machines are used, or as more effective methods of presentation shall be developed. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, secs. 5 and 6, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27301</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>