<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.379</section_number><catch_line>Telephone account wagering -- Use of credit card. </catch_line><order_by>379</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A track may engage in telephone account wagering, if all moneys used to place telephone account wagers are on deposit in an amount sufficient to cover the wagers at the track where the account is opened. All moneys wagered by telephone account wagering shall be subject to the applicable pari-mutuel tax levied in KRS 138.510 and shall form a common pool with other pari-mutuel pools at the track for each posted race. The racing commission shall have authority to promulgate necessary and reasonable administrative regulations to regulate the conduct of telephone account wagering, including regulations for the deposit of funds by credit or debit cards or other means of electronic funds transfer. </section><section prefix="2">A track shall accept and tabulate a telephone account wager only from the holder of a telephone wagering account. No person shall directly or indirectly act as an intermediary, transmitter, or agent in the placing of wagers for a holder of a telephone wagering account. No person shall in any manner place a wager through telephone account wagering, on behalf of a holder of a telephone wagering account. Only the holder of a telephone wagering account shall place a telephone wager. Any person violating this subsection shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">Telephone account wagering conducted in accordance with the provisions of this section shall not be considered a violation of KRS 528.110. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 480, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 36, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 30, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 9, effective March 30, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10875</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>