<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.190</section_number><catch_line>Annual report.   </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>Each limited liability company and each foreign limited liability company qualified to transact business in this Commonwealth is subject to KRS 14A.6-010. </text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 112, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 151, sec. 78, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 112, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  This section was repealed and reenacted without change to the existing language by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, effective 7/15/10, and repealed and reenacted with the new language by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, effective 1/1/2011. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intent of the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment by ch. 51 not serve to void amendments made by other bills, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict, therefore, they have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36709</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>