<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.4603Determination</section_number><catch_line>of motor vehicle retail price for sales on or after July 1, 2014.   </catch_line><order_by>4603Determination</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Effective for sales on or after July 1, 2014, of: <section prefix="1">New motor vehicles; </section><section prefix="2">Dealer demonstrator vehicles; </section><section prefix="3">Previous model year motor vehicles; and </section><section prefix="4">U-Drive-It motor vehicles that have been transferred within one hundred eighty (180) days of being registered as a U-Drive-It and that have less than five thousand (5,000) miles; </section></section> the retail price shall be determined by reducing the amount of total consideration given by the trade-in allowance of any motor vehicle traded in by the buyer. The value of the purchased motor vehicle and the amount of the trade-in allowance shall be determined as provided in subsection (2) of this section. <section prefix="b">The retail price shall not include that portion of the price of the vehicle attributable to equipment or adaptive devices necessary to facilitate or accommodate an operator or passenger with physical disabilities. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The value of the purchased motor vehicle offered for registration and the value of the vehicle offered in trade shall be attested to in a notarized affidavit. </section><section prefix="b">If a notarized affidavit is not available: <section prefix="1">The retail price of the purchased motor vehicle offered for registration shall be determined as follows: <section prefix="a">Ninety percent (90%) of the manufacturer's suggested retail price of the vehicle with all equipment and accessories, standard and optional, and transportation charges; or </section><section prefix="b">Eighty-one percent (81%) of the manufacturer's suggested retail price of the vehicle with all equipment and accessories, standard and optional, and transportation charges in the case of new trucks of gross weight in excess of ten thousand (10,000) pounds; and </section></section><section prefix="2">The value of the vehicle offered in trade shall be the trade-in value, as established by the reference manual. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44483</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>