<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.635</section_number><catch_line>Osteoporosis prevention and education program -- Public education -- Powers of department. </catch_line><order_by>635</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Public Health shall establish, promote, and maintain a statewide multigenerational osteoporosis prevention and education program using available federal funds, state funds appropriated for that purpose, and other available funding. The program shall: <section prefix="a">Promote the public awareness of the causes of osteoporosis, options for prevention, the value of early detection, and treatment; and </section><section prefix="b">Increase health care provider awareness of national clinical guidelines related to the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of osteoporosis. </section></section><section prefix="2">The public education component of the program created in subsection (1) of this section shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">The cause and nature of osteoporosis; </section><section prefix="b">Risk factors; </section><section prefix="c">The role of oophorectomy and hysterectomy in the development of osteoporosis; </section><section prefix="d">The prevention of osteoporosis, including nutrition, physical exercise, and weight; </section><section prefix="e">Diagnostic procedures and appropriate indications for their use; </section><section prefix="f">The risks and benefits of hormone replacement therapy; </section><section prefix="g">Environment safety and injury prevention; and </section><section prefix="h">Availability of osteoporosis treatment services in the community. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department may consult, contract, or establish a cooperative relationship with local health departments, the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture Cooperative Extension Service, libraries, and community organizations to carry out the requirements of subsections (1) and (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The department may use existing publications, the Department for Public Health Web site, and the Kentucky e-Health Network to promote health care provider awareness of clinical practice guidelines related to the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of osteoporosis. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8447</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>