<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.1722</section_number><catch_line>I Support Veterans special license plate. </catch_line><order_by>1722</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application to the county clerk of the county of his or her residence, the owner or lessee of a motor vehicle registered under KRS 186.050(1) or (3)(a) may obtain an I Support Veterans special license plate. </section><section prefix="2">Each initial or renewal application for an I Support Veterans special license plate shall be subject to payment of the fees set forth in KRS 186.162 and the distribution and auditing requirements set forth in KRS 186.164. </section><section prefix="3">The EF portion of the fees collected under KRS 186.162 for an I Support Veterans special license plate shall be distributed to the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs and are hereby appropriated for purposes that support veterans. These funds shall be in addition to any other appropriations or resources available to the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs. </section><section prefix="4">The I Support Veterans special license plate shall be administered in the same manner as other special license plates as prescribed in KRS 186.162. </section><section prefix="5">The printing of the I Support Veterans special license plate shall not be contingent on any minimum number of applications. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 (see note) </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute takes effect on July 12, 2012. Its effective date was subject to a contingency, but the contingency has been removed. Section 5 of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 139, which is effective July 12, 2012, repeals 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 4, which established the contingency. Section 6 of 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 139 states, "KRS 186.162 and 186.1722, as created or amended by 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 10, relating to an I Support Veterans special license plate, shall be effective on the normal effective date for the legislation enacted at the 2012 Regular Session of the General Assembly." The normal effective date for that 2012 legislation is July 12, 2012. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>