<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="181" order_by="181">COUNTY AND CITY BRIDGES, TUNNELS, AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>181.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Bridge" includes the bridge and the approaches thereto; </section><section prefix="b">"Employee" includes agents, servants and independent contractors; </section><section prefix="c">"Owner" means any person having any title or interest in lands, structures, rights-of-way, franchises, easements or other interests in land; and </section><section prefix="d">"Streets" includes lanes and alleys. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in KRS 181.560 to 181.840, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Cost of bridge" as applied to a bridge acquired by purchase, includes the purchase price, cost of improvements, financing charges, interest during any period of disuse before completion of improvements and for a period of six (6) months after purchase or completion, cost of traffic estimates and of engineering and legal expenses, specifications and surveys, estimates of cost and of revenues, other expenses incident to determining the feasibility or practicability of the enterprise, and administrative and other expenses incident to financing and acquiring the bridge and placing it in operation; </section><section prefix="b">"Cost of bridge" as applied to a bridge to be constructed, includes the cost of construction, the cost of acquiring necessary land, property rights, easements and franchises, financing charges, interest during construction and for a period of six (6) months thereafter, cost of traffic estimates and of engineering and legal expenses, plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of cost and of revenues, other expenses incident to determining the practicability of the enterprise, and expenses incident to financing the constructing of the bridge and placing it in operation; and </section><section prefix="c">"Improvements" means repairs, replacements and additions to a bridge acquired by purchase which are deemed necessary to place the bridge in a safe and efficient condition for public use, when such improvements are ordered prior to the sale of bonds for acquisition of the bridge. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 166. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 19. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3037k-1, 3037L-1, 3235g-8. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5575</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>