<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.110</section_number><catch_line>Officers, employees, and agents of Cabinet for Health and Family Services and regional community programs for behavioral health, developmental and intellectual disabilities not to sell to or make contracts with institutions, facilities, or organizations under cabinet's control if conflict of interest involved.   </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No officer, employee, or agent of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, a regional community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability or a nonprofit corporation administering a regional community program for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability shall sell anything to any institution, facility, or organization under the control of the cabinet nor participate in selection, or in the award or administration of a contract supported by state or federal funds if a conflict of interest, real or apparent, would be involved. </section><section prefix="2">Such a conflict of interest would arise when: <section prefix="a">The employee, officer, or agent; </section><section prefix="b">Any member of his immediate family; </section><section prefix="c">His or her partner; or </section><section prefix="d">An organization which employs, or is about to employ, any of the above, has a financial or other interest in the firm selected for award. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 71, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 309, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 254, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 79, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (9). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 48. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40799</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>