<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.395</section_number><catch_line>Salary supplement for national board certified teachers.   </catch_line><order_by>395</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, a public school teacher, or a secondary teacher employed in a Kentucky Tech school or career and technical education program operated by the Department of Education, who has attained certification from the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards as of July 14, 2000, or thereafter shall receive an annual national board certification salary supplement of two thousand dollars ($2,000) for the life of the certificate. The supplement shall be added to: <section prefix="a">The teacher's base salary on the local board's single salary schedule and shall be considered in the calculation for contributions to the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System; or </section><section prefix="b">The state-employed teacher's base salary and shall be considered in the calculation for contributions to the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System. </section></section> If a nationally certified teacher becomes no longer employed as a classroom teacher or a teacher mentor in the field of his or her national certification, the supplement shall cease. <section prefix="2">A local board of education or the Department of Education shall request reimbursement for these purposes from the fund to support education excellence described in KRS 157.330. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 40, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 1, (9) at 626. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42219</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>