<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="267" order_by="267">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1912 </unit></structure><section_number>267.120</section_number><catch_line>Meetings -- Office -- Records -- Reports -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall meet when called by the president. The president shall call a meeting upon the written request of two (2) or more directors. The board shall have an office at the county seat, which shall be provided with all necessary furniture, stationery and records. The board shall keep complete records of its proceedings, which shall be at all times open to the inspection of the public. </section><section prefix="2">By April 1 of each year the board shall make a complete report of its acts during the previous year, showing the amount of money received and from what source, and the amount paid out and for what purpose. The report shall be spread upon its records and be open for public inspection. By April 1 of each year the board shall publish pursuant to KRS Chapter 424 a financial statement of the previous year, showing the amounts received, the date of receipt and from what source, and the amounts paid out, the date of disbursement and for what purposes. </section><section prefix="3">All expenses incurred by the board shall be taken out of drainage funds and not from any general funds of the county. </section></text><history>Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 181, effective June 16, 1966. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380-7. </history><metadata><effective>June 16, 1966</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>