<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.731</section_number><catch_line>Pilot projects to grant performance incentive funding to community corrections programs -- Annual calculations of cost savings of state funds. </catch_line><order_by>731</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission may: <section prefix="a">Approve up to five (5) pilot projects to grant performance incentive funding to community corrections programs in judicial circuits with high rates of targeted offenders who are ordered to serve a term of imprisonment; and </section><section prefix="b">Approve up to five (5) pilot projects to grant performance incentive funding to community corrections programs in judicial circuits with high rates of supervised individuals who are revoked for violations of their conditions of supervision and ordered to serve a term of imprisonment. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon development of an approved pilot project described in subsection (1)(a) of this section, the commission shall annually calculate: <section prefix="a">The percentage of targeted offenders in the judicial circuit for that pilot project who are convicted of a felony offense and sentenced to a term of imprisonment. This calculation shall be based on the fiscal year prior to the fiscal year in which the report is required pursuant to KRS 196.736. The baseline shall be the percentage of targeted offenders convicted and imprisoned for that judicial circuit in the fiscal year prior to the implementation of the pilot project; and </section><section prefix="b">Any state expenditures that have been avoided by reductions in the baseline percentage as calculated in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon development of an approved pilot project described in subsection (1)(b) of this section, the commission shall annually calculate: <section prefix="a">The percentage of supervised individuals in the judicial circuit for that pilot project who are revoked for violations of their conditions of supervision and ordered to serve a term of imprisonment. This calculation shall be based on the fiscal year prior to the fiscal year in which the report is required pursuant to KRS 196.736. The baseline revocation percentage shall be the percentage of revocations for that judicial circuit in the fiscal year prior to the implementation of the pilot project; and </section><section prefix="b">Any state expenditures that have been avoided by reductions in the revocation percentage as calculated in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.71, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>